14 years of struggle.
I have gone through a depression and a separation.
I got my "Eureka Moment".
I was standing at a Rejvfest in London when it suddenly came to me.
Damn, I see it, I know how to do it.
A few months later I lived in Bolivia.
Most things went wrong there.
I wanted to be so happy.
We were hours from a bankruptcy.
"Not a chance. No one wants to invest in such a company."
Lars Kristensson has invested everything in the realization of the entrepreneurial dream-
-He carried on since 2008. Although he does not look at himself as an entrepreneur.
That was never what I thought I would be.
I was necessarily.
And because I want to give my innovation to the world-
-If it was necessary to run a company and go the way I have gone.
Today, Lars Kristensson is the man behind the air search site Aviono who is on its way to-
-Take up the struggle with industry giants such as momondo, air travel.se and expedia.
At home in the apartment in Malmö, he talks about the long road to Afiono's birth.
As a teenager he created his first computer game.
And when he studied computer science in Lund and discovered AI, he found home.
Suddenly I got together all the parts I am interested in.
I have an easy time for math.
Has easy for programming and the logical.
I am interested in philosophy and love people and psychology.
Actually, it is most important to me: people and psychology.
But to get together computer science, math, people and psychology-
-Do not be so easy until I finally landed in AI.
Before he had completed the study-
-They he had headhunted to one of Sweden's largest gaming companies-
-But ended some time later for ethical reasons.
He did not want to make products-
-As was aimed at getting users to never want to leave their screens.
He himself has not played for a second since then.
Instead, he ended up in the travel industry and quickly discovered how inflexible-
-The aviation sites on the net worked.
But changing was difficult to technically and the industry was conservative.
In the end, after scratching it for so long ...
... I saw it.
I got my "Eureka Moment".
I was standing at a Rejvfest in London when it suddenly came to me.
Damn, I see it, I know how to do it.
I sat down on an oil barrel, pondered and structured my thoughts.
What I cracked was how to get over the restrictions-
-In the underlying layers.
How you can make completely open searches.
The search technique I sketched out makes it possible to search in free dimensions in endless space.
Free dimensions and endless space
—power that it became possible to make the open and flexible searches-
-When previously been impossible.
Like searching for destinations with a particular climate-
-Combined with other characteristics such as family -friendly or restaurant -proof.
He tried to implement his innovation at one of the industry giants-
-When today belongs to Aviono's competitors, but even there he encountered resistance.
Instead, he was headhunted again, this time to South America.
A few months later I lived in Bolivia.
And tried to lead a development team there instead.
It didn't go so well.
-Usch ... -What happened there?
No ... most things went wrong there.
It sounded like gold and green forests when I got there.
I got a fantastic offer, but ...
No, there wasn't much that worked.
The money that would have existed was not there, the organization did not work ...
No.
Most things didn't work.
So that project did not go well.
Did you discover it pretty quickly?
Not fast enough.
And I kept fighting, because I wanted to so gladly-
-That it would go well.
So I fought myself.
But the South American adventure was not in vain.
Within the framework of the project in Bolivia, Lars Kristensson announced a competition.
To design a flight search site.
Halfway into the competition, a contribution came in that did not resemble anything else.
Strange, odd ... until I saw it.
Until I saw through what he had done.
Whoever the person was, he had gone much deeper into his design-
-Ever I have ever seen someone else do.
He went completely outside the box-
-Ad all the requirements of the competition, but redefined the entire structure of the design-
-And solved actual user problems at a depth I've never seen before.
I was so deeply impressed and fascinated that I wrote to him.
"Hello. I see what you do. Who are you?"
It turned out to be Anton.
It was the well -qualified Russian interaction designer Anton Tyulenev.
While the project in South America went to hell, Anton and I couldn't stop discussing.
We couldn't stop saving and talking.
So I finally went home to Malmö.
I was very worn and broken.
Now I shit in this, I thought.
Now I do something else.
But why did you think so?
It went to hell in Bolivia-
-But you had found your future couple horse.
Absolutely.
But I had already made several attempts.
I had been fighting for several years.
-And ... -you were exhausted.
Yes, I was absolutely exhausted.
He had simply gone into the wall and decided to put down the plans-
-To start your own company.
But Anton Tyulenev thought differently.
He didn't listen.
Instead he stood at a whiteboard-
-And showed what he had been thinking about.
"What are you thinking about this?"
He triggered me so I started sketching on how to do it.
So he looked at me: "You can't stop."
Then followed a couple of months of persuasion on his part.
"Shit in everything that has been and everyone else," he told me.
"We're doing this."
"You and I do this. We are two of the most competent in our respective areas"-
-"Who the hell can beat us? We're doing this."
It had been in 2015 before the company Aveiono founded-
-A Lars Kristensson and Anton Tyulenev in Malmö.
Then the work of creating-
-This, in their words, would be "the world's best flight search site".
Three years and a first investment round later-
-Kunde An audience beta site will be launched January 2018.
Then we were it for a long time in beta to test.
We wanted sharp data and users, so we tested and ited for quite a long time.
And finally launched Aviono December 1.0, 2019.
Sharp version.
We felt we had the concept in place.
Then we would go out and lift marketing money-
-and do our go-to-market ...
And we had intended to close it in March 2020.
But the first few weeks in March 2020, the entire travel industry closed down.
Completely.
-Pandemic.
-Yes.
It was hard.
Like running into a wall.
But...
After I had landed from the first shock for a week's time-
-I started slowly realizing ...
Wait.
This doesn't have to be completely negative.
What dampened the panic was that the fall height was not so great.
You had just started.
Could one use time right it would be possible to get out stronger-
-If with more infected competitors after the pandemic.
But then they have to survive.
And for that, money was required.
That was the problem.
We had already done our launch-
-And ended liquidity, so we were hours from a bankruptcy.
Literally.
When we got the solution in place-
- We were less than twelve hours from the board meeting that would have decided on bankruptcy.
Old and new investors saved the company from bankruptcy.
And with new money-
-Cheat development of the service continue.
Aviono survived even though pandemin-
-Gleaned longer than most people could imagine.
During the years of struggle through the pandemic, I finally saw that it opened up.
The vaccine works, until spring it opens up.
We planned for it, put up our strategy.
We were ready to run our go-to market.
Now we drive the one we would have done when the pandemic came.
We are ready.
First we pick in 10 million-
-As a first step to finally come out and be visible.
Said and done.
We signed up a "Corp company" to help us.
And so on.
Everything was rigged to run go-to-market in spring-
-In connection with everything opening up.
Aviono 2.0 was launched in December 2021.
But by the planned marketing campaign-
-And upset in the winter of 2022 there was nothing.
February 24, the Russian tank rolled into Ukraine and the war was a fact.
And suddenly everything changed.
Again.
After all, Anton is Russian.
And lived in Moscow.
And most people in our development team sat in Russia.
There the Corp company backed down.
"Not a chance. No one wants to invest in such a company."
We got to restructure the company fundamentally.
Today no one sits in Russia.
Anton has been allowed to leave and relocate-
-We have had to reorganize the company ...
-So that it ... -has Anton left Russia?
Yes.
And the developers have either left Russia or the company.
-Fann's Russian invested money in the company?
-No.
No, we do not have that.
Now it's "Clean", but it's been a process.
It had been late autumn by 2022, the situation for the company was again critical.
But with the smallest possible margin, Aviono survived again.
During the winter and spring, the struggle continued to keep the nose above the surface of the water.
A situation that has become a normal state for the company.
In the autumn of 2023, Lars Kristensson contacted EFN.
Something had happened in Aviono.
Now I will meet Lars Kristensson at his office in central Malmö.
It's been almost a year since we were last seen.
The question is: How has it been?
Most were giving up at the end of the year.
Our accountant had given up, my parents had given up, that is.
-The most people were probably prepared for a bankruptcy.
-But it didn't.
-No.
-Where do you stand today?
Now we see an explosive increase in our site-
-A fantastic growth right now.
We haven't come to the Breakven yet.
So the next step is to secure up-
-The last funding needed for us to become a profitable company.
-When have you intended to be according to plan?
-When the forecast looks now ...
... we will be profitable before the end of next year.
What became a turnaround was when one of the employees managed to find a technical solution-
-This meant that it was possible to capture resiliented internet surfers considerably faster.
It was about being visible high on Google, without having to pay big money for it.
It has been a complete breakthrough.
When we felt confident that this-
-really was an opening, we started developing it and launched at the end of May-
-A first, sharp version of the solution.
Only the first few days in June we got the very first digits.
When we saw them, I and Anton cheered, because then we knew this was going to work.
This will go away and go well.
But can we say that Aviono has survived now?
I think we can do that, actually.
We will reach Break-Even as well, we are still not funded to Break-ven.
That is what we are working on now, but I think we can say that Aviono has survived.
-I think this will succeed.
-You have struggled incredibly much with this ...
... it is evident from the report, you have gone on some bangs.
Has it been worth the personal price you have had to pay?
I said a number of years ago that no matter how it goes, it will never be worth it.
-And I'll probably not change the story.
-It means you hadn't done it?
-I hadn't done it.
-But now you have done it, so now you drive?
However, in contrast to it, it will never be worth it-
-I have I over and over again re -evaluated and looked at: Is it worth continuing?
But based on each given point on the road-
-Have always the most rational and best choice has been to continue.
How big do you think Aviono can be?
"Can be?"
It can be any size.
We are constructed-
-To be able to take over the market.
Then it takes so much more to be the biggest.
But in terms of construction; structurally aviono-
-Factically rigged to become the biggest player in the world on this.