My name is Max Halbwachs and I am a PhD student in the Versam- project
-Which is about regional collaboration processes.
In my research I look at the collaboration of private employers-
-With municipalities and regions when it comes to sustainable commuting.
I'll tell you more about this inside the elevator.
61 percent of Swedes live within 10 kilometers from their workplace.
Still, many people choose to take the car there. Employers may have great impact-
-To switch to a more sustainable mobility.
They can take measures that facilitate, for example, cycle, walk or go collectively.
But usually no such measures are taken.
Therefore, our research will investigate how Sweden's municipalities and regions-
-Can get more workplaces to participate in the transition.
This is to be done by identifying the “intermediate” actors-
-What spreads knowledge and ideas about work commuting.
For example, it can be associations or corporate networks.
The aim of the research is to provide the municipalities and regions tool-
—while, they can support such an intermediate-
-And thus facilitate regional cooperation.
If you want to know more, hear from you!