Hi, my name is Lina Lundgren and I am project manager I-
-Heart failure readmission prediction harp-
-A project within the University's focus area Health Innovation.
In this project, we work with information -driven care.
That is a way to contribute to solutions that can help-
-Health care in its transformation.
Join us and I'll tell you more.
Heart failure affects about two percent of Sweden's population.
Many patients are in hospitals several times for a short period of time.
In order for healthcare personnel to be able to take the right decision-
-How they take in a large amount of information.
With the help of AI tools, historical information can be compiled-
-And contribute to a risk assessment.
In the Harp project we investigate in the project team how we can develop-
-A such AI tool, how its output should be presented to user-
-And how it should be implemented to function in daily healthcare activities.
The project is part of CAISR Health and is implemented together-
-With Cambio and Region Halland.
Do you want to know more? Get in touch!