There are many different tools you can connect to a clearing saw
and today I thought I'd try one like this.
It is a steel brush that must be connected to the trimmer and what do you use it for?
Well, to clear slabs and paving
that have become overgrown with grass and moss.
Here in front of my house, I have exactly that.
It was paved many years ago and over time, grass and moss have
slowly worked their way up and taken over, so now it's on the border.
It's like a cross between lawn and paving.
But will see if this steel brush works.
You have to think about a few security requirements.
It says a maximum of 10,000 revolutions per minute, and
you won't reach that when it comes to the clearing saw.
And then: use eye protection.
It feels quite natural too.
You don't want a loose wire to fly off and get stuck in the wrong place.
Start by switching to the right gear.
This would fit and use for the
protection you have for saw blades and grass blades.
But I'm putting on the guard that's for the trimmer line because I suspect
there's going to be some stuff going around with this.
The next step is to rake the paving as much as possible
and remove as much rock as possible, so I suspect it
will splash this unit down and then Happi can go in.
This is not an activity that you do
together with the dog, but she has to wait while I do this.
This is my first time trying
this so hopefully it goes as intended.
Here we go!
Yes, it was definitely a dirty job.
Perhaps it should have been done before there was so much soil on top.
But now I've moved on, so I'll take and rake away and sweep and see the result.
I'm guessing that maybe one more round is needed, but pretty promising.
I had a problem. I didn't really know.
Because when this paving has gone this far,
you don't know how big the paving is, but think that the edges only had soil.
But then you start shoveling a little, or
brushing and then it turns out that there is stone underneath as well.
But like I said, it's not easy.
Now we will see the result soon.
Far from perfect, but 90% better anyway
I'd say.
Had I had the waters -
I haven't put the water on yet -
as there is still a risk of frost.
So I had gone over this with the high pressure after.
But how it turns out will come up on
my Instagram, once it has some water on this too.
Then maybe a little post-work is required.
It's hard to see in this cloud of dust that
you work in, but this is how it worked anyway.
You can see more videos about clearing saws here if you are interested.
Thanks for watching! See you again soon.