I watched several different videos on installing particleboard before tackling my own.
I still managed to find a number of mistakes that they didn't cover in these videos, so
I thought I'd show a little again which five mistakes I made and which ones I avoided.
One thing that is easy to miss is that
chipboards have an upside and a downside.
I don't know what role they play, but it's just as well to do the right thing.
A near-death experience you can avoid
if you think about it - is that the discs become slippery when you have them lying in a pile.
Don't try to jump down on a stack of discs
or take a big step between the joists on a stack like this.
It could end badly.
One of the first and most important steps
when laying particleboard is to get the first row perfectly nailed.
If it started to warp a little, in any direction, you will get a fault that will
propagate throughout the floor and you will also have to fight with it
every new row you start with and the fault will
always be with you and you can't get rid of it .
To get the first row straight, you can
lace the floor and above all make sure that the short sides lie tightly against each other.
Are they completely tight so they don't miss anything.
So the rows will be straight they just need to be adjusted laterally.
One mistake I made here was that I started with the wrong page.
As you can see, these are chipboards. And if you see, they are
on one side, it is a batten that lies
close to the joists, while the other comes as a lip from above.
You must of course have the lip that lies down against the bars outwards at all times.
Then you glue it directly to the floor and you avoid the problems I ran into
trying to get this lip under the previous board.
This means that when you have screwed it and glued it.
If you have waited a day, there may be
glue residue or something else in between, which makes it completely hopeless to get it in there.
That's why you have to check each and every disc you place so that
it's free underneath before you start hitting it.
Because once you've put on glue and start hammering in
the disc, it's not easy to remove it and fix it afterwards.
And above all, even if it succeeds, it's very messy with all the glue.
So start with the right side out.
It's not very difficult, it's just
that you have the right side up on the disc and make sure that the lip down - is outwards the one
you put against the new discs.
One point I missed in the chipboard videos I saw
was how to join the corners.
To put one long side against another long side.
It's just a matter of pressing and it usually works quite easily.
But what they don't show
is how they do it to get both the long side and the short side to be tight together.
For the pros, it seems it's just a matter of
throwing the discs there and maybe stomping and kicking them a bit and they end up right.
It hasn't been that easy for me.
I have therefore manufactured a hangover with
the same function as you use when laying
parquet or click flooring.
And this hangover makes it possible to knock the disc there.
It is not possible to knock on the real sides of the board because they are chipboards.
It is very easy to ruin the edges.
The batten on these chipboards and you also have to think about that when you handle them.
If you put them on the short side when you
bump, you will immediately destroy this little chipboard batten.
Another mistake you can make, which in and
of itself you learn quite quickly and avoid, is to apply the glue in the right order.
If you start by gluing
all the batten edges, you will keep smearing the glue on your hands.
Therefore, I put the glue on the one
that is stuck first and then I glue on the disc that
is to be put there. And you do it in the right order.
In this way, you avoid getting so much glue on your fingers.
And when you have to push the disc there,
you also have the glue under the rules, which makes it slide quite easily.
If you pull it back and forth a little,
the glue spreads out and then you push it there.
And as is so often the case when I put these
discs in anyway, it doesn't go right into place,
but that's when I pick out my little hangover.
I made the hangover from a piece of waste wood from another chipboard.
Corresponding seam on the one on the board and then I have nailed
or screwed on a piece of chipboard and a block to be able to tap.
You don't have to touch, you shouldn't touch
very hard, it's just that you have power in the right direction.
It's pretty hopeless to get power
in the right direction otherwise with these discs if you're going to try with manual power.
And like I said, you can't hit the clean
edge as it is because it ruins it.
And the goal is to get
the boards in so tightly together that glue penetrates between them.
And finally make sure to get the short side tight.
Here you can see that it
doesn't go fast, but it comes so slowly and slides in and then
finally you see the glue push up when it's in place for real.
There comes the glue.
Another mistake you can make that I have made here and before
is not having a damp cloth to wipe off the glue.
Do not wipe off the glue.
Then you will need to sand it off when it hardens.
And if you do as I do here, use a small scrap piece to
remove the glue, it's easy that you'll be satisfied.
At the end of the working day, you leave the piece of wood and then it is glued to the floor.
Mistake number five that I've made a few
times is trusting my eye gauge a little too much.
I screwed the chipboards into the joists.
Three screws in each rule except where you have a joint.
There should be four screws in the chipboard on each rule next to the joint.
And if you trust the eye gauge, you think that this is the rule,
and then it turns out that when the screw is tightened, it
just spins in the air. It's not a disaster
but you shouldn't do what I did here.
To guess that "the rule is enough on
this side" but do as I do on this film.
Have a straightedge of some kind so you
can lay out so you know where it should sit.
Because it is easy to mistake where the rule
is somewhere and it is unnecessary to be annoyed.
Putting it wrong puts the screws wrong.
If you got anything out of this video
at all, please give me a thumbs up, making movies is more fun.
And if you want to keep
learning from my mistakes, please subscribe to this channel.
Have a great time and see you again soon!