The slope of a staircase should be a maximum of 46 degrees.
But it depends on what the area of ​​use is.
The most important thing is to get the angles right. I do this so as not to make mistakes when transferring from a drawing.
To get the right angle at the bottom, I use the same height as the beam and floorboards at the top of the stairs.
Then just cut to both angles and see that it has become right.
And it is spot on.
When the first piece is right I transfer the angles to the other side. So they become identical.
The best step height is 17-18 cm and here I make a template to get it just right.
It is important that the steps become equally high so that you do not stumble on the stairs.
I measured the height from the floor  to the floor in the attic. With twelve steps, the step height becomes 18.3 cm.
And it's so wide I saw the template bit.
Then I make a jig to get the steps exactly at the same angle.
I start by attaching the template piece to the step height so that it has the same angle as the underside of the side
piece.
Then I have a sacrificial bit and a support piece that I attach so that it will be a sledge that can slide on the sidepiece.
To get the right distance, I use the circular saw plus a piece of junk wood with the same thickness as the steps.
If you want the exact fit, if it is going to be really nice stair, then subtract the double thickness of the blade.
I am building a staircase for the machine room and it will be much easier with a little play. That's why I ignore the fin.
I set the depth of the saw blade to fifteen millimeters - one third of the thickness of the sidepieces.
The sacrificial pieces can be thrown away.
I am now making a beginner's mistake that it will take me a while to discover.
See if you discover it before me ...
It is now that I suddenly realize my mistake.
You may have noticed it earlier. Look here:
I have ticked off what should be the cut off. But sawn on the wrong side all the time.
But since one piece is done and I've come halfway with the other, I'm not going to start over.
I adjust the error afterwards. It can be solved, I have figured that out.
A bit frustrating when making an instructional video and making the most basic mistakes yourself.
But - you might not do the same now.
So – mistake fixed.
Since the distance between the steps is correctt all the way, the stairs need only be adjusted at the top.
Then I pre-drill for the screws that will secure the steps.
and countersink the holes for the screws that will sit against the wall.
As the color dries, I start to cut the steps.
I use the same thickness on the steps as for the sidepieces.
I think it will be the best - and it will be sturdy too.
Besides, I don't have to count on the width. Thinner steps cannot handle wide stairs.
Now I make 75 cm wide steps and the thickness is no problem.
As you can see, the top step is a little too long, but I saw it so it fits perfectly.
As you can see, I have attached the steps with only one screw in the side facing out from the wall.
Why – I will show you in a minute.
To secure the stairs, I fasten it with two screws at the top.
The stairs are in place but not yet finished.
I'll make it nicer by changing the screws to wooden plugs.