It's been almost five years since I planted river crayfish (Astacus astacus) in the pond.
I planted 200 river crayfish, about 50/50 males and females.
The reason for having so many males is genetic diversity.
In recent years I have fished pretty hard on the breeding crayfish. Especially the males
because they have become really big and it is important to keep after them
so that they do not eat the fry,
Tonight, it is now mid-June, Im planning to do a little test fishing
to see how it looks.
When I recover the cages tomorrow, I have no idea if there will be any crayfish in them.
It may be that they are scaling now and when the crayfish are hiding down in their holes
unprotected without shells they do not go into the cages. Then there will be no crayfish.
Another reason why you do not fish crayfish in June but traditionally in
August. It is that for every scar change, the crayfish grow about 10 percent.
and you want the growth over the summer.
You do not harvest  carrots when they are small, but wait until they grow larger
if you want a big harvest.
So...
We'll see how it looks tomorrow.
As usual, I bait with Frolic.
But I only put out four cages this time.
Then we'll see how it goes.
The reason for the bait boxes is that it will be a little more difficult
for the crayfish to access the bait
so they stay longer in the cages.
I only have four cages so it goes pretty fast.
Apparently I had five cages.
Then I put a little loose bait in this and we will see if there will be anything.
I can't bother to go up and get another bait box.
Frolic "Fresh Ox" - someone asked me what kind I used.
Almost every time I post a movie about the pond or the crayfish
someone will write "what a dirty water you have".
I am fully aware of this, but if you have a pond with natural clay bottom without canvas –
and crayfish digging holes. You will have  muddy water.
I have reconciled to the idea.
The light starts to fadel.
And tomorrow I will see if there is anything in the cages.
Hopefully there will be crayfish of different sizes.
It will be exciting to see if those born in the pond have come up in size.
\
It's morning and it's time to pick up the cages.
First cage - just two small crayfish.
It may be that the larger mudbugs
changes shells at a slightly different time than the small ones.
Here it looked a little better - somewhat bigger crayfish.
I have a theory that crayfish of different sizes are found in different parts of the pond.
But I have no documentation on this yet.
There are several details that separate the river crayfish from the signal crayfish.
If you are offered river crayfish and are a little unsure I can show some of them.
Here we have a river crayfish.
Firstly:
The crayfish has no white spot in the fold
but rather a little red dot.
But it is not certain that you can see it when the crayfish are cooked.
but something you can always feel is if you drag your finger between the main shield and the back shield.
Then the river has spikes.
Right here
there are small spikes, the signal crayfish don't have them.
Another way is to look at the claws.
Signal crayfish usually has wider claws.
and additionally
- it might be difficult to see if you can't compare -
The river crayfish has thinner claws than the signal crayfish.
This is how you can tell if it is a male or female.
This is seen on the underside.
Here you can see that there is no extra pair of legs after the walking legs,
The males have that.
Sp this is a female.
So she's going back.
During the summer - from May to September.
I feed the crayfish once a week with feed peas.
The feed peas have several advantages.
They are pretty cheap and they sink in the water.
and when they start to go bad after a while, they do not remain and deteriorate the quality of the water.
They float up and flow into the beach
and there the birds eat them.
So there will be no problem with eutrophication in the pond due to overfeeding-
In addition, feed peas have a high protein content. Which is good for the crayfish.
Goldfish like them too.
If you want to follow life here on the farm, please subscribe to this channel.
If you like the video - give me a thumbs up.
Have a great time and we'll see you again soon.