The art of moving to the country.
Have you ever thought about moving to the country?
It's been almost ten years since I took that step - and I haven't regretted it.
Time goes by and everything does not go as you imagined.
I was going to do a little series about what it's like to be a beginner in the country.
This first part will be an introduction. Then I intend to address other topics such as:
Economy,
how to support yourself,
buying a farm
Utensils, neighbors and much more. I have many ideas.
If you come up with more ideas then write in the comments and will put it
on my to-do list.
That said - it's been almost exactly ten years now since i bought the farm.
and everything has not become as I imagined.
But much has nevertheless fallen into place.
In the beginning when I had the farm - when I had just moved here full time.
I took a course in food crafts
One of the first tasks was to paint with watercolors.
You would show with a picture what you thought the future would look like.
Much has actually become as I planned.
If you look at the map here – don´t get stuck in the artistic qualities.
I know it's a masterpiece. But see beyond that.
See what it represents instead.
In this picture I have included the dreams I had for the future.
You can see here: the bees,
The pond with the crayfish cultivation - it was not dug then.
The forest is gone and instead I have crops.
Rhubarb cultivation and apple cultivation. You see the hens too
I even got a bus stop.
One of the ideas I had.
All of these things have actually come true.
But, not everything has become exactly as I thought.
I had three more hopes:
That I would be rich, powerful and an amazing lover.
Everything will not be as you imagined,
but one in three is not so bad.
That said, this is supposed to be a series about what it's like to be a beginner in the country.
There is a lot of television being made and a lot is being written about how fantastic it is in the country.
But they only show the sunny side.
With this series I'm planning to give you the whole picture, from my experience anyway.
and bring both - the good - and the bad. (You may remember that TV series.)
I will also adress the problems, it will not be exactly as you planned.
There are drawbacks to living in the countryside.
Mainly practical: there are long distances
you usually pay higher taxes when you live in the countryside
and you usually get worse service.
There is worse public transport
Worse - or at least longer to medical care.
The time to get an ambulance here is considerably longer than in Stockholm.
That is a part of the decision to move to the country.
There are still plenty of qualities.
The great quality of living in the countryside is freedom.
You have freedom and a huge amount of opportunities to do the things you want to do yourself
and that's hard to do in town.
If you live in a residential area it can even be difficult to have chickens if the neighbors complain.
Here you can get chickens - start beekeeping without anyone protesting.
You can get lots of animals if you are interested.
If you are interested in cultivation you can do it on a variety of scales.
You can have your little garden where you grow your own apple tree
or you can farm on a big scale.
It all depends on what you want to do yourself.
If you, like me, are beginners in the country, it requires a lot of change.
Above all to think about
to start thinking about things you didn't do before.
For example, there are no property managers.
If a pipe freezes in the barn during the winter, you have to deal with it.
and you have to deal with it right away.
If an animal gets sick or injured then you have to deal with that situation.
And you have to deal with it right away.
When I moved I thought that it would be a more stress free environment in the country.
And it is in many ways-
Especially because I decide for myself what to do, and when to do it.
By and large.
But when things happen, you have to deal with it. There is no one else to turn to.
Not in the first stage anyway. You have to take responsibility yourself.
This can be seen as a disadvantage - or an advantage.
The advantage is that you feel that you are in control of this yourself.
This is also a big difference between having a holiday home in the countryside
Spending a few months in the summer cottage is not at all the same thing as living in the country.
Above all, you will notice the difference during the winter months.
When you have maybe six months where most of the day consists of compact darkness.
My first winter out here – one of the first steps was setting up exterior lighting.
So that you could see something outside the windows.
It is easy to feel claustrophobic otherwise.
You also have to get used to dealing with loneliness.
I have had no problems with that. But if you are a very social person
it may be a struggle.
In the summer you can have visitors all the time
not so many want to visit the farm in January.
However, what you have - which you do not have in town - is the neighbors.
The neighbors! I know pretty much all the neighbors here. I didn't do that in Stockholm.
There I hardly knew who lived in the door next door.
Here you have some form of contact with just about every neighbor
and it's a real community.
We know each other and we hang out. Not every day, not every week, but regularly enough
so that you feel: If something happens I can call the neighbors.
Neighbors are more important than authorities, municipalities, police and so on.
It is the neighbors who are first in place if something happens.
Like when the barn was burning.
Then the police and fire brigade did not come first - it was the neighbors.
This is a small taste of this series. I'm planning for it to come out
once a week. The goal is a new episode every weekend.
If you like the idea, give me a thumbs up
and if you want to follow life on the farm and this series, please subscribe to this channel.
Bye – see you again soon.