"Why should we know this?" Say you maybe when the teacher pulls out some old text that was written hundreds of years ago.
The question may initially seem reasonable, but you - even if it sounds strange - were not created when you were born.
You were born into a world that has been shaped by people who have thought and thought things for thousands of years. It is very good.
Therefore, every person who is born does not have to reinvent the wheel and mobile phone, or come from the ground up how to build houses or bake bread.
It is already fixed. By reading old texts we gain an understanding of the world around us.
We get smart fucking who knows things. Those you listen to.
Some call it general education. You can also see it as a way to avoid appearing as an idiot.
Literature history is the story of how different texts have changed society and how society has changed the way we write texts.
Thus, by learning about literary history, you automatically learn a lot about society and thus also about yourself.
You become one of those smart bastards - a one you listen to.
The written language has not always existed. First, people just talked to each other and then they started writing down important things.
It was pretty short things you wrote down. Name of a person who had died, how many horses you had or otherwise important to remember.
The writing has, like the advantage that the words even live on after someone dies.
After a while it developed there and texts became longer and longer. You started writing and reading texts to find out how other people think and what other people think about things.
People finally started reading and writing without any other direct reason than it was fun.
You realized that with reading it was so nice that you could call such texts that you just read for pleasure for "fiction".
You can divide literary history into something called epoch.
"Epoch" is about the same thing as time period.
A man who lived in the eleven centuries lived during an era called the Middle Ages.
This they had no idea whatsoever that they did because it is a name that we have found afterwards.
A simple epoch for literary history looks much like this: