Here we will look at how to tag a cushion with wetting and rolling technology.
The film is suitable for the craft theme "something to sit on".
To wetting with rolling technology so you need
something to roll in.
It can be a bamboo, a yoga mat or bubble plastic.
So we also need a round rod, a little longer than the yoga mat/bubble plastic.
Rubber band,
soap
or hand soap.
The best thing is really olive soap.
Both for hands and wool.
A Denkese Bottle,
A spray bottle.
A funnel can be good.
Deciliter dimensions, tape measure, paper and pen.
And a washing bowl.
So we also need carded wool.
If we have a drawing for our "something to sit on" and want a round cushion for it.
With the diameter of 340 millimeters.
Then we need to make a calculation, to see how wide we will put out the wool.
Wool shrinks when we swallow it.
So to know how large the surface we are going to lay out the wool, we need to figure out the size of finished pillow
Plus fifty percent.
With a cushion that is to be thirty -four centimeters wide
Will we need to put out the wool fifty centimeters.
We produce what we should roll in and a tape measure.
And measures out a square with the sides fifty centimeters.
It is important that we leave a bit out to the edge, so that the wool is a bit in.
Here we can see a schematic picture of what is shrinkage and what gets ready cushion.
Then we will put out the wool.
With a light but firm grip we can pull out the fibers and get just a big "flare" of wool.
We put the wool with the fibers in the same direction, next to each other, to the desired width.
The second row we put the wool a little up on the former, a little wrap, like tiles on one roof.
When we put out the entire first layer.
We add one to layer with wool, on top the first layer, in the opposite direction.
With the fibers at ninety degrees angle to the first layer.
In the third layer, the wool is laid out with the fibers in the same direction as the first layer.
And so we continue, layer by layer and put out the wool, in opposite directions.
Here we can see the technique of how we pull out the wool.
We can't hold too hard, but we have to release a little.
Then it goes easy.
Several thin layers are better than few thick, for good quality.
We need to post about six layers.
By lightly pressing the wool, we can get a feeling for how thick the cushion will be.
Hot water and soap or soap, which is basic and helps to open up the epidermis mountains, found on the wool,
facilitates the felting.
We mix to three deciliters of water
And about a teaspoon of soap.
We also prepare our Denks bottle.
The beam on the spray bottle needs to be set, to a soft beam.
Then we spray around the whole wool.
It can be nice to change hand sometimes.
All three deciliters are sprayed over the wool.
Then we will roll in the wool.
We fold over the piece of extra support we have.
To protect the wool, when we put on the round rod.
Gently we start rolling.
We lift over the round rod so that the wool remains.
And then we put on rubber bands, to hold the roll together, when we are going to roll.
In the beginning you need to roll gently.
Move your hands out and in along the roll.
So that there is even pressure.
Roll for about two minutes, before opening the roll.
Also it needs to be done carefully,
In the beginning when the wool has not felled together properly.
We can still see that it has started to fell a little.
So we move to the sink.
Tie on an apron, to protect the clothes from garbage water.
So we wet the wool with more soapy water.
It is possible to fold the wool on the edges and "glue" with soap water, for more even edges.
We roll everything together.
Now you can print a little more.
For the wool holds together better now.
We put on the rubber cords.
And continues to roll.
And moves your hands out and in.
With a little more pressure than before.
Then we roll about two more minutes before we open again.
When we open, we see that the wool has felled further.
Now we will roll about two minutes from each direction.
Front and rear, from behind and front.
From right to left and left to right.
But we can turn everything around so we can roll from the same direction.
So we start by turning it in the opposite direction.
And dinks on plenty of soapy water.
Then continue to roll with pressure.
Press properly because it is the pressure that causes the wool to be together.
We need to fill with soapy water.
Several Denken bottles will be needed.
About one tablespoon soap to five deciliters of water.
When we have rolled for two minutes, from all four directions, it is dax to turn the wool.
And do the same procedure on the other side.
Roll from the front, from the front, right to left, left to right.
But first on with plenty of soapy water.
Roll with a pressure from all four sides.
Fill with soap water in between.
When we roll the wool at the end it is really wet.
And the last time we open up, the wool has felled well, well,
to a cohesive textile.
If you want the wool to shrink further, but you do not want to roll more, you can rub it, pick it against a washboard,
Or against the grooves in her.
Another tip is to throw the wool in the ground a few times out.
So it is very important to wash out the wool at the end.
Wash out the soap and any dirt that has remained in the wool.
We use olive soap or unpainted hand soap to wash out soap scent.
And for it to be gentle on our hands when we wash.
Then it is important to rinse to the water is perfectly clear.
We measure the wool and see that it is a little too big still.
Then we can do so that we can shock the wool,
In alternating giant warm and giant cold water.
Then the wool shrinks further.
Now that we measure the wool, we see that it has shrunk to thirty -five centimeters.
Then we hug properly and put the wool on the dryer.
Also clean everything you used, so that it can be used many times by several.
Wool is a natural fiber, the sheep's hair, so wool can be composted.
It turns into soil.
And not only that also increases the humus content in the soil,
that helps the plants grow.
And the plants they collect carbon dioxide from the air, so wool on the compost is good for the environment in several ways.
When the cushion has dried, it can be cut to the desired size and shape.
We take the help of a passer to get a round cushion.
The cushion can then be decorated in different ways.
For example, using a template and textile print
directly on the cushion or on a case.
Or with dry turf by stencil.
See links to the instructional films in the comment text below.
There you will also find a link to a brief written instruction for this film.
Like and subscribe to find out news and to support the work.
Warm thanks to everyone who contributed to this movie.
Learn more about the properties of the wool and why wool can be felt.
In the movie Ull a natural fiber from animals.