My teachers and classmates must have taken that I did not
was feeling something good.
I have had problems with self -harm and such and it was
Not something I hid because I wanted people to
Know so I couldn't say I needed help.
But I needed help and I want people to understand.
Yes, the doctors, they said I was exhausted, but they put
No diagnosis on it.
I had a lot of performance anxiety and then became
that I thought exactly all the time about what I did and how
it would be submitted and every little thing would be
Perfect for me.
And to think so all the time was not sustainable for me
And my feeling.
So it became very, very difficult in the end.
I was exhausted.
They just thought I was tired of school and happened in school.
Because I was not at school and I was up on
The nights and slept in the days.
So my biological clock was not there.
When I was home that I really had shit.
It was the lowest point in my life I would say.
It was as I said before that I go about high school so will
I kill myself and I have met people who say that
It's extreme.
But it really was.
It was like that.
Then there are no points.
I can't, I can't handle it to high school.
So yeah, I've never felt worse.
Partly I was glad I was home and I
let go of school, which made me like satisfied
in the whole.
But how do you really feel when you sit at home,
isolated and playing TV games on at night and up in the days
Or sleeps in the days at night?
How are you doing?
I think it says a lot of my feeling.
After all, it was on the summer holidays between the six and seven.
We used to go out to our cabin by the Dalälven and swim.
But I was just lying inside.
I couldn't be able to be out and bathe and
It was well where we noticed that something was wrong.
It is hard not to think negatively because one does the same
thing every day.
You wake up, stay home and go to bed basically.
You meet the same people and you see that it is going well
for them.
It went well for my siblings to go to school, so why went
that good for me?
And it becomes more negative the more
It is built up.
I felt the worst.
So I even stopped going on the handball that was one of
my favorite chores before because I had kind of not peppy
to do something.
I felt completely emotional and not yes, it didn't feel
Like I wanted to do something.
My self -image deteriorated I would say.
And thus my self -respect.
All this is connected.
And to see everyone else go to school, my siblings,
go to school and see my siblings become annoyed and
confused that I was not at school creates a
confusion in me.
There is something human about comparing yourself to others.
It feels like everyone does.
I think it is quite natural to do it and
I compared myself to everyone around me, with my siblings,
With my classmates, with my friends and such.
But for me there were.
It was a time when it went over from comparing to
That you went.
It was against someone, that was all the time became one
Competition against everyone.
And I know it even now that I've finished high school.
But it feels like my job is too bad or that I
performs too bad or that I am not really where I
want to be because everyone else is like,
Everyone else is so good.
Although not true.
I often asked mom what it was wrong, why I didn't
Went when everyone else could.
And for every single day that went as I was at home that have it
also even more worse because I thought how much had
missed and I would not get with me and all the tests and
Rating and all that I sabotaged all the time.
And then it was laid on even more anxiety
than just performance anxiety.
Now that I've got a functioning schooling so have
Like everything has started to work it with talking to people
And the medicine also helps in a large part.
After I started at my new school, I felt that I got
more self -confidence because I was able to be with more on
the lessons and then I hung with more teaching and
Succeeded on the tests.
I never had to reproduce or anything and then I had
more self -confidence in myself that I would actually succeed
with my goals in life and then I managed to fight further and
come to school more often and stuff like that.