My absence started in nine, but it was still okay to
one in high school.
Then I was at home at 85 %.
My schooling has been like a roller coaster before.
During middle school there was a little on and off with
absence and presence.
It was more in high school as things really happened
With my absence.
Because that's when I felt less safe in school and I
Started sitting at home and I played.
And I turn around the clock which of course makes one not
going to school.
What was most difficult in school was that there was so much sound
And so much impression and so long days all the time.
We sought help all the way from me began the seven, but they said
Just that it is puberty, you are tired, you are a girl.
Then it is like that.
But we knew that the symptoms of ADD existed, and that it goes in
The family and such.
So I got my diagnosis in November 2021,
first year of high school.
It was a big school, there were a lot of people and I felt
That I had no support.
There are no rules for how to, how to behave
yourself at lunch or who you can sit with.
And I thought it was difficult, learning it myself.
What was hard for me when it was to be able to even get out of bed
It took such power so it was not possible to go
to school.
I was very stressed by all performance anxiety and all
that all the time and feel every day that I needed
do my best.
And if I failed one day then the whole could
the future be over.
Type.
The school didn't understand me at all.
There was no understanding from their direction.
There was no adjustment from their direction.
It wasn't that they wanted to sit down and talk
with me.
But what really happens?
The time I was at school, it was.
There was nothing adapted to me at all.
I had a very messy class and everything was messy.
I had needed the teachers to listen to me and
actually believed that I could also be right and not
Just themselves.
Less class, definitely.
It is kind of the first thing I think about.
Smaller classrooms, not so large classes,
More people or others may have similar problems as I do.
Because I think that would help.
Then you understand each other better.
What I would have liked from school is understanding that they
Just would have realized that something is wrong.