I never had a genuine contact with the school that they
actually cared or how I felt.
It was just, you should do this and do this and do it
Here and came here and all that.
You are better when you are in school.
Once I was home most of the time I barely had
any contact with the school.
They called and said that if not you do this then you get f in it
Here's the course and.
They just pressed.
They didn't understand as well.
But once I came to school, then it was
also.
Well, you are here now when it suits you.
And it wasn't like,
-The fun that you are here now!
Once I was home from school I had nothing
Good life, no health really.
I sat at home and ate sweets and drank soda and energy drinks.
Was like malnourished and I had computer games as abuse.
It sounds awful to say that a pandemic was needed to
I would do school, but that was what was needed.
When I was home so the school didn't want me to work
at home at all without they just wanted me to come
to school and do that and they didn't want to care about
My solutions to work remotely.
I was home the whole seven, eight, nine and then it was
Not until one in one that I began to come
back to school.
I got the chance to start at a less adapted little school
And then it felt like I got another chance and the teachers
believed in me that I could actually succeed when I got
go about eight and then it felt like I had more time on me
To learn and then perform in nine.
Now I have found the right line in high school, children and leisure,
and i have got some adjustments like most
Teachers follow, but it is still not quite.
That they have perceived that they should follow it.
At this school.
So it was.
Everyone had had this time when you were burnt out, one was
At home and you were sick for a longer period.
And it wasn't something I could explain to
My classmates before.
It wasn't so I could explain why I was home
Or why I didn't want to be at school.
But now it was like.
We sat for hours and just talked about what we could say about
This was why I was home.
We were constantly discussing it and it was nice
That someone understood.
One reason why I could get back to
The school was then again the relationship between
Pupil and teacher.
It was that they asked questions and they had.
Therefore, there are very specific questions and there were many meetings
Before you started at school itself because they wanted to get to know
me as a person and know my needs so they could take it on
Sig and tie together.
Then once you started school and then it was at Bellevue
high school where I would supplement
My elementary school grades.
Then there was a corridor that suited me.
There were 15 students approximately divided into four classrooms
Maybe and then it was a quiet atmosphere during the lesson.
Fewer students.
Then you get easier help of course.
It becomes more individual.
Plus that one had individual schedules that I think is one
Key to be able to cope with the school.
Autumn term there, when I started at the new school so
Was I at home pretty much anyway, but it was for
that I was not able to, because I was not used to
That pace.
So I was pretty much gone.
But then it gradually got better and we had good calls
With the school about how I felt and stuff.
Now in high school I have a good mentor because he is
Also one.
He sees me and knows what I need help with and understands
And pepper me.
It is like that is what is required.
And so it is with some other teachers.
It was very much that made it one
So big change.
I had teachers who cared and understood and had background
To treat those with NPF.
I had friends.
I knew how to do in the dining room for example.
I was no longer afraid to go there.
I had a very structured day.
I always knew what to do at school.
It was never so that I got there and so it was over me.
We're going to have outdoor day or something like that
were no surprises.
It was good.
I felt that.
Instead of me being to become
limited and treat like i was normal so i got to have
the problems I had and so the teachers learned
to deal with me.