After all, there were staff I could talk to but.
And I had one after all
a support.
But what I brought up with her that she would take
Up with the teachers.
The teachers did not really listen to her.
But we talked a lot and it was nice to have
Like conversation therapy almost about school
With someone who also works at school who knows what it looks like.
It was.
I needed that support.
I just wished the teachers like to take her a little more
Seriously, I think.
I would have liked the others in the staff also only saw that
I exist and maybe ask I felt and not that you are
Here when it suits you.
While I was home, I had contact, or my
Mom most had contact with the school.
But I had the most contact with a single person and it was
after all with resource teacher Roger that I wrote if I was sick
or if I was not able to go to school at all and he
Tried to pull me there.
He usually told me that you or that I just would.
I would not think so much, I would
Just do it.
At my old school I could sit in my place and so could
teachers come into the room without even looking in my direction
Or care as if I were there or not.
But then when I came to my new school it was always a
Good morning and it was always positive stuff they said.
And had you become ill one day they could write
to one directly.
And how are you?
They play a greater role in young people's lives than they think
and what they do and say will affect more than what
They also believe.
What Maria did that was good, it was she she saw me and
Like almost took care of me.
Like I was one of her children.
It was like.
She.
Yes, she saw that I was among all others who were outgoing
And heard as well.
So she saw anyway that I existed
In a way he saw us was that he did not focus on that
We had arrived too late without us being there.