What is autism spectrum disorder?
Previously used, among other things, to use the diagnoses
Asperger's syndrome, atypical autism, autistic syndrome.
The research found that these diagnoses
Actually has more similarities than differences.
Although one may have different needs for support
Or have other diagnoses too.
Therefore, you have chosen to merge all the diagnoses
to the collection diagnosis ASD.
But it is not wrong or strange to still say
For example, Asperger's syndrome.
What is the Asd on?
Today you do not know exactly what ASD is due to.
But you know that it is something you are born with,
or is something that occurs during pregnancy
or childbirth, which affects the development of brain.
Common misunderstanding about ASD.
Is ASD a disease?
No, ASD is no disease,
It is a disability.
Having ASD only means having
A different way of thinking, feeling, thinking and being.
Society is adapted to how most others work.
It makes it harder for people with ASD
to work in everyday life.
Are everyone with Asd Superner and HUGE INTERMATE?
No, to have merely the diagnosis of ASD does not mean
That you are more or less smart than others.
But some people with ASD have one or more
Special interests in which they are very well read.
Is it just guys who have ASD?
No, it is both girls and guys who are diagnosed.
What does ASD mean?
People with ASD are at least as different
each other as people are at large.
However, there are some areas where people
With ASD can have a reduced ability.
Which areas this is
and how large the reductions will be
varies from person to person.
Now we'll meet Charlie, Alice, Malte and Ayla
To hear what things they experience as extra difficult.
I think it is most difficult to be with friends.
It takes a lot of energy from me.
I like to make a lot of effort
To be able to be social.
It doesn't come naturally to me.
Things that are hard for me can be
to listen to when someone tells about such
Which I don't think is interesting.
It can also be difficult to know how to
Take me into a discussion without interrupting.
To know how long I will keep eye contact.
Ideally, I would avoid it completely.
Sometimes I hear that people think I'm staring.
That I interpret things literally
So that there is a misunderstanding.
When friends tell me "we hear",
So can I go around for a long time and ponder
On what it really means.
Should I call, should he call?
Or does he just mean that we should be seen in school?
To read people's facial expressions and body language.
It takes a lot of energy from me
And sometimes it gets completely wrong.
That I most preferably spend time with a friend
At a time and do not like to spend time in groups.
- I seem to experience the world at a
completely different way than others.
I have very sensitive hearing and can
Pay attention to sounds that maybe no one else hears.
I tried to go on green grove this summer
But it didn't work at all.
I had to go home.
The metal sparkle from mountains and the roller coaster
Made me completely exhausted.
When I'm out and about I see everything.
And then I really mean everything.
It's like I have no filter.
And everything I see goes straight into me.
I can walk on the town in type 30 minutes
Then I'm completely done.
It's also like my skin
is completely hypersensitive to touch.
Showering is the worst I know.
It's like a thousand needle sticks come out of the shower hose.
Clothes are also very busy.
When I was little, my mom sat
and softened all my socks
before I could have them.
Now that I am older I have learned
Which clothes work.
Pants that sit at the waist for example,
is the widest thing there is.
I may also think it's hard when people
Getting too close to me without me being prepared for it.
Once I happened to push to a friend,
Who just wanted to give me a spontaneous hug.
- Stress is my biggest enemy.
When the stress strikes it is like I
Gets completely blocked and freezes.
What stresses me most is rapid changes.
It happened to me last night at the Scouts.
On the schedule it was said that we would fire.
When I got there it was too few leaders
And we had to keep up with cipher instead.
I just couldn't change.
And chose not to be at all.
How my day becomes also depends very much on
How stressed I am in the morning.
If all my morning routines float on
And I get to take things at my pace so it will be good.
If my little sister locks in to the toilet,
Or if Mom gaps that I have to hurry,
Then it gets bad.
At school, the dining room usually stress me the most.
I have a definite place in the dining room
but sometimes it is taken and then it becomes completely
crazy in my head.
Where should I sit down then?
Last time it happened I just went out without eating.
I couldn't calm down and find a solution.
I will be calm with rules because then I know as well
What is expected of me.
If rules are in any way broken
or if one makes exceptions
So the stress strikes right away.
When I was younger sometimes thought my friends
That I was hard because I was a little class police.
- There are also good things.
I think it's so hard to distinguish
What is me and what is my diagnosis.
That's like this I am.
I often think you talk about what is difficult.
But there are actually things that are good too.
My friend likes I'm honest.
And don't keep up with lots of white lies.
That I think differently is just good!
Because I often think of things that others easily miss.
I can see details in the picture
that no one else sees.
I have very easy to learn those things
Which I find interesting.
People look at me as a specialist.
Because I can have difficulty with the social codes
Am I not so judgmental against others
which is a little different.
I am thus less prejudiced
Against new people.
Because I try to avoid stress
So I always come on time.
Often long before agreed time.
Now have you heard different voices about how it
may be to have ASD.
It is important to remember that
it may differ very much
from person to person.
Depending on the surroundings and circumstances
the difficulties can be labeled more or less.
That which works with those you know well
may be difficult together with
new people or new environments.
Those things one sees as challenges
can also vary over time.
One thing that was perhaps very difficult in early
School age can work without problems
in later age and vice versa.