Today I will go to an open house.
Nobody else. I am here myself and should be a bit of a reporter and go around and ask a little about school.
Hang on!
There we have the school.
Now I'm at school. Here is the entrance. So now I'm going to go in and get some knowledge about open house.
Knack, knock, knock.
Hi Aliyah, welcome to our open house. Hi thank you so much. Fun to be here.
Here is a small suspension surface, where the students hang. And here we have lots of classrooms. A little student work here.
We have the picture room here. Then we have our big media center in here.
This classroom can be almost anything. It's huge.
Then it is this corridor where we have everything that our students need.
Why do you think you should go to an open house?
I think it is great to come to an open house where you get to meet students and teachers,
And feel the environment here in school.
What is it you can do at an open house?
You get to talk to us ambassadors, you get to see how the school is and experience a whole new world.
Now they will show me around a bit in the media center. Exciting!
Here we usually have our movie and photo lessons. We have lamps, flashes.
Here we have our editing room. This is our hall, for us movie and photo students.
Why do you think you should go to an open house?
I think you should go to an open house to get to school, see how the premises look
And ask questions to teachers and students to find the right school.
What can you do at an open house?
You can see what the schools look like, talk to teachers and students, and know how the education goes to make the right choice.
I recommend everyone to go several open houses before you make your high school choice.
It is much easier to get a real picture of the school in place.
Right now, several schools also have digital variants if you do not have the opportunity to visit the school physically.
Another step closer to high school!