Welcome to the Gothenburg City Library.
Mirjam is my name and work as a program librarian
and we have for some time made a series of reading armchairs
that is actually an old program series from the 90s
There the actors at the City Theater of Gothenburg
come in after the Saturday rehearsals and
told stories or read poems on different themes.
We invited Gothenburg's freelance actors for this
And we have been running for three semesters now.
And today we have Timo Nieminen and
Annika Nordin here and the theme are prospects.
Yes right now we have to keep away from each other.
For it is hard to hug you have to keep more than one
arm's length.
It is said that every time we hug someone hot
So our lives are extended by a whole day.
At least it says Paulo Coelho.
So we would not be able to write a book about all types
of hugs that exist for it would never end.
There are as many types of hugs as there are
people,
situations,
Relationships.
So here's a reading chair
full of poetic, lyrical, crazy,
Romantic hugs.
But
at a safe distance,
like this.
Prospects yes ..
In the synonym dictionary we find words like:
panoramic,
hope,
hopes,
Views.
And from views
the associations can easily go to windows.
Windows, it is a strong theme of many artists through the ages.
Charles Baudelaire highlighted in one of his prosepoem:
There is nothing deeper,
Secret
richer, richer,
dumb and more dazzling
than a window illuminated by a light flame.
What to look like in the sun is always less interesting
than the one that adds
Behind a window pane.
In this black hole
living life
Dreaming
Suffering.
From Baudelaire to Saarikoski, Pentti Saarikoski.
One dark gray morning I go to buy wine.
The only one in the small bus and in the big one, out of three.
Until a day when the little one is no longer needed
It replaces the big one and we, we have become a winery
And the great bus drivers drive the small and the small bus drivers chop our firewood.
Desolate to be the only bus's only
and embarrassing that in the big product one of three looking down at the knee
A dark gray morning in February.
New thoughts are not needed for a long time
On the high bridge I doubt its strength
The fairway is dredged for larger boats