Hi, my name is Marit Kapla
And I have written a book called Osebol.
In Osebol I have interviewed
almost all adults living in Osebol,
namely,
My old hometown in northern Värmland.
So there are 42 people talking in the book.
Now I will read a little from the book
And I thought, I have chosen some parties that are about
crisis consciousness, you might say,
in Osebol,
Speaking of what we are going through right now.
Per-Erik Andersson,
Born 1940.
“I have old -fashioned payment with Giro.
Someday it is to go to Torsby
to Nordea
They had offices in Malung
But now they have moved it to Mora
it said.
As if they would not have had
Any office in Mora before.
There was a note on the door.
"We've moved our office to Mora."
Not that "we have put in Malung".
It had looked worse.
Not many people handle cash.
And the ATM,
who was at Värmlandsporten,
Have they removed now again.
I'm so much in Malung
So I can withdraw money there.
But that's not good.
Non-profit organizations,
that sells lotteries,
How should they carry on?
How is it going
If it were to become
A proper power outage?
Then one cannot trade anything,
without cash,
If it even goes with it. "
Anna-Karin Larsson,
Born 1972.
“Last time we talked
It was winter and misery.
Then I felt
Well,
I'm not going to stay.
Now the summer is coming soon.
Then I feel that it's pretty nice
Living here anyway.
Then you can also feel this way,
I mean, Stockholm last Friday.
It is quite quiet to live here in the country anyway.
It is a security here as well.
A social network you have.
I have a hard time seeing
That someone else would live here.
It's my house.
It's split.
There would be a good intermediate. ”
Levi Stenberg,
Born in 1973.
“Maybe there is a huge book
where all people's lives are written down.
How and when, he or she is going to die.
If I'm going to die next year in a climb, so ...
I am not afraid.
There is always something in play
that can be bad.
I can die
If I go out and it's slippery.
in a car accident
or a flight crash.
I believe life is more dangerous
In a city
than up in the mountain.
I've talked to Åke about this.
We feel happy
that we live here
and not in Stockholm
Or Gothenburg.
Not in large cities.
There is still security here.
We are not close to terrorists.
It was horrible,
What happened in Stockholm.
It is the same thing
As in France
And in Germany.
It's a new world. ”
I wrote the book about Osebol to,
For many different reasons.
The most important thing was to
I felt that
It stands too little about such villages in the media
and people know too little about who lives there
And what's going on there.
Even I
In the process of becoming one who didn't really know what was happening in Osebol.
I grew up there
But in 2007 my parents sold the house.
When started working on the book
Then I had barely been Osebol in eight years
And then I felt that even I was becoming such a person
Who does not know what is happening in a village in the countryside.
I think the book
Tells about so many different things.
It shows that,
I chose to make the book as an interview book,
It is not my story about Osebol directly
Without it, those who live there are now telling us about life there now.
They also tell about their lives
They have,
they are different old,
It's men and women,
They come from a lot of different places -
some have lived there all their lives
and some come from other countries
Or other places in Sweden.
The book got along
Very much of Sweden and Europe's present history.
Above all, I think it has got with
urbanization,
So this with that very many people
have left the countryside and moved into cities,
Just as I've done,
I live in Gothenburg now.
I think there is some kind of sense of loss at
a large part of - not just Sweden's population but
The world's population - somehow.
There are many who,
somewhere consciously or unconsciously
Maybe have ties to a place
as one has left or the family has left,
The family has left for a long time
But somewhere there was something that was lost
with this move.
I think that's why
so many
can take the book.
It is anyway
many who contact me and say
that the book has got one to think about
their old relatives
or any completely different village elsewhere
or just a feeling of something
lost.
Yes, what has happened in Osebol since the book came out
It is that people,
Other people have started to go to Osebol
in a way they didn't do before.
It is quite common for a car to come
and drive down to the bridge over the Klarälven -
The bridge is very much in the book -
you can't drive a car, you can't really have
Some traffic on it now but sheep goes and cycles across the bridge anyway.
The cars drive down to the bridge,
goes out,
takes pictures of the river,
Takes selfies at the road sign.
This thinks those who live in Osebol are fun.
We have quite a lot of contact
and have had during this year now
That has passed since the book came out.
That was the point then,
There are plans for,
or like this,
It should be a printer course about Osebol
At the Folk High School in Stöllet
which is just three kilometers away.
But as it looks now so
is it still supposed to
The course will get rid of in early June.
And then we'll see.
It's full, it's great,
The places on this course went to,
were filled very fast.
I hope the course gets off
And then I come,
then you will try to
to write that way I have done
this book,
And so it's a poet with too
So you have to try writing poetry too.
The book has, well,
as they say,
Sit ocebol on the map.
But not just Osebol may
Without the entire countryside in Norra Klarälvdalen.
Yes
Books, for me, books have always been a huge part of my life.
Yes, but, for me ...
I believe that books and literature mean different things
for different people.
Through literature and books of different kinds so
partly is books something that takes longer to read
than a newspaper text,
or takes longer to take part in a television element,
so one gets like a depth in something
I think it's important,
Just that time it takes to read a book,
that one gives something that time
and take that time to think about
and be involved in this particular
which this book is about.
I have been thinking about that may have become more important now when
the information flow is still much larger
than it was when I grew up in Osebol.
Then also books are a way to
try out their own view of the world
Against others' view of the world.
It is unbelievable...
an incredible tool for discovering the world and oneself
Is books and literature.
Right now I'm reading Michel Houellebecqs
Second novel, I think it is,
The element particles.
I have read his later books
But I hadn't read it.
It's just an example of I think,
one, really,
His novels are books that make me,
They challenge me
In my view of the world and
humanity.
Then I read in parallel,
I often read a trade book
At the same time as I read a fiction book,
So I am also doing a book by Anna Jungstrand,
The documentary and literature,
So it's all about a little neighbor
What I am doing myself.
Yes, but I think,
A thing that I think,
As I have read more of lately,
These are short stories
and there are a lot of good short story collections
As a man, there is as much as possible,
But for example
Olga Tokarczuk
have a short story collection called
Games on many small drums.
Then I have also just read Sven Olov Karlssons
The yearbook
And Annika Norlin has just come out with a short story collection,
And it's something you can read aloud to each other,
If one splits this one
quarantine time with someone or some
so a short story is like,
one just right,
It takes just a long time, somehow, to read a short story
In a while in the evening, for example.
So that's my tip.