Welcome to International Writers Stage Gothenburg! \ H My Name is Tone Schunnesson and I'm a Writer. \ H \ H
Today I'm HERE TO TALK TO "V", Formerly \ Heve Ensler, About Her New Book \ H \ H \ H \ H \ H \ H \ H \ H \ H \ H \ H \ H \ H
"The Apology" or "sorry" in swedish, \ hpubished at word front publisher.
Welcome V!
Thank you, I´m very happy to be here!
Thank you for being here.
You are Most Famously Known for the \ H IConic Play "The Vagina Monologues". A Piece that \ h \ h
Explores Sexual Experiences, Body Image and Several \ H Other Topics Through the Eyes of Different Women. \ H \ H
It's Translated Into 48 Languages and Has \ H Been Performed In Over 140 Countries. It's \ h \ h
Like a cultural fixture and a feministic and \ h Political Groundbreaking Piece of Writing. \ H \ H
The Play Laid Ground for Your Non-Profit V-Day \ H Movement. The V-Day Movement Raises Money \ H \ h
and Educates People About Gendered Violence and \ H Makes an EFFORT TO STOP IT. You raised over \ h \ h
100 million dollars. Besides that you've \ h Written Several Other Plays, Books and Movies. \ H \ h
Among Others "I'm an Emotional Creature", "The Secret \ H Life of Girls Round the World", The Book Made \ H \ H
The New York Times Bestseller List. You've Also \ H Written "The Good Body" Which Starts \ H \ h
With Your Own Tormented Relationship With Your \ H Aging Body And Then Introduces Us To Women Around \ H \ H \ H \ H \ H
The World Who Have Found Peace With Their Bodies. \ H 2013 You Wrote A Memoir "In The Body of the World" \ H \ H \ H \ h
Which Dealt with You Getting Cancer. You Also \ H Made A Book Into a Theatrical Performance in 2018 \ H \ H
You Received Numerous Awards, Like A Million of \ H them! Among Them A Tony Award in 2011. But Today \ H \ H
We are going to talk about "The Apology". "Sorry" in swedish and the first of your books \ h \ h
Published in Swedish. I HOPE It's Not The Last \ H SINE YOU HAVE SUCH A BIG AND EXCITING PRODUCTION. \ H \ H
"Forgive" is a very touching book. It's an apology \ h from your Father, writen by you. An apology from \ h \ h
Your Father's Point of View That You Waited \ H For Your Whole Life and Never Received.
An apology from your Father's Point of \ H View That You Waited For Your Whole Life \ H \ H
and never receives. Your Father and Pergetrator \ H WHO Sexually and Physically Abused You Never \ H \ H
Owned up to his Wrongdoings. When Writing the \ H Book He'd Been Dead 31 Years. You decided \ h \ h
to give yourself what you needed. Him Taking \ H Accountability for His Actions and Him Explaining \ H \ H
What led him to treat his oldest daughter this \ h way. This Book is a Letter to Eve from Arthur.
I was deeply touched by your book "sorry" \ h and it resonated with me in more way than i \ h
would have imagined. I was \ h so filled with strong emotions \ h \ h
When Reading, it was like \ h a physical experience reading it. \ h
SINCE THERE SO HARD TO READ ARTHUR \ H RECOUNTING THE EVENTS, I WAS FILLED WITH SADNESS, \ H \ H
Relief But Also Anger and Rage. One thing \ h that Kept coming back to me was the extensive \ h \ h
Emotional Labor Behind Your Method. To Bring \ H Back Your Father From The Dead and Evoking His \ H \ H
Voice couldn't have been easy. Can you please \ h Tell me about the process behind this book \ h \ h
And how the book came to be?
Thank you so much \ hor that introduction and for the response to "the apology". It's funny that you're saying \ hthat about the physicalness of your response, \ h \ h \ h
Because Writing This Book was so physical. \ H it was so physical in so many way.
I Never Had an Experience \ Hlike that, Writing Before. I'VE WRITTEN A LOT OF \ H \ H
Books and a Lot of PlayS But it Felt As \ H I WENT INTO A Kind of Trance State. \ H \ H \ H \ H \ H \ H \ H \ H \ H \ H \ H \ H \ H
My Father, My Dead Father was very, very present \ h through the whole thing. In Really Learned \ H \ h
a lot about the dead. The Dead Are Always With Us. \ H they're Always Around us and often they Long to be \ h \ h
In Communication with Us to Help Them Understand \ H Where they are and to help them get free and other \ h \ h
Zones Where they live. But the Experience of \ H Trying to Climb Into My Father, to Live Inside \ Hhim.
The Book is a Conjuring, \ hit's fiction. I don't know if \ h \ h
A Lot of It's Even TRUE BECASE MY FATHER REALLY \ H NEVER TALKED AND HE NEVER TOLD ME About Himself. \ H
But it Feels Like It's TRUE BECAUSE HIS PARSENCE \ H AND BEING INSIDE HIM FELT SO REAL WHILE I \ H
Was Writing It. It was excruciating, it was \ h liberating, it was terrifying, it was maddening. \ H \ h
In Had Moments Where I Was Literally Curled Up \ H IN A BALL, just just weeping. But it was
Incredible Cathartic. In Always Say, \ H there's a line at the end of the book \ h \ h
which I don't know if my father \ h say or in say because by the end of writering \ h \ h
The Book in Didn't Know Who Was Writing \ H It, But The Line Is "Old Man Be Gone" \ H \ H