Hi, Elza here from Elza's bookshelf.
I have been to the Book Fair and I have gone bananas. I bought, I don't know, wait to check, nine books.
It's been a long time since I have bought so many books.
I think it is to compensate that I am a reading, because I comfort myself by buying books.
You know that buying books and reading books are two completely different hobbies and I love them just as much and I have them just as much.
But now I think I show which books I found and found at the book fair simply and there are a lot as I said so we start at once.
The first book is a non -fiction book that I wanted to read for a long time and the author stood there, went ahead and said hello and asked if I could get a signed and I got that of course.
I'm talking about the moms by Alexandra Pascalidou.
Very nice like that, the whole page. It was really nice to talk to her, really cool.
She has just come out with the dads but I haven't read the moms yet so I thought I would.
I know it exists as an audio book too but this is a pocket so it can be quite nice but it feels very good to have it.
I feel that I am in a period that is starting to get hungry and snail at non -fiction books.
The second book I will show is a book I got because I bought the gold card and then you got a goodybag and in it there was a book.
It is a book that I have seen a little everywhere, songbirds by Christy Lefteri nominated 2022 for this year's book.
I don't know what it is about actually. It's about Cyprus anyway, maybe.
I have not read, I know she has another book that was quite popular too. You have seen a little here and there on Bookstagram and on Booktube.
But I haven't read anything from her. I think this one is so good looking so I was pleasantly surprised when I saw it in the box simply.
I have said that I have kind of ended with Swedish decks but it is a writer like me ...
I do not follow many writers on Instagram but I follow her and I am very curious about her books.
So I saw this and thought, okay, I give it a chance.
I'm talking about Anna Bågstam, the eyewitness.
This is the first book in her series. I don't know, brutal murder, Öresund we are.
It is a tempo and exciting dick that takes place in the Öresund district.
Harriet.
Honestly, this sounds like a classic Swedish cover that I've ended up with.
Which I just don't want anything more and read anything more.
But, but, I like the author and I have only heard good things about this one.
So I and Swedish decks are on a break and we start flirting with each other again.
Yes, me and Anna.
Then a book that I became overjoyed when I saw.
And it was no doubt that it should accompany me home.
A Tunnis, which I have seen a little here and there.
But as my favorite Booktuber Books with Emily Fox.
She is chatting about this book, she thinks it's amazing.
And I'm sick of it.
I WHO HAVE NEVER KNOWN MEN BY JACQUELINE HARPMAN.
Harpman maybe.
And this should apparently be some kind of dystopia.
A number of women are locked in the basement.
And then a lot of things happen.
Apparently you should not know much about this book more than that.
That it should be perhaps something feminist touch, as socially critical in that way.
In addition to being sick looking, it is thin.
And I have heard her chatted about this book.
So I think I have to give her a chance.
And it sounds like a book I would like.
And I love when people say they don't know much about this book.
Just know this and read.
Then I immediately get curious and gladly pick it up.
So this one had to come home with me.
I have a relatively new favorite author and horror.
And I have read a book by her, which I have chatted about a lot on this channel.
And then I have read a short story collection.
And then I found another short story collection that I have not read.
I'm talking about Mariana Enriques and The Danger of Smoking in Bed.
A small short story collection.
Maria Enriques is she who has written our part of the night.
I love that book.
The horror that is so amazing.
Oh how good it is.
Oh god it is so good.
I recommend everyone to read it of course.
Although those who do not like horror can probably appreciate this one.
But it is incredibly unpleasant.
Trigger alert for a bit of most.
But it is so, so well written and so good.
And I have read a short story collection.
And now I own this one too.
The one I read was Things We Lost in the Fire.
And it is in Swedish.
Things we lose in the fire I think it's called in Swedish.
This I do not know if it is in Swedish.
But I have it in English and I probably want to buy this one.
The second short story collection that looks a bit like this one.
Fantastic.
I'm so peppy on this one.
A bit nervous.
But I love Mariana Enriquez's way of writing.
And her way of putting the mood on things.
It is an incredibly unpleasant atmosphere.
I love her.
Another book I bought was also a bit of a chance.
But I've seen it a little everywhere and want to read it.
But I have been like this, I should not, I should not.
But of course I should.
We talk about The Seven Moons by Mali Almeida.
Shall we see. Shehan Karunatilaka
I apologize so much that I slaughter this name.
Great name.
I apologize so much so much.
At least this one.
Check out how good it is.
And this is the typical trope I like.
We can accompany Maali.
I think this person dies quite brutally.
But end up in the afterlife.
And there has this person, Maali has seven months.
Seven days, seven moons.
To be reconciled to the people she loves the most.
He loves most I even think.
And yes, it's vague.
As you know, vaguely.
I think it's all about that.
I read a little quickly in the back page.
Got such a feeling.
Magical realism.
After life.
Feeling.
And thought this seems to be a book for me.
I chance.
And so it says it's a book.
The Book Pricer 2022.
So this one won.
Book Pricer.
Price until 2022.
So why.
Oh here comes a receipt too.
So why not anyway.
And so check.
I mean check.
Check it out.
Another chance?
A book that I thought sounded so fun.
And I don't know.
I have said that I do not like cozy books.
But I've started.
Think they are right okay anyway.
At least this year.
So I found a book that seemed very fun and very funny.
And it's called.
The cat who caught a killer.
By L.T. Shearer.
Maybe you speak it now.
I don't know that much more than that.
We can accompany a woman.
One.
In all cases.
A cat helps a woman solve a murder.
I mean the title says everything or how.
So I think so.
I think it seems so cozy.
And I enjoy reading.
Books with animals like.
Who has one.
At least animals I like.
Who has as well.
Aben that has a chapter or a character and such.
And cats are cozy I think.
I am both a cat and a dog person.
And of course.
Must test.
Okay next book.
I bought for two reasons.
Like the idea itself.
The title itself.
You will grasp.
And.
The cover.
Look.
On this cover.
So I die.
How good it is.
The Girl Who Fell Beneath the Sea.
Axie Oh.
Oh maybe.
Perhaps.
Again.
Sorry.
Okay I don't know anything about this book.
It's fantasy.
I hope it.
Check.
You see some fish and choices.
Here is a choice.
One more choice.
So.
I mean I'm lost already there.
It feels like she's going to fall into the sea. Is about the sea.
I do not know.
It sounds so.
I chance.
Check out how good it is.
So it's at that level.
In fact, I don't really know what this is about. More than it is very nice and the title attracts me.
Another thing that I do not like is to back the text. When it's just a lot of quotes of people who like it.
But what is it about. I do not know. It says so beautiful, she says this one. Enchanting says this one.
Tale of blah blah says this one.But I so. What does it mean? And so it just stands. Don't Chase Fate. Let Fate Chase You.
What does it mean? Where are we somewhere in this story? Who is it about?
What happens?
What should we solve? I do not know anything. And there is nothing.
There is nothing.
And then you should browse somewhere.
And find either back or here.
There are a lot of things.
But as I said I don't know.
I do not care.
It is good looking.
The title attracts me.
It had to come home.
So.
Why do I have to explain myself?
Why do I buy books?
I bought it. It was fine. Let me be.
The last book, another non -fiction book that I really want to read and is curious about.
It is the Kurge track by Joakim Medin.
Sweden, Turkey and the price for a NATO membership.
This whole NATO process when Sweden wants to join NATO and Turkey make demands and say they have to disclose some of our citizens.
And what's going on there.
I am the very curiosity of this.
How could we do that? I believed better about us. Sweden.
I just think this seems so interesting. It happens so much.
And I haven't heard much about this.
And he has dug in this.
The journalist.
So I was curious and thought I would learn a little.
A little general education simply.
So corner.
There were a lot of books.
All these I am super pepp to read and really curious to read.
And of course I'm curious about which of these books you like.
Who are you curious about?
Who have you read?
And what do you think about them?
Help me somehow find a way in.
Which one to start on.
Come on that maybe I should show them.
This is how you have them.
Of course, as usual, I am very curious about what you think about them here.
And if you have read any of them.
We are heard in the comments section.
We will be visible next Monday.
Don't forget to give me a thumbs up and subscribe to my channel.
If you don't already.
Farewell.
Bye!