Hello to you today i will show you how to bake
Really good bran.
-—-—-
The perfect bran in my opinion
consists of an airy bun bun,
nutty almond paste with a little chew resistance and fluffy whipped cream.and one (semla)
That's what I will show you how to bake today.
And what you need to bake the perfect
The bran is:
room -temperature butter, salt, wheat flour,
eggs, fresh yeast,
milk, sweet almond, cardamom,
Water and icing sugar.
And that I will
Start with, it is to crumble the yeast in a bowl.
And this should only be stirred together until the yeast has dissolved in the milk before I have in any other ingredients.
-—-—-
So now the yeast has dissolved in the milk
and i'll go down with powdered sugar
As I don't think I mentioned
When I stabbed the ingredients earlier.
But at least it should be sugar in this dough.
Two eggs.
As you can exclude if you want but
They give a little extra juiciness to the bun.
A must for the bran: Cardamom
This is ready -ground but
If you want even more cardamom flavor, then you take entire cardamom seeds and mortar.
Room -temperature butter.
I don't know if you've noticed it yet
But so far all my ingredients have been room -temperature.
The milk, the yeast, the eggs and now the butter.
It is partly for the sake of fermentation.
But when it comes to the butter, it is important
that it is room -temperature for if you melt the butter
does it become a fluid and the more fluid you have
the more wheat flour you need in the dough
and a dough that contains a lot of wheat flour
becomes much more compact since it has been baked and we want
An airy bun bun so we use room -temperature butter.
-—-—-
And then i have in half of the flour
And a little salt.
But the salt and the rest of the flour we save until later
Because we do not want the salt to make direct contact with the yeast because then it disturbs the fermentation process.
Then we don't want to have all wheat flour at once,
Without a little at a time so we get a messy but still manageable dough.
Then the buns become the airiest.
Such something.
Now I just hip
Because I did this so many times but accurate instructions and dimensions
For how much flour and other ingredients
As you need, you will find that as usual in the description.
There is a direct link to the recipe.
Like this now when the dough slowly
but surely have started to go together to a messy batter then I have in a little
Salt and even more flour.
And as you see
so i have in a little flour at a time so i see exactly when it goes together to
a manageable dough and never cross the limit
to this compact and
Thick the dough that just becomes a dry and dull bun.
The dough, it should be kneaded for at least 10 minutes
in machine or double if you do it by hand.
And that is because we really want to activate the gluten in the dough
so that we get these airy and juicy buns that
Raise well in the oven.
So don't skimp on the kneading
Although I know it is the most boring thing in this whole process.
But it's worth it, I promise
When the dough releases from the edges of the bowl
Then it is ready to be formed into buns.
You see how easily it attaches to the hook
Without stuck in the bowl.
Then you know
That then it is really done.
Like that now you divide the part into the same number of parts
As you want buns.
Do you want to make big bran
So you do it.
Medium -sized or small.
It's all up to you.
Want to weigh your buns before
You bake them so you can do it.
One usually says that
30 g of dough per bun gives minis selection
Or 60 g of dough if you want to do ...
Such there are ordinary ... who usually be in cafes ...
The most common
the size of the bran.
That's about
60 g per bun.
It's about this size.
So you have something to compare with at home.
Now the dough is divided into the same number of pieces
Like I want buns.
They weigh exactly as much
Which is wonderful
And now it's time to shape them into buns.
Now you want a resilient bun that is
Nice and smooth rolled.
The trick behind it
is simply to curse your hand
around the bun and pushes slightly lightly
while rotating your hand.
One pushes it as well as towards the table, couples the hand
and rotates at the same time.
It doesn't have to go fast.
And then you do this until you feel that
There is no joint on the bun.
And this is just repeating for all of them, yes
30 buns you have in front of you to roll.
Twice as many
If you make mini seems.
Now the buns are shaped and ready to be fermented
and is it that you don't want to bake all the buns the same day
Then you can actually freeze them uncoated
And unequal just before fermentation.
Because in normal order I ferment my wheat doughs
only once.
And that is because if
We will now take this up with the fermentation again:
(But it's so important)
So it is very bad for the fermentation if you ferment it for a little while
And then you start to knead in the dough just like I did now [when I split the dough into pieces]
And then ferment again.
Then you have swamped it
You ferment once.
And the advantage of that
In addition to being very good fermentation on the dough,
It is that you can do this to freeze the buns
Before they ferment and baked
And then you can take out and thaw and ferment
Whenever you are craving.
So you don't have to
Stand and make a new dough every time.
So I cover them here with a back cloth now.
So that they can ferment in peace and quiet.
At least 2 hours.
Now is the time to make the almond paste and personally so love
I am almond pulp.
And almost takes a little bad up
If someone has stabbed the almond paste
When I get served a holiday.
Much almond paste it should be
And the best I think, it will be
When rusting the sweet almond before mixing
it together into an almond paste for then you get forward
An even more nutty and good taste.
So i'm going to spread the sweet almonds here on a baking sheet paper on a plate
and roast in the middle of the oven at 175 degrees
for about 10 min.
Thus, roasted sweet almonds smell so good
And I should actually have in them directly
In my food processor and mix them properly
Before I go in with icing sugar and some water.
I don't usually scale my sweet almonds because I think it's good.
There is no reason to scale them but do you want
so you can either buy pre -roasted and peeled
Or you rub them with a kitchen towel
When they are just pre -roasted
Then the shell falls off super light.
I prefer an almond paste with some chew resistance
So I don't mix the nuts completely.
But it is entirely up to you how you want to do.
It smells so good.
And so I have in the icing sugar.
And a splash of water.
I actually think I should have in some salt ...
... and vanilla sugar
Vanilla sugar is absolutely nothing must, now I just got feeling.
Skip it if you don't have or don't want
Vanilla sugar in your almond pulp.
Here we go again.
Now almond pulp has a perfect texture.
The almond paste, I fill it up
In an alcohol bag.
So I just push down
An alcohol bag like this in a glass.
Then it becomes easier to fill it without scratching.
And so the almond paste is allowed to stand and go here in
the spirits bag until my
Semmel buns are fermented, baked
And the whipped cream whipped.
Now it's a few hours later and my
Semmel buns have yeast to almost
More than twice as big.
Which is perfect this will really be wonderfully fluffy
And airy buns that I love.
Now I will brush them with a mixture of
eggs, water and salt.
And why I have in water and salt
in this mixture, it is for the egg not to clump
so that we really get a nice brush
on the buns.
So I just break down the egg here.
And so i have in
some water.
One just splashes, it's not so careful.
And a little, a little salty.
And whisk
This gently together.
Until it is not clumsy, but a smooth and yellow batter.
That's how.
Do you see completely lump -free so that
We get a nice brush.
And the worst thing I know,
That's when it lumps.
So do you have an omelette
on his bun after baking.
Now the buns are finished.
And i bake them
in the middle of the oven at 200 degrees,
Over and under-heat for about 10-15 minutes.
-—-—-
When the buns are ready -baked so
is it just to let them stand on a grid to cool
Before we fill and decorate them.
Now my ballets have cooled down and
Become wonderfully soft and fine.
That which remains now
It is to get to a small lid, dig out,
fill with almond paste,
whipped cream and then decorate
with icing sugar.
How easy and
lovely as soon as and when I dig
clock and make a lid for my bull buns,
so i use a scissors like many others
and the trick here is not to cut straight on the surface
Without cutting into the bun
-—-—-
Because then you come while removing the lid
even have dug out of the bun
So you do not have to stand and dig in the bun to get the inside measurement.
Like that, a triangular lid I think is the finest.
So you get the inside of the bull bun.
If you want, you can dig out with, but this I think is good.
What is left over on the lid I usually remove.
The buns have received a lid and been excavated.
They may stand a little on the side while
We whip the whipped cream.
There is some stuff you need to think about
To get an airy and lovely whipped cream for their bran.
And the first one is
That you use refrigerator shell whipped cream.
It is easiest to whisk up, and one can whisk it longer
than room -temperature whipped cream, without butter.
Then you also don't want to whip the cream too much.
For remember we should stop the whisked cream
In an alcohol bag.
And when one has in something in an alcohol bag
Then it is further processed.
For one is on your hands
And the hands are a little warm.
And have you already whipped it
too hard.
Then it comes
to become butter -like and
in all likelihood cut
Before you can spread the cream.
So refrigerator cold and not whisking too much.
Then it is also good to whisk at slightly lower speed
So that you get a lot of air into the cream.
Do you whisk the cream quickly at high intensity
so you won't get as much air into the whip cream
Like when you whisk slowly.
So the three tips
Gives you a phenomenal cream to your bran.
Like that now the whipped cream is whipped
to soft tops and what remains
Now is to fill the buns
with almond pulp, whipped cream
and then decorate with icing sugar
Then it's just chopping in
The Sems are clear and ready to be enjoyed
And if you also want to try baking bran at home
So I put a link to the recipe down in the description
During the video.
Don't forget to like
And comment on this video and I will be happy.
Subscribe so you don't miss any upcoming videos.
And bake a lot of bran at home now
Because they are so good have it so great.
Bye