Clara: What the heck are you doing?
Kimba: I thought you weren't recording!
All: Hey!
Clara: Well. What are we doing tomorrow?
Kimba: We're going to Kebnekaise!
Clara: Hi youtube, this is my dad and little sister!
Kimba: Hello!
Kimba: (singing Wizard of Oz theme song)
Dad: Follow the yelow brick road!
Clara: Tomorrow I'll be climbing the Kebnekaise mountain with these two!
Or, we're climbing the day after tomorrow. First we're going to Kiruna and Nikkaluokta.
Kimba: Nikkaloukta is where we get off the bus.
Clara: It's 9 PM the night before.
So tomorrow we're flying to Kiruna, then taking a bus to Nikkauokta,
then we'll be trekking 11,8 miles to Kebnekaise, and 5,6 miles to the top.
Then we'll trek back down the mountain, and back to Nikkaluokta,
then we're taking the bus and sleeping at a hotel and then we're going home.
And this will take us four days.
So let's go!
Kimba: Come on, let's go.
Dad: (bangs head against the frame glass)
Clara: Bloody idiot
Kimba: You are so stupid.
Kimba: I'm ready! OH WAIT. Clara. Safety first.
Clara: Good morning! We're on our way to the airport to catch the plane to Kiruna.
Kimba: Beautiful, beautiful.
We're gonna have so much fun.
Clara: Are you sure about that?
Clara: We're here! Dad, what's the name of this place?
Dad: Nikkaluokta!
Clara: What was it called yesterday?
Dad: Nukkolokta.
Clara: And the day before that?
Dad: Nakkalikta.
Clara: So we've gone by bus from Kiruna to Nikkaluokta.
And it's freezing. But at least it's not raining.
Excited?
Kimba: Let's take photos!
Clara: OKI OKI
Kimba (in fake danish): ... in the little pocket.
Clara: What in the little pocket?
Kimba (still in fake danish): And then, you push... like hell.
Clara: If you want to say something in Danish and you don't know the Danish word, you say it in English.
With a Danish accent, and it'll sound Danish.
Like, I don't know the word for "dinner", but I can say like this:
"Jeg ska hjem og spise lidt dinner."
It works?!
Look at this! Kebne, babe!
Kimba: I'm yor kebne-bae.
Clara: The long wandering has begun!
(Wizard of Oz theme song)
(and the Wizard of Oz fecken DANCE MOVES)
Clara: Dad, what's that on your rucksack?
Dad: A baguette? Salmon baguette. For dinner.
Clara: Wooaah, oh god
FECKEN HELL
Damn!!
That bridge was horrible!
One adventure completed! Now continues...
Kimba: The great adventure!
Clara: CORRECT
Clara: Next... I'm gunna drink me piss.
And you didn't cast me for the Wild Kids TV-show you bastards?!
Look at me now!
Gosh this feels like the Blair Witch Project.
Since the last time I recorded, it's been raining.
And it's been raining.
And it's been raining some more.
So I've had my camera inside my raincoat all the way to the mountain lodge, where we are now.
That's 7,5 miles of pouring rain. Everything we brought is soaking wet.
My sleeping bag is so wet I could squeeze the water out of it. I don't know how I'm gonna sleep tonight.
I'm gonna freeze my ass off.
Can you hear the rain? This is so distressing.
I wasn't built for challenges like this.
I feel like a spoilt city kid. Which I am, to a large extent.
But it's taken so long?! Soon it's midnight. I think the last time I recorded it was 6 PM.
Holy fecken christ.
But, to see it from the bright side, we've arrived.
Kimba: And you could've had your period.
Clara: I could've had my period.
And also, we get to fall asleep to the cosiest sound on earth.
So we're gonna try to get some sleep and dry up a bit. See you tomorrow, good night.
Morning. Time for oatmeal.
How are you today?
Kimba: Wet.
Dad: Tired. Hungry.
Clara: We're so bloody miserable.
I slept really bad tonight, I had the worst pillow. It's just air, basically.
But now it's time for... mmmmmmhh delicious, look.
I think I'm gonna let the vapour get off of the lens, but
today we're climbing Kebne, right? But it's super foggy and it's raining.
If we're lucky, we might not be allowed to climb. He he.
Well. Here we are again. Ready to get soaked.
It's still raining, and these two are convinced that we're gonna reach the mountain top today.
I'm way more pessimistic. And I'm usually an optimist.
Kimba: Leeeet's doooo thiiiis
Clara: It's raining so much and I'm so happy that we're not crossing here.
We're going up to the snow instead.
I've got sore feet and no energy. Five out of five nasal sprays.
Okay, so, this is what's going on: my feet are super sore,
while we went down this hill to cross the bridge, over a frickin river,
my leg buckled twice and I have blisters on three different spots on my feet.
So I felt like, nah, I'm going back home. And I ain't even disappointed about it.
But these two will continue a bit more! Go you!
On the initiative from one of them, guess which one.
Okay bye, enjoy!
Clara: You're back! How did it go?
Dad: Like two fishes out of the water.
Kimba: Or like two hikers in the water.
Kimba: That's what we were.
Dad: We came a hundred meters from where we said goodbye to you.
Clara: So now we're here, having lunch. Noodle, soy protein and a very fake sweet and sour sauce.
Morning! Day three, with these two, in the forest.
Today we're trekking back to Nikkaluokta, then taking the bus to Kiruna and checking in at a hostel,
and tomorrow we're going back home! It's just that there are these 11,8 miles to Nikkaluokta.
So we thought we'd steal a ride with the boat.
Or, we're gonna go by the law and pay for our tickets, but
we'll be walking for 5,6 miles instead, and then go by boat.
Which is going to be lovely, since my right foot is aching badly.
This is something you can do.
This is a solution when the road is going to be wet
and you know you're gonna have to step in water with at least one foot
but the other foot can't wear a boot because it'll die.
I'm very not fresh right now.
Dad: I'm longing for a shower. But apart from that, I feel good!
Clara: Here's my rucksack. I'm longing to put that on my back.
See you along the way, bye bye!
Wow so pretty.
CUUUUTE
Kimba: Memebulle!
Clara: Woho, 0 miles left! After 5,6 miles!
Kimba: Hello
Clara: It's me
Clara: Gosh I'm so sweaty. Let's go find the boat.
Clara: What's going on?
Kimba: No!
Dad: You hate people?
Kimba: No! I love them!
Dad: She hates people.
Kimba: I love them.
Clara: Here comes the boat!
We've got off the boat, and can you see what I'm seeing?
Where the heck is it now
Clara: Can you see up there?!
Kimba: We haven't been there.
Clara: But we made a great try. We strained the bow. The string broke. So we went home. Shit happens.
Woohoooo!
We're back, bisheees!
Kimba: What did you say?!
Clara: Clever!
Dad: Clever yourself!
Dad: Well done!
Kimba: Arrhhhh clever...
Clara: We're on the bus to go back and I thought about something.
We've trekked over there. We've walked to that mountain.
How crazy is that!? We've walked all the way over there!
I can't even.
Good morning! It's day four on our great adventure.
Today we're going home!
We came to the hostel last night and had dinner, washed our clothes and went to bed.
I didn't film anything and you didn't really miss anything,
except for when some dude mansplained to me how the washing machine worked.
So now we're going to the airport transfer to go home!
Great!
I'm home, Bob!
Oh, really...
Shine bright like a diamond.
I'm home, I just said bye to dad and Kimba, and it's wonderful to be back home.
Oh my god. I'm gonna sit down and edit this video now, which is going to be interesting
because partly I feel like we haven't done anything because we never reached the mountain top.
It's 5,6 miles to the top and I don't even think we reached one and a half because of the heavy rain.
On the other hand, I'm not really disappointed that we didn't make it because it would've been so tough.
and partly, if you put together all of the distances we walked during these days, it's 21,8 miles.
21,8.
I understand why my feet have blisters and started to develop an extra heel.
I mean, look at this.
What is that.
But anyway. Thank you so much for watching and for joining our miserable mountaineering.
I enjoyed bringing you.
Take care and I'll see you guys as usual next week.
Bye!