Hey!
Guess what I've done? I've downloaded all my old pictures from Bilddagboken ("Photo Diary"). ALL OF THEM.
Holy ...
... cow.
Sorry in advance that the lighting is shifting, there's a lot of cloud and sun going on.
Those of you who are around my age, I'm 23,
you'll probably have very vivid memories of Bilddagboken.
Those of you who are younger might not at all recognise the name Bilddagboken,
in that case "Dayviews" might ring a bell?
I used Bilddagboken between the years 2007-2010.
Between the ages 12-16, ish.
I'd say that Bilddagboken was the instagram of the time.
Except you weren't as picky with which photos you uploaded.
It wasn't unusual to go to school, bring your camera,
take like fifty photos, go home and upload all of them to Bilddagboken.
You really had no shame. Or, perhaps that was because we were in seventh grade.
Anyway: Bilddagboken, which nowadays is called Dayviews, is closing down.
Dayviews/Bilddagboken won't disappear any more.
Won't exist any more, I mean.
So that's why I logged in and saved every single one of my photos, from 2007 to 2010.
And I thought we'd take a look at them today.
So what do you say? I say let's get going.
Okay! First pic! Wooo!
Hi and welcome to my Bilddagboken!
From year... 2006! I lied to you. August 16th, 2006. I was 12 years old here!
Here's a hint of my magnificent taste in furnishing.
When I was smaller, I had pink walls with big Peter Rabbit stickers along the sides.
12-year-old Clara thought "No. That is baby wallpaper. I'm a big girl now. I want another wallpaper."
Look! Lime green wallpaper with big, pink flowers.
HOLY SHIT
If you easily got carsick, you wouldn't wanna be in my room.
On the other hand, lime green and pink were my favourite colours. I got to chose the new wallpapers myself.
My mum thought they were "groovy" and encouraged me to choose them.
I'm raised in a family without a lot of money, so the next time we could afford to change wallpapers, I was 18.
It WAS fun to bring home your cool high school classmates or a first crush.
What more?
WOHOHOHO! Groovy glasses!
I'm 13 here, I've got long hair and I've started to get a lot of acne.
My whole forehead was like a bubble bath.
I remember a girl in class, and this is so mean, who said:
- Errr, Clara, you've got something on your forehead?
And I thought to myself:
- Errrr, I know, unfortunately I just can't pick them off?
And I responded, out loud:
- I know. My cat scratched me.
Niieeeee :'(
Oooohhhhhhhhh.
Selfie session! I'm 13 here.
Without as much acne? Maybe it went up and down, I can't remember.
It's also my sister, Kimberly, who's 11.
I don't really know what to say about this photo. I don't know what we're looking at, either.
Back then, you couldn't see yourself in the camera while taking selfies.
Also, we're taking the picture and we're very aware of that...
It's a mystery.
I got a thing for Photoshop, too. And it's so badly done.
I also thought I did it pretty neat.
I've made us a bit more tanned, Kimberly has got red hair and I've got brown,
we both have got brown eyes and we've also got some eyeliner each.
I regret that I still don't now Photoshop. I could've learned...
What's.... ooooohhhhhh.
Awww! This is quite cute.
Gosh so small!!
This is the period where everybody were chavs. Except for me.
Everybody had bleached, teased, hairsprayed hair,
bronzer in their whole face, white lipstick,
remember those days? Ah god, I wasn't cool.
Here I'm on my way to an athletics competition, I did high jump and hurdles.
Yeah. Cute.
Ahhhhh, speaking of cute.
To all 13-year-olds out there: it gets better.
Puberty hit me like a frisbee.
In the back of my head. On a frisbee golf course. Ouch.
There are 13-year-olds today who wake up, do a full drag make-up and then go to school.
This girl did not. This girl had never even heard of hairspray.
I love not being a teen anymore.
AWWW
My sense and interest in/for fashion still hasn't kicked in.
A lime green winter jacket, which like I said was my favourite colour,
and let's match that with an Örgryte football team beanie.
Did I know who Örgryte football team were? Nope.
Did I even watch football? Nope.
Which team did I cheer for? SWEDEEEN
I tried. This is how cool I was.
Remember that I said that everybody else were chavs? They had teased hair, push up bra's and started drinking.
And I... did this.
Oh my god.... no, what is this?!
Charming.
Oh god. I think I was the definition of white trash when I was 13.
I mean, I was cute as a baby,
and I've been lucky in the genetic lottery as a grown up,
but the years in between..?
Can you see in the background, can you see what's approaching..?
It's PUBERTY. Like a fucking TRUCK.
Yeah. Good stuff.
Hey look! This is from one of my competitions!
Between the ages 12-18 I did high jumping, and I LOVED it.
I really did. Also, observe my little tongue over here.
I couldn't do a jump without doing this:
This is in Stockholm! It says "The Klara Grill" here, and there's a sign that says "Clara" here.
And my dad said "Clara. We must take a picture."
What else is there? Oh good god what is this.
I remember us playing with these IQ-test puzzles,
with all pieces looking different and you're supposed to put them together to a square?
I took them and threw them in the air, while my sister took the photo while they fell.
And I was supposed to look "funny".
I look like a five year old on crack.
Oh yeah, I had a dark phase as well.
I don't think I've ever talked about it, but I had quite a tough time in secondary school.
In short, me and my bestie had a fight, which escalated and became much bigger than it had to be.
Our parents started fighting and we broke our friendship.
And I realised that she was the only friend I had that I could hang out with,
like I had other friends in class but I never hung out with them.
And all of a sudden, I was just so lonely,
with no friends at all outside of school.
And then, I started taking these kind of photos, that I thought represented my feelings.
This was at that time when emo-pictures,
which were either too under-exposed or over-exposed, were trendy.
I really wanted to be part of the emo gang.
This is fun, this is from the day before I turned 15.
As we all know, the law says that you have to wear a helmet when you're bicycling if you're under 15.
This is a pretty accurate description of how much of a teen revolution I had.
None at all.
When I was 15, I thought it was fun to...
... wait, it's way to bright in here.
I thought it was kinda cool to take artsy photos.
The caption says "I don't know who I am".
"I DON'T KNOW WHO I AM BUT I KNOW I'M YOURS" (- Håkan Hellström)
Here I've made it to second and third place in the district finals.
I'd guess I've won silver in high jump and bronze in hurdles?
Wooo, here I cut my hair short! This is in the beginning of ninth grade, and I cut off my hair.
This was the first picture I took of my hair when I was on my way home from the hairdresser.
It really isn't the prettiest haircut.
Once again: styling products.
Have some dirt in the hair.
Because now, it's just hanging there, Clara, I'm just saying.
I think this is from the same day when I cut it. The side fringe was my best friend throughout secondary school.
I loved this haircut, it was my best decision as a 16-year-old.
Once again: artsy pic. Black and white.
This was back when you drew a mustache on your finger and was like
Bonjour! Sacre coeur! Je suis Française! Come over here and kiss my french lips!
Isn't this the haircut that every art teacher has?
Awww, look..!
A haircut that's been growing for too long.
I can see the insecurity in my eyes.
I didn't like to be photographed. Little did I know that I'd make a living out of filming myself for the internet.
If I'd known, I would've got cardiac fibrallation.
Friends, those were all my photos!
I didn't show you every single photo because I have a LOT of boring pictures over there.
But these were the most interesting ones. Still fun though, how these have been out on the internet for anyone to see.
Okay guys, that's all for this time, thanks for watching!
Don't forget to write a comment, subscribe and share this video with your friends!
Take care and I'll see you as usual next Monday.
Bye!