Hey!
Do you know what it's time for today?!
It's time for an ALWAYS VLOG!
This video is made in collaboration with Always.
Pads, everybody!
Nostalgia, or what?
For those of you who might not have been around for a while, I've actually worked with Always before.
A couple of years ago I did SEVEN videos with them during half a year's time,
and it was all very appreciated.
I appreciated that you appreciated those videos.
So now, me and Always have put our brilliant heads together once again,
and it's time for a new Always Vlog!
Today I want to talk to you about Keep Going Like A Girl.
2014 I made a video about the phrase "like a girl".
To do something "like a girl" is to by definition to do something in a bad way.
They throw like a girl. They drive like a woman.
Or, on the other hand, to do just anything "like a man":
Wow. Cool. Solid.
Like a man, man up, grow some balls.
And you might think this is weird, since about half of the world's population are girls,
Or women. Or hags.
So if our identity is used as slang for doing somethng badly...
... then that's pretty dull. I won't accept that.
It's basically worth repeating, so here we go again.
But this time I want to talk to you about the phrase "keep going like a girl".
I think many recognize the feeling of not wanting to fail.
And not just like:
Well, it didn't work this time, shit happens but let's try again.
But more like:
ARRGHH NOO EVERYTHING'S RUINED I'M DYING
And I believe that a lot of people therefore don't even want to try new things
because in that way they don't risk failing.
But this is stupid, really. Of course you have to fail sometimes.
And this is something that me and Always want to change!
Keep going. Keep going like a girl.
Or like a boy, if you prefer that.
Or like a queer. Or like a human.
Or like a boss ass bitch.
I am a girl. So deep down I feel like everybody should keep going like me.
Because I'm, believe it or not, really good at going all in like a girl.
But I thought, it's not just girls who uses pads, so I asked Always if it would be okay to interpret freely,
to add your own identity or what you want to be.
And Always were like "wohoo keep goin gurrl"
but the main thing is to keep going like a girl.
Maybe because girls are the best. But I don't know.
And I know it's super easy for me to sit here and be all like
COME ON DON'T BE AFRAID TO FAIL
But believe me, this is a struggle for me too. Because you know what? I suck at failing.
Not that I'm a bad loser. I'm neither a bad loser or a bad winner.
I just don't like letting myself down.
Can we all just agree that bad winners are ten times worse than bad losers..?
I'd rather avoid situations where there's a slight risk of failure,
instead of throwing myself out there with the chance of succeeding.
Which I guess makes me kinda stupid.
Because this makes me miss out on loads of fun things.
Here's a list of three great things that I've never done because of the fear of failing:
One: dance classes at the gym.
The dance classes look like so much fun. But I think I'm too bad at dancing.
And that makes me don't want to try to learn, because I know I will fail on my way to learning.
That is stupid
Two: to apply for certain jobs or educations.
I could really just apply, and the worst thing that could happen is that I'd be declined.
But that rejection is freaking me out.
The thought of going to a job interview or taking an admission test
and recieve, in black and white, that "no, you're not good enough, you've failed"...
Just the thought of that is so much tougher than the joy would have been great if I'd get a positive response.
I suck. I'm worthless.
I'm gonna die poor and lonely.
And cold. Brrrr.
Three: stand up.
This says a lot, since I'm actually already working with humour.
I consider this, youtube, my profession,
to be humouros. I make an effort. I want my videos to be funny and entertaining.
But the thought of standing up in front of a live audience, and that audience might not think you're funny...
Ouch, my heart.
I've wanted to try stand up for four years. FOUR YEARS.
I've signed up for three different gigs, and then dropped out a couple of weeks before the event.
It's so hard. Maybe the thought of failing is harder than actually failing?
OH DAMN GURL that's deep
But I also think that in this hysterical fear of failing
you succeed with other things, because you basically forgot to be scared of the risk of failing.
Here are some things that I've succeeded with, despite my total fear of failure:
I cut all of my hair off. Twice.
I became a freelancer and started my own firm, and then an incorporated company.
And I actually failed, twice, before I understood how to fill in the damn paperwork correctly.
And I moved here. To Stockholm, from Gothenburg,
when I was 19 years old. I knew zero people here.
It's harder than you expect to build up work, a home and a social network from scratch.
I felt so lonely and like such a failure for like a year,
but now I've lived here for four years and I'm so happy I did it.
Inspiration!
So how do you do to keep going?
I think it's very important to practise failing.
Since it's so terrifyingly hard, start easy.
Buy a scratch ticket, and try not to get disappointed if you don't win anything.
After all, that's also a failure.
After that, intensify your failures. Apply for a job you certainly won't get.
But don't prepare to not get the job. Prepare to give it your best.
The risk is huge that you won't get it, the risk is huge that you'll fail.
But what if you actually get it?
Sometimes you gotta do things that are bound to fail, just to learn how it feels.
Are failures really that terrible..?
I mean, they're only dreams... getting crushed...
And the thing is, when you succeed, you go forwards, upwards,
but if you fail...
... you just stay. You don't go backwards, you don't get worse. You just stay.
And then you try again. Keep going. I believe in you.
And that's what I and my beloved Always wanted to speak about with you today! Failures.
But here's the thing. In a couple of weeks I'll be doing another Always vlog.
In that video I'll do something that I've dreamt about for several years,
but never dared to try because I'm too scared of failing.
I'm so so so so nervous.
Ahhh!! But I'm also so tired of holding back.
Time to go! And keep going!
I also want to be kinda inspo and say that if I can, then you can.
You don't wanna miss this! In a couple of days I'll announce on my instagram what my challenge is.
Do you also not like failing? If you have funny stories about failures, please write me a comment.
Guys, thanks for watching, and thanks Always! See you later!
Take care and I'll see you guys as usual next Monday.
Bye!