Damn, that's one nice rack! Huh?
I wouldn't be opposed to having some fun with her. What do you say, huh?
I've become gay
What?
Yes, I heard you, but what the hell do you mean by that?
Well, I mean that I would rather have some fun with you instead of, for example, that chick
With me?! Are you fucking queer or what?
Yeah, that's what I said
mean, maybe not with you, but I'm so freaking tired of all chicks
They're so fucking hard to please, and just keep on pestering me, and they never put out
I never get laid
But imagine if you start going for guys instead, I mean fag
I mean, you just have to go out on the street, find a gay guy and say
Hey, do you wanna fuck? Hell yeah, he'll say, 'cause he's a guy, horny and gay
It's fucking brilliant
But, for fuck sake, are you serious? No?
But do guys turn you on? It's a big fucking difference, you know that right?
Well, you could have the lights off.
I just think it's the most practical and logical choice, for me at least
So you've gone queer out of laziness?
Exactly! That's one way to put it.
It's more masculine as well, I mean, it's sort of gay to
suck up to and dance with the chicks just to get laid.
Come on, it must be a hell of a lot more gay to sleep with guys?
No fucking way it is. I don't think so.
It's way cooler, more masculine not at least, two men.
So, are you like turned on by me now?
Well…
What do you mean "well"?! What's wrong with me?
Come on, you're skinny.
Skinny?! Fuck it I'm skinny? I work out three times a week.
Yeah. You do. Good for you
But now that I'm gay and everything, I mean, now it's possible to raise the bar a bit
Before, when I slept with girls, there was no way being picky
Now I can pick and choose
No skinny boys for me
Fuck off!
Exactly!
That guy! For instance. I wouldn't mind having some fun with him