What is this? What is this?
What the hell .. away.
What the hell.
Hello?
What the hell is this a fucking joke?
Seriously! Hello?
Away with you ball fucking!
I don't get any air, help me!
Kent's cat and party?
I don't remember this.
I don't remember anything.
Oh, it's so hot.
"The Blue Man"
Hello?
Hello! Hello!
Thank goodness, damn what happy I am.
I come from inside the forest here.
I'm stuck in this damn costume. I don't know where I am.
This costume, it's so damn hot.
It's a fucking circus everything together.
What the hell…
No, but what are you doing? Hello?
No, stay! I must have help getting rid of my suit. I don't get out of it myself.
No, wait! You can't just leave me here.
What the hell...
Quiet. Sit, sit ...
I'll just go and, if you ...
No, his still.
Schas, disappear!
Why do you have to follow me for?
My God what a fucking day, that's not true.
Okay the cat.
What are you called now?
"Sailor Moon"? Okay?
Wow, wow, wow ...
Take it easy.
Listen to me now.
I go away and then I ask someone to help me out of the suit.
Then I'll come back to you. And helps you.
Is that good?
Great!
What the hell...
“I'm Allan Svensson, this is Dagens Nyheter
The investigation on the brutal politician murder is still taking place behind locked doors. "
Hello! Hello!
Hello! Do you only have time for a little while? I would really need help getting out of this suit.
What the hell...
Excuse me. I know I look the right foam. But I don't get out of this damn stuffed animal myself.
Oh, thank you as hell. It's so sickly hot ..
Smurf devil!
What the hell! Can't I just borrow a phone anyway? Huh?
Satan's phone ...
Look for fuck, so I can fit.
"I love you for who you are"
Hörredu, it's closed.
Leffe for fuck! Lol!
"Front and back!"
"Come on girls. Front and back."
Where is the brake?
Where is it?
Oh fuck.
Hell, Sailor Moon. Sorry.
Sorry, damn. You must be completely destroyed everywhere.
But what the hell should I do now?
Okay, now I'll help you here.
Okay, there is no danger. No problem. No danger.
Huh?
Myspace?
No, but what? Is there another cat?
Are you Sailor Moon? Who is it over there then?
Oh my God.
Okay?
Excuse me but .. I will .. no but ..
No but..
No, then you. Take it easy. Take it easy.
Excuse me, but who are you?
Where did you come from?
Hörredu, can't you just help me remember a little?
It feels like everyone else knows a lot of things about me and I kind of are the only one who knows nothing.
Why are you so kind to me? Huh?
I can be just what the hell inside this ...
I may not be like this at all ...
Blue...
The bear sleeps, the bear sleeps, in his calm nest.
Welcome to our simple home! He is not dangerous
Only you are serious.
But you can, however,, but you can never believe him.
He is not dangerous, only one is serious
Come all children. Now it's play.
But you can, however,, but you can never believe him.
You are not welcome here.
No!
Help!
"I am so happy I have a friend. His name is Otto and will then"
"I love life, it's me in love"
Blue Dabadi Dabad. Blue Dabadi Dabad. Haha Blue Dabadi-Dabada ...
Drop by me. Don't you understand?
Let me go! I'm going to buy cig for fuck! Stop now.
Calm down, now you calm down! Come on now!
Listen, stop putting off with this. I'm not a fucking stuffed animal.
What the hell? Mange?
You are alive? What the hell!
Where the hell have you been? Huh?
I've been running around the woods and looking for how damn ... oh damn!
You, you will never believe this.
I drive around looking for you.
And so damn suddenly I get to see the Negro fucking kid running around in the woods. HA!
The damn rat must have been infected from the party.
Damn lucky that I found her huh!
Wait, you I'm just going to buy some cig. Then we pull back.
Add the hell fucking rat. Come!
Come!
What the hell?
Mange?
Mange huh hell in hell. What are you doing?
The car is here?
What the hell? Release!
Release the rat I say for hell! Release!
Who
Damn
think
you
to
is?
Mange!
Release me your bastard! Damn!
Move!
What are you doing?
Don't you remember who you are?
Mange!?
Well, your bastard!
What is the fucking fun?
You, didn't you order a sausage?
What the hell..
Sub -text: Crazy Pictures Sync: Jacob Danell