LIKE
I’ve been diagnosed with ass cancer.
Can’t be cured.
I will die in a month.
For real, Morgan?
Here for you.
You’re kidding?
Yes, I’m kidding.
I don’t have ass cancer.
Haha, spot on, Morgan.
Awesome!
Cancer is not a joking matter!
I can joke about what I want?
Let’s do a mexican
wave for the tsunami!
Damn right! Lol.
Excuse me?
Totally crossed the line!
Chill out, I can say what
the fuck I want, right?
No, not if it’s discriminating
towards someone.
But don’t we have freedom
of speech in Sweden?
But then we also have
discrimination laws.
Where’s your fucking
sense of humor?
Do you think Kent and his
cat are funny too then?
For me it’s not humor when
you joke about cancer victims
and people who have
lost their families.
Well said!
Love your blog, Millan.
What gives you the right
to decide what’s humor?
I haven’t said I know
what humor is.
But I think it’s connected
to solidarity and joy.
And when you say
something discriminating,
that’s a really odd sense of humor
that would only make sick people laugh.
Love!
Have you seen Katla?
Stuck-up fucking cunt.
Nobody likes you.
I hope you die.
If you don’t delete your
blog and shut up,
I’ll soon be outside your door.
You won’t have any time to run.
I will cut your throat and rape
you with a fucking baseball bat.
Look, the cat’s in the bag!
Cute!
Adorbs!
Can’t you feed it some gravel?
Then the cat is stoned.
Morgan, what’s wrong with you?
Like a boss!
You’re so fucking inconsiderate!
It was a little bit funny?
Go Sanna! Woop woop!
You better watch it so that
Millan doesn’t tell you off again!
Burn!
Millan won’t say
anything anymore.
She’s deleted her blog.
What, really?
Sweet!
Why?
She’s probably saving
some plagued brats in Africa.
Hell do I know.
Fucking king, Morgan!
Was that supposed to
be humor too then?
Plagued children or you?
Hello?
Hello!?
Millan Danielsson is
so fucking pathetic.
I don’t even understand why
anyone would want to speak to her.
Damn right.
I actually think Millan
is pretty cool.
She’s actually a bit annoying.
She thinks she’s smart just
because people follow her blog.
False motherfucker!
What the fuck are you saying?
I love your blog!
Stop posting shit like
this on Facebook!
Millan is a false little whore
who spreads her PC bullshit
just because she is so
fucking horny for attention.
I’m not a racist,
that’s not what I’m saying.
But why in the hell should
a fucking nigger get a flashy job
just because he’s a nigger?
And why the fuck should a trashy
fucking whore get all this space
on her blog just because she’s
got a pussy between her legs?
Give the feminists more dick,
then they’ll be happy!
You need a punishment fuck. Whore!
One night we’ll be outside
your house, disgusting skank.
You trashy cunt.
You will die!
Negro means black. What’s wrong
with saying the name of a color?
Ignorant creep!
You suck dick!
If you prefer to suck dick then
go ahead, you fucking faggot!
At your contrary, I’m married!
Learn the language if you’re
gonna live here, raghead cunt!
Cunt!!
Someone should fucking kick
your ass, you fucking creep.
Someone should shove a
flag pole up you’re ass!
Your* not you’re!
You uneducated idiot!
Shut up cunt whore!
Fucking whore!
Whore!
Cunt!
Skank!
Bitch!
Die!
Subtitles: Lisa Gotthard