"OVERTIME WAR"
Ouch! Ouch! Ouch! No! Ow, ow, ow!
It's five o'clock, it's five o'clock!
Ah man, and I just got off my shift.
Ow, my intestines!
Oh no, I've got coffee-stains on my uniform,
you've got to be kidding me.
I can't get them out!
OK... A positive attitude strengthens the team spirit.
A positive..
Well at least we get our over-time compensation!
A little bit of extra money...
What?
Yeah, when you're at war after five o'clock
you get a bonus for your over-time.
We don't get a bonus...
Really, you don't?
No.
What? You guys should really bring that to your union's attention.
What's you hourly wage?
Six...
Six bucks?
You do know that minimum wage is nine, right?
We're having a strategy-day on Sunday,
planning the attack on you guys and what-not,
we aren't getting paid for that either.
They can't just exploit you guys like that.
You need to get your days off, there are laws on that, you know.
Man, you guys seem to have a sweet deal over here.
Yeah, it's pretty nice actually.
Here, have a Danish.
Well hey, you guys are winning at least.
It looked terrific when you came running in here before.
You seem great at this.
What the hell... You guys have toilets in your trenches ?
Yeah, we used to only have urinals,
but someone complained about it being discriminating.
Not everybody has a penis.
Great! Hey you! We're in a bit of a jam...
Blast–Bengt has transfered to the Suicide Brigade
so I need you for the night shift.
Oh, okay...
I'm actually starting to feel a little sick,
I'd really like to go home.
And you have a medical certificate for that?
No, I don't have one...
Well, for a leave of absence with full compensation
to be justified you need a medical certificate.
I really need to fill this schedule.
I understand, it's just that...
I could probably take the shift.
But you're German...
Well great! So then you'll take the shift.
And remember our motto
"A positive attitude strengthens the gut feeling."
I meant team spirit...
Oh, yeah! Would you be a sweet-heart and clean up
the toilet before you go on your next shift?
It's such a sorry sight,
especially now that we have the coffee table here and everything.
Absolutely.. I'll take care of it.
Employee of the month!
Oh wow, thank you! How nice.
God damn it...