It’s just so fucking hot.
SEE ME
And the leather, you just slide in,
sit down, and then…
It’s getting erotic in here!
The BMW’s got four-wheel drive.
The BMW is a fucking dick car.
Yeah, exactly.
The Audi, on the other hand.
That’s a cock magnet!
Didn’t that get your pants wet!
Some of us don’t need
a car for that.
Hey, don’t forget
who’s boss here!
Karin, was it?
Yeah?
What’ll it be then?
The BMW or the Audi?
I had a BMW on my last job, so…
And there it is, Ingrid.
That’s right.
It’s a fucking dick car.
Fuck yeah!
Hell, I think you’re
gonna do just fine here.
So Karin here, she’s gonna
relieve us a bit in admin.
While I’m looking for
our new section manager.
There, right!
Now girls, it’s Friday.
Let’s stop talking business, right?
I just had something
on the S.E.K.S report.
That we talked about yesterday.
What I did was, I put
the result in a diagram.
It’s really quite interesting…
Goddamnit, sorry girls.
But I had to leave
the kids at daycare.
Something that’s apparently
impossible with prostate cramps.
Well anyway, how’s the
After Work plans going?
Good that you brought that up.
Girls, we need someone to get
some snacks, some finger food.
Somebody, anybody? Come on!
I could do it. For sure, yeah.
Cool, boys. I’ll leave it to you then.
You did a fine job last time, so…
Yeah, really.
Yep, let’s go make some cash then,
so we can reward
ourselves with beer later.
Let’s get to work girls!
I just wanted to say that, I think
you’re doing an amazing job.
You should know that I see that.
Thank you.
Well, if they’re downing beers before,
then we should get to drink some wine.
Right?
Cheers, honey.
Cheers.
So, tell me about you know what?
What do you mean?
The position, has she asked you yet?
No, they’re not gonna give it to me.
Are you kidding me, hun?
Everyone knows that you’re
pretty much running this place.
Sorry, but that’s how it is.
You’re the most qualified.
I don’t know about that.
Who else would get it? Henrietta?
”Yeah, I’m just gonna scratch my
pubes first, then I’ll get you the report”
You’re awful!
If not, you’ll have to
convince the boss?
Ew! Seriously?
God gave us tits and ass, honey.
If we use them the right way,
it’s not us getting taken
advantage of, right?
I guess so.
You’re so cute, sweetie.
You’ll get this. Trust me!
Thank fuck I had a
burger before this!
This thing about
men faking orgasms…
Looking good, boys!
Honey, I wanna dance!
This is the funniest fucking
chick I’ve ever met!
Did I miss something funny?
Tell it again!
It might not be very
suitable for guys.
No, I’m okay.
Okay.
An intelligent woman, an intelligent
man and Santa Claus were out walking.
Suddenly, they find a fiver on the ground.
Who bends down to pick up the bill?
I don’t know.
The intelligent woman of course.
The other two don’t exist!
You’re not offended, right?
No.
It’s just a joke.
It was funny.
You should be a fucking
comedian or something!
So, I guess you’ve heard that I’m
assigning a new section manager?
Mhm, I think I
picked up on that.
I’ve been thinking of you.
I mean, you have all the
right merits, experiences.
Great!
You gotta be able to get your
hands dirty, when you need to.
Don’t be afraid of that.
Really get things done.
Just, dare to be...
...hard really, when it’s needed.
I, eh.. I think I’m gonna
head home, actually.
It’s been such a long day and…
But it’s been fun,
a real success.
We have to do this
more often. Really.
I guess I’ll… see you on Monday.
Show your balls, fucking cock!
I am convinced that you’re
the right person for the job.
Congratulations!
Thank you for this opportunity!
Hey, you!
I’m just going to a meeting.
You don’t wanna be a sweetheart
and take this to the kitchen?
Mhm, of course.
Great.
[Wash up the dishes.
Your dad doesn’t work here!]
SEE ME
Subtitles: Lisa Gotthard
POETRY FOR FISHES