2021 was the year when the rap world in Sweden was really shaken. The giants in the genre in popularity were described for several notable events, Einár who has been Sweden's most played artist was brutally murdered when he was shot dead outside his home in Hammarby Sjöstad, he was suspected of several serious crimes when he died. The rapper Adel was with Einár when he was killed and is also said to have been shot at the same time.
Two weeks earlier, Einár, Adel and the rapper ZE who was in the Netflix series "Fast cash" were involved in a serious assault, when a man was seriously stabbed, on Nosh & Chow. After all this, ZE has in 2022 been arrested and later arrested as a suspect on probable cause for a felony in an apartment with two other men, ZE has been convicted of a number of crimes before and risks a multi-year prison sentence if he is prosecuted and convicted for this. crime.
Adel was arrested and convicted of aggravated assault in 2022. Adel was sentenced to two years in prison in the District Court for beating his girlfriend and her sister bloody.
The well-known rapper "Dree Low" has been linked by the police to the criminal gang "Husby Hyenor". "ABZ" a member of Husby Hyenor was convicted of a high-profile murder that took place in front of many witnesses at 15:30 after a chase through Husby Centrum on 31 May 2021. However, 3 other people connected to the gang were acquitted of their suspected involvement in the murder, "Dree Low" mentioned the suspects in several of their songs and music videos such as "The Sweeper" and "Go Pro".
On August 18, 2021, 27-year-old Dree Low and several other men entered the Akalla Direkten store, where they took cigarettes, snus and sweets for more than SEK 5,000 without paying. The store's staff, who first stated that they had been robbed and threatened with death, later withdrew their information.
Despite his refusal, Dree Low was sentenced to one year in prison for robbery. At the end of 2021, there have long been rumors that Dree Low will end his career, which he then confirms on his instagram.
"Sho people! I'm quitting my music career to focus on the better. Will continue my creative work but in other ways. Thank you" - Dree Low
Dree Low's plans to quit music had been circulating for some time. Before this for a while, he deleted his Instagram. After his statement, the rapper's music videos also disappeared from YouTube, and then, among other things, the album FLAWLESS was downloaded from streaming services such as Spotify.
But that was not the last we heard from Dree Low. On April 6, 2022, the news that Dree Low will be prosecuted for his denial of aggravated gun crime and gun crime. According to the indictment, he kept a semi-automatic pistol completely open in his apartment and the prosecutor assesses that the weapon was "possessed in a criminal environment". This incident must have been in 2020 on two separate occasions when a house search was carried out in his apartment, it remains to be seen if he will be convicted of this and isf he risks a prison sentence of several years.
28 people will be sentenced in 2021 in the large gang case around the Vårby network. Two of the main characters: are the rappers Yasin and Haval.
Yasin was convicted of trying to lure a minor Einár into a kidnapping trap from a music studio in late March 2020. The court finds that he received an encrypted Encro phone for the criminal purpose, and that he collaborated with the former youth national team player in football, 24 -year-old Ilija Jurkovic about the plans.
Jurkovic has been singled out as a captain in the Vårbyn network. Yasin was sentenced to 10 months in prison for preparation for kidnapping. The prison term thus amounts to 1 and a half years, as he carried out the crimes under conditional release, and he had eight months left to serve for a previous sentence. Yasin has been serving his sentence for a few months now and wants to take the case to the Supreme Court to be acquitted.
After the failed kidnapping attempt in March 2021 with Yasin, Vårbynätverket instead turns to another artist, Haval, when that kidnapping was later carried out in April, according to the court. Haval attracted Einár, but was not in the apartment, the district court writes. In the apartment, Einár was tied up in the back, injured and photographed in humiliation. After that, Haval was involved in having "transported the plaintiff for the purpose that he would pick up and hand over to the perpetrators a weapon and two gold chains", according to the court.
Haval was sentenced to two and a half years in prison in the district court and the court of appeal for aiding and abetting kidnapping and aiding and abetting robbery. According to information, Haval can be released already during the summer.
Several other popular rappers have been suspected, prosecuted and convicted of various serious crimes. A rapper was sentenced to 1 year and 8 months in prison for a felony and was suspected in a murder investigation regarding a gang conflict.
Another well-known rapper was suspected and arrested in connection with a shooting, he can in preliminary investigations and on social media be linked to and have close ties with a group that is suspected in 6 murder investigations and several attempted murders.
One can more or less say that the top tier of the rap elite and Stockholm have been beaten out in different ways. Some people think that rapping about things like this is a self-fulfilling prophecy, that negativity attracts negativity.
When you hear this, do you make your own connections or draw your own conclusions about what this is due to and what went wrong?