At 16:44 you can see on a surveillance video how three men leave a car that has stopped in the middle of the tunnel and these three run towards the tunnel opening.
Two of them returned to the car, but the third continued to run.
20 October 2022
From the police documents it appears that the driver of a car while the picture was in a tunnel and the car was driven at low speed then it stopped completely.
Once at the scene, the police find a lifeless man in the driver's seat of the car, the driver is not wearing a seat belt and a revolver is found in the car.
The 21-year-old man whom the police find in the car is dead, he has been shot, at close range.
Kurdo and Allan are described as very close friends, pretty much even best friends.
September 27, 2021.
The police are ordered to Mälar Hospital in Eskilstuna due to the fact that a man came to the emergency room with a suspected gunshot wound.
It turns out that the man has been shot once in the left thigh and you can't get the bullet out.
it turns out that the young man has been shot once in the left thigh.
In Eskilstuna on this occasion, conflicts begin to flare up after a power vacuum has arisen in the city.
8 June 2022
The police are called to the Tallåsvägen and Högbovägen bus stop in Fröslunda in Eskilstuna due to a fight at the scene.
A fight has taken place and an unknown person has cut plaintiff Kurdo in the arm with a knife, which has caused major injuries.
20 October 2022
Kurdo together with two others and his close friend Allan's little brother Darin are on their way from Eskilstuna to Stockholm to go shopping.
Kurdo is said to have called Darin and said he wanted to shop in different stores and Darin says he mainly bought a t-shirt at NK. When Kurdo comes to pick up Darin, the two other young men are already in the car with Kurdo, he states that he does not know them.
The two other young men in the car said that Kurdo came driving from the center of Fröslunda and thus came behind the guys and then stopped when he reached them.
It was then about ten minutes past three on Friday afternoon.
Kurdo rolled down the window of the car and asked if the boys wanted to come with him to Stockholm. Kurdo was shopping and wanted company.
When asked, he says that it was not decided beforehand that they would come with them to Stockholm. It was just a coincidence that they met. They had had no contact earlier in the day with each other, he and Kurdo.
The third guy was not in the car when he and his friend jumped into it, but they drove a short distance and picked the guy up.
Asked if he recognizes the guy from before, he says that "I know who it is". When asked, he says he knows the guy's name.
The 4 young men with Kurdo as driver then drive towards Stockholm. The journey takes a little more than an hour and they stop on the way to Stockholm at a gas station in Strängnäs and do some shopping, the time is around 3:38 p.m.
Darin then changes his seat from the front seat to sitting at the back, Kurdo who drives the car sits diagonally to the left in front of him.
When they arrive in Stockholm, drive them into the Björk tunnel at Gullmarsplan in Södra länken.
Kurdo drives the car while Nasir sits next to him in the front seat and Ahmed just behind Kurdo, Darin sits on the right side of the back seat of the car.
Kurdo was sitting in the driver's seat looking forward when he was shot multiple times from behind and from inside the car, the shots striking the right side of the head.
The car then stopped abruptly and the three other young men get out of the car and move away.
Two of them soon return to the car and one of them calls 112, which you can hear here.
SOS 112 what has happened?
man shot in the head. hurry up, hurry up
we're coming. where is he shot somewhere?
shot in the head, the head.
is he breathing
he's not breathing... just come quick!
The third young man moves further into the tunnel and finally ends up in a shelter where he remains for a few minutes.
then he moves out of the room and into the tunnel again.
Finally he is met by the police who stop him and he is arrested.
The police are also at the car where Kurdo is shot in the front seat and he is quickly found dead.
The two young men nearby are also arrested.
In the backrest compartment of the front passenger seat, the suspected murder weapon, a revolver, is found with the barrel down.
A pair of gloves is also found in the tunnel about 100 meters from the crime scene / car.
Quite soon into the investigation, suspicions are directed at Darin, the younger brother of Kurdo's best friend, as the perpetrator. He denies any wrongdoing.
No clear motive behind the brutal murder can ever be ascertained or ascertained.
Later in the summer of 2023, the two other young men who were in the car are released and the suspicions against them are written off. However, Darin remains in custody and the suspicions against him are strengthened in the form of technical evidence.
17 April 2023. Alarm about shooting received by the police at 22.06 on Monday evening.
The shooting occurred in the Fröslunda district in Eskilstuna and once on the spot the police find a man with a gunshot wound.
The 25-year-old man is already known to the police and he dies later during the night from the gunshot wounds.
The 25-year-old's name is Allan and he is none other than the older brother of detained Darin.
4 days after the murder of Allan, Kurdo's little brother is detained on probable cause for the murder of Allan.
Kurdo's little brother is detained for six weeks on suspicion of the murder of Allan, Allan is the older brother of Darin, who is then detained on suspicion of the murder of Kurdo.
In other words, the best friends Kurdo and Allan saw both of their younger brothers as suspects for the murder of the other's older brother.
But after six weeks, Kurdo's little brother is released.
He is released because the suspicions have not been strengthened during the time he has been in custody. At the same time, the prosecutor says that the suspicions remain, but that they are weakened.
Back to Darin, at the end of August 2023 he is charged with the murder of Kurdo. Darin had just turned 18 two weeks before the murder.
At first he denies the crime, but the day before the indictment he is said to have changed his story. There he claims that the shots were fired in emergency defence.
Darin states that he has been threatened by Kurdo with the revolver and then allegedly managed to take the weapon from Kurdo and then shot him in self-defense.
The investigation shows that 21-year-old Kurdo was sitting in the driver's seat, looking ahead and driving the car when he was shot with four shots from a revolver, which hit the right side of the head.
Bullets and fragments remained in the head and exited through the left side of the face and these bullets/fragments then hit the driver's side a-pillar, the top of the driver's window frame and went through the glass of the driver's door.
The murder weapon, a Revolver, was fully loaded at the time of the shooting and was fired at Kurdo's head at close range.
The gloves found in the tunnel, about 110m behind the car, are linked to Darin and ended up there after they were in close proximity to a weapon that was fired and Kurdo suffered a bleeding injury.
After the shots, the other passengers fled from the car. While two of them stayed together and returned later, Darin disappeared from the scene on his own
. The weapon used in the murder was later found in the car and the investigation shows that the police were able to find out from which angle the fatal shots were fired.
The district court writes in the verdict that it is clear that Darin sat in the right part of the back seat, and from there fired four shots into the head of the 21-year-old man.
Now 19-year-old Darin is convicted of the murder of Kurdo and receives ten years and six months in prison for murder and aggravated weapons offences.
According to the verdict, the sentence has been shortened because the now-convicted has cooperated with the police and contributed information regarding another murder.
He has thus become a so-called crown witness.
What do you think happened inside the car on October 20, 2022 and why??