A group of young people has been charged in a serious incident in early April 2023.
The incident, which began in April, involves ten young individuals from different parts of Sweden, aged between 15 and 24 years.
All are suspected of serious crimes. It is about a kidnapping which then results in an attempted murder.
The incident unfolded when a 20-year-old man was shot during an escape attempt from his captors.
The victim alerted the police that he was kidnapped from Salem the night before and taken to an apartment in Vega in Haninge municipality in southern Stockholm.
The victim has stated that there were two light-skinned Swedish men aged 15-16 and four or five dark-skinned men in the apartment, that he was sitting in a car with a friend when he was taken away from Salem to an apartment at gunpoint by masked men and that he was shot in the calf when he fled.
Two teenage boys were arrested the following morning, suspected of kidnapping, extremely serious assault and aggravated weapons offences. one is from Ludvika and the other from Smedjebacken.
According to the indictment, six of the defendants planned to murder another young man in the apartment.
In order to attract the victim, one of his acquaintances was kidnapped in Salem and taken to the place where he was later subjected to threats, punches and kicks. He was also filmed in an attempt to pressure him to lure out his acquaintance. When he tried to escape, he was shot.
The primary murder victim never arrived at the apartment, thus averting his murder. The prosecutor has filed charges against six people for involvement in attempted murder and kidnapping.
A seventh person is charged with involvement in kidnapping alone. Two others are charged with felony weapons offense and one girl with failure to disclose the crime.
In addition to this, both the kidnapping victim and the intended murder victim are charged with drug offenses, a crime that came to light during the investigation.
The indictment suggests strong ties to the Foxtrot criminal network. Among other things, a defendant is said to have referred to the fact that he "drives with the fox", i.e. the "Kurdish fox", which underlines the gang connection.
There is talk that the 22-year-old from Gothenburg has stolen 11 bags of narcotics from the Kurdish fox, it should be worth 1 million kroner.
The 22-year-old has taken a batch of hashish worth around 1 million kroner in the street. This party "belongs" to the Kurdish fox.
The 22-year-old took on the task of transporting the party from Stockholm to the north of Sweden, such as Skellefteå which was the target. But during the trip, the 22-year-old regrets it and goes to Gothenburg instead.
Later, he takes the train down to Malmö and jumps off somewhere where he leaves the hash, which is alleged to have been sold at a greatly reduced price.
When the 22-year-old is in Gothenburg in March 2023, he has arranged a meeting with his friend, the 20-year-old victim from Stockholm, who comes to him and hangs out for a few hours. then the 20-year-old gets 300 grams of the hash to sell on in Stockholm.
On the evening of March 13, the 20-year-old goes with a friend to Salem's cemetery. They drove into the parking lot and stop a little way into the gravel field.
Then several guys come running with guns and drag the victim out of the car and into the back seat of the other car. The victim is then comforted by his friend and then they drive the victim to an apartment.
The victim does not want to state which friend is stalking him, but he is said to live in Salem and has connections to the Kurdish Fox. If you are forced to do something by the Kurdish fox, then you do it, he states.
The kidnappers told the victim that he would get a guy from Gothenburg, the 22-year-old, if the victim did not come to Stockholm, they would kill him instead.
The victim himself says that:
"To an apartment where they are holding me captive. A number of perpetrators. Forces me to bring out an old friend. But I can't get him to Stockholm either. So that I get beaten there as well. Being beaten, stripped and they took money and my mobile and my shoes and sort of stripped me and beat me.
Then they hold me prisoner there for maybe three or four hours at gunpoint. Then I get, they sit and smoke hash inside the apartment we were in. Then finally I manage to get, get them to give me a little leg walk outside because I think I'm not from any air. So we go for a little walk. Then on the way back in, I managed to trick my phone into me without them seeing it.
Then I send a location inf... a location pin to my older brother and write to the police that he should call the police. But then those who are holding me prisoner hear that I am sending this SMS this little ping that it is being sent away.
Then they aim the weapons at me and then I take my, my, my second there and thus the opportunity to succeed in running out of the apartment and then they start shooting after me inside the apartment.
Then I run out of the apartment and scream and down the street towards chain houses and ping and knock on every door and scream. Finally, I find a door that is open on a chain house. So I go in and lock the door and yell and tell them to call the police. So then a family wakes up and calls the police.”
At 03.30 on the night of Wednesday, the police received several calls about shots being fired, approximately five minutes later the police find the victim.
At 04.45 an order is made for a taxi to pick up Spetsbergsvägen in Vega.
The taxi driver gets a bad feeling on the spot that the young boys who were going to go with him felt a bit dangerous and therefore left without picking them up and calls the police.
When the police arrive at the address, it is empty at the designated address, but they make contact at the back of the house by the forest.
They order a young boy to lie down and in connection with this, another policeman discovers another perpetrator on a roof slanted behind.
When they have shackled the boy on the roof, it turns out he has a gun in one of his jacket pockets.
The first boy arrested said himself that he had a firearm on him and he also had a pair of assembly gloves/"nubber gloves" on at the time of his arrest.
The weapon appeared to be an older black gun, probably old eastern state arms. So two minors and armed 16-year-old boys are arrested at the scene near the apartment where the shooting and kidnapping allegedly took place.
The investigation shows that the empty casings, the ricochet marks in the hall, the bullet holes in the kitchen and the entrance door together with the bullets show that at least five shots were fired in the direction of the entrance door and the kitchen.
One of them hits the 20-year-old in the leg.
In summary, the 22-year-old steals narcotics belonging to Rawa Majid aka Kurdish Fox. The 22-year-old hands over parts of this to 20-year-old J, who will sell it on. For this, the 22-year-old is to be murdered.
In order to get hold of the 22-year-old, the 20-year-old is kidnapped so that he can attract his friend the 22-year-old.
16-year-old K, who has been involved, suspected and prosecuted in several high-profile cases in recent years, including recently he was acquitted in the case of Skogå's murder in January 2023, is charged with the kidnapping.
K, together with other people, must now be activated. Among other things, there are contacts with the alias Jokern2, which the police have previously suspected and connects to the rapper Moewgli belonging to the Bro network, which is allied with Foxtrot and the Kurdish fox.
The rapper Moewgli is also suspected of, among other things, inciting the murder in Skogås and inciting kidnapping in the Vega case.
Not only that, the suspected and accused 16-year-old shooter in this case regarding the kidnapping is now also charged with an attempted double murder he is suspected of having carried out just a few weeks earlier as a 15-year-old.
March 14, 2023. At 00:38 on the night of Tuesday, the police were alerted to a shooting in Rönninge in Salem municipality south of Stockholm.
When the police arrived at the scene, two elderly men were found seriously injured. In connection with a townhouse property, the police patrols quickly found a man who had been hit by several shots.
Inside the townhouse, another man was found with a gunshot wound and both of them were taken to hospital.
16-year-old L has now been charged with being the shooter and trying to kill the plaintiffs B, the teenage boys' father and another elderly man by breaking into their home on Järpstigen in Salem municipality, and there he fires several shots with a gun at the plaintiffs who were hit by several shots from the gun.
The violence caused extensive, severe and life-threatening injuries to the plaintiffs, but both men survive the attempted murder.
The target of the attacks is one man's son, as both of his sons are suspected of having committed acts of violence against the Foxtrot network.
One of the victim's sons was charged for the explosion in Hässelby on March 16, 2023, when rapper 5iftyy's father's house in Hässelby was blown up. 5iftyy belongs to the Bro network which is allied with Foxtrot and then had a conflict with Dalennaverket and allied 23st.
The rapper, Amin, and JJ, who are members of the gang 23st, are also charged with the explosion. Several of them are also indicted for the explosive device that was found on Importörvägen in Årsta on March 9. So both sons of one of the victims in the Salem shooting are connected to the 23st gang and are said to have made music with them.
April 14, 2023. At 00:08, i.e. shortly after midnight on the night of Friday, the police were alerted to a shooting in Rågsved in southern Stockholm.
When the police got there, they found an injured man right near an underpass in a residential area. The young man, who was 21 years old, had been shot with several shots, according to information including in the head, and he died at the scene.
On April 14th, approximately 9 days after the kidnapping and attempted murder in Vega, 21-year-old Abdou is shot dead in Rågsved, south of Stockholm, in an underpass.
In the investigation into the kidnapping and attempted murder, it appears that Abdou was involved in the kidnapping. His DNA has been found both in gloves and on a cigarette butt in the apartment where the kidnapped person was held prisoner.
Among other things, the death victim had previously been convicted of aggravated robbery regarding events in 2019 when there were seven taxi robberies in two weeks in the Rinkeby area and the surrounding area.
He was then sentenced to closed youth care together with several others, and placed in a SiS home. He has also been convicted of minor drug offences. No one has been charged yet for this murder.
Those indicted for the kidnapping and attempted murder in Vega are:
L 16, the suspected shooter in the Salem double murder attempt is indicted regarding Vega for attempted murder, aggravated weapons offense, kidnapping. He has written that he is going to do something to a guy in Stockholm and get 300, that it is a gang war and that he is "running" with the fox.
J is 16 years old, the suspected shooter in the case in Vega as the gloves Joel was wearing at the time of the arrest were in close proximity to the firearm when it was fired., he is charged with attempted murder, aggravated weapons offence, kidnapping.
the DNA and fingerprints of the two 16-year-olds have, among other things, been found in the apartment where the kidnapping and attempted murder took place.
K 16 years charged with inciting kidnapping and inciting attempted murder. He allegedly instigated L and J as shooters. Before and in connection with the crimes, he has provided information and instructions to L and J.
Modou, 24, charged with kidnapping, attempted murder, or aiding or abetting murder. On April 3-4, 2023, he went with J and L in a taxi from Rågsved and showed them the way to the apartment on Hermantorpsvägen in Haninge where L and Joel N would kill the plaintiff. He has also participated in the kidnapping, which was aimed at luring the target to the apartment on Hermantorpsvägen where he was to be killed.
Two brothers are charged with aiding and abetting attempted murder and aiding and abetting kidnapping. G has, at an unknown location in Sweden sometime at the end of March to April 4, 2023, promoted the act by conveying the assignment to L and J and promoted the act by giving advice and instructions on how the plaintiff should be shot dead.
22-year-old A, who was a friend of the kidnapped 20-year-old, is charged with kidnapping.
The victim, 20-year-old J, and the target, 22-year-old J, are charged with drug offences.
What do you think about this case?