Imagine that you are a very close business partner of someone.
You make a lot of money together.
What would they have to do to you to get you so upset that you get rid of their mother?
Let's find out the answer now.
How does the child of refugee parents go from being a boy to finally settling in a small dark, cold and Nordic country,
to growing up over 30 years later to a man who finds himself in the middle of cross-border politics and diplomacy, the most wanted and ruthless criminal and leader of a feared gang wreaking havoc across multiple continents.
Bosnia, Tunisia, Turkey, Norway, Iraq, Sweden, Iran, the whole world has been the playing field.
This is the story of the Kurdish fox and the foxtrot. And where is he now?
When the Foxtrot network, once a unified crime syndicate, split, one of the most violent periods in the history of organized crime was unleashed. The now fractured Foxtrot network has split into two hostile phalanxes, with ten central targets of highest priority for each gang.
At the heart of this bloody conflict are two men: Rawa Majid the Kurdish Fox and Ismail Abdo the Strawberry.
They, along with their followers, have turned their former bonds of friendship into a battle to the death.
Ask yourself, could you kill the mother of your worst enemy?
Benzema has previously been painted as the Kurdish Fox's right-hand man in the Foxtrot network, now it seems that the wind has turned, at least if you look at the surface.
Has Benzema distanced himself from the Kurdish fox and foxtrot and made peace with the Strawberry?
all these questions you will get the answer to!
drug smuggling, kidnappings, arson, assaults, bombings, shootings and fake deaths.
This tragic story has it all.
We know how the wave of violence started a conflict with the Dalen gang about, among other things, the city of Sundsvall and the region's drug market.
One man in particular has a strong hand in what happens in Sweden in 2023, making him one of the most wanted men in Sweden.
This is the story of Rawa Majid, 37 years old, better known as the Kurdish Fox, the leader of the Foxtrot network.
Rawa Majid is of Kurdish descent and was born on July 12, 1986 in Iran. His parents fled when the Iran-Iraq feud intensified. Only a few months old, Rawa came with his family to Uppsala.
Uppsala is a small city about 70 km from Stockholm, Sweden's capital. Rawa did well in school as a child. After finishing school and turning 18, he opened his own small business in Uppsala.
However, his career in crime began not long after. In 2010, he was sentenced to eight years and six months in prison for several drug offences. This included handling cocaine that he imported from the Netherlands.
In February 2015, he was granted early parole. He owned an ice cream kiosk in Uppsala which he later used for money laundering. However, the freedom of the Kurdish fox was short-lived. Just months after his release, he violated his probation and was imprisoned once again.
In 2018, he was released again and banned from leaving Sweden.
One of the Kurdish Fox's cousins, Shad, was the leader of the Headshot League, or HSL. Shad was shot dead in his car in Barkarby 5 June 2018.
A double murder occurred in Kista in 2017 when the leader of the gang Lejonen, was shot dead in his car together with another young man on 8 March.
Shad's brother, Kurdish fox's cousin, Lanko was convicted of the double murder. After Shad's death, there was even speculation within the family that the Kurdish Fox was somehow involved in the murder of his own cousin Shad.
For some reason, threats directed at him, the Kurdish fox got permission to leave Sweden.
He was allowed to travel to his parents' country of birth, Iraq, and eventually registered in his mother's birthplace, a city in the eastern part of Kurdistan, Iraq.
The Kurdish Fox picked up where he left off and began smuggling and selling narcotics again.
It wasn't until 2020 that he had appeared on the radar as a major drug trafficker in Sweden. After the police managed to hack into the encrypted chat services he used, he became a wanted man.
Sweden is one of Europe's richest nations and was previously one of Europe's most peaceful nations.
Recently, Sweden has fallen into an unprecedented wave of violence. Throughout 2022, 391 shootings were recorded and 2023 was no different.
In the month of September 2023 alone, eleven people were shot dead. These gangs recruit young adolescent boys, some as young as 13 years old, to carry out missions.
Rawa Majid is better known as the Kurdish Fox, leader of the Foxtrot network.
The central and important members could at least be identified early on by their golden fox rings and chains they wear.
The Foxtrot gang mainly focused on bringing in large consignments of various drugs to Sweden and then selling them on to other gangs.
They are now also notorious for not shying away from using brutal violence.
At least since 2020, the Kurdish Fox had total control over the Foxtrot gang and its operations. In November 2021, Swedish police together with Iraqi police started an operation and raided the house that the Kurdish fox was in.
Unfortunately for them, he had been tipped off and the fox was gone.
The Kurdish fox seems to have political connections and contacts in this area of ​​Iraq, they seem to be trading favors for favors at this point anyway. In March 2022, he is moved to Turkey under a false name and by buying expensive real estate there, he manages to become a Turkish citizen.
His name then slowly but surely starts to appear more and more in the Swedish media.
After two large shipments of narcotics were seized by Swedish police on February 11 and 14, a conflict started between the Kurdish fox, his Foxtrot network and the Bandidos MC in Sweden over who would take the loss for these lost drug deliveries.
Within two weeks of the lost and seized shipments of narcotics, the Bandido MC clubhouse in Brandbergen, south of Stockholm, was fired upon with an automatic weapon.
On March 4, 2022, an innocent hairdresser was shot dead in his car outside the same clubhouse after the shooters misidentified him as a Bandidos member.
Among other things, members of the Zero network were convicted of this murder.
Two weeks after this murder, the Kurdish Fox ordered his minions to get ready for new actions against the Bandidos MC
March 28, 2022 a young man can be seen entering a gym in the middle of Stockholm City and then running down the stairs to the gym's basement level.
His mission is to shoot a certain Bandidos member who is training at this gym. About to do so, another man inside the gym, Fredrik, a completely innocent man who was familiar with the Bandidos member, tried to step in and stop the young lad.
Several shots are then fired inside the gym. On surveillance footage, you can see visitors running up the stairs in total panic.
You can also see the intended target, the Bandidos member, being limped out of the gym.
The shooter also ran back up the stairs and even tried to escape through the wrong door before someone guided him in the right direction.
Fredrik who tried to help died of his injuries in hospital a few days later. The hired killer turns out to be only 16 years old when he did it.
Rapper 5iftyy, who belongs to the Bro network, which is allied with the Kurdish fox and foxtrot, is seen in a music video wearing a t-shirt that reads, among other things, "Free Frunze" who was the 16-year-old killer.
In April 2022, a gardener in a park in the Turkish city of Marmaris found a bag that someone had left behind. The bag contained wads of cash and was handed over to the police.
Police counted several currencies with a total value of over $12,000 inside the bag.
After checking the security cameras in the vicinity of the park, the police managed to identify a man named Miran Otoman. They invited Miran to the police station to collect the bag.
He introduced himself as a shipping tycoon, but the police decided to run his ID through all their databases and discovered that this was an internationally wanted man
Interpol had a red notice for him. The man in front of them was the wanted Kurdish fox.
The Turkish police arrested him at the same time they raided his villa where they found unlicensed weapons, large sums of cash and luxury items such as designer clothes, watches etc.
But this was not the end of the Kurdish fox. He had bought Turkish citizenship for around $400,000 in 2020.
Turkey has become a haven for criminals as they can buy citizenship by investing in real estate in the country. Despite the fact that Sweden, together with Interpol, has requested his extradition, the Turkish authorities have refused to do so.
Following this, Swedish police shared an extensive police report on the Kurdish fox and his Foxtrot network in order to help Turkish intelligence prosecute him.
Information about the whereabouts of the suspects, pictures of them and what they are accused of and more evidence. The report was highly confidential and could only be read by certain police officers.
The document was leaked, the Kurdish fox got access to the report, it turned out when later in 2022 a gang member was arrested in Sweden and on his iPhone was found the highly confidential report they had made to help Turkey.
But the worst was yet to come.
Towards the end of 2022, a conflict between Foxtrot and the Dalen network began.
Michael alias the Greek is a 25-year-old man who, despite his young age, is said to have managed to become a leading figure in the Dalen network, he is said to live abroad for his own safety.
The police describe Dalen as a criminal network that, among other things, originates and operates in Enskededalen, but also in Skarpnäck and other areas in Stockholm.
They also have branches in other parts of the country, including Sundsvall and Gotland.
They engage in drug trafficking, violent crimes, weapons crimes, extortion, etc.
That they are active actors in violent conflicts is also a well-known fact through, among other things, investigations and intelligence.
The fact that members often wear bulletproof vests, even with heavy plates to withstand heavy ammunition, is also a clear indication that they are in violent conflict with other criminals.
The police's belief was that Mario Golzar, aka Super Mario, was until recently the leader of the Valley Network and their various areas.
He is said to have supplied the areas and networks with large quantities of narcotics. However, Michael, aka the Greek, has probably largely taken over his role as a leader,
including because Super Mario was imprisoned when he was convicted of drug smuggling and also for his involvement in the kidnapping and blackmail of the famous rapper Einár before his death.
Rapper Thrife is described as a high-ranking member of the Dalen network and he is considered to be just below Greken in the hierarchy.
He is often seen with the rest of the older core members of the gang.
Another well-known Swedish rapper, Haval, is also considered by the police to be a high-ranking member of the Dalen network.
Haval has already served several prison sentences, most recently for his involvement in the kidnapping of the now-deceased rapper Einár.
We know how the wave of violence started, a conflict with the Dalengänget about, among other things, the city of Sundsvall and the region's drug market.
In the middle stands KP, a 21-year-old man who has been singled out as the key person and the extended arm of the Kurdish fox and foxtrot in the area regarding the conflict in Sundsvall with the Dalen network.
KP has initially been part of the local Dalennättverket grouping in Sundsvall. Then after an argument with his old friends and Dalen, he switched teams and went over to the opposing side Kurdish Fox and Foxtrot.
When KP, who became central to the major indictment in 2023, felt badly treated by his cronies, the seeds were sown for what is now being played out during one of the country's largest gang trials to date.
KP is suspected of having coordinated several attempted murders through shootings and explosions, all in order to eventually expand Foxtrot's control over northern Sweden's drug markets.
“He's not going anywhere. Inshallah. Tomorrow he will already be in the crocodile's mouth." A message sent by KP.
The recipient of this message was a person hired to spy on an intended murder victim and chart his habits and then report this back to KP.
et starts with some chat messages in November 2022.
The conversation starts with KP feeling badly treated by his old friends in the Dalen gang. That's KP's version of events, and he also alludes to accusations that his old friends tried to "cheat" him, trick him into a death trap.
He writes to a key person in the Dalen gang, you will have war now. I'm gonna fuck you. And you will see.
On December 2, 2022, there will be a shooting in Sundsvall. The recipient of the messages is shot at together with two friends. He is hit by several bullets, but survives.
KP is thus believed to have taken lethal measures against his old friends and now he belongs to the Foxtrot gang constellation.
This is confirmed by the fact that he himself talks about Foxtrot's goal on Snapchat to become the biggest drug dealers and suppliers in northern Sweden and wipe out the competition.
But what both parties think they are saying to each other in secret, encrypted messages online is in reality under police surveillance, step by step.
Then 19-year-old Yosef Key was very close friends with gangster rapper and superstar Einár at the time of his death. Einár had just turned 19 the month before when he was betrayed, chased and shot dead outside his apartment in Hammarbysjöstad in Stockholm.
In addition to the fact that after the murder of Einár Yosef still seems to have a continued close relationship with Einár's half-brother, Einár's name or nickname Nisse is mentioned several times in the criminal investigation by Yosef or by others involved in the murder plans against the rapper Thrife, a member of the Dalen network.
Does this assassination mission have anything to do with the murder of Einár. Is it Revenge or is it connected to something else entirely? or both?
On December 13, 2022, after being under surveillance for several weeks, Yosef was observed under police surveillance. Yosef acted nervously, jogging a few stretches and looking around a lot. Yosef bent down and placed something next to a couple of pots outside the gate.
Yosef was then stopped and checked on the same street. He was arrested when police discovered he had hidden a weapon, a loaded Glock, outside the gate. Joseph's phone was confiscated and very interesting things were later found there.
Through external and internal intelligence, Joseph can be connected to several addresses.
House searches are therefore carried out in several places. The police find ammunition and narcotics in an apartment in the basement and the storeroom, the police find several kilos of amphetamines, hash, etc.
They were seized in connection with the house search being carried out. Gazmend and another man came walking towards the building. They were checked by police personnel and taken in for questioning.
Gazmend is the same man whose name is on a long enemy and death list created by the Dalen network. Seven months later, Gazmend was shot dead on a balcony in Ulvsunda on July 10, 2023.
Yosef Key is also on this death list. It appears that Yosef Key had a close relationship with the now murdered Gazmend and Einar's half-brother.
Having been in custody since mid-December 2022, there are several interesting chats that touch on the then-ongoing major gang conflict in Stockholm with, among others, the users Ghost worldwide, Animal shopping and El Zorro, one alias of which belongs to the Kurdish fox.
According to the investigative report, Yosef is in a group chat called Team Nisse, aka Team Einár on the encrypted network Signal. The following content consists of, among other things, the planning and preparation regarding a murder of the rapper Thrife.
The chat material shows that several attempts are made to locate where Thrife lives or is staying. They are trying to assemble a hit squad of at least three men to carry out this murder.
The sender, a person with the username Ghost worldwide in the encrypted chat app Signal is then said to be a high-ranking man within the Foxtrot organization, takes the lead in instructing Yosef how to plan Thrife's murder in the chat material.
It is also stated by Ghost Worldwide that a "japping" or murder must be taking place as an unknown rapper allegedly said very disrespectful things about Einár in a TikTok video, both Ghost worldwide and Yosef Key are wondering who this rapper is.
The user Ghost Worldwide writes that the Kurdish Fox is basically Upplands Bro or the Bridge Network, and that they were very close friends of the now murdered Einár.
Yosef was convicted of the crimes and sentenced to seven years and ten months in prison for his involvement in the conspiracy to murder gang-linked rapper Thrife.
Now we go back to KP and Sundsvall, the origin of the extremely brutal conflict between Dalen and the Foxtrot network. The feud stems from a battle for control of the drug market in certain cities and regions.
Sundsvall had long been supplied with drugs by the Dalen network. Then Foxtrot tried to enter the market, which led to the beginning of this conflict.
The valley network was not going to back down.
Police investigators have been able to follow what is happening in real time through data monitoring, while the various sides begin to plan and map out how to kill their enemies. A total of ten murders are believed to have been planned and to help him, 21-year-old KP had his own death list.
According to information, he had not been at the address for a long time and was believed to be abroad. He has several ongoing conflicts. One hypothesis was that he was involved in the murder of Einár.
"I stand with Scar, brother it sounds *bang*"
They were childhood friends, but ended up on opposite sides of a conflict. Gang member and rapper Dumlee was shot dead on 25 December 2022 in Rinkeby, Dumlee was with Einár when he was shot dead in October 2021 and was formally suspected of being involved in the murder.
So one theory was that now even Scar, 23 years old, is subject to reprisals because of Einár.
Scar is described by the police as a person with great capital for violence.
From the beginning he was considered a running boy for the Dalen network, but he was soon responsible for security at larger meetings and as the one who was armed at these, also acting as the Dalen network's responsible for handling and moving the gang's weapons.
It soon became clear that he began to act as a climber or perpetrator in violent crimes, something that he seems to find satisfying. He sees himself as a "sicario" assassin.
Scar has also acted as a bodyguard for the Greek, Michael, the leader of the Valley Network, both in Sweden, but also when they went abroad.
Scar is said to have carried out acts of violence, shootings and murders on behalf of his Dalen network, but also carried out missions for payment and favors for other networks that are allied with the Dalen, for example 23ST from Farsta.
The police authority's overall assessment is that SCAR is part of a criminal network, the Valley for Organized Crime.
Scar is suspected of being a target for attacks during the conflict with the Kurdish Fox and Foxtrot.
A hand grenade is thrown into the doorway where Scar and his family are written. In addition to that, Scar is also suspected of being an active actor in acts of violence against Foxtrot and their allies.
After the attack on Scar and others in the gang, the conflict between Dalen and the Kurdish fox is a fact. Several shootings and explosions targeting homes in Stockholm occur.
In the early morning hours of New Year's Eve 2022, an apartment building address linked to the rapper Haval, a member of the Dalennävterket, has its gate blown off by a bomb.
The valley network then begins to plan revenge against the opposing side. They recruit climbers and torpedoes from all over Sweden who, in exchange for payment, will carry out various acts of revenge on their behalf.
Here are some of the incidents that the police believe the Dalennävretnet is behind.
Among other things, the police have compared the names and addresses of those who have been exposed to crimes against a so-called "death list" that they found on an arrested gang member's mobile phone. There are names and addresses of people whom the Valley Network at the time considered to be on the opposing side and are their enemies.
January 2, 2023. Early in the morning, an explosion occurred in Bagarmossen in Southern Stockholm. Someone threw a hand grenade into a stairwell of an apartment building, causing shrapnel damage as a result.
The aforementioned Yosef Key connected to the Foxtrot network and his brothers are listed at the address.
Yosef Key is on the Dalennäverket's list of enemies when he was convicted of murder plans on the Dalennäverket's rapper Thrife.
An 18-year-old rapper from Huvudstad in northern Stockholm who was signed to a record company controlled by the Dalennätverket is found guilty and sentenced to five years in prison for throwing the hand grenade.
January 5, 2023. A hand grenade is thrown into the stairwell to the address of the apartment building in Farsta, south of Stockholm. A person on the death list lives there.
The conflict between Dalen and Foxtrot escalates significantly.
On January 12, 2023, shortly after 04:00 in the morning, a door and the facade of an apartment building in northern Stockholm are sprayed with bullets. It is an attack on the Greek and the address he is connected to.
January 14. On Saturday morning, bullet holes were discovered in an apartment door in Märsta. Another attack on the Greek.
January 16. At 19:38. A shooting takes place in northern Stockholm in Hagalund on the home court of the NBA gang.
A then 21-year-old rapper was found at the scene lying with gunshot wounds, enlift data the victim was shot from behind. He was shot several times and taken to hospital with serious injuries.
Now 22-year-old rapper Lee Blockboy, who then belonged to the NBA gang from Hagalund, is shot with several shots and seriously injured, but survives the assassination attempt. The rapper's name was on the death list.
According to reports, this was due to an internal split within the NBA gang where they took different sides in the Foxtrot and Dalen gang conflict.
January 17. On Tuesday morning, a restaurant on Södermalm in Stockholm was damaged by a powerful explosion from an explosive device. The restaurant is connected to relatives of the Greek.
January 18. A new bomb is placed and an explosion occurs the next day, on Wednesday morning, this time at a company property in Kista in northwest Stockholm. This attack is also directed at the Greek.
Early in the morning of January 18, the Greek himself enters into a discussion with KP. First he tries to persuade KP not to run with the Kurdish fox.
“Do you think the fox cares about your family?” he asks in the chat conversation. “This is about you going with the fox against me.”
"You're getting into something that won't end well."
KP responds to this message by writing, “we will go to war with you in the street. But since we can't find you because you're hiding, we have to lure out your whores.”
“This pisses off the Greek. The Greek writes back that KP will soon cry blood and that relatives and family are also in danger because of KP's choice. "The fox only has 15 yearlings."
“I have snipers, real killers.” “You will be hunted for the rest of your life. You are dead."
Soon after, the police can follow how KP is suspected of having planned a murder of a member of the Dalen. The 21-year-old and the Foxtrot gang rely on using and hiring freelancers, mainly very young men and teenagers from other parts of the country, to help them carry out violent attacks.
For payment, three so-called steps, people who carry out the deed, travel from different parts of Sweden up to Sundsvall.
They are assigned to detonate a bomb outside the home where the target from the local Dalen network lives. Three other young men, "shooters" also travel from different cities up to Sundsvall
They have been assigned to carry out an assassination on another member of the Dalen gang and they have a Glock with them.
Finally, two bomb experts from the Stockholm area travel up to Sundsvall who have previously helped them to supply the Foxtrot network with explosives. "Blow up his entire whore balcony," writes the alias Hamado from the Foxtrot network.
During the planning, those within Foxtrot agree that the cubs will carry out the deed. It appears obvious in the investigation that it is a stated strategy to use minors as soldiers.
They are either lured with money, status tricked or threatened to take on these assignments while some young people actively seek freelance assignments, they want to do this.
KP is very clear that you cannot back out once you have agreed to an assignment. When it appears that the girlfriend of one of the intended victims may be in the residence to be attacked, the perpetrators receive the following orders from KP.
"Kill her too if you must."
"It's not a problem."
21-year-old Wafi is a local rapper in Sundsvall and also a high-ranking member of the local Dalennävterket phalangen in the city.
At one point, KP tries to use an older woman to lure out his former friend Wafi so he can be shot dead. But KP will go no further than planning because on January 26, everything changes.
Until then, the police have followed every step of the planning and hours before the attacks, the police raid a number of homes and properties in Sundsvall.
The police find thermos bombs, automatic weapons and pistols, among other things. Several of the now over 20 defendants were arrested there.
KP himself denied all the allegations and claims that the mobile phone and chats linked him and which of the police's biggest evidence against him is not his.
In books that he has borrowed, notes have also been found where there is no comment all the way through, apparently as a call to other detainees not to answer the police's questions.
January 19, 2023. Three incidents take place on the same day. Several shots are fired at an apartment in Farsta in southern Stockholm.
Several shots are also fired at an apartment door in Husby in northern Stockholm. On the death list, the address in Husby is listed as "Foxy far" aka the father of the Kurdish fox.
even a shooting at a house also takes place in a smaller, exclusive neighborhood outside Uppsala. The target in the house is on the death list with address and name.
This is the same residence and area where a completely innocent 24-year-old female student dies when the address is subjected to a bomb attack and several nearby houses are destroyed during September 2023.
On the evening of March 2nd, the television program Wanted is broadcast. Two young men are wanted for crimes.
They are suspected of carrying out the January 19 shooting, the drive-by attack targeting relatives of the Kurdish Fox. The residence is fired upon from a car with automatic weapons.
The TV program publishes the names and pictures of the suspects. 3-4 hours later there is a knock on the door of a house in Tullinge, south of Stockholm.
A man in his fifties, the father of one of the wanted young men, lives there with his family. He opens the door and is immediately shot several times. A moment later he is dead.
Serdar, the victim, is believed to have been killed only because he was the father of the 25-year-old man who police say shot at the relatives of the Kurdish Fox.
A swift and brutal revenge exacted by the Kurdish fox.
January 2023, a hand grenade is thrown into the stairwell of apartments in Skarpnäck in southern Stockholm. They can also be found on the death list with given apartment numbers.
In the first 26 days of 2023, there had already been at least 13 bombings and one shooting each day.
Explosions, shooting, arson and other excessive violence.
In the past year, Swedish news has been dominated by such headlines and gang violence has taken an unprecedented hold on Sweden.
According to police data from 2023, the Zero network was established shortly before 2020 and originates from Jordbro, which is located on the south side of Stockholm.
This neighborhood has been home to many notorious criminals throughout history. They eventually became an ally of the Foxtrot network.
The Foxtrot network is led by the Kurdish Fox. According to Swedish police, the Foxtrot network organized large-scale drug smuggling to Sweden for wider distribution both within Sweden and outside its borders.
Cocaine, cannabis and other drugs are often marked with fox symbols. At first, the police believed that the Kurdish fox was only involved in drug smuggling.
It wasn't until 2021 that the police realized that much of what was happening in Sweden could be linked to the Kurdish fox and how he went about taking over existing markets and controlling them.
One of the most significant alliances was apart from the Bridge network with the Zero network.
Initially, the Zero network began distributing and selling drugs for the Kurdish fox. But later, the Zero gang became even more important in supplying young boys from the area to carry out violent attacks against Foxtrot's enemies.
A member of Zero called herself Louise Gucci. Born in 2004, Louise Gucci was a young man early on involved in crimes such as violent robberies and small-scale drug dealing, while slowly falling deeper.
Louise Gucci became one of Foxtrot's most important men when it came to coordinating attacks against enemies of the Kurdish fox in Sweden.
On January 20, 2023, Louise Gucci orchestrated the attack targeting gang member and rapper Thrife's ex-girlfriend. Thrife is closely connected to the Greken and Dale network, a gang that Foxtrot is at war with at this point.
The attack was recorded by the two youths who carried it out and posted on social media for all to see.
It was Louise Gucci who recruited the two 14-year-olds to carry out the attack, supplying them with firearms and instructing them in detail what to do via text message.
Just one day later, on January 21, 2023, an eyewitness filmed something that happened in broad daylight in Enskededalen, the base and home ground of the Valley Network.
A young man runs for his life between houses in the neighborhood while being chased by two young boys, one of whom carries a firearm and shoots at the young man. The young man shot at was a random 20 year old.
The two boys who chased and shot at the victim were two 15-year-olds from the Jordbro area, who belong to the Zero network.
They had received instructions from Louise Gucci to kill any youth who looked like a gang member. Examples of people either wearing a Gucci cap or an expensive designer jacket were given as description.
Basically, shoot anyone you think might be a member of the Valley Network. Just one day after this incident, Louis Gucci recruited a 20-year-old, an 18-year-old and a 14-year-old for yet another mission.
Again, they were supposed to shoot someone in the Valley network on Louise Gucci's orders. The 20-year-old was driving the car and the other two would be the shooters.
However, the police intervened just in time because they had this gang member's address in Hammarbyhöjden under surveillance. The police tried to stop the car, but the suspects tried to flee.
After a short car chase, the suspect's vehicle crashed in the Gulmarsplan roundabout. All three were eventually caught and firearms were found in the car, and the police suspected that they had just stopped another assassination attempt from happening.
Shortly after this event, Louise Gucci was arrested.
January 26, 2023. Explosion at a property in southern Stockholm where a company has its premises. A person on the death list is a plaintiff in this case.
January 27, 2023, an explosion at the gate of an apartment building in Akalla in northern Stockholm. An address linked to the rapper 5iftyy from Upplands Bro and gang member in the Bro network allied with the Kurdish fox and Foxtrot.
In several other arrests, the police seized several mobile phones. By examining these cell phones, they were able to gain insight into a web of thousands of signal messages that revealed how these attacks were orchestrated.
This information obtained led to Louise Gucci being accused of helping to coordinate another attack, a murder that took place at a sushi restaurant on January 28, 2023 in Skogås on the south side of Stockholm.
The police were alerted to a shooting that had taken place in a small but crowded restaurant.
The victim was a 15-year-old boy who was shot in the face by another 15-year-old boy who did not know the victim at all.
Although Louis Gucci was already in jail days before this incident took place, he was a prime suspect as messages showed that in the days leading up to the encounter he was asking where the targets might be and if anyone had extra information on him. However, he was acquitted in the trial.
The motive for the murder of the 15-year-old boy was revenge. He is said to have been involved in a shooting against one of the family members of the Kurdish fox. Almost immediately after that incident, retaliation was planned.
Louise Gucci was ultimately sentenced to 18 years in prison for her part in these aforementioned attacks.
The shooter, now 16, but at the time of the crime he was only 15 years old, was convicted of the murder but because of his age was given the maximum sentence of four years. He was paid SEK 100,000 for the murder.
These young boys commit these cruel acts for relatively small amounts of money.
For the convicted shooter and murderer, Zikke, the money was more than enough to accept the job and afterwards flex with the money. He had taken several pictures of himself and displayed wads of cash.
CCTV footage from NK's department store in central Stockholm shows him using cash to buy himself a brand new moose knuckle jacket and new shoes. Rapper Adouli was present at Zikke's trial and was also kicked out.
January 29, 2023. An explosion in the stairwell of an apartment building in Bro in northern Stockholm. The rapper Moewgli and his brothers from the Bridge Network are written on the address.
Prosecutors have now brought charges against nine people who are suspected of having contributed in various ways to public destruction through bombs and explosions in January 2023. The accused were all men and were between 17 and 30 years old at the time of the acts.
All events are connected to the conflict between Dalen and the Foxtrot network. The so-called bomb maker for the Dalen side of the conflict was arrested when explosives were found during a search of his apartment in Kungssängen in northern Stockholm at the end of January 2023.
The rappers Haval and Thrife are linked by the police and are considered high-ranking members of the Dalen network.
The rapper Pékénio, real name Amin from the gang 23ST, is also suspected of involvement in the bombings. The 23st gang is closely allied with the Dalennätverket and has at one point been considered to be the same gang by the police.
The rappers 5iftyy and Moewgli from Upplands Bro belong to the Bro network and are allied with the Kurdish fox and the foxtrot network, something you can clearly see in their music videos.
The totally ruthless and deadly conflict erupts in December 2022 between Foxtrot and the Dalennaverket.
March 2, 2023. Several shots were fired at an apartment in Farsta in southern Stockholm. Second attack against the same address.
March 16, 2023. Someone pours flammable liquid and sets fire to the stairwell in Skarpnäck. Second attack against the same address.
During the same day, a huge explosion occurs and someone blows up the entrance to a house in western Stockholm.
The father of rapper 5iftyy, who was also targeted on January 27, lives at the address. As previously mentioned, the rapper from the gang 23st allied with the Dalennaverket has been in custody since that day and has been suspected of this crime.
For two consecutive days, a designated key member of the May network, Furkan becomes the intended victim of an assassination plot.
The May network is, at least at this point, a close ally of the Foxtrot gang.
Furkan's name is on the death list. On March 19, 2023, outside the apartment building on Östbergabackarna, a car with masked people inside is stopped, three young men from Linköping, a murder squad, are arrested and later sentenced to prison.
Furkan was lured to come and look at an apartment where the murder squad was waiting for him to arrive.
A fake estate agent was used to lure an unsuspecting Furkan there. The next day, March 20, 2023, Furkan who is still unaware of the events of the previous day is contacted again by the fake real estate agent.
He says he has another apartment for Furkan to look at, in Bromma. On the way there, Furkan is stopped by the police and arrested a few hundred meters away from the fake apartment showing.
The police are sending additional patrols to the address Furkan was going to. At the scene, two black-clad and masked men on electric scooters are waiting.
Both flee when they see the police arrive. One of them throws a gun but is caught after a short chase on foot.
The arrested man is called JJ, 22 years old and a member of the 22ST gang. The police take his phone when he is caught in the act, on JJ's phone the police later find the so-called death list.
The other perpetrator manages to escape from the scene and is not caught.
During the following investigation, Scar, age 23, a known member of the Valley Network, is seen on surveillance footage in the taxi he left the area in. The taxi picked up Scar near the spot where the masked man escaped the police and shortly afterwards in time.
Scar has since left the country, according to the police. JJ is sentenced to seven years in prison for preparation for murder. In total, at least 16 serious crimes have been committed and documented between January and March 2023 against twelve of the 41 people on the death list according to the police.
Two of the men who were charged as perpetrators of several of the bombings directed at the Foxtrot network are from Malmö in southern Sweden.
One of them is called Samer. Two of Samer's brothers were shot dead in Malmö in separate shootings.
Samer's third brother, Meysem, was tricked by his best friend on the day of one of the brothers' funeral to Dansörgatan in Malmö,
where he was left alone in a car by his friend and then shot five times. Despite serious gunshot wounds, the brother survived the assassination attempt thanks to his bulletproof vest. His best friend was convicted of aiding and abetting attempted murder and aiding and abetting another murder of the "Sheep".
Samer can be seen having conversations with a female acquaintance about who has paid them to carry out these bombings against Foxtrot. Samer singles out the famous rapper Haval, who was one of the targets of the violence in late 2022, as responsible for ensuring that he would be paid for his mission.
In a chat conversation he also mentions the rapper Thrife. The conversation turns to talking about why Haval and Thrife, who are famous rappers, do such things.
Samer says the two rappers weren't the ones who started it. Foxtrot blasted Haval's gate and fired at Thrife's front door, recording it. The police have branded both the rapper Thrife and Haval as gang members, and that they are both in the inner core of the Dalenna network.
When the conflict between the gangs has been in full swing for a few months, in April a 25-year-old man who was connected to the criminal network Foxtrot is attacked.
On April 17, 2023 at 6:59 p.m., the police received a call regarding a shooting in the middle of Umeå. A witness states that he heard several shots and at the same time the witness saw a person collapse to the ground.
Patrick is then found shot multiple times. In connection with the incident, several eyewitnesses observe and film a person leaving the crime scene on an electric scooter in an easterly direction.
The victim was shot three times. A few hours after the incident, Oliver and Liam and three women were arrested for suspected involvement in the shooting.
Shooter Liam and Oliver pose for a picture 33 minutes after Liam shot the victim three times, leaving him to die.
They are connected to the local Dalennaverket phalanx in Umeå and are considered to be behind it. The trial runs until December 2023. The victim survived the attempted murder, but in September 2023 he was arrested by the police task force.
The victim, Patrick, is sentenced to two years in prison by the district court for serious drug offences. The police have singled out a 23-year-old man as the mastermind behind the attempted murder in Umeå, he is suspected of inciting attempted murder, serious drug and weapons offences.
It is about an organized operation where they want to control the drug market in northern Sweden. Oliver visits John alias Don Svenson, the alleged mastermind behind it all, on at least one occasion in Spain before the assassination attempt.
In a picture in the preliminary investigation, it can be seen that John has published a picture of himself insulting the Kurdish fox and Foxtrot. There are several photos from Oliver's stay in Spain on his phone.
There are, among other things, pictures of a meeting with John, Robble and the rapper Wafi from Sundsvall from the same occasion. The rapper Wafi is connected to the local and allied gangs of the Dalennävternet in Sundsvall.
Sundsvall's area has not been calm since the big operation in January 2023.
An incident on July 9 turns out to be a continuation of the gang war when two teenage boys were found seriously injured. The boys were found on Sunday evening bleeding and badly injured after they sought help in a villa in Sidsjö in Sundsvall.
A 20-year-old from Sundsvall is both suspect and victim in the same case. Just as with the big police operation last winter, he is the one who, according to the suspicions, was the target of a planned shooting. Twelve people are on trial after the gang settlement in Sidsjö in Sundsvall this summer.
Three are suspected of preparation for murder, eight of kidnapping and six of attempted murder - among other things.
According to the police's investigation, Foxtrotsidan once again planned for one of Dalen's men in Sundsvall to be killed. It is about a 20-year-old who for several years belonged to the top tier of the Dalen network's Sundsvallsfalang.
He is also still among the suspects for the still unsolved shooting death in Korsta in Sundsvall in December 2020 when a 33-year-old man was shot dead with several shots, also the rapper Wafi and KP were suspected of this murder.
Three young shooters – aged 14, 15 and 16 – had been recruited by the Foxtrot side to kill the 20-year-old. A 24-year-old Karlshamn resident with Sundsvall's past had arranged housing for them.
But talk of the plans began to circulate in the criminal circles, and eventually the information reached the target himself - the 20-year-old.
On the evening of July 9, a group of Dalen trusts led by the 20-year-old searched for the three hired shooters, overpowered them and took them away. They were badly beaten for a couple of hours, and two of the teenagers were left to die in the residential area of ​​Sidsjö in the middle of the night.
Bleeding heavily, they sought help in a house, and the injuries were so serious that they were sedated at the hospital.
A total of 12 people with connections to the two networks are charged in the case, which has two parts. It is about, among other things, preparation for murder on the one hand, and attempted murder and more on the other.
The minor of the three hired shooters - who is thus under 15 - is a criminal suspect but is not charged because of his young age. He becomes a case for the social authorities.
The 21-year-old rapper Wafi was one of the targets to be murdered last winter, but he is now charged with, among other things, the attempted murder of the two boys in Sidsjö.
KP was the central figure in the prosecution in 2023 since he left his former friends to become loyal to the Foxtrot gang. In October 2023, KP, whose real name is Soran Merzai, was found guilty on several charges and sentenced to eleven years in prison for preparation for murder.
After the incident in Sundsvall during the summer of 2023, the conflict between Dalen and Foxtrot seems to be slowing down, it feels almost quiet after six months of daily events.
What happens behind the scenes?
In addition to the many enemies the Kurdish Fox has created in other gangs and networks, internal conflicts within Rawa Majid's own Foxtrot network began in the summer of 2023.
Disputes and disagreements within the Foxtrot gang started for various reasons. The members began to turn on each other.
Ismail Abdo, 33 years old alias Strawberry, was once close to the Kurdish fox. The 33-year-old comes from a very wealthy family. He has big money behind him.
The Kurdish Fox and the Strawberry have been working closely together for the past few years and they know each other's weaknesses.
They know where the other's relatives live and where weak points are.
After several violent actions against each other abroad, kidnappings, assaults and shootings, there is a shooting in Istanbul on September 6.
On surveillance footage, you can see that two men arrive on a moped and one of them jumps off and fires several shots at five people.
These five people in turn shoot back. No one was seriously injured, but the stakes were raised.
The following events for the next 30 days seem to come straight out of a movie.
In Sweden, the day after the shooting, as immediate revenge, Ismail Abdo's mother, a woman in her late 50s, was shot dead in her home in Gränby, an area of ​​Uppsala.
For obvious reasons, the intensity and brutality of this conflict soars after this.
Bombings and shootings in Sweden and abroad occur daily after this, a few days after the murder of Strawberry's mother, a shooting directed at Rawa Majid's mother-in-law takes place.
An unknown assailant fires several shots from outside into the home of the Kurdish fox's mother-in-law.
Then, two days after the shooting, a man with no connection to the conflict was shot dead in the stairwell of his apartment early in the morning in Uppsala. The young man on his way to work was in the wrong place at the wrong time.
The intended target was a family member of the Kurdish fox who lived in the same apartment building.
On September 11, 2023, gang violence in Sweden claimed one of its youngest victims to date. The remains of a 13-year-old boy were found in a wooded area in Haninge on the south side of Stockholm.
The boy had been reported missing a couple of days earlier and the youngster was said to have gang connections, one of which was to the Foxtrot network before the internal split.
In the summer months before this incident, the remains of Mohamed Suleiman and Layth Al-Azzawi were found in the northern and southern Stockholm region. Both boys were 14 years old and had been murdered.
The police and the media speculated that both boys, who were friends with each other, were reselling weapons they had received from the Foxtrot network.
When they were unable to retrieve the weapons, the leaders of the Foxtrot were out to make an example of them and eliminated them both.
No other country in Europe has seen anything like it in modern times. Although Sweden has struggled with gang violence for years, the outbreak of shootings and bombings in September has been incredibly brutal,
three people are murdered in just 12 hours due to gang violence and the same conflict. Sweden's outdated and naive laws are not designed for brutal gang wars and child soldiers.
The Kurdish fox is still at large, isn't it? In any case, he is out of the hands of the Swedish authorities.
While Louise Gucci is in prison for following orders from the Kurdish fox, the internal conflict within the Foxtrot network has taken place six months later.
For example, foxtrot was once close to the so-called Zero network. But as the internal conflict continued, the Zero network decided to follow Ismail Abdo's Strawberry side.
It wasn't long before Benzema or Mustafa who was then still a member of Foxtrot also became a target. On September 25, shortly after nine o'clock in the evening, there was an explosion in the stairwell of an apartment building in Hässelby, and this explosion was very powerful.
It was made and placed with the intent to cause serious damage to the targeted apartment and possibly the people inside. Three people had been injured and taken to hospital.
It turned out that this attack was directed at Mustafa or Benzema's family members.
9 hours later on September 26 at six in the morning, a bomb exploded so powerful that the entire front of the apartment building flew off.
According to the bomb squad that arrived at the scene, the building was so damaged that some parts could collapse completely. Despite the magnitude of the explosion, only two women suffered minor injuries. The goal was again related to Benzema / Mustafa.
This time it was a family member of his wife.
With the increasing number of brazen attacks, it was only a matter of time before more people who had no connection to the feud became victims.
During this time, the Zero network has distanced itself from the Kurdish Fox and Foxtrot. They are now on Ismail Abdo aka Strawberry's side.
something that makes this extra clear is that the rappers 5iftyy and numerouno release a song and music video called "gulag", 5iftyy belongs to Foxtrot and Nummeruno is from Jordbro and is connected to the Zero network.
The video is released towards the end of August, then in September the rappers stop following each other on Instagram and dissing each other online.
September 27. On Wednesday evening, the police received several calls about a shooting in southern Stockholm.
An 18-year-old man had been shot multiple times, execution-style, on a lawn at the Mälarhöjdens IP in front of a large number of witnesses, including teenagers and young children.
The 18-year-old was treated at the scene, but his life could not be saved. The victim is a rapper, Adouli. He just turned 18 the month before.
According to reports, the rapper was linked to the Foxtrot conflict and he was apparently on the side of the Kurdish fox.
The shots were intended for the rapper. Among other things, the rapper wrote on his Instagram "Free Zikke", a reference to the 15-year-old who was convicted of murdering a 15-year-old inside a sushi restaurant in Skogås in January 2023. The
murder of the rapper was filmed by one of the perpetrators.
In the video, shots are fired from several men sitting inside a car. A little to their right, a young man lies still in the grass. The video was published and spread on an Instagram account.
At 23:54 just before midnight that evening, the police were called to another shooting in Jordbro, south of Stockholm.
In Jordbro Centrum, someone opened fire with at least one automatic weapon from a car and the police find two people with gunshot wounds at the scene, completely innocent victims and not connected to crime or the Foxtrot conflict at all.
A 23-year-old man was so seriously injured that he died a few hours later. After the fatal shootings on Thursday morning, the police received a call about a huge explosion in a residential area outside Uppsala.
Two houses were completely destroyed in the explosion, which was so powerful that three adjacent houses were also damaged.
A 24-year-old woman, a student who lives in a neighboring house, was seriously injured by the explosion and she dies of her injuries.
12 hours, three people murdered in the conflict. The bombed address in Uppsala has previously attracted attention when the same house was fired upon with an automatic weapon from a car in January 2023 in the middle of the then wave of violence between the Dalennävterket and Kurdiska Räven's then-intact Foxtrot gang.
In October, Friday the 13th, an hour past midnight, a 16-year-old boy breaks into Louise Gucci's older brother's house in southern Stockholm.
His older brother is a 40-year-old man, completely unrelated to any crime or his younger brother's gang activities. He is even a famous musician and part of a music group known for their positive messages and spreading joy.
After somehow getting into the house at night while several adults and at least three children were home, the boy opened fire with an automatic weapon,
after the smoke cleared, two women were dead. Big brother's mother-in-law who was in her sixties and a twenty-year-old woman are the victims.
There was another adult and three children in the house as well, who fortunately were not physically harmed.
Less than an hour after the incident, they managed to arrest the suspect who was sitting in the back seat of a taxi. It is not uncommon in Sweden for suspects to flee the scene in a taxi, often booked by a third person or someone anonymous.
The police stopped the taxi and inside was a 16-year-old boy. He tried to escape on foot, but after a struggle he was captured. The police searched the boy's pockets and they found ammunition and magazines in the trunk of the taxi. In a bag, the police found an automatic weapon.
They suspected that this was the murder weapon that had just been used. The arrested suspect, a 16-year-old boy from Linköping, was then also suspected of another murder just 24 hours earlier with a very similar approach.
The 16-year-old boy suspected of gunning down a father inside his home in a shooting in the middle of the night on October 12, the man died from his injuries. The man's wife and child also suffered gunshot wounds during the incident.
The victim could not be linked to any criminal activity. He just seems to share the same last name as a gang member.
On Sunday evening, October 15, a well-known Swedish rapper, 5iftyy known for his gang connections to the Bridge Network and Kurdiska Räven, announced that he would have an Instagram Live.
This would take place at 20:00 in the evening Swedish time and a special secret guest would appear. Many thought it would be the Kurdish fox.
In the same vein and week of all the murders, shootings and bombings, there is a rumor, especially online and in the media, that the Kurdish fox has been arrested abroad in Iran.
and that his so-called right-hand man in Foxtrot, a man who calls himself Benzema is now dead.
There was reportedly a huge price on Benzema's head. According to these rumors, Strawberry orchestrated Benzema's arrest and subsequent killing in Iraq.
A short video circulated online showing a bloody man sitting in the driver's seat of a car, this person appeared to have been shot dead.
When Benzema's friends started posting Instagram and Snapchat stories containing rest in peace and pictures of Benzema, the rumors seemed to be true.
October 15, 2023. Rapper 5iftyy goes went live on Instagram. After half an hour of playing some new music to be released, the rapper and his friends revealed that the guest had joined the live.
The guest was none other than Mustafa aka Benzema, alive. He was sitting on a chair posing with a gold colored AK47a and there were three masked men with automatic weapons posing as bodyguards. He claimed that 300 men guarded his house.
Benzema made several interesting statements during his life. Benzema then claimed that the strawberry is a police informant, that he has worked together with the police in several countries.
He also claimed that the strawberry paid $1 million to have Benzema killed in Iraq. Benzema got wind of this and, with the help of a hired camera crew and actors, faked his own assassination in Iraq and then collected the prize money for his own life, which he claimed was $1 million.
He proclaimed that he would donate half a million dollars to charity and that the other half of Strawberry's money would be used by Foxtrot in the war against Strawberry himself.
Benzema also said that the strawberry alias Ismail Abdo only kills completely innocent people and has not harmed a single person who is actually involved or connected to this conflict with the Kurdish Fox and Foxtrot.
He claimed that the strawberry was behind the bombing that killed a woman, a 24-year-old student who lived next door to the house that was blown up in September.
He also claimed that the Strawberry and the Zero network were behind the execution of 13-year-old Milo, the boy who was found shot in the head and dumped in a wooded area on the south side of Stockholm in mid-September.
Several members of the Bro and Foxtrot network were arrested at the end of October in Tunisia. Five Swedish citizens were arrested because they had several pistols and narcotics in their possession. The police also seized nine mobile phones.
The gang members are currently under investigation by a special judicial authority dedicated to the fight against terrorism. They are being investigated as suspects of terrorism. The criminal classification may be due to the fact that for several years the Tunisian police have specifically targeted a phenomenon known as Islamic gangsterism.
This has arisen in suburbs and poor villages where drug trafficking and radical Islamism have intertwined and cartels have collaborated with jihadist groups. Several acts of violence in the Foxtrot conflict have been carried out by the Bridge Network on behalf of Rawa Majid.
October 23, 2023. On Monday morning at 05:42, the police received several calls about an incident in Enskededalen, an explosion at an apartment building.
Now deceased superstar Einár's former close friend and rapper Hamko and his brothers are listed at the affected address.
Hamko and his brothers have previously been involved in the Dalen network before the internal split within the gang took place. Hamko and his brothers' names and the address they are written to were on the death list that has been circulating.
Now 21-year-old Hamko has just served a prison sentence. Hamko, his older brother and a friend were convicted of an attempted murder of a 14-year-old boy in 2020. The
14-year-old was walking with two friends when a car suddenly stopped and shots were fired.
The 14-year-old was shot in the abdomen and the boy was close to death, but managed to survive. Since Hamko's recent release from his prison sentence, he has said he will release new music
and has posed for pictures with what police call a gang leader of the Farsta-Fagersjö network, a 24-year-old man known as Chris.
As old alliances are abandoned and new alliances seemingly formed overnight, only time will tell how things will end.
October 31, 2023. We are in Bosnia and the city of Sarajevo.
On Halloween and Tuesday afternoon, there is a shooting after 4 p.m. Masked people on a moped opened fire in a residential area in Sarajevo and then left the scene.
A Swedish citizen, 30-year-old Harris Österdahl, died at the scene.
Another Swedish man was shot in the abdomen in the shooting and taken to hospital with minor injuries. According to police, both victims of the Sarajevo shooting, Harris and Elvir, belonged to the Kurdish Fox side of Foxtrot.
Harris and Elvir were both shot during the shooting in Istanbul on September 6th. Both were arrested after the shooting, but were later released and then quickly left the country and traveled to Bosnia.
Harris, the victim, was a figure from Stockholm's criminal underworld and the murder is linked to the internal conflict within Foxtrot.
That same evening at 19.30 a 26-year-old Swedish man was arrested. Later in the night, two more 19-year-old men, Swedish citizens, were arrested on suspicion of involvement in the murder.
According to records in 2020, after serving two years in prison, Harris joined the Foxtrot network. Several of the acts of violence in the conflict have affected family members or outsiders who are not related to the conflict.
This was the case earlier in 2023 when Harris' family was the target of an attack.
The detained 26-year-old Swedish man, Oliver, is also suspected of an earlier shooting in Turkey. Oliver is believed to have worked as a sort of hitman for the Foxtrot splinter faction led by Strawberry Ismail Abdo.
Oliver is suspected of having carried out at least three acts against Foxtrot gang members since the split. After the shooting in Istanbul, Oliver is suspected of having followed five other Foxtrot members, including 5ifty and Elias Bäck, to Tunisia.
However, Tunisian police arrested the five Foxtrot men before anything happened and after that Oliver traveled to Bosnia and sought out two of the Swedish men from the shooting in Istanbul.
26-year-old Oliver has appeared in several investigations on Swedish soil as well. He has been convicted several times in drug cases and has also been suspected of both murder and attempted murder recently. Among other things, he has been linked to the wave of violence that hit the Swedish city of Kalmar in 2022.
In early 2023, he was arrested on suspicion of a murder in central Kalmar in February 2022, but was released in the summer of 2023 when the suspicions against him could not be substantiated.
The murder of the 22-year-old in February 2022 is considered to be the starting point for the wave of murders and shootings that followed in Kalmar during 2022. Earlier this year, Oliver was also acquitted in a trial that included aiding and abetting criminals in an attempted murder case.
Oliver is believed to have previously been loyal to the Kurdish Fox, but is now believed to have switched sides in the internal Foxtrot conflict and is acting on behalf of Ismail Abdo.
Two young men aged 19 are the suspected shooters.
One of them is from Jordbro, south of Stockholm and is connected to the Zero network.
The other is from Malmö in southern Sweden and he is also suspected of being the shooter when 19-year-old Giovanni was shot and killed in Vasastan in central Stockholm on September 13.
Benzema or Mustafa has now spoken out again saying that he and the Kurdish Fox or Rawa Majid met in prison twelve years ago and have been business partners for a long time.
Benzema claims he was never Rawa's right-hand man, but more of an equal partner.
He also says that he has retired from the Foxtrot network and has started his own organization called La Liga.
After this war between Rawa Majid and Ismail Abdo, people got tired of all the shootings and bombings, especially that completely innocent people and family members were affected.
November 28, 2023. The shooting occurred just before 5 p.m. at the Mossehallen sports hall in the town of Moss in Norway, which is located about five miles from the Swedish border.
At least 7-8 shots must have been fired at the scene and the person shot was a Swedish citizen. The police were looking for at least two perpetrators who allegedly left the scene in a dark car.
The victim, a 33-year-old man, was hit by several shots and his condition is described as serious but that he would survive.
The man is registered in the Stockholm area and in 2022 he received a sentence for minor drug smuggling. Before that, he has been convicted of, among other things, drug offences, assault and theft, and has also been convicted of a number of crimes in Norway.
According to information, he is connected to the Foxtrot network.
Since this is happening in real time, who knows what the fate of the Kurdish fox and the Foxtrot network will be?
what do you think??
Take a quick second and subscribe to our YouTube channel to keep up with the latest news.
It takes a second to subscribe and it helps tremendously to grow the channel.
Watch uncensored gang-related videos on our Instagram: Follow us on Instagram at @Crimeswedeninvestigators