"Witnesses heard Pang Pang and someone fell together"
"Of course it was my Broski, he shoots like an idiot"
"You'll find us at Flashback for any crimes we made"
He reportedly had not been at the address for a long time and was assumed to be abroad.
He has several ongoing conflicts and a hypothesis was that he was involved in the murder of Einár.
And that, too, considering the murder that was passed in Rinkeby a day before (Dumlee) is exposed to retaliation.
Scar, 23, is a person with great violence.
From the beginning he was a bit more of a running boy in the Dalen Network, but pretty soon he was responsible for the protection at larger meetings and be the one who was armed at these.
He seemed to be the one in the network responsible for managing and moving the network of the network.
Soon it was clear that he began to act as a provider in the event of serious violent crimes.
Something he seems to think is satisfactory and also sees himself as a "sicario" (assassin).
Scar has also acted as a bodyguard for the "Greek" ie Mikael Tenezos.
Both in Sweden but also when they went abroad.
Scar must have performed violence on behalf of its own network, but also performed assignments against payment and gene services for other networks allies with the Dalen Network, eg.
23st.
As mentioned, Imdar is called "Scar" which, among other things, police officers have heard friends call him.
He has also marked his slippers with it when he was arrested for various crimes.
The overall assessment of the police authority is that SCAR is part of a criminal network, Dalen, for organized crime.
Scar is suspected of being a target for attacks during the conflict with Kurdish fox and foxtrot.
A hand grenade is thrown into the gate to the address in Enskededalen he and his family are written on.
In addition to that, "SCAR" is also suspected of being an active player for violent acts against the opponent side.
After the attack on Scar, the conflict between the valley and the Kurdish fox is a fact.
When the conflict between the gang has been at full speed for a few months so in April 2023, the 25-year-old man who is linked to the criminal network Foxtrot in central Umeå is shot.
The competing valley network is considered to be behind and now prosecution for the murder trial \ h on the east in town in Umeå has arrived and the trial is ongoing in November.
The prosecutors raise a case of a case where eight people are charged with a person in a \ hom, among other things.
Murder attempts, serious drug crimes and extremely serious weapons offenses.
Police have pointed out a 23-year-old man as the brain behind the shooting.
He is suspected of instigating attempts at murder, serious drug crime and serious weapons crime.
The event is considered to be part of the incredibly intense and bloody conflict between the Foxtrot and the Dalen Network.
This \ here a settlement in criminal circles.
These are organized activities where you want to control the drug market in Umeå and Skellefteå.
According to the indictment, the business has been ruled by the 23-year-old who has stayed in Spain and the Netherlands before being arrested in The Hague in the Netherlands.
He is suspected of having a person to Umeå to ensure that the shooting is carried out properly.
Of the eight \ Håtalade, seven are detained and one person is on the loose.
The 23-year-old who is said to be behind the shooting in Umeå is described by the police as a driving force in a constellation who conducted drug trafficking in the city.
When he was arrested at a tavern in late 2022, he threatened both police and guards by force.
- Health "Police Chief's \ Hame" that it is war now!
He screamed among other things.
The 23-year-old man \ here linked to the violent dalen network.
The man was indicted in \ HJANUSURE for abuse, attempted violence against an official, violent resistance, drug crime and illegal threats.
But the trial never took place.
According to documents from the Prison and Probation, the man had gone abroad and stayed away.
In a picture in the preliminary investigation, you can see that he has published a picture of himself where he insults Kurdish fox and Foxtrot.
April 17, 2023. At 18.59, alarm calls were submitted to the police regarding shooting in the East district on the town near Hamrinsgatan in Umeå.
A witness states that he heard three sounds that the witness interpreted as gun shots, the witness saw a person collapse.
At the site, Patrik is found shot with several shots and in conjunction with the event observes and film witnesses a person leave the site on an electrical kick bike in the eastern direction towards the Öbacka beach area.
The victim gets shot with three shots, a shot with input opening on the right side of the abdomen, a shot at the back on the top of the right shaft and a shot in the left hand.
The shooter has shot Patrik at the site between Suntan and a restaurant.
The victim has then moved around the scene several bleeding injuries, and then stop next to the garage length where the ambulance staff found him.
In the parking lot, a dog driver found a knife.
The knife was located on a motor heater socket and was of the model Morakniv with black and red shaft, the knife blade was really rusty.
The knife was found about 38 meters from the crime scene.
When the victim is taken care of after the shooting, it is noted that he has SEK 5,390 in cash.
At the crime scene, 2 empty sleeves 9 mm Luger were found.
Two bullets were operated from his body in the victory's sweater.
Information in the preliminary investigation claims that the victim must have met with the counterparty "Dsquared" and that it should have been about drug dealings.
During the same evening as the shooting, an electrical kick bike is noticed in a storage room on the Hope's alley that is similar to the electrical kick bike that has been seen in connection with the shooting.
Overall, interest is directed at a woman's apartment at Hope's alley and just before 01.00 a house search is done in a woman's apartment.
Liam, one of the men's mother and two other women is found in the apartment.
All are arrested.
A few hours after the incident, Oliver "Sheisty" and Liam were arrested for suspected involvement in the incident, sheisty is said to act as manager for rapper "Chapo" under Sheisty Management.
As well as as the shooter, Liam and rapper Chapo together were previously convicted of an attempted murder together.
Together and in agreement with three other men, the victim has assaulted and attacked him with a number of punches and kicks and at least six stabs against the body.
They were convicted of gross abuse.
Chapo mentions the knife cutting in Skellefteå and the shooting in Umeå in two different songs.
"Witnesses heard Pang Pang and that someone fell together"
"Of course it was my Broski, he shoots like an idiot"
"You'll find us at Flashback for any crimes we made"
All are considered to belong to the local grouping in Umeå, which is allied with the Dalen Network.
The victim in the shooting is linked to the Foxtrot network, a potential motive is that Oliver has been beaten by "some from the south" some day before the shooting.
The shooter Liam and Oliver pose for a picture 33 minutes after Liam has shot the victim with three shots and left him to die.
The police conduct a number of house searches after the arrest and on April 18 a larger amount of drugs and most weapons are found on Bryggargatan and on Tegsplan in Umeå.
In connection with the investigation work linked to this case, a large number of phones are taken into account and in the analysis work of these phones, the police have identified a signal alias called "Don Svensson" which has a significant role linked to the investigation.
In connection with investigative measures regarding the attempted murder, the drug and the weapons, it has subsequently cleared up a picture that the cases regarding the murder attempt, Bryggargatan and Tegsplan are closely linked to each other.
Information has also emerged during the investigation that several people in Oliver and Liam's circle have been involved in the acts in various ways.
Through the investigative measures, a picture has also been crystallized that John, the 23-year-old, has held a leading and governing position in handling from abroad.
The victim described the incident as a person shot him with a gun.
The first shot must have hit the stomach and the victim must then have fallen over.
Then two or three shots came into rapid succession and he must then have run (against the witnesses) for help.
The victim survived the attempted murder but in September 2023 he was arrested by the police's force.
He was linked to a drug heritage linked to a large seizure at a workplace in Umeå worth SEK 600,000 in March 2023.
Large sums of cash were also found in his apartment.
The victim, Patrik, is sentenced to two years in prison by Umeå District Court for serious drug crime.
In interrogation with the accused Sagittarius, who admits that he fired the shots, he described that from a jacket pocket he produced a gun from a few meters to perhaps two meters away, three shots fired at the victim.
He described that he saw that the victim fell "type back" after one or two shots, but that he himself did not know that either the first or the last shot hit.
He stated that he thought the gun was broken for the sleeve after the last shot was not thrown out of the gun.
He then could not shoot more shots.
He stated that he was aiming for the lower part of the victim and did not believe that the first shot had taken his stomach.
When he learned in retrospect that the victim suffered a gunshot wound in his hand, the shooter believes that the first shot took in his hand.
That the victim was then hit by shots in the upper body meant the shooter happened because the victim fell.
Oliver visits John Aka Don Svensson on at least one occasion, in Spain before the attempted murder, he is identified as the leader and the brain behind the murder attempt.
There are several pictures from Oliver's Spanish stay on the phone.
Among other things, there are pictures of a meeting with John, Robel and rapper "Wafi" from Sundsvall, from the same time.
The rapper Wafi is linked to the Dalen Network's local and allied gang in Sundsvall.
During the past year, the police in Umeå followed the development of violence in southern Sweden and at the same time worked actively to follow developments in Umeå linked to these conflicts and alliances.
During the past year, the police in Västerbotten have seen that local individuals in Umeå, who occur in violence and drug context, have been spent with individuals from Sundsvall and Stockholm, individuals who are linked to the Dalen network.
Through this, the police have made an overall assessment that these individuals are loyal to the dalen network.
The conflict between these networks should primarily be about controlling the drug market in Västerbotten.
In connection with the attempted murder on April 17, 2023, two witnesses filmed when the perpetrator left the crime scene.
The perpetrator then wore a black jacket.
A well -like jacket was later seized at his mother's workplace, in a dressing cabinet.
After the shooting, the shooter fled to an apartment nearby.
There was, among other things, his mother.
According to the indictment, she helped her son remove evidence, among other things by hiding his clothes in a cabinet in her workplace.
The prosecution shows that police technicians found the shooter's DNA and shot remains in the form of ignition particles on the clothes in the cabinet at the woman's workplace.
The police view is that she tried to remove evidence.
The police have mapped how the mother moved during the crime evening, including via her phone and access card to work.
The drug found in this case was as follows.
Amphetamine, 3-CMC, MDMA, cannabis resin, oxycodone, pregabalin, alprazolam etc
Them defendants are:
Liam, 20, the recognized shooter is charged with attempted murder, serious weapons crime, extremely serious weapons crime, serious drug crime and violation of the Flammable and Explosive Goods Act.
Oliver aka "shiesty", 21 years, is charged with attempted murder, extremely serious weapons crime, serious drug crime, violation of the Flammable and Explosive Goods Act.
Liam and Oliver have together tried to kill Patrik by Liam armed with a semi -automatic gun and repeatedly shot Patrik to the body.
Oliver has been involved in the specified deed by planning and organizing the shooting together with Liam during the period in April until the attempted murder.
They have been in contact with John, who ordered the deed, Oliver has conveyed the assignment to Liam.
Oliver and Liam have subsequently reported to John that they completed the assignment by contacting him after the shooting took place.
John Aka Don Svensson, 23, is charged with extremely serious weapons crime and the instigation of attempted murder.
John has managed to try to kill Patrik by preferably through extensive contacts with Liam and Oliver through encrypted telephone traffic
Provide instructions to them to shoot Patrik and by ensuring that a person monitored the execution of the shooting.
Do you think the men will be folded and what will this have for Umeå in the future?