Nineteen -year -old Swedish rapper Einar died after being shot south of Stockholm last night
.
The shooting took place at 23 o'clock in Hammarby Sjöstad (where he lived) and so far no one has
been arrested.
Einar would become a witness in the High Court next week after the noted
The goal where he was kidnapped and robbed by a Stockholm gang.
because he did not show up to
The trial in the district court planned the police to escort him there next week.
The 19-year-old has previously described his upbringing in "Dalen" in Stockholm as
affected by drugs and weapons.
he got his breakthrough as a 16-year-old and has
Won several awards for his music and in 2019 he was the most popular Swedish artist on Spotify.
Einar was born September 5, 2002 and grew up on the south side of
Stockholm in "Dalen" He always wanted to become a rapper and started rapping as a 6-year-old.
he made his first serious song on a beat when he was only 10
And he was early recognized as a talented rapper in this area.
Einar had problems in school and started acting and ended up in trouble.
He was taken from
her mother and was placed in state premises for troubled children on several occasions.
February 18, 2018 When Einar was only 15 years old he and a friend divorced a teenager
from his other friends, he beat the other boy and then tried to take him down to the ground
.
The stomach then continued
to steal his jacket.
Einar releases "Ducks Popo" with a music video on May 24, 2018.
It gets a lot of attention but also a lot of counter -reactions with people who are wondering the quote "why
pretend this little white boy be gangster. "Later that year, just three days after Einars
16th birthday, September 8, 2018, he cut and cut another teenager in his arm with a knife, he
was charged as a minor for abuse with a deadly weapon.
At the beginning of his career
got Einar support from SSTV (Southside TV) who supported him with money to make songs and music videos that also gave him
much needed backup and "street cred" in the gangstarap genre Einar made music in. He had a hood
to claim and the "valley" network as his muscle he was managed at that time by "Paki" and "Chapo"
December 16, 2018 Einar close friend and manager "Paki" is shot to death inside an apartment in
"Dalen" at least seven shots were fired and "Paki" was shot in the head and chest several times
Chapo is brought to trial for the murder of "Paki" but the charges are not stuck and he is found innocent
First in the "District Court" and then in the "High Court".
Einar continues to release several songs and
Videos on Youtube But it was in January 2019 that the rapper was blown up overnight
When he released the song "The Cat in the area" that solved can be translated to
The neighboring villain.
At that time, Einar got into a rap beef when he and another rapper named
"MPL" went back and forth online on social media with DISS song stands that acted insults and threats
Einar and MPL had collaborated on a song with Dilly D released in early 2018 but the two rappers had problems
with each other after that for unknown reason, at one
Opportunity Einar uploads a story on Instagram where his armed with a gun says he is looking for "MPL"
on his overnight star with the "cat in the neighborhood" Einar had this to say "I first released it on
Youtube and there the trend as number one started and it received 400,000 views in five days
Then I dropped it on Spotify and the next day it had 250,000 streams it was blown up
things got completely crazy I couldn't understand it and it was number one
In Sweden, the most played song in the whole country, the numbers just grew and grew "
After his first banger became all that the gold child touched gold
and took first place on the lists.
d his song with over one hundred million streams
was the common theme in Einar's music violence and gang crime.
Einar's texts often referred to
Arms violence and drugs and his music videos also show both weapons and well -known criminals.
Most of these music videos are recorded and took place in the "Enskededalen" which is an area of
the south side of Stockholm and in this neighborhood there is a group of active that the police have
Identified as a criminal network after the success of success with the success.
“The cat in the area”
Then it was time for Einar to introduce himself to real he then delivered his debut album
"First class (first class)" The record had elements from the rappers "K27" and "Adaam".
on the record were found, among other things
The acclaimed title track "First Class (First Class)" which today has over 40 million streams
the magazine "Expressen" and reported that Einar in just 10 weeks in the fall of 2019 had one
60's list placements that completely crushed all competition after the extremely successful year
2019 when Einar the light -skinned gangster rapper basically became Sweden's gold boy he
Praised in media on television and in interviews he becomes Sweden's most played artist extremely fast
at his rapid rise to fame in retrospect might be too fast for a 16-year-old boy at the end of
In 2019, Einar had released both his debut album "First Class (First Class)" and his second album called "Number 1 (number one)" which was released
on the rapper's birthday.
At the beginning of 2020, the rapper ends with winning the prize for this year's newcomer
At the Grammy Awards, he also won this year's hip hop.
on another
Price exhibition "P3 Gold Gala" he took home the category of this year's song for the super hit "The cat in the area"
But at the same time, Einar has huge and unseen commercial successes as rappers and artist, his
Personal relationships deteriorate and there is a dispute about money where the record companies'
Production companies and criminal elements that support Einar early in career
Feeling stiff on profits when Einar begins to generate million income.
The details
differs, but Einar's mother is said to have started another company "NS Production Scandinavia"
In order for Einar to release music that would legally allow him to break his contract
and keep all the money he comes in for himself, this did not fit well with
People on the street.
Einar lost his backup and was vulnerable to being attacked.
In April 2020, Einar believes that he is going to a studio session with rapper "Haval" but
Instead, kidnapped by a criminal organization called "Vårbynätverket (Vårby network / gang)".
he gets beaten degraded
and stolen by its prisoners on a Rolex watch worth more than SEK 300,000, two gold chains
worth over SEK 160,000 and a gun.
not just that his kidnapper also tries to push him after they
released him and said they want 3 million or they will release humiliating pictures they took on him during
the kidnapping itself.
When the blackmail does not seem to work, the gang contact another gang
and pays them for a bomb to be built.
they want them to take the bomb and blast it outside einars or
His parents' home, members of the gang are on the way with an explosive charge in a car to Einars
Home but they turn when they are met by the police on the spot.
So the kidnappers released
The pictures on the net but it did not have the effect they were looking for.
Einar's career was not destroyed and
He briefly commented on this on social media and basically said that "anyone can be kidnapped"
Instead of paying, Einar sought protection for "May network (May Network / Gang)" and "Västerås Network (Västerås Network / Gang)"
which are the arch rivals and number one for the "spring village network (Vårby Network / gang as kidnapped Einar)" allegedly pay them one
Cash sum and percentages on their music career.
"Free Mayk (Mike) Makyil Yokhanna" "Free Namo (" Namo Stress "Boss of Västerås Gang)" Free Ali "" Free Alan "Shoutout" Kardå (Namo Stress Little Brother).
With the Encrochat network cracked, Encrochat was a European-based communication network and
service provider used primarily by organized crime to plan criminal activities,
The gang's kidnapping of Einar was revealed and good evidence of the crime was given
Because Einar never reported this event to the authorities and never cooperated with
law enforcement agencies.
During the police's work on the case, it was revealed that another famous rapper
"Yasin" was involved in a previously failed kidnapping attempt by Einar, where Yasin's role
was to attract Einar to a specific place so that the kidnappers could take him.
“Yasin” was found
guilty and imprisoned for his involvement in the preparations for the kidnapping he has
already served their time and "yasin" is a free man "yasin" is coupled and considered to be a member
In the infamous Stockholm gang "Shottaz" which has close ties to the gang "Filterless guys" or "flg"
Another famous rapper and "friend" to Einar "Haval" later took over Yasin's role in it
Successful kidnapping and attracted Einar in the kidnapper's hands.
Haval could be seen on pictures
When he and Einar arrived at the kidnapper's apartment and later dressed in Einar's gold chains
received "Haval" a penalty of two and a half years in prison for his role in the kidnapping
he will probably be released in the summer of 2022. "Haval" is considered close to one of
the leaders of one side of the "valley network (valley network/gang)" with the nickname * Super Mario * He is also considered mostly having
Control of nearby neighborhoods "Bagarmossen" and "Skarpnäck" where "Haval" comes from at that time.
several other people involved in the kidnapping had previously been seen standing side by side with
Einar's music videos and pictures not long before this event Einar was at least robbed
once with gun threats in the fall of 2020. At the end of 2020 and early 2021, Einar will start to dismay
Yasin but most rapper Haval and other people who "lit on" him both on social media and with
Subliminal diss and on a live on Instagram he calls "Haval" a snake and a son to AB! TCH.
At the beginning of 2021, Einar goes through Haval's district "Skarpnäck"
in a car and plays Haval's verse of their collaboration track before the beef called
"Hell Ye" is sent a clear message to Haval
Which is reportedly responsible for Haval's Instagram account since Haval was locked then for Einar's kidnapping.
answered Einár with an Instagram story where they stand on exactly
The same place as Einar was hours before he posed with weapons.
Einar posts more stories
With automatic weapons in response ...
On February 18, 2021, Einar was arrested for a serious weapons offense when two guns
found by police in his home.
Einar releases a song along with rapper “23” in
early April 2021. "23" is backed up and supported by "May network (May network/gang, leader is Mayk)" and that gang is led by Mayk (Mike)) *Real name Maykil Yokhanna *
And they are at war with the spring village network (the gang that kidnapped Einar) that Einar hate for obvious reasons.
In the song "Trendsetter", both rappers take shot at the spring village network.
On April 18, Haval's little brother "Dara" is shot dead in Kista, Stockholm.
stands
Outside his apartment building and smokes with his girlfriend at night.
he has been shot several
times and two masked men leave the crime scene on electric scooters, allegedly killed "Dara"
Because Haval was imprisoned at that time for the kidnapping of Einar.
Einar laid according to the police
Theories money on "Darras" head as revenge.
After this, Einar spent most of his time 2021
Abroad in Dubai, Amsterdam and Spain to record their fifth album.
it has been said to
There was a great reward on "Einár", a large sum of money to be paid to the one who killed him.
In September 2021, Einar releases a song with rapper "Adaam" from Märsta, Stockholm called "Dance".
After the release of this song it was strongly speculated that
Einar in his verse takes on the honor of having killed Haval's little brother "Dara"
"Brother I'm going to pull up on your block and spill blood tonight after you are away imma make your brother ..."
When he returns to Sweden after the summer he is often seen with the older rapper
"Nobility".
With Einar's own words, "Adel" had served as a mentor and big brother for him in
The music industry.
"Adel" has a long criminal record and thread bands.
Near “Husby Hyenor”
and other criminal organizations in the area "Husby" and "Järva" (Rinkeby, Tensta, Akalla)
Until the autumn of 2021, there had been much gang violence in Stockholm with abuse, gunfire and
Murder is at a record level and former friends turn to each other at a rapid pace.
newly released from prison and now the prospective rapper "Dumlee"
He is the old friend of "Adel" and "Dumlee" is a member of the "Death Patrol" who is in a
brutally and deadly gang war often called "Shottaz vs. Death Patrol" dating back to 2015 as we
mentioned earlier is rapper Yasin who was convicted of involvement in the kidnapping of
Einar a member of the gang "Shottaz. The rapper" Ze "is also seen hanging out with Einar, Adel and
Dumlee, this can certainly be seen as a statement about whose side you stand on or support in these mortals
Conflicts and gang war.
People and fans commenting the pictures Einar posts on their Instagram can
See worry about the company he holds and that something will happen to him soon.
the night
Until October 8, 2021 Einar is in the company of Adel, ZE and other people at "Nosh and Chow"
in central Stockholm city.
After midnight, a fight breaks out between two groups and a 25-year-old
one is severely injured when he stabbed in the neck and shoulder ei nár and another
Known rapper and a friend of them are arrested by police leaving the area.
They were released
The day after but were still suspected in the investigation of attempted murder.
This whole
Event is enveloped in secret.
speculation has been that there was a quarrel with and
Or that "einár" owed a bunch of money and then escalated things.
On October 20, 2021, "Dumlee" was involved in
A shooting in Sätra, Stockholm near a music studio, no one was met or injured in this shooting.
The day after October 21, Einar spends the morning with rapper "VC Barre" also from Märsta, Stockholm.
He later goes home to his apartment in Hammarby Sjöstad and sleeps in the days.
Sometime during the evening, Dumlee and Adel Einar meet at his house.
The three men enter a locked bike garage that belongs to the apartment complex
But at a lower level and by the water.
When the three men go out again
they meet with gunfire when two masked armed men shoot at Einar.
Adel runs away along the water channel
and dumlee is hiding in the locked bicycle storage
.
Einar is hit by one of the many bullets flying and trying to run
Back to his apartment with a bullet in the chest.
he never gets into the apartment complex and armed man will catch him
and shoots at least one shot in the head up close.
They make sure Einar is dead
And that the two masked maple killers run away and leave the place ....
It all was over within 60 seconds and "einár" be pronounced dead at the scene
he had turned 19 just a month before speculation theories and rumors have run wild
on the internet about what the motif was and who is behind the murder of the rapesuper star
One thing is sure his death was mourned by a whole generation who considered him to be one of, if not the best
that ever did.
so if something can be said for sure if Einar is that all under
his short life had an opinion of him and he made a great impact on the culture
And in Sweden as a country.
His murder aroused great political discussions and potential reforms
.
have been made at this time and the case remains open and unsolved