The picture and associated text can be interpreted as the fact that there is "price" of the guys who are included in the picture and that it should be spread further with that message.
In the phone among the images, a screenshot is found from a chat from what appears to come from the Signal program.
The picture sent depicts several individuals from the Ronna side in the Södertälje conflict.
Among other things, in the picture there is rapper Nineb Yok, murdered Lourens, as well as Marcus who is arrested in Portugal for a murder and also in the picture is Yousef Saado.
24-year-old Yousef was sentenced to prison for seven years and ten months in prison for 17 cases of serious drug crime during the period June to September 202. Out of a total of 13 accused of this, 9 were released by them.
The fact that the guys in the picture with clarity belong to the Ronna side shows that L2 has part of the conflict in Södertälje.
Another screenshot from the program shows how L2 wants help with "getting" the guys from Ronna.
26-year-old L2 is said to be linked to Saltskog Falangen and is now being charged with stamping for murder.
The person L2 is talking to is in the Foxtrot network, it is no less than the leader, Kurdish fox, wanted Rawa Majid, the man is talking to.
In addition, according to the preliminary investigation protocol, the designated and prosecuted shooter "Guldish" poses with an AK47a in rapper Sticky's music video.
The Lourens Issa who was murdered when he was a designated leader figure for Ronna Falangen, he has a little brother who is reported by police in the conflict.
The little brother has also recorded various songs and freestyles as a rapper.
Here he rapes "Goldish on my neck and I talk no chain."
In other words, he suggests that the designated torpedo "Guldish" is looking for him.
“Brother, the grower How to get him?
He sends to the kids from Ronna, the one in the picture I sent.
Don't you think he could fix them for money?
They have sought help from everyone, none except for acids from Södertälje help them and them from Västerås, Namo Stress Liga.
And Maykil Yokhanna's league the so -called May network.
These are real Muslim haters.
They tell people we get Muslims to the city and try to fight against the Syrians.
Brother asks you to check with the grower, he could easily fix these h kids.
Let's send them here to Jannah and I are loving both of your and the growers' business will go around everywhere in Södertälje via us my brother. "
"Okay my brother solves it now."
Says Kurdish fox.
According to the police and the prosecution, L2 must therefore contact Kurdish fox and offered him shot money to clear away three leaders from Ronna Falangen.
The prosecution is based on audio files that the police have come across.
According to prosecutors and police, he is heard to talk to a person whose alias is linked to Rawa Majid, the so -called Kurdish fox, leader of the Foxtrot network.
According to the police, L2, SEK 300,000, offers per head.
The targets discussed were Ronna Falangen's highest leader, a 27-year-old man, Markus who is now being arrested in Portugal suspected of murder.
Through voice identification, the prosecutor believes that it is Kurdish fox and people linked to his network Foxtrot.
Now 13 men are charged with crime in connection with the fact that Mitt i when the conflict was most intense, a 41-year-old man, murdered by mistake when he was mistaken for another person by the shooter.
Nothing in the view has shown that the victim should have had to do with the gang conflict.
A little more than a year, that the 41-year-old was shot dead in Ronna, 13 men are now being charged with suspected involvement in the murder.
It was just before seven in the evening of October 2022, that the 41-year-old man walked at the Enhörnaleden in Ronna in Södertälje with a friend.
When they were at the intersection Enhörnaleden/Robert Anberg's road, the killer appeared on an electric bike, stopped and shot dead the 41-year-old.
Now, 13 \ Hmen, one of whom, are charged with murder, two as fellow or assistants, and others for gross protection of criminals and failure to reveal murder.
The motif is believed to revenge a death shoot that took place the day before when George Shaya was shot dead, the event was part of the ongoing gang conflict between different phalanges in Södertälje.
The prosecutor's theory is that the murder of the 41-year-old was a so-called mistake.
The shooting was the \ hfjärde shooting in Södertälje in a week.
The murder has been expected despite very high police presence in the area as a result of previous shootings in Södertälje and is founded in an infected conflict between two criminal groups in Södertälje.
After the murder of their friend the day, before probably performed by the Ronna side, the gang is revenge and bloodthirsty.
Despite the massive police presence in Södertälje at the moment, they go out and spin for enemies.
The so -called Saltskog Falangen has a specific target they are looking for this evening.
T who is linked to Ronna Falangen, T is appearance like the death victim and was near the murder scene but that the shooter was wrong.
Surveillance films show that the intended target T and two other people were at the Ron-A school on Robert Anberg's road 24 in Södertälje between 19:28 and 19:40 in the evening.
Police were alerted at 19.41 to the district \ Hronna \ Hi \ Hsödertälje after several people must have called in after hearing a gunfire.
The shooter leaves the crime scene on an electric bike in the direction of Lina in Södertälje.
On October 2, 20, 22, an unlocked garage you are searching on the ceramic road in Lina in Södertälje.
You will find an electric bike and a protective vest as well as a bag containing weapons, magazines and garments.
The electric bike's frame number is consistent with an electric bike that has been in an industrial premises in Södertälje on April 6, 2022.
The same room as the rapper G1OCATOR in April 6, 2022 was seized within a day when his friend had been murdered in Norsborg.
According to the preliminary investigation protocol, the rapper is related to people who have previously been with Saltskog Falangen.
The day of murder, October 1, several of the accused and other gangs linked before, during and after the murder went to and from the room on the ceramic road.
Some people leave the room by car while the shooting takes place.
L2 and Guldish are stopped in a car 21:39 on the murder night while Guldish mobile phone shows that he is on the way to Tumba, Botkyrka municipality in the car where those who left Lina at the time of the murder are in.
An attempt to give, among other things, Guldish an alibi at the murder according to the prosecutor.
The Glock 22 found in the room is found to be the murder weapon.
It has been used at least for two previous shootings in Södertälje.
First a shooting against Rösberga preschool center in Södertälje in December 2013. And also in September 2014 when five bullet holes were found in a building and 14 empty sleeves were found at Robert Anberg's road in Ronna, Södertälje when people on a moped shoot.
Both murdered G and "Guldish" were linked to a serious weapons crime on July 27, 2022 in Lina.
At the scene, where a police officer has been spoken of a conversation about gunfire, cartridge sleeves and bullets were found, that the cartridge sleeves are fired in the murder weapon found in the garage on the ceramic road and the cartridges rehearsed/handled in the said weapon and that DNA from Guldish was detected on a water bottle and a beverage can
And DNA from George has been detected on a cigarette fimp.
The autopsy protocols regarding the victim show that he suffered 19 gunshot injuries as a result of ball weapons and that he died as a result of extensive damage to the skull and the brain.
One of the shots that hit the face was judged to be at least one close shot, a execution, fired in the Glock gun found on October 2.
As well as most noted gunshot injuries in the arms, back and chest.
No visible damage was noted on the lower body.
According to several witnesses who also photographed, the shooter fled on an electric bike in the direction of Lina.
The previously mentioned garage on the ceramic road is located there and it takes about 2 minutes and 52 seconds to get from the murder scene to the garage on electric bike.
NFC makes an opinion that a total of 78 ignition particles are detected on the electric bike found in the garage, on the left and right handles of the electric bicycle and that 50 of them are of the same type detected in scraping samples from cartridge sleeves from the murder site.
Several of the now prosecuted young men are bound to various things police and prosecutors are linked to the murder with DNA hits.
Among other things, masking, transport and other accessories that are alleged to have been used for the murder.
Guldish or Tawhid Sozan, which he is called properly for attempted murder, grossly illegal threats, causing danger to other, serious weapons crime and the murder of the 41-year-old.
Because his actual age at the time of the murder is debated, we do not know which penalty scale becomes relevant if he is convicted of these crimes.
Franki, 26, is charged with serious abuse on another occasion and murder or assisted in murder or gross protection of criminals.
Maikel, 23, is charged with murder or assisting in murder or gross protection of criminal.
Franki and Maikel, both of them are charged with being fellow or assistants at the murder of the 41-year-old on October 1.
The two must take care of the Goldish mobile phone before the shooting and then before, during and after the crime brought the phone by car from Södertälje to, among other things.
Alby and Tumba since the day after returned the phone.
The measures have been intended to counteract the fact that it is discovered that Guldish committed the crime and/or that he is held responsible.
L2, 26 years, is charged with serious weapons offenses, nutritional laundering, gross protection of criminal, failure to reveal murder and for stamping for murder.
Since L2 is the one who is charged with contacting and talking to the Kurdish fox from the Foxtrot network about killing and ordering murder on at least three main characters within rival Ronna Falangen.
Several other men linked to Saltskogs Falangen are charged with various crimes, serious weapons offenses, gross protection of criminal and failure to reveal murder.