Welcome to the new video on the channel
Today we will deal with LED lighting strips
OMLOPP LED lists for kitchens
There have been no IKEA products on the channel for a long time, but now while in the store I found a promotion (sale) of this model
The standard price is around 22 Euro
In my opinion, it is quite a lot, although they are solid
Ikea has accustomed us to solid quality at fairly affordable prices
Unfortunately, LEDs from IKEA are quite expensive The
sale price of these LED strips is about 7 Euro
So I bought 2 pieces of such Omlopp LED strips
Parameters: 60cm / 300 lm / 5.4W
Two such The strips are enough for me to replace the lighting in the kitchen with new ones above the kitchen worktop
. Remember, however, that these strips require not the more common 12V, only 24V voltages.
Cents of such power supplies outside IKEA start from about 10 Euro.
LED, I had to spend on the power supply
The cheapest 24V power supply in IKEA is ANSLUTA (Cost about 17 euro)
I saved on the strips, and on the power supply not anymore ....
But I preferred not to waste time adjusting a power supply from another manufacturer (except IKEA)
Thanks to this I can be sure that everything should match
24V power supply
The power is limited to 19W
One strip is 5.4W, so we can power up to 3 such strips
The power supply is modular, let's
connect the ends of the strips
IKEA also has more expensive wireless power supplies, but they are definitely more expensive
. Then we increase the cost of such installation even more.
Therefore, my choice fell on the basic model of the power supply.
It is not a very modern design, rather classic, but it is sufficient
You can not use the switch
The use of a traditional switch is also not a problem in my opinion
. Such a switch is definitely more reliable than control by external servers
The splitter itself supports the current up to 3A
. Remember, however, to limit the power supply to 19W
There is also such information on the packaging.
Therefore, we can power up to 3 such LED strips.
What will probably interest you is ...
How does such an OMLOPP strip light?
I will demonstrate it in a moment. Let's
see what we get in the sales kit.
In addition to the strip itself, we also get a
Clip for screwing to the cabinets
.
Screws are included.
After screwing the guide,
we
can
mount the list with
clips
. It
looks
much more aesthetic.
Connect
the LEDs .
The
plug is detachable.
Connect the power supply . Connect
the
LED strips to the distributor
. LED
It turns out, however, that it is completely unnecessary.
Let me know in the comments what you think about the IKEA LED offer.
Write what your opinion is.
I also ask for LIKE and SUBSCRIBE