Student life in Halmstad. Student David tells.
David is my name and plugs the nursing program.
Right now I am on the western beach.
My favorite place on campus is in the R-house, in the health lab.
Although it is mostly for nursing students-
-And other programs such as PIM (Psychology Specialization Sports and Exercise).
It is very cozy in there, there is your own kitchen.
It is very large and many places to plug in.
This is where I am most right now.
It is very beautiful down here.
There are many places to run and exercise, many places to hang out.
I love being down here in Halmstad.
It is a fun city and easy to get to know new people everywhere.
There are so few living here, so it will be most students.
You can get to know people from sports centers to different-
-The training facilities to meet people on the beaches.
It is very beautiful down here.
Many my friends have plugged down here-
-And they have said that Halmstad is a good plug city.
There are so many fun things to do, such as various events.
It's also a little warmer down here, a little more open.
Easy to get a home, I thought.
It was just to come down here and start hanging out.