Chicken drumsticks recipe ! Chicken recipe easiest and tastiest delicious recipe !
4 chicken drumsticks (~600g)
You can change subtitle to your country language by clicking 3 dots at top right corner
Cut the chicken like this
how to cook chicken drumsticks? Watch this cooking videos until the end
Cooking oil
May I know which lovely country are you from?
Fry for 4~5 minutes on each side using low medium heat
4 tablespoons light soy sauce
3 tablespoons tomato ketchup sauce
2 tablespoons honey
1 teaspoon sugar
Â½ teaspoon pepper
3 cloves of garlic
Mince the garlic
Everyone can cook this easy chicken drumsticks recipe with only few ingredients needed.
Mix well
Flip and fry another 4~5 minutes using low medium heat
Flip and fry another 1~2minutes using low medium heat
Pour in the prepared sauce
I love to cook this easy chicken recipes for dinner as it is fast to prepare and best to eat together with rice
Close the lid and simmer for 5 minutes using low heat
Flip it
Close the lid and simmer for 2 minutes using low heat
â£ï¸ Consider subscribe for cooking delicious food for your love one!
My family said this chicken recipe is incredibly tasty
ðŸ‘ LIKE THE VIDEO! ðŸ‘ - this make me more enjoy to do more video and important for the development of our channel!
Incredibly delicious chicken recipe
WRITE  A COMMENT or at least write a smiley face ðŸ˜Š
I will try my best to reply every comment
Do you love this chicken recipe?
Bon Appetit
tasty recipes
I recommend you to watch few videos above and you will find it is amazing! ðŸ¥°