We want to see Jönköping, with all its fantastic attractions
bubbling with life and activity.
We also want to play to the city’s strengths as a hub for meetings and events
and make Jönköping an obvious stop for trade fairs as well as touring music and culture.
We want to become one of Sweden’s top places to visit, so why not join us?
The advantages for any destination are found in its background,
and we see the city’s location, nature and heritage as being particularly important.
Our location and nature speak for themselves,
but our heritage is to do with those who came before us and helped build up this place:
from Amalia and her Polkagris candy canes, to the Husqvarna factory and many others.
We have a strong sense of community and excellent cooperation between local organizations.
Being used to working together, helping each other out,
is an extraordinary strength that makes success possible
and gives us a head start on many levels.
Our target groups place ever higher demands on us as a destination management company
to work wholeheartedly for the community and the planet.
The hospitality industry plays an important part in the transition towards a more sustainable society
and Destination Jönköping wants to help lead the transition towards making us as sustainable a place as possible.
What attracts visitors to a particular place is what they can do and experience there.
More people want experiences where they feel involved and can develop themselves.
Our cultural and sporting events create experiences and memories you can share with others.
Our regional businesses and institutions possess extensive know-how and carry out outstanding research.
By exploiting all this and enabling meetings
where Swedish and international participants rub shoulders and get to know Jönköping,
we increase our attractiveness and pave the way for a future skills supply.
Travel is changing, and we are evolving from being a place with a strong dependence on business travel
to somewhere where private tourism is increasingly important.
We are now doing all we can to help companies take advantage of this trend
By finding new reasons to attract independent visitors.
In getting people engaged and collaborating,
By developing possibilities and identifying strengths,
we can position ourselves, nationally and internationally, as a meeting and events destination.
Just look at Dreamhack, O-ringen, our unique music festivals, international bike races and countless knowledge-sharing meetings.
Excellent hospitality is often decisive for how a place is experienced;
we need to make sure that visitors can easily find inspiration and information,
either digitally or in person.
That’s why we are making tremendous efforts to educate, inspire and develop the hospitality industry here.
We want a programme that appeals to many different people.
We want a close dialogue and cooperation with both local and national organisers,
that leads to a wide range of cultural events at Jönköping Theatre and Jonkoping’s concert and congress halls.
Everything we’ve talked about is essential for creating a sustainable tourism destination,
and we at Destination Jönköping are more than happy to take the lead on this.
But we can’t do it alone, we have to do it together with you all, making use of your engagement.
Together we can create an attractive location for both residents and visitors.
A place we can be proud of:Jönköping