Et Voilá
Multo Bene
Where would the key lie down now again
You can put it in the blue cup, on the cabinet.
Yes
But you
Really good job today.
You were a star at the coffee machine.
Not many people can make such good milk foam art, the first day.
Really good.
But so, I will dream about cappuccinos and lanttish all night.
Then maybe i will show up in your dream as your good looking supervisor
You never know.
No, you never know.
I really hope for many more passports before the exam weeks start.
I really need the money
So I thought if you could put a good word for me to Marianne?
Of course I can do it.
We are a good team, or how
I really also feel that it is a tiring job.
I will be stiff like a stick tomorrow.
Yes ... you are really stiff.
You, if you try to relax a little in your shoulders.
No, I'm a little Wierd actually.
I don't like massage so much.
But then you have not met the right one.
You
I know someone who would like a massage.
No.
How was it now again, did you want more passports
Hi, it's Henrik.
Hi Marianne
Yes, it has been great.
She really is a star.
You, could you put her in on more passports next week
Yes I think so.
But it will be good
perfect.
We'll do that
Hello.
You
I must go now.
After the coffee machine, you can take the disk as well.
So we will talk more about this next week.
Don't forget to alert.