[Music]
Diversity Charter Sweden is part of the world's largest network for diversity
and inclusion questions for those who believe in ongoing knowledge refill
and together with others want to move forward your
Positions Warmly welcome to spring's last Friday creation My name is Anna
Carlsson Sigstedt and Secretary General of Diversity Charter Sweden and today so is
It the last day at Diversity Month something we have done together
with the entire EU the 27 countries where we have really focused on showing
the weight and of a more inclusive working life and there have been made lots of different
activities I have seen someone have produced a movie I have seen some
big banks that have been out and gone and in this way talked more about these
the questions and there have been lots of different seminars so it has been very much
And there you can go in and look at the Diversity Month website therefore you can
Of course click on activities and see what has been done in the different countries
And it may happen that there are still activities today and among
Otherwise, there is this activity Friday's knowledge since we have the last
Friday in every month and today we actually have one
small unique prior knowledge for the first time so we have gathered the representative from
All the Riksdag parties and we are the party we do not belong to any party but we
think it is so important to be in the service of democracy and especially now that
here the euval which is June 9 and when I talk to people about the election, people can be
So no yes, a choice now comes they have not so much information and then thought
We like this then we want to serve for you what the parliamentary parties do in these
the questions we are passionate so much for a more inclusive
work life and as usual, it is not me who will lead this call in
Today we brought in a
Professional model from Lead 20 Thank you so much Anna Thanks for being here eh yes
and I have received the great benefit and moderate this call and my name is
As I said Liselott v Her Maggie Eh and I think that this moderator's role
Today might rather be about being a little time pair
These candidates to the European Parliament from the various parties and we want to
they should have space all to come to speak so if they think I am a bit
hard and go in and say that now the time is out, it is just because I want to
Everyone should have the time that, like yes, they should be entitled to so to speak eh but we are so
Glad we have several candidates with us today eh and participate in this
The conversation makes Abir Al Salani from the Center Party Eh M Hollis as
represents the Christian Democrats Karin Karlsbro from
Liberals Magnus P Volin from the Environmental Party The Green Evin Ins from
Social Democrats Jesper Skarberg Karlsson from the Moderates and Z Vera as
represents the Left Party eh Sweden Democrats' representative's shoulder
also been involved but have been prevented so those candidates should we listen to
Eh but i want to give some instructions it is that we have one
chat but in this Friday fun creator you will not be able to ask questions in
The chat on the other hand, there will be ongoing information eh we will also
set up a link to the page where all parties have answered questions about how they
will drive diversity and inclusion perspective in the EU and it is
What is the theme of this call the arrangement will be like that
that all candidates will get first three minutes were to lift it as they
think is most important the most important thing they will drive linked to these
the questions in the Eup Parliament EH and then we will make one to round a couple
minutes where each representative is allowed to comment on something that is said or
clarify some of what one wants to highlight from one's party and so can
it be that I can with some one too
follow -up question but i should not take up more time but i was going to leave over instead
the word to the first of our candidates to the Eup Parliament and then
Do I want to give the word to you abir from the center party
Please thank you so much and for this seminar and for the invitation because I
may be here and good morning on you all all committed people in
diversity issues my name is abir and i have previously worked
with diversity as diversity as a project for a diversity project that we had what
Applies to precisely political organizations and eh it is a very big job
But with diversity and much is actually about both political will and
Priority and leadership eh I Center Party consider that many of
labor market issues in the first place should be handled by
had in Sweden a tradition of eh and that is because it is after all
Labor market policy works at I level or at home in Sweden should detail
The labor market, for example, through the works quotation or
The wage guarantee hike, on the other hand, should, after all, guarantee all people's
equal rights and opportunities for example by ensuring protection against
After all, discrimination and the Center Party have worked actively on the issue of EU
common standards for equality body
Eh what is then equivalent to discrimination as the man in Sweden we
have pushed on politically for the Council of Ministers to adopt
Anti -discrimination agency Fald without it must also be a legal
Backing and Antidal Discrimination Date
also create a union for all eh a union that is available to all there
our freedoms that we have won as citizens should also apply to everyone on the same
way and therefore the functional law council has
with and lately we have as one as a profit that we have then won is after all
The Functional Law Convention
within the Union for people with different disabilities and that I
would like to be that then eh work continued to work as we have done
In the Center Party that we wear three glasses that we have then as we
The Center Party considers incredibly important one to be equal
the equality perspective between men and women it is
functional right and that is the anti -racist perspective and by having these three
different glasses all the time on in on it when we work with
Legislation so we believe that we can also take concrete steps forward in terms of increased
Diversity but one last thing I want to say is that representation Matters and
It doesn't matter how eh how well one speaks of diversity
If you look at the parties' lists, I think that including my own party
I am equally critical of all, so it leaves a part to be desired in terms of eh
diversity of different candidates so we have a lot to do and work on both
internally in political life at home in Sweden that party political life but
also
[Music] Legislative Power to Mikaela afterwards
that presents the Christian Democrats
Mikaela thanks so very much Mikel Hollis is my name I come from Gränna there
Karin is sitting now so I see my old high school and its flags in
background nice to see this we this morning eh very fun to be
here very fun to get into these issues I am not sitting in
The European Parliament so it becomes that you can read as well as what has been said
the last eh five years but i think this has been exciting questions to
Get to learn more about too and I thank you so much for arranging
This this morning I work for everyday as General Secretary for
Christian Democratic International Center We work a lot with countries where not
is there any democracy or there is very little democracy and a lot of it
work we do and in all parties represented here have such
organizations and what you work it it is precisely to get eh groups that
are under -represented eh and strengthen them in politics eh and so there is some kind
anti -discrimination we work with that I still work with for everyday ehm
And for the Christian Democrats and I mean sure it is for everyone here
so these questions are about an inclusive working life very very
Important but with that said so so we still think that
labor market policy is something that one should have at national level and as
We the member states ourselves should control the eh and then of course we have an Indre
market where we compete with each other eh and then it is clear that we think that
Also the countries that are part of the internal market must have the nice conditions
eh and work against discrimination eh but in Sweden we have a very
strong discrimination protection EH in the Discrimination Act
eh and that it involves all forms of discrimination and ensures that they
Human rights are respected in working life and on a number of other
social areas ehm and there decides there are also
provision for employers to work very actively and continuously
also to strengthen these rights and, like all the time
work so that there is no discrimination
Eh but I think we can have a stronger exchange of experience in Europe VI i
Sweden we often hit our chest because we are the best in these questions eh
maybe we are not always but we can also be eh be good at that
Exchange experiences I think eh But the Christian Democrats do not believe you should
lift up these issues eh at an eunal level for there is risk then we
Compromise with what works well in Sweden and we don't want to do that
I still emphasize eh so should see a little more jo eh yes but one thing like me too
want to say that is that a challenge ahead we think is that if one now as well as
proceed at eunal level to go into these issues and that it becomes for
Of course, detail rules eh there are a number of conventions that are eh that are
very good and I know abir mentioned this with working to
Disabled people should be given rights in working life and so on and that is
something that all of which all countries must take their responsibility and the EU states there
the strengthened in terms of basic human rights and that we must
protect eh all people so it is important but we don't think we need
lift it up at euns level with special directives in that way and then begins
Finally with regard to EH companies' sustainability reporting, we think that
It is very good thus this CS RD Directive EH which was one of the questions
from you but I still want to say that we may be careful so that it does not become
Too great workload for small businesses so that you can't cope with that
becomes too much administration It is clear that large companies can handle this
good but but we must also make sure not to have too much eh detail regulation in
In the EU that's what I wanted to say thank you so very big thanks Mikael thanks for
That then I think I should invite the next representative and then it will be Karin
representing the Liberals and I will say that I know that several of you are
after all in the middle of campaign several of these candidates eh so that it is very happy
That you are with us I know Karin is one of those who are on the move but
Please Karin thank you so much eh yes my name is
Karin Karlsbro I am the top candidate of the Liberals eh I'm just as you said
I'm on a trip I'm on my way to Stockholm but right now I'm sitting on
a park bench in beautiful Gränna so I Mikaela in your home areas and it was
Great to be able to share the morning coffee and a little lovely moment in this
hectic time with you and talk about these important issues and
Before I became a European Parliamentarian as I became in 2019, I worked as
sustainability manager in the real estate industry so that these issues are also lies
personally in the professional life very hot about
The heart the Liberals go to election on a message a stronger Europe for a
Stronger Sweden and we live in a very dangerous time with Russia's war
against Ukraine who threatens everyone's peace and freedom and we liberals say we we
want to see a stronger EU that stands up against Russia that can stop the war that can
take on the common challenges that Europe stands
For those issues that do not stop at national borders, there are parties that
We make sure on the outer edges both to the left and right who want to see a
weaker EU or a decent EU and then we want to exactly
on the contrary, we think that the issue of human rights for that is
actually what we talk about democrat and human rights is a matter
that lacks boundaries that we have to handle jointly together over
national borders and between countries that they are far too important to not yes
simply ending a pact globally and we have at the UN level global level eh come
a bit late in compliance catastrophic but eunal level is actually very important for
these issues and at this time where we yes wrestle with war with freedom
and oppression and we see how democracy is mounted down in several EU countries and threatened
I think primarily about what has happened in Hungary development in Hungary de
In recent years, we should be aware that eh EU Europe is not vaccinated either
against eh one one very negative development and there the EU comes in and we
thinks it is important that just these issues of human rights
actually lies at euns level that's not details that is where this is exactly where we
Must be because our vision is that the EU is a home port for democracies internally
in Europe but also a strong vote globally for a democratic world and are one with
In the EU then they have actually signed to stand up for democracy and
Human rights and countries that violate those like Hungary for example
To yes, you should withdraw the support for you should be sanctioned to get rid of
voting right eh because eh man it is simply not acceptable
eh with dismantling democracy, you also see a negative development for
eh diversity issues eh gender equality issues eh and all questions
that are linked to this so you can't see it isolated and it is
Therefore, it is so important to protect this and in terms of what the EU can
and should do in concrete terms so my colleagues have mentioned some things and we are
also very positive tilla discrimination or antidime
Discrimination date
in the EU to eh we have an internal market a common labor market and certainly we
Also defends the Swedish model EH it is a bite support the Swedish
the parties but the issue of gender equality is also a human rights issue
eh then when it comes to eh sustainability reporting and the eh de
the questions then there is something that is left to stay and we also see in
other eula law that social sustainability is woven in I have to
Example negotiated EU's
Sustainability to do you can think of yes today when we work with such a pretty
Technical really climate law founding so you weave in human rights eh
working conditions eh elsewhere in the world so that it is also linked to
This but in the end the EU is one union and should be and we have to guard guard
about E's role as union for democracies and then racism eh homophobia has Islamophobia
In anti -Semitism and all that now we can put words into has no place in our
Union and then we together have to set up rules EH that counteracts eh hatred and
threats and the restriction of
AG and organizations jobs together in the same direction but don't forget EU weight in
This I stay there and then I will turn off the camera because we will sit in
The car and drive on to Stockholm but I am listening and hope can
jump in but only I apologize that it might get a little a little worse a little
worse sound and picture and so on but then you know why no danger giant attack too
you Karin eh I quickly leave the word to Magnus representing
Environmental Party The Greens Be Magnus Yes but thank you so much my name
Magnus Pevin and is Municipal Restsjö but also number four on the Environmental Party's list
to the euval and it is very exciting times eh right now of course
And I would have been out and campaigned today too but have I gone on throat flux
So I get to sit at home and take care of the work digitally instead of this term of office
That has passed has been extremely important and we have mainly had Alice here
Bakke as our eh pioneer so to speak in these work areas and she got
already at the beginning of the term of office as
main hearing on democracy and equality and anti -discrimination
which we are very proud of the work needs to be ongoing and it needs to be
powerful and we need to put a very strong pressure on the Commission EH
For this is about human rights, thus to be able to work to
able to have a job no matter who one is whether one has a disability
or not where one comes from or whatever it may be about is about
human rights and here we don't have to be so frightened around it
The Swedish model because this is about a framework legislation at EU level
that must antiden discrimination legislation to
Examples that have been blocked since 2008 thus for 16 years it is absolutely incredible
EH and here Alice and the environmental partners have the green group in the EU
The last term of office worked very hard to
The Commission should get rid of this but it is also about the fact that we cannot have
individual countries that slow down development in the field of human rights and then
Do we have to remove the veto in the Council of Ministers on these issues because it is absolutely incredible
That Aban in Hungary can sit with several should be said and slow down this type of
extremely important legislation that must come to
eh then we need to remove the veto and we will fight hard for that eh it
is also about this about having to know what actually happens and
We go ahead and are very clear that we have to pick up
Equality data We need to know what it looks like in the labor market which are the ones
are discriminated against which ones do not get jobs which is it that not for part out of
Salary increases We know we have a wage gap between men and women of 13 %
that has not changed over the past 10 years it is a disaster and it must
we do something about but then we need to know who it is and so we have to
actually work with quotation in the environmental party The green so we are completely
convinced that in fact, sometimes with legislation must be told
How you want and how we want it to look like the increased gaps de ekon omis
Increased gaps, not least in Sweden, perhaps increasing among the OECD countries
is a challenge as well for the labor market and here one cannot then
as the Swedish government go in and say that we remove the contribution to
employers who have high sick pay costs that are total
counterproductive, but we must increase the security of people at
the labor market to be able to be retrained to be able to become employed even if one has one
disease picture behind it that our companies should feel confident in hiring the right
competence even though this person seeking the work has previously been
Sick -sick, for example, then you cannot reduce the contributions to that way
eh in some kind of ideal world create incentives for more people to come in
work without we believe that it is totally counterproductive but basically as I said
So I have to say that this is about human rights and fearful
the hot around the Swedish model or speech that the EU should be v law on it
may not be about human rights these are frame laws that need to and
Then it is up to Sweden and the Labor Market Party to make sure that
It will be reality thank you very much thank you also to you Magnus Eh and then
I think I leave the word to Evin representing
The Social Democrats were evin yes but thank you very much
Eh good has been said Ieren, but we can start by saying that EHM EU: S
The slogan is united in diversity EHM and this shows that the EUlands
should really take eh diversity issues inclusive from the saw eh and
Without it means that all EH the entire population of the European Union must
be seen and must be included eh I have myself during this term of office
that has gone as sitting as, among other things, in a cross -political intergroup
and called eh anti anti -racism and diversity eh intergroup where i have
Worked, among other things, with these eh inclusion FRR
Ågor an eh important eh question as or an important legislation that has been raised
As I think is worth mentioning again as like the EU should EH continue to negotiate
around and then assume it is after all
I think that would be a hugely important step forward to it I must too
may also mention that I mean in the EU's eh fundamental rights statute so is
all of course the inclusion anti -racism and everything like that is very very or
Anti -discrimination very very clear so all of all EU's really
Basic eh document eh rests, after all, that eh that eh the whole community should join and
included and discrimination is not acceptable since so eh
The Functional Law Convention
and was one of the eh shadow reports as they are then called Social Democratic
the group's then eh representative in the negotiations precisely about this card
eh we also have during this term of office for as things as
Also is positive eh with EU's first eh eh anti
Eh what is the name of the anti -racism action plan eh in place ehm and but
Of course there is very much left to do especially what it
applies to go from OT to action I also fully hold
Of course eh that representation plays role politics and representation thus
political suggestions and representation must go hand in hand because we must after all
ensure that all our citizens know themselves recognize themselves in
decision makers but also in other people around EH I in the community
Because it is also only when you feel that yes but eh can they so can I
And there I see that there is a huge defect but partly among political
the parties but also in society at large and the further up the hierarchy you come
eh i i different at different workplaces the more the more
ehm homogenic eh the most often man white hetro eh without any kind of
function variation eh so with that said there is very much to
do but one of the most important things comes in the coming term of term V
would actually be to ensure one
Big thanks also to you Evin for that then I think I give the word of course
Also to Jesper who represents the Moderates big eh big thank you too
for the opportunity to be with you here today eh yes but the EU should include a
collaboration that increases idea exchange between countries eh that also spreads good
Example reinforced exchange of experience is and and will remain
One of the foremost forms of cooperation in the labor market and the EU should, of course
Of course, put the majority of their power and focus on issues where intercourse
required eh war threat and the weak competitiveness for example we
Moderates yes but we believe that labor market policy should be designed by
Member States themselves eh it is our way of safeguarding the Swedish model it
also provides the opportunity to develop the same I think it is also worthwhile to
note when I listen to this discussion that companies that are more
Equal more inclusive also have higher profitability over time tips eh
At the same time, I would like to emphasize that the EU should ensure that all member states
have good protection against discrimination we moderates also think it is
Reasonable for the Statute of Rights to be extended with certain additional rights and here
Need the EU to ensure that every country takes responsibility for its part in that commitment
Eh you can describe it as the floor needs to be raised and the whole toolbox
Need to be used then there was a question in advance regarding the CSR directive eh
And on an overall level, we are moderates positive to the CSR Directive
We believe that it is a problem that sustainability reporting eh it is good
that sustainability reporting becomes more
Standardized for that has been a problem with low unable hot between
countries and companies and there has also been very lacking in some cases
Quality in the information that the companies leave and here I would say
that I notice that many in business at least the part of the business community that
Feel free to talk to politicians are positive to increased standardization on
this area at the same time it is worth having
In mind that this is an EU Directive that is very extensive and therefore has
It has been important for us in the Moderates to keep us at a reasonable level for
to safeguard the competitiveness of the companies and especially the small and medium -sized
companies that are often under suppliers and lack these great legal
resources that occasionally required and that is also the background to why we have
implemented this directive at an EH minimum level
thanks big thanks Jesper eh and now I think I leave the word to z as
represents the Left Party please thank you very much and good morning
From a little goaln North Tälje ehm I I work within the Left Party
with education about anti -racism so it is very fun to be here and
get talk about eh yes but equality and discrimination with you
ehm today we have a rather insufficient insufficient picture of the width of
discrimination within the Union EH Although there are guidelines from the Commission
If equality data we still lack a common picture of perceived
discrimination when we work for quite a few different parameters
The Left Party EH thinks we need a clearer directive regarding
equality data based on voluntariness he he iT and
Especially self -identification eh A clearer directive would help countries
Like, for example, Sweden not to be so embarrassingly bad at bringing statistics
an allocated gender affiliation in the EH Census Register
The Left Party wants the Swedish model with Partfinder
trade union rights eh for others we want the EU to change procurement rules
eh so it becomes possible to make demands on collective agreements at all public
Procurement without exception eh in the third we want to
Labor immigration shall be based on the salary and conditions that apply in
Sweden or other EU countries should also apply to what immigrants we cannot
retain this system we have now leading to pay dump and bad
working conditions eh it only drives on segregation eh and creates great social
and economic differences that provide racist power structures ehm that it
structural racism is reflected in our workplaces is
No wonder as long as we pursue on increased segregation at the same time eh like that
We reduce this segregation, we want to see at least that labor market parties
where both employers receive greater responsibility and trade unions more tools for
put pressure on companies regarding equal eh action but then it is so that
We have an ever -growing gig and platform economy with extensive many
negatively racist workers who are completely out of backing from
trade unions ehm and if we don't get buck on it so
Will we not get very far that is why we want platform companies to
regarded as employer and platform work should be regarded as
workers to enable
party interrogation what everyone has mentioned a bit about the ehm eh left party is positive
to EH systems like CSR what enables companies to take responsibility for their entire
However, value chains eh we want the requirements for companies to be raised for
Environmental and Social Ehm Social Sustainability Ehm therefore we want
that justice should be a more central part of CSR and that legislation should in a lot
a greater extent apply to subcontractors therefore we also want
that we introduce a limitation of max two stages of eh subcontractors throughout the EU
Ehm i stop there thank you very big thanks too to you c yes as much as
You say so much wise so much interesting eh now is that everyone should
Get an opportunity was one of you to see as well as is something you want to comment
as any other representative has said or perhaps something you wish to clarify
Or as you don't have with the first round so now we run one like this a little faster
round but everyone should have the opportunity for a few more minutes and then I do so completely
simple that I go after my order so I give the word to abir from
The Center Party first yes very wisely has been said and it is
Great fun to see that there is such a commitment to the question EH but I think
that somewhere if I am to stick to today's theme and that n I
organizes about precisely diversity in the labor market and how to think then eh
Work for it so there is very much thrown with concepts here as in eh
I do not want to be the one that is that shows that one really does not
Join this match we have then a labor market policy in Sweden that is
Swedish and according to the EU City City, it should be the case that labor market policy
It is a national matter and I think it is a good and good order
It has served us well now there are then some groups that have not been allowed to join
And where we then have in Sweden because of the Swedish labor market model but
Also on GR of the inability of the social parties to also have inclusion and
diversity in their negotiation rounds as a priority
Ask eh also ended up in the aftermath and created high thresholds for people who
Do not meet the requirements of the norm yes I just want to give an example so svia
would hire people to Arlanda and on that on the ad they had so had
they wrote that one of the requirements is that eh those who seek work work must be able to
fluent Swedish in speech and writing when they then got when they got a lot
Applications but no one really was good enough to be able to work there
And then they got help from some diversity expert and this diversity
The expert studied the workplace and studied the job ad and then realized
This this consulting company that really so you don't have to have eh
fluent and great Swedish in speech and writing to 90 % of the time as
The people who work for Swedavia talk about language other than just Swedish so
After all, we have an outdated an outdated way of working in recruitment what
applies to seeing people's skills we have after all
giant otter skills for example we we usually laugh a little but it is a
Incredibly great finds we make we have the world's most educated
Taxi driver training
Both have politics with them but also the social parties I am quite critical
against both eh eh as well as nutrition employer side and employee side
where one does not have a conscious work on having members of their
organizations that have a different background and actually give them space one of my
Biggest Problem has been in politics has been that yes abir yes exactly it was
just like this is clear we all want to join and discuss thanks so much
And thanks for like concrete examples, I think it also helps to
Understand the Eun level so thank you so much I apologize for interrupting but I
Thinking everyone should catch up and comment on something and Mikaela I thought
I leave the word to you yes but thank you very much I think it was
very interesting and it is interesting what abir says about validation it is
The of course incredibly important it has been pushing for a long time that one must become a lot
much better at being able to do it eh eh and precisely in terms of
The language then I still just want to lift into this debate now it becomes like a
mass from above perspective on in terms of discrimination in terms of human
rights how to treat eh people with other skin color or or
And so on but somewhere I still want to say that here we have a
responsibility also as parents eh as in the school eh at the municipal level thus on
many different levels to bring in eh the right values for how to look at their
Fellow human beings I think we also have to talk about in this
The context so it is not just that we put on a lot of directives and how
one is going to work so everyone would have a good way to look at
sin on their next and on their fellow human beings so I don't think these
the problems would be so big eh so I still really want to press it
And you work that I myself am involved in the City of Stockholm We work after all
hard for that in our operations that it should be inclusive in I in the municipality's
Own businesses and that, like S, should be upwards even then eh so it wants
I say then I think it's good that as Karin Karlsbro said that it
Is this tool on the rule of law and that you land
As for example, then Hungary who does not live up to human rights then
Must one be able to pull away the eustic that still exists to such countries and
I think that could be used to a much greater extent actually
Thank you big thanks Mikael so very good Karin should see if Karin is with us or
If she's on the run but I leave the word but i'm with yes well so hello yes no
But very very wise have said when I thought maybe a few questions in order to
You should get a clearer picture of the differences between the parties
Also and eh that I started with so the Liberals are a very European friend LT
party because we believe we need stronger cooperation on all the issues there
We have to solve common problems or where we need to guard the joint
Right is we are we are so positive about the EUSAM work so we want Sweden
shall change the crown with the euro for example eh but labor market policy is after all is
After all, it is national and we also guard the Swedish model but
At the same time, we are challenged by eh new business models new new
forms of employment, so to speak and then I think of gigg work and there have
EU now eh worked out this as one calls
platform doors
Text about it and and so and it shows that we live in a global economy and
Also, a European labor market has at the same time as the digitalisers regen eh
challenges us in a whole new way so that you have to be able to EH also find new ones
new regulations that, to solve the problems you want to access it is a late
A question that I get quite often in these contexts it is about
quotation and then I was just thinking of telling us we are from the Liberals' side
very committed to gender equality issues and have always been
And here is the question that we have because it is also a matter of equality but
It is also a matter of growth for Europe that we cannot afford that so many
Women in Europe do not fully participate in the labor market and that is because of the fact that
Man in the Member States has legislation such as joint taxation you have
a family policy that does not make it profitable for women and work and we
usually go as far as we say that but for the EU sake for Europe's sake we have
not advice then eh to have the best of the world and the world's well -educated eh as well
housewives because eh this is, after all, affects everyone's economy and it is
Also one it is a right is called fair question of gender equality so that
There is and here we need to work together in the Union to eh
strengthen women's eh labor market and gender equality in the labor market eh and
Then you usually get the question as a letter on the post what do you think about
Quotation to corporate boards it is a hot issue and here has the Liberals
landed in the fact that we are we think it is a bad idea with quotation to
Board of Directors without we have to find other seats but yes these issues
If you are often wrestled in when talking about this kind of eh of questions so
that yes I just wanted to clarify some points where we often get questions I
Stay there thanks great thanks Karin Eh for that eh
Magnus I thought the word is going to you now yes but thanks so much no but it is
many things that have been said here and that are important to lift up I believe and not
At least that CS RD Directive is completely deciding and where we are with our green
main hearing on precisely that one should be able to increase the requirements of reporting social
human rights and diversity issues but this needs
Go further this applies to companies with 500 employees and a turnover of 40
Million euro eh there are thus very few companies actually that end up here
And we believe that the companies that may be at the forefront that can report that they
are sustainable will also win in the future because we will set
requirements for public procurement, for example, we already have many companies that
themselves set demands in their procurement of subcontractors and need to get in
This type of reports then of course needs smaller companies one
Support in this accounting and it is quite obvious eh it is so that when
one talks about these things to happen at eunal level the parties that often talk about
That the EU should be more decent, so you are happy to talk about what we war in Europe and we
have to work together toward Russia we have a problem with
competitiveness in Europe and we have to work together with it but you mention
thus not human rights in the same sense it is a problem
Human rights are one of the foundations that the EU was built at one time
In time we have to keep up and when we take frame laws at euns level
Human rights will affect Swedish labor market policy and
It should affect Swedish labor market policy it is up to
The parties make sure it happens eh and if it does not happen then it must come
Pressures from the EU It is entirely in order and then it is again that
We need to have a zero tolerance against racism we need a directive a legislation
which is clear and that must not be slowed down by individual countries in the Council of Ministers and
We need a powerful eub budget that actually spends money on civil society
and the organizations that are fighting for human rights as well on
The labor market please yes thank you so much for that too
Magnus I leave the Word to Evin here NO NO but also to make
a little difference between things that have been said by different people from
Of course, different parties are so that we are of course as Social Democrats
Even with the fact that labor market issues are of course mainly a national
Ask but this is not about EH just about labor market issues it
is about securing access to the labor market for when it comes
To wage formation and everything like that and eh, of course the EU should not hold on
and poke in our contract module
So this will be eh even if it goes into labor market issues so it will be
Ju a matter of fundamental rights ehm the secure of fundamental
Rights and then you have to think broadly it is about women and men
of course it is about eh hbtq people it is about people with
Functional Variation This is about people who are outside born outside
Sweden and EU borders Eh or or people with as me that is a bit
slightly darker eh tone eh in skin tone ehm so we really have to address also
the question eh broadly to ensure that the EH Eh Eh's slogan on
real eh realize so it not only becomes word eh and not just on some
Areas EH thus the labor market area is hugely important but we get with us
that it is usually related to also eh lack of inclusion and actually eh
racism and discrimination on in other parts of society eh there are they eh
In our society that does not even want to go and visit the social services because one knows
to go there, you are already dead in advance and you will not get it
the help eh as when you want to have or you are not believed at that help
that one would not as you would need because you have bad experiences or
other person with the same background eh as one's self has bad experiences eh with
The education system is hugely important so we really need a large
grip eh about inclusion and anti -discrimination in all parts of
the community for that is actually related to just
eh discrimination in the labor market but as I said you need
just distinguish the labor market our labor market model
the eh with just eh precisely anti -discrimination and diversity issues
eh because this is actually basically about fundamental free and
rights thanks so much evin too those for the clarifications eh then we have
Jesper next in turn
Jesper we shall use the intergovernmental European cooperation to
Sweden should be able to be more freer safer and richer but there seems to be a picture
in many that it will become reality by the fact that the entire EU must become eh exactly
As Sweden and otherwise member states, in principle, EH should be sent out of the Union
And here I find it important to have the perspective that the EU can work
purposefully constructive and long -term to persuade member states that
really meet the minimum requirements for human rights it is through
This continuous work eh in processing these countries inside the Union
as we can make sure that Jews in Hungary Roma in Romania women in Poland get a
better or at least a decent eh life situation and it is difficult to
Write it on a Vala Fish like a slogan eh but this is this continuous
the work of raising the floor and using the toolbox within the Union it is as
We can get a working union to feel eh pride
because yes thank you so much Jesper and eh last but not least in this round so
I leave the word to the Zi Left Party please thank you very much eh and I want to
just say that there have been a lot of wise eh input here so I will actually
keep me pretty brief i want to say that it is very wise of what
becomes in descriptions of the Swedish labor market and that all parties
characterized by a slightly outdated way of thinking I would like to see more people in
Companies municipalities regions trade unions that work actively with education in
discrimination but specifically eh anti -racism as i do in the left party
eh then I want to clarify that the Left Party is also against
Low -wage country The Swedish model in games and further stagnate salary development
eh over time and increase eh i stay there please
very big thank you to yes corner i would part i can say i would wish
that we had all day on us and talk about these important perspectives to hear
also even more from the representatives of the different parties about how to look at
perspectives diversity and inclusion in the EU but it is noticed in any case that you all
are incredibly engaged which I think is very very important we want to
Those who represent us in us yes Sweden in the European Parliament they drive
Here the questions we think that in ie charter is very important eh and before I leave
Over the word to Anna who will round this Friday's knowledge so I want
just say that now I hope that all of you who listen and have looked today have
used your voting rights or do it eh and last day is June 9 to vote in
This important eupa -parliament election but big thanks for all
To all of you who took and so Anna you get closing words this thank you very much
Liselott and thank you very much all you who have also what is called signed in and
Participates in this one and wants to engage more in and use your voice
And above all, V of course thank all of you who are running for now I know you have
Extremely hectic time both behind you and in front of you so I am so happy that you have
Taken to time to be here and I am very happy Liselott that you took that time
to moderate this important conversation and diversity charter swen for us is after all
Like this foundation it is the human rights we like
After all, under the EU Commission and we are, as I said, we do not take any party but we
Still believe in collaborating so just like Lis said used
Voice June 9th But it is also possible to participate in next Friday's knowledge
that is this fall and then we will start talking about mental health and that is the 30
August and registration will open up here next week and then we have signature
Event in it