“It is genetic” or “it sits in the genes” we hear often-
-But what does that mean and can we say so? We will learn more about that now.
DNA is an abbreviation of deoxyribo- nucleic acid and is a large molecular-
-which containing information for how your upcoming cells should work-
-And is a drawing for how the body should be built up.
The DNA structure can be likened to a ladder.
The sides consist of sugar molecules and phosphorus that are repeated in succession.
The step pins consist of nitrogen bases:
Adenin, thymine, cytosine and guanine.
It is the order of nitrogen bases
-which just gives you your unique DNA.
Adenine, thymine, cytosine and guanin-
-Dructions are shortened with the letters A, T, C and G.
The nitrogen bases must be assembled in a certain way for it to work.
A binds with T and C binds with G.
Together they form base pairs.
This means that if one side of the steps has the consequence A, T, A, G, C-
-So the other t, a, t, c, G.
A certain number of base pairs then form what we call a gene.
The DNA molecule itself becomes long-
-And gets the structure as a helix-shaped ladder, a DNA spiral.
The DNA spirals can be up to two meters long if stretch out them-
-But to get a seat in our cells they are tightly rolled like new-
-When we call chromosomes. A human has 46 chromosomes.
They are composed in pairs, 22 pieces, with the same genetic information.
The twenty -one couple are gender chromosomes.
Depending on the gender, they have different combinations.
If it is a set of an X chromosome and an Y chromosome ...
... it is a man.
If you change the Y chromosome with an x-
-The there will be a woman with two X chromosomes.
The chromosomes, your DNA, are available in exact copies in all your cells.
We can say that everyone sits with the same drawing for how your body should be built.
Different genes are turned on in the cells to give them specific tasks-
-Something we call gene regulation.
It helps the cell regulate its tasks.
Skin cells are coded to divide quickly and quickly produce skin.
The nerve cells, with long committees, are coded to send out signals-
-And the blood cell is coded to transport oxygen to all our cells.
To be able to do all this, the cell needs to produce protein.
They are the body's building stone-
-And builds tissues, bones and organs.
They also ensure that cells can communicate with each other.
Can you say that everything is genetic? No, that does not work.
There is a lot of research on what is inheritance and what is the environment.
For example, one-egg twins that have identical hereditary mass are compared
-But that still becomes different in both appearance and personality.
So the DNA gives us certain characteristics and conditions-
-But our environment has a major impact and impact on our genetic mass.
If you have genes to become tall, but go through a trauma in puberty-
-Can the surrounding factors, such as the environment, dominate your genes.
The same goes for diseases. If you have cancer in your family-
-You, by eating right and exercising, never have to get sick.
So to say that everything is genetically is not possible.
But your DNA definitely has a crucial role in being you.
Swedish text: Gabriella Eseland Iyuno Media Group for UR