You've just learned the basics of simpler stock analysis-
-Hit a stable real estate share with low debt-
-And Press Buy. Congratulations to the investment.
Everything went wrong. You are poor.
So it can go when you can't hybrid capital.
Therefore, you should learn how it works. Now!
In the balance sheet you will find the company's assets.
These assets are financed by loans, the rest is equity.
The most important thing to know is that when too much that is borrow-
-Is the bank worried. Then they want higher interest rates and maybe stop lending more.
Fast -growing real estate companies need a lot of money to continue buying new.
What do they do when they can't get more loans?
Well, then they give out a preference share.
There are special shares that are over ordinary shares.
They simply ask investors for money. In return, they receive dividends.
"Give us money now, we give back a little at a time and even more."
Type as a loan.
But preference shares are not counted as loans. They instead end up on equity-
-Fastän they are rather something between loans and shares.
Then there are D shares. They are not as strong as preference shares-
-But works in a similar way.
Thus, as a loan, but is not seen as a loan, but as equity.
But you can try even more. For example, start a joint venture.
One takes properties you already own-
-And asks if anyone wants to buy 50 % of them. For 40 million.
Some company thanks yes. The properties then end up in a jointly owned company.
A joint venture.
In addition to receiving 40 million, the loans follow on the properties-
-With the Joint Venture company.
Now the debts are not visible in "our" company.
Joint venture is seen as an asset owned to 50 %.
The debt of the Joint Venture company is not visible among "ours".
How should you be able to see this? Well, by counting margin.
Pretending as if the D shares and preference shares are debt-
-Do to take the number of D shares and preference shares times their respective share price.
That value minus equity plus debt,
Now you get a more conservative picture of the company's balance sheet.
Now you can. Good luck!