How does it feel not to have to work?
Maribel Leander Lindberg-
-and Oskar Lindberg, who decided to take control of his time and money-
-and become financially free.
-Welcome here, Oskar and Maribel.
-Thanks.
You have been financially free for six years, but we back the band a bit.
What did your life look like before you started saving against it?
We usually have 2011 as a small starting shot.
But before it-
-So it was probably the lives of many.
We then had two small children.
We both had full -time positions at large Swedish companies.
We worked pretty much.
No more than others maybe, but it was 8-17 every day of the week.
And six weeks of vacation on it.
So there was a lot about the logistics-
-To have an everyday life with our children and full -time jobs.
It was the feeling of having the breath in the throat and to catch with-
-To get them food before going on something else.
I traveled a great deal in the job, so sometimes Maribel-
-At home and managed everything yourself.
So there was no time left.
In 2011 we were on a longer trip together, the whole family.
We were gone for eight months and in the meantime we started to get perspectives on things.
When you live outside your everyday life, these thoughts come.
We were in Mexico, where I have family and suddenly had more time for each other-
-More time for our children, and more time for friends and relatives.
We felt we wanted to get that feeling at home.
At home, it felt like a transport route for the weekend or for the holiday.
They worked to get these breaks.
We wanted to bring that feeling we had.
We didn't have the words for it then.
But now we call it an everyday life that we do not need to take vacation from.
We want the change where vacation is something different to everyday-
-But it should not be a quality difference.
Everyday life should be good, desirable.
Then we will take a closer look at some special events-
-As has meant a lot to Maribel's and Oskar's savings.
We have with us a person who has inspired you a lot: Mr.
Money Mustache.
Who is it and what does he mean to you?
It is an American blogger who started in 2011, while we started saving.
He and his family and wife-
-Haded in early retirement, as he called it.
They were in their 30s, after working for eight years.
They felt like an ordinary family.
Admittedly, it was in the United States, but we could interpret it to our conditions.
It felt like Goldable.
Then it coincided with our experience in Mexico by a life-
-As we looked like we wanted life to look.
So it fit perfectly together.
I think it says: "Financial Freedom Through Badassity."
There was a lot of focus on thrift.
Cycle everywhere.
Do a lot of yourself.
We were attracted a lot of that.
Don't be so small.
There is a quote that inspired you some.
-Here we have it.
-"Common Sense is not very common."
It may not have inspired us so much, but that is something we have discovered.
It should be common sense not to waste money, nature's resources or their time.
Sometimes when we talk about what we have done, it feels like we just stumble up common sense.
But then you look around or listen, and notice that so few live after this.
Then there is a need for the message, because we may have forgotten somewhere ...
Older people, 70 plus or 80, have come to us and said:
"But we've always lived like that."
Then you wonder where it has gone.
Has it been lost?
Like this with walking and cycling.
Does it make sense if I will only be five kilometers, then to bring a two ton heavy steel monster?
Is it enough with my legs or a bike?
But it is so natural for us to be so ineffective.
Here I also have you - where you pull in the same direction.
Why has it been important to you during the savings journey?
Yes, it is almost a necessity.
To talk together, to have common goals that you pull against together.
You know what happens if you sit in a canoe and paddle in different directions.
When we have common goals, we have been able to pepper each other.
When someone is not really motivated, you do not have a bad day at the same time.
Then we have been able to pepper each other because we are heading in the same direction.
It applies to both economic and all our lives that we try to choose the direction in the same direction.
And tune in this direction.
It can change.
Do you have any tips for others who save in pairs?
A kickoff.
Preferably once a year.
Maybe two, to follow up a bit.
It is obvious in many companies.
But you may not do it in your own privacy.
Which for us has become obvious.
So we have this lovely picture.
What is the smiling family we see here?
This is 2011 in Mexico.
We sit with our children on the stairs outside the apartment we rented.
In that apartment we had much less space than at home, because we had too big a house.
It was a big apartment, but it was half as big as the house at home.
-We had a simple equipment.
-We went there with our suitcases with clothes.
We didn't have a lot of commitments, but it was very simple.
It was a wonderful start.
We got a taste of it.
Although we were not to move to Mexico, it was that composition of life-
-As we have had our eyes.
We all had parts there that we wanted to bring home.
What changes did you do?
Where did you start?
To save a sum of money that we can then live on for the rest of our lives.
When we arrived at it, we began to look at-
-What expenses that do not add to our quality of life.
In the short term, it was the simple things.
Actually what is always in the newspaper on January 24:
"Bring your lunch box, cycle instead of taking the car" ...
"Pull in everything everyday, don't buy more clothes if it's already full in the closet."
It was the first things.
We started to cooperate, started living more locally and seeing what we had around us.
In the next step it was to design for life.
Oskar likes to count, so he started counting on it.
We saw a pension around 55.
But it went a little faster.
When you started counting on it, what was the sum you got?
We started from the four percent rule.
I want to call it a rule of thumb.
If you think it is an absolute truth, it can be a little dangerous.
It is about that if one can expect to safely get 4 % return-
-To you can live on that return, and theoretically, capital should suffice for eternal
-or at least for a very long time.
As long as one can be expected to live.
If you look at how we use it, then it is a feature of-
-How much you need to live and how much capital you have.
One of the reasons why this time became shorter was that we became more capable on-
-To put away money, but also live better on a smaller sum than we could dream of.
When we realized it, it became a smaller sum we needed to save.
This time shrunk.
Didn't you feel that you sacrificed anything or missed anything?
The cheeses maybe.
I am very fond of good cheeses.
But it was also like an experiment to see what you can do.
What do we want a lot?
What do we want in our lives?
To buy really nice cheeses from France and Spain for many hundreds of kronor-
-Ir not directly life's emergency.
You can be without it for a while.
For you then, Maribel.
Is there anything missing?
No ... Many people ask, "Have you chosen a lot of things?"
When we started it was very clear that we started planning our life-
-And our economy, but above all we made a life plan.
We usually sit down twice a year and look at what we want with this year-
-Card.
What do we want five and ten years ahead?
Then it becomes clear where we want to spend our money and what we want to choose.
As we make the reconciliations it becomes mentally easier-
-The thing I save money for what I want this year or next year.
I don't feel like I miss anything.
We have had much more focus on what we have chosen than what we have chosen.
What sum did you consider to be enough to live on?
Six million.
And how big is your monthly cost?
Then it was 20,000. Now it is rather between 25,000 and 30,000.
The children have become older, inflation-
-And then we have received a leisure activity that draws some money-
-An if we try to be smart ... we go a lot of skiing in the winter.
How did investment go in the beginning?
We made a plan at the beginning of the year.
Around this much we can probably put away per month.
Then we bought shares for that amount every month, so it became an equally large buy-
-In the end of each month.
Wages and expenses went up and down-
-And it got a little over we saved it on a bank account
-So that for a period, for example, we could buy for 25,000 per month.
If the stock market went up it was fun and went down we got a little more for the money.
It didn't feel like we went in with a huge amount-
-So that it gets too hard to hold on if it goes down.
Have you been worried sometime during the savings trip?
No, rather the opposite.
The more we have saved, the safer we have felt.
The little rucksack with money is growing.
Like a backpack that becomes more full.
For us, it gave much more security.
In 2008 it was also a bit crisis, some companies pulled down-
-But we felt: happens something we have something to take from.
So we didn't feel worried.
No, and we see that our greatest strength-
-Is that we can live well on a small sum.
It means ... We work every now and then when we feel it-
-And when there are fun things to do.
Do we need to supplement with income-
-Is not so large sums, we can live well on a little money.
It's almost the biggest.
The backpack with money is good-
-It probably thought Pippi too ...
But the setting is more important.
And the ability to live well on a little.
-It's the great strength.
-A very great strength.
Security.
Somewhere there you must have seen that it started to tick on pretty well.
What did it mean to see the money grow?
If we are to relate to something where we started counting down it was more
-"When can we quit work".
It was rather that than the sum of money.
That was always what was the goal for us.
We wanted to own our time-
-and when we saw that we began to approach that point, it was probably bigger-
-An the very sum of money in the account.
Do you have any tips for those who are aiming for being financially free?
Start today.
It's boring, but find out where the money goes.
Many people probably feel that the money is not enough-
-Ca even more today with the high inflation ...
But you have gone through and seen where the money takes the road ...
Are these really things I value?
If you do, you can see ...
I put a lot on this, but do I appreciate it so much?
Most people are probably very surprised.
Once you have pulled down the expens-
-So that those with margin is less than the income and one-
-Avy a good life, you have already become much more financially free.
So that's not a point where you have to go to the finish.
Already there is suddenly ...
I can do something happen.
I can change jobs if I get craving it.
Completely different opportunities open.
But then also to think out what is the goal of financial freedom.
What do I want?
To get down to the core.
-You have to put the idea.
-It must be motivating ...
If you want to make the whole trip, it does not happen overnight.
For us it went faster than we ever ... but you have to endure for six years.
And with some lifestyle changes, you don't even hold out for a month.
Then we have come to our absolute best savings tips ...
What then became a book.
To live locally.
To use what is in your immediate area.
To move in your immediate area for work, leisure, the service you need-
- Everything should be on walking and cycling distance.
Because then you win so much.
Big thanks, Maribel and Oskar for coming here and shared with your savings.
-Thanks so much.
-Thanks.
Want to hear about more exciting savings and get savings tips?
Follow us on social media.
Thank you so much for looking today.
Bye.