I like my expenses. They give me the lifestyle I want.
The ones I don't like I have cut away.
I have to keep track of my finances - now.
Mia Ingelström is not just an economist. She is also a personal trainer in finance.
You hear. Should we start?
Please, say I can cut off many of my expenses.
It's done. You can cut down than you ever thought.
I want to put in another thing. I like my expenses.
They give me the lifestyle I want.
The ones I don't like I have cut away.
You have already started this.
I've got started. I have some service with broadband, TV and a film service.
I didn't have to have TV. I called and asked them to remove what I paid 900 for.
"Hang on for a moment," they said. When they came back they said:
"You get exactly the same but we cut it down to 400 instead."
Thank you who invite.
So SEK 500 per month by lifting the handset.
-How did it feel? -That they've cheated me before.
I have paid for something like ...
Could there be other agreements that you could do the same with?
Then this is where we should start.
How should we cut down the fixed costs?
Fixed costs are all that you pay as a subscription or have an agreement.
It is important that you find out what you pay today, but also what you want to pay.
Compare with what others pay. Then you call.
-Variable expenses? -Then you have to negotiate with yourself.
It's about a behavior.
Look how much you put on different categories, type of food.
Then put up a goal and give it to reach it.
Before the stop. Don't go to the store if you are not going to shop.
Make sure to shop when you are measured. Make sure you really keep it.
It's a choice you make. It's your behavior.
What you do not consume today you can take advantage of tomorrow.
I eat sweets for 80 bucks a day. You don't touch that money, Mia.
It is my goal. May I be allowed to offer a good cup of coffee?
Gladly. Thanks.
You, Mia, if I follow your excellent advice ...
I have saved SEK 2000 a month.
Now I can shop at Pressbyrån weekly and do not have to go out to Willys.
-Now you talk about the lifestyle trap. -Yes is not it?
It is about correcting the mouth for the lunch bag.
-You have more money and get rid of them right away. -It will be lobster again today. Great.
You were used to fish sticks. Now it's lobster.
This is where you have to decide what you have for goals.
If you have a goal to save the money to do something late-
-You must help yourself to keep that money.
This is the hardest thing for us humans.
We are used to having money, we get rid of them.
But it is deferred reward. You have to learn to see that there is a late.
"Hello! I'm the worst impulse shopper. How should I do?"
You should give yourself the opportunity not to end up in situations where you can shop.
Do not go out in the stores to check for lunch.
Do not google to look for the newest bags or clothes.
Help yourself to fill your time with something else so that you do not end up in the temptation.
This is about a behavioral pattern that you have to change for you want.
Help yourself actually change it.
You can introduce a purchase stop and not buy anything for the next 30 days.
When you see that the money is growing, you are motivated by seeing that it works.
-That's really good. -You can't just say, "sharpen you!"
You have to be kind to yourself and see that it is a thing you have to work with.
Today we have learned that fixed expenses can be negotiated. Just drive on.
Variable expenses - negotiate with yourself.
Set some lovely goals.
Lifestyle changes take time.
Then you say, "Get in the collar!" I say: "Be a little kind to yourself."
Don't be so hard all the time.
-Or? -It sounds really good.
We'll talk later. Perfect summary.
-You are so hard? -Really not.