Then the day came. The 328th and last program of EFN Market.
Today we will remember, reflect and try to get to a dignified finish-
-To one of the world's most popular television programs.
Warm welcome to the closing program!
Almost four years ago, EFN Ekonomikanal launched a brand new stock program.
The idea was to do something that would reach a wider audience-
-An the usual "stock exchange audience".
The result saw the light of day on February 3, 2020.
Warm welcome to the first episode of EFN Market on February 3.
-Do you have premiere nerves, Albin? -Yes, they're outside.
What kind of program?
A program on investments that we broadcast each day's day 11.55.
Now we sit here 300 programs later.
It is the very last program of EFN Market.
-We have dressed us up. -I go like this every day.
As if we come from a James Bond casting.
-I'm not a Bond bride. -Are you the villain?
It's done. Rather the villain.
The years have passed, what memories do you have?
Many ... I remember when we started creating EFN market.
We were tasked with the responsible publisher to create a new program from Scratch.
I remember all good meetings we in the team had.
We chopped ideas, chopped, pondered, threw in the trash and started over.
It was very fun. It was just as fun that creation lived for almost four years.
I have two hats on me.
The strongest memory is when I test played-
-To become the program manager for EFN Market.
It was sickly nervous.
It has almost deleted all other fantastic memories.
-Do you were so nervous? -It was so strong.
It came to me, the opportunity to actually start.
Then you have followed all these incredible programs-
-And the response you have received in town by everyone who loves EFN market.
It made me think of my test filming before the program-
-Then I spent on Albin.
He was told to ask some "curveballs", difficult questions.
-It was fun and memorable. -And traumatizing ...?
I still remember it, so something was ...
I think I had to interview a guest.
I do not remember. So traumatized I was.
-Albin got to play guest. -Was that you...?
In honor of the day, we have produced statistics on how things have gone over the years.
We have had 264 guests and made 328 programs.
-Not bad. -Wow!
Awesome that we have had so many guests.
Not only have a small number rolled.
There have been an incredible number of guests over the years.
Imagine we scouted 264 guests, called and got them here.
Really not bad.
Guess how many broadcast hours of EFN market we have done?
I guess 110.
125.
We check the facts ...
-Oh oh oh! -Do you cheat?
I counted a little logical.
Was the EFN market farther from the beginning?
It has always been around 15-20 minutes.
-I thought it came from stock exchange lunch ... -it was 15.
Sometimes EFN market has been up to 20. So it's been a little longer.
Then there have been some "curveballs". Some section has been 30-40 minutes.
-Ny balls some "curveballs" ... -I took Christian's expression.
In the beginning we broadcast every day. Now it is twice a week.
We also have statistics on the guests who have been most in the program.
-I know the answers, so you have to guess. -The fitted quiztime.
Do you have any person? We'll get a list.
Uh ... look, now we got ...
Frida Bratt, Christina Nyman and Anna Svahn.
Who do you guess in place number 3?
-Then I guess ... oh, hard. -Princhorn?
No. I guess Maria Landeborn.
-What are you saying? -Erik sprinchorn.
We check the facts. Shared second place between Eric Strand and Carl Armfelt.
-I was not far from there. -Armfelt is almost sprinkler.
They run fund together.
Then we have place number 1 left. What do you guess?
I try Landeborn again.
Who else could it be? I really do not know.
-Ah, we check. -Yes.
-It was Maria Landeborn! -How could you know that?
I was going to guess her until I got it right.
You should have your guess until it sits.
It's like betting on red. Sometime it must be red.
-Really. Nice work! -Runally.
As of an event, we have place number one in place in the studio.
Maria Landeborn, welcome in!
-You get a small applause. -Welcome. Fun!
Yes, what a surprise.
I have been in and of itself a few times, but ...
Did you think of any competitor?
I thought it might be some manager.
Maybe Armfelt, Sprinchorn or Jonas Olavi ...
He was not on the list. I had guessed that kind of guest.
How does it feel after being eleven times that the program is now closed down?
It feels very boring. Generally, there is too little specific stock.
It's a pretty good focus here. Everything from specific corporate cases and managers-
-To little more general stock exchange, market prospects.
It is generally high ceilings and good substances.
And good guests. One reason you have been allowed to come back-
-Is that the programs have been immensely popular.
If you look back, what kind of favorite memories do you have?
During the pandemic when it was at its most turbulent on the market-
-There it was very exciting. Then it happened so much.
It's such a memory.
I did a program together with Jonas Thulin which was quite fun.
There were quite a few who looked at.
It was about market prospects for some year. May have been 2022.
I was a little more hesitant and he was pretty positive.
He is always.
I think it was I who led the section.
I remember it went very well. There were at least 20,000-30,000 viewers.
You're something on the track. We must take the opportunity to take the temp for the new year.
But before we do that we need to look back-
-And get the stock exchange perspective on these years. What has happened?
It has been a very exciting period.
The pandemic has set the tone for what has happened.
Partly in the beginning when we had the strong stock market fall ...
-. with huge course movements. -We have a graph over it.
I have it in my catalog with graphs that I usually use.
You wanted to talk about the stock market development during the pandemic. Then it was perfect.
-It's about the life of the entire program. -Just.
Some boxes have emerged in the background.
It is an incredibly special period. There is a lot you can talk about.
Partly in the stock market with incentives from monetary and fiscal policy-
-And the almost nail -shaft stock market rise from March 2020 until the end of 2021.
Partly the interest rate hikes.
Who could have believed that the central banks could raise interest rates in such a short time?
There is still no recession, the stock exchange has continued to rise.
It is up 42 % against the world index since the beginning of pandemic.
It has been a fantastic period in many ways.
When talking about market development and macro-
-To come back to things that happened during the pandemic.
To say that it is different this time, you would rather not-
-For it doesn't usually be. But it has been this time.
Both with the huge stimulus and the incredibly high inflation.
The interest rate has been increased and consumption continues.
There is a lot that does not work the way you expect it to normally do.
But it makes it very exciting. There is always something to talk about.
We have not had a shortage of subjects to deal with.
Not with other guests either.
The major movements in sectors on the stock exchange ...
The growth companies that went so incredibly strong, with the decline in 2022.
There has always been something exciting to pick out.
We will look at how the program correlates with the stock exchange.
We have a graph that shows the stock exchange and the most viewed sections on Youtube.
Do you see any clear correlation?
A strong trend that we become more and more seen.
We may never have had as many viewers as we have had this past year.
The information around the stock exchange ... many tell me:
"It's great what you do for the stock exchange goes so well."
But even when worried, there is a great need for information-
-From different perspectives and to have it described.
This speaks to that in troubled times when there is uncertainty-
-The you are looking for reliable sources.
You see that people have done. The 4th, 5th and 6th are from a tough stock market period.
The 2nd, 3rd and 1st are from when it has recovered a bit.
But all six episodes are from turbulent times.
Rapid decline or rapid rise.
People get curious when something happens quickly.
If it is flat for two years, it is worse for Aktiesteve.
Then it's a bit boring. What to talk about?
But at a rapid decline or rise, people want to know how it is.
Then there is extra value in talking about how to act-
-and what to think about.
When it looks like the curve with very steep fall-
-And everyone suddenly wants to sell, a few want to buy, but most people want to step out.
Or when the market has rushed and many want to buy in-
-In themes on the market that have already gone very strong.
2021 when there were IT funds, theme funds and theme-ETFs.
Often you come in quite late when it looks that way.
Here is a great value in being educational and talking about long-term view-
-And how to stick to your strategy in these turbulent times.
Now unfortunately none of these top 6 sections are with you-
-But if we had added one, you would have been.
-What episode was it? -It was probably what you remembered.
I'm not sure. Here we see the most viewed throughout history.
It started to approach 100,000 viewers at the last season finale.
These programs are from the last two years.
We really got a push. A red thread seems to be strategies-
-Dividends and well -known financial profiles such as ...
-Putin? -Recis ... Hagströmer and Gardell.
-Marcus Hernhag is extremely popular. -I can imagine.
He goes straight into the target group looking at this type of broadcast.
Many equity enthusiasts who can withstand a little more profound information.
Dividend strategies and direct returns think people are super exciting.
It has been during this period when many have talked about fire-
-And that you should build a stock portfolio that you can live on.
I'm not fire. I am for living and having a good time.
No, I'm not Fire, but I'm saving a lot. I've always done that.
I like to work. I love my job. I like to work on.
We have looked back at all the exciting things that have happened.
But we have to take the opportunity to take the temp on the coming year-
-and hear your thoughts. The program will be the most viewed for 2024.
You can hope.
I think 2024 will also be an exciting year.
Now I think we put the period of two years of high and rising inflation-
-And interest rate hikes from the central banks behind us.
It will be a bit like from 2021 to 2022.
Now we turn leaves and get something new to look at.
Then I think we have the interest rate top behind us.
It will be positive. Inflation is clearly on the way down.
We'll see when it is 2 %. But it is clear that it falls steeply.
We'll see when we get that soft landing.
Speaking of that, the focus will be a lot on macro for a while.
Now everyone expects a soft landing.
The more the stock market rises, the more we praise from the upcoming soft landing.
But we will surely get periods when the statistics do not come in-
-So as the market wants. Then it can cause concern.
If there is recession, the fall height will be larger-
-When we have praised very positively.
But we believe in a soft landing. Now that inflation comes down quickly-
-Haming the central banks in a position when they can start lowering interest rates.
We have low unemployment, people still have money to spend-
-and uncertainty decreases. It is positive.
I thought you can be positive for 2024.
If you are to be even more long -term, then, which you should be happy to be when investing ...
This will in some way be a last fellow to the viewers.
If we look ten years ahead, what themes should you keep track of when investing?
There are themes, but to the last program and long -term I want to send with ...
Before looking at themes, ie what will go strongest on the stock exchange-
-Ka man building a long-term portfolio, ie a broad and well-diversified portfolio-
-Where you can put themes on top. Private savers, and even we who sit here-
-Will be happy to look at themes when things have already gone well. There are funds in top charts-
-And news in Fundspress and Media ...
This is when you discover them, when the trend is already at the end.
This can be seen, among other things, on green energy, superpopular a few years late-
-San it has gone pretty badly, and now everyone sells, which is probably the wrong timing.
The green energy conversion and electrification is a theme one should have.
You should not sell now, but rather start saving in it.
And most who have bought it when things had already gone well.
You came in wrong. And the research also shows that just tight funds-
-temafonds and sector funds ...
The return that the investment provides is not at all the same as investors receive.
The majority of investors come in late and are down. So the theme can look great out-
-But for many it will not be. They come in too late.
But if you have such things, you should keep it.
After all, there is a huge need to replace fossil fuels and electrify.
Then we have seen a large AI rally on the stock exchange.
But it is narrow, it is the big US giants that have passed.
But then there is a second wave in this, when other companies that are not directly winners-
-And that does not manufacture the semiconductors in software ...
When you see companies absorb the technology, implement it-
-Do better, safer products, tailor affordable offers ...
And the other wave of AI, I think, but then you should invest a little wider.
It is difficult to find which companies among all these who look at-
-How to use the new technology in energy or AI.
Rather aim a little wider, so you get the companies that succeed.
Thank you for coming here, Maria. - You have something else for us, Christian.
We three program managers are the active at EFN Market right now-
-But over the years a number of other program managers have been in front of the camera.
We will see a clip here with their reflections from the program.
I think we had many viewers because we had so much fun, in front of and behind the camera.
It was so fun! We had cannon atmosphere, good guests ...
Both small issues and small shares were noticed, but also large companies.
It was CEOs and renowned guests. I think that's the mix of all that.
It became part of my new job here at DI, that I could do television here as well.
I learned a lot from the team behind the camera too, super -lovely to work with.
"Basically" I do what I did on EFN with all videos, but in another workplace.
I have learned as much as I have brought with me.
Without EFN, I would not have had this job.
My favorite section was March 9 when the stock exchanges fell under Corona.
On March 9, 2020. That morning the oil collapsed 30 %.
I said the oil has collapsed 30 %-
-But the stock exchange has only collapsed 6-7 % here in the morning. It was pretty stable.
Georg Norberg was there and I asked how to think in such a crisis situation.
He answers calmly and methodically: "Yes, Matilda, even this crisis we will go through."
Favorite guests I have a lot, and I will miss several pieces.
But you know that there are three names that usually show up when guests are to be booked.
Anna Svahn always stands up, is committed and loves raw materials that few can get interesting.
Roger Josefsson, Makroguru, I loved listening to him, I learned lots.
Three were Eric Wall, the cryptocill who knew everything about crypto.
I took a maximum of 75 % of what he said, but that was enough.
Sven Hagströmer, I must say. He talked about many subjects-
-And was very nice and happy. Inspiring.
Thank you for this time. I hope you got some good tips.
I want to thank the viewers for being with you. It is you who have made it possible.
Thanks thanks thanks!
That was all phenomenal program leaders over the years.
How does that feel? I almost got a little tear in my eye.
I have had the privilege of working with everyone, both you and them-
-So I have seen many nice colleagues pass.
-Are you the institution? -Yes, they don't get rid of me.
After the program, they run in a tingle and lift me out of the studio, strapped.
Break you.
It's fun to have seen so many colleagues grow.
Everyone has gotten better at what they do during their time here, and become ...
... very, very good.
Speaking of program leaders, we will look at more statistics.
Which program managers have led the most programs? This is what it looks like at the bottom.
What kind of guesses do you have about who is in third place?
I guess at ARA. He has done many programs, but ended up ...
-He should miss the top two. -Gabbe or albin on one and two.
Gabriel quit before we started with EFN market.
-You are you one. - And you second. -We are checking.
-No, you're third, Christian. -I think Christian is second and ache third.
I'm one. That's my guess.
-There you see. Pallet site anyway. -Really.
You have made many good programs.
-And ARA ... -85!
-You are an institution! -I have done over a hundred pieces ...
One, two, three, a nice figure. A fanfare on it, huh?
-Ases, what many programs. -You've done more than ...
If anyone has come and has not gone, it is you.
-As I said, they get to go away. -How does it feel?
I didn't think there were so many. Maybe over a hundred.
-Lite less than half. -It feels good to have been able to.
-You have carried this channel. -Or vice versa.
-Will it feel empty now? -Yes, and above all that everything disappears.
I am very proud of the archive we leave behind.
A fun thing with the EFN market has been our thinking-
-That the sections should be able to live a little longer than just until tomorrow.
Much of what we have done is relevant today, tomorrow and in three years.
Therefore, it is a pity that it disappears. There is a lot of wisdom in the archive-
-As you can benefit from in the future.
-You can find it in the Royal Library. -Yes, you are geeky enough, so.
The one waiting for something good.
-Yes, it felt a little ... what do you say? -What.
-But ... -worthy too.
And everything has an end. Even Rome fell. Remember that.
It was a good final word.
That was actually what we had to offer in our last EFN market.
I hope you will miss us, because we will miss you, really.
That's what has made fun of driving.
Number two: Fun guests and colleagues. Number one: Funny viewers.
Big thanks from us all for continuing to look, comment, like and follow.
-Thanks. -Good Christmas, and hello!