Who is the Fed Manager Jay Powell?
Once he has fought inflation-
-The he often mentioned old Fed chief Paul Volcker as a role model.
Volcker stomped out inflation in the 80s-
-And did not withdraw to create multiple recessions.
But yesterday Powell took rather on-
-Tom clothing.
The market had tense arc-
-Prissed many interest rates in 2024 and Fed confirmed everything.
Inflation is on its way down.
There is no reason to keep the interest rate for high-
-When inflation falls, interest rate cuts are coming.
And the market rushed.
Exchange up, interest rates down, everything is ready for Christmas.
I guess Jay Powell didn't get up in the middle of the night-
-To see Swedish inflation figures this morning.
But had he seen them-
-They he probably nodded satisfied.
For Swedish inflation thundered down in November-
—care than we and the market counted with-
-And perhaps most important, lower than the Riksbank expected.
The market is concluding
-That interest rate cuts come not only in the United States and Europe, but to a large extent also-
-During 2024 in Sweden.
At least 150 points, 1.5 percentage points are now pricat-
-In Swedish interest rate curve in the form of interest rate cuts in 2024.