The most important thing I've learned is not to listen to no-sayers.
The more no you get, the more triggered man-
-To prove that you can really deliver.
So I feel.
-It has been successful so far.
-Yes, quite.
Therese Nyrén had a good and safe job at Bank-
-When she chose to resign and start her own.
Since 2021 she runs Lucy Global Fund-
-A fund that invests in luxury and lifestyle brands-
-Som Hermès, Moncler, Fenix Outdoor and Ferrari.
How did you dare?
I had a pretty good, well-paid job in asset management and advisory-
-And started looking at a portfolio that I thought was exciting.
I met many entrepreneurs and then I thought, "If they can, then I can."
At first I thought about advising it, but then there was a woman who told me:
"Shouldn't you start funds, then?"
Then I thought, "Yes, I will."
And so I did.
-Did you encounter any resistance?
-Jajamän.
I have done that right from the start.
Many have said, "Should you really start a foundation? It's so hard."
But I feel that the more they say it is not possible, the more triggered I have become.
So I've just been driving.
-Is it hard?
-Yes, but pretty ...
Then it is important to have the right people around themselves.
I have been working for a long time in the industry so it's great fun-
-To get to manage a fund that you are interested in.
I love this.
It's really fun.
The idea of a lifestyle fund is according to Therese Nyrén-
-Th the one who bets money in well-known and strong brands that one thinks-
-So feel greater security and enthusiasm for their investment.
After a tough first year the fund has the past year had-
-A eight percentage points greater increase than the Dow Jones World Index.
I think this went well.
We are up about 20 % this year.
We have managed relatively well.
Would you have done something different if you had to change anything?
No.
Maybe I would have started a little earlier.
On the other hand I have long experience now-
-So I think it feels great that we started when we did.