He came as a refugee from Iraq to Sweden as a 13-year-old. Today he is 30 years old and a millionaire.
Mohammed Salih is a savings economist, stock market inspector and Instagram profile.
He is a podder, writer and dad-
-And today he is here to talk about his journey towards the million.
-Welcome here, Mohammed. -Thanks.
So fun to have you here. We will hear about your trip to the million today.
-Do you have always been interested in savings? -Yes, I've been.
I can remember back to when I came to Sweden.
Already then I started to take an interest in savings and the entrepreneurial.
Now it is prescribed, but before New Year-
—I used to ask my dad to buy out a bunch of big rocket-
-And then I sold them pieces.
In this way I made money and I know my family always needed more money-
-So I tried to contribute as much as possible.
You and your family fled from Iraq to Sweden. Can you tell us a little about it?
Yes, and it wasn't that we took the flight from Iraq and landed in Sweden.
Without it was a long escape route, we were on the run for several years-
-And did a lot of middle stops before we landed in Sweden.
We are incredibly grateful for that.
So a long escape route that resulted in the new home Sweden.
-You grew up in Ronneby. -Yes, first Rosengård and then Ronneby.
Or Kallinge that is the metropolis for me. It's just there that I feel at home.
That you have this escape in the luggage, how has it affected your view of money and finances?
This is probably what has made me so interested and constantly want money.
It creates such security.
During the escape trip we did not even have money for food and clothes.
Then Mom got to beg clothes and food.
Although I will never end up in that situation in Sweden-
-So money is a damn security for me and the dependence on money comes from it.
What does it mean for you to be in Sweden?
It is difficult to explain with words. My love for Sweden is really boundless.
There is nothing that I am so grateful for-
-As Sweden opened its arms to our family.
For after 13 years on escape-
-or 13 years of uncertainty before getting this residence permit-
-It can't describe how nice it felt.
-When did you discover the stock exchange? -When I was around 22-23, quite a few years ago.
It was through a friend actually.
We were going to MMA training. I drove a car, he sat next to it.
I'm pretty social so I like to talk.
He was not as social at all so I asked what he was doing.
Then he bought and sold shares on his mobile and earned a lot of money-
-On this short part we drove.
Then I felt that I had to learn about shares if it is possible to make money via mobile.
Before you put your savings goal to become a millionaire, what did your life look like then?
Can you get a snapshot from Mohammed Back in the Day?
Then I had bought my first apartment.
I had no savings goals, and without savings goals it is quite difficult to save money.
Because then you feel that you have nothing to save for.
An economic yet spent Mohammed who did not care very much about economics.
I had no budget at that time, but I took life as it came.
It was probably more before.
How did it go when you decided on the million?
Money is very taboo in Sweden.
No one talks about it, you must never ask what anyone earns, hardly what anyone has in interest.
I wanted to try to change that, document everything I do-
-and become a millionaire before I'm thirty.
How did it go at the beginning of your investment trip?
It went okay, actually.