The Riksbank has, like many central banks, purchased bonds.
From 2015 they did it-
-To get inflation up.
During the pandemic to strengthen financial markets-
-and provide support for the economy.
The price of bonds moves in the opposite direction to the interest rate.
The interest rate has risen sharply, the value of the Riksbank's bond portfolio-
-Have have fallen sharply, so much that it has erased the Riksbank's equity.
According to the new Riksbank Act, the Riksbank must have a positive equity-
-When with high probability, the Riksbank must request large sums from parliament-
-A after the end of 2023. At present, the Riksbank considers that this is concerned-
-Shely SEK 80 billion, close to 10 % of Swedish government debt.
How much is needed in the end we do not know until February 2024-
-When the Riksbank comes with the financial statements for 2023. Then you present to the Riksdag-
-How large supplement you need to strengthen equity.