-Today we will talk about income. -Yes.
-You really like income. -You too.
-You are crazy in income. -No, you are.
I have to keep track of my finances now.
Mia Ingelström is not only an economist, she is also a personal trainer in economics.
Yes, you hear. Should we start this?
Hello. Here Mia and me and "Chitchattar" are about economics.
-Nice. -Yes is not it?
-Today we will talk about income. -Yes.
-You really like income. -You too.
-You are crazy in income. -No, you are.
I like expenses.
-Do you know which ones earn the least? -Women.
That's right. According to Statistics Sweden, the average salary for women is 35,100.
And for men: 39,000. Boring.
-Very. -A structural societal problems in part.
We should not talk about that here. We teach both men and women to maximize their income-
-So that you can have a safer life and earn some penny here and there.
That's right, but things can be done yourself to reduce the gap ...
-Jeimability? -Yes. When you want to create a family ...
... you should also talk about how you want it within the family.
You discuss parental allowance, try to share equally on parental leave ...
Vab and those parts ... how much you are away from the labor market often determine-
-How much lower salary you receive. And it remains to the pension.
A little tip. What should we talk about more?
About negotiating and also about investing.
The red thread is to try to do more of what you already have.
-And make better use of it. -My large income is of course the salary.
What can you do about it? Is it as it is?
Both. You should start talking about the salary. Taboo in Sweden. We hardly do it ...
-. even with our partner. -Who should I talk to?
With friends, colleagues and test ... Is your salary good?
With my colleagues I should not talk. It creates a boring atmosphere at work.
-Is it not so anyway? -No.
Many people wonder about colleagues' salary. That's a problem.
Sure you can choose to talk to some-
-But you have to get a feeling for the possibility of improvement.
And who benefits from not talking about the salary?
-The employer. -Yes, and you're probably losing it.
In order for you to receive incentives to negotiate wage-
-with the employer and see if you can get other benefits ...
... you have to start somewhere. And then you need to know how you are.
"How to negotiate your salary." Many such tips are available.
I never succeed. The manager says how much I get according to the collective agreement.
And then it is. I say: Yes, but he earns Si and she so ...
"Yes, but this is what is there."
Do you know that there is nothing more to negotiate, it is good.
Then you can choose. "Is it good enough or should I go somewhere else?"
The choice is yours. If you choose to remain, you have chosen it.
You choose to be satisfied with what you have.
I tried to change it, it couldn't, but I choose to stay.
Just that, you have to do it. Not be bitter.
-Just. -Lite bitter coffee, maybe?
No, but good coffee.
It was the salary and some ways to raise it.
But you also have some money that lies and lurks at home.
-Som just lies there ... -Absolutely.
How much do you have in the wind?
Around 15,000 or more we have on average in the wind or in the basement-
-What could be realized. Not bad.
In the short term, but I want to talk about something else ... in the long term.
To invest and make money from it.