Time to look ahead. We go through ideas for 2024 and talk autoliv-
-Together with one of EFN's most popular guests.
With me in the studio I have no less than Anders "roll" Rudolfsson. - Welcome.
You are one of those who have been here most-
-And also very early in stock exchange's history.
How will you remember EFN that is now suffering to its end?
I am grateful that I have been able to participate in so many sections.
It has been incredibly professional.
All program managers have been good, read and it has always been just as nice.
A memory that has etched itself firm-
-We one summer when we drove different themes.
I was there when we drove the 80s.
We had to borrow clothes and ran a section on what it looked like in the summer of 1987-
-fore the crash. It remains for a long time. Great fun.
The clip is probably left in some archive. We'll see if we can dig it.
-Yes, it's worth seeing. -Yes indeed.
When they were recorded was about when I started here.
So I ran straight into a recording so I would talk to Charlotte.
It was probably the recording from the tulip crash. Where did I end up, I wondered.
-Ny at work ... -Very funny episodes.
We will look a little at 2023, but mainly look into 2024.
You who are so close to the market, how has 2023 been?
Very challenging. One knew that some interest rate hikes would come-
-It was obvious. It started, but still-
-Where the first weeks in January pretty well. The courses were up.
Then came the first interest rate hikes. And then they came in kind.
At each Fed and Riksbank meeting came increases. It surprised the market-
-It went so fast. Then we got a banking crisis suddenly.
Also in the spring when a number of regional banks in the United States went down.
The interest rate had run away and they had not been able to handle the deposit rate.
Suddenly there was no capital left. One must write down their long bonds-
-And then no equity remained. To recover from it took a moment-
-And Fed handled it pretty quickly. Then AI suddenly appeared like a big thing.
At least I was very surprised that it got so big so fast.
From having spoken a little about it, to it being commercialized so fast-
-To so many and suddenly the biggest "innovation" then became the mobile phone-
-or Microsoft was invented.
And then another hefty set came in October-
-and another war. I sum it all up with: Very challenging.
And what you also bring is that the "performance" and rise we had-
-As come from large companies. In the majority of all companies, not only in the US and Sweden-
-Outan throughout the world, the small companies do not have performed at all.
Rather, it has been minus in most places.
It leads into something you might test in 2024: Small companies.
Our picture shows that they are very pressed-
-and that they followed the interest rate pretty well.
Yes. The left image shows the real interest rate in the United States, "10-Year Tips Rate".
It is inverted.
At the top is minus 1.5, ie minus 1.5 % tip interest.
At the bottom right of the table it was recently down to plus 2.5 %.
Obviously, "Small Cap" is very sensitive to how the real interest rate develops.
So the correlation is very strong.
Now we have seen the interest rate peak.
We can assume that. And one is already starting to praise a number of reductions-
-In the US and Europe in 2024.
And that's why we see the meter hook at the bottom.
The question is whether it should be up further or not. If we shift focus to the right image-
-Is it how the valuation has been over time in Small Cap and Big Cap.
This applies to Nordic shares. As we see, the P/e number does not differ much over time-
-Between large and small companies, forward-looking p/e ratios.
But the big companies have gone through this year without affecting the P/E century-
-But the little ones have seen a huge setting.
And we think the real interest rate will not come down anymore, but rather will back-
-And gets a little lower, the P/E figure should also be able to be picked up.
Then we see that there could be some p/e number's higher valuation on Small Cap.
Interesting. Small Cap was almost down to the Coronabotten in valuation.
Yes, the corrections were very strong.
Given what we have seen with so many quick interest rate hikes-
-Features many companies may be challenges for their business models. Many people need new money.
If you look into 2024, I think Small Cap will be very good.
It doesn't have to mean that all companies are going well, you have to be a little "picky".
"Stockpicker's Year" again next year. I think so.
But there are reasons to continue to be careful about which shares you pick in.
Could it be liquidity and flow driven?
Gets the funds outflows ... it feels more in small companies-
-When a fund steps out of 50 million-
-An when it happens in H&M, there is just a little ripple.
A strong point, it is absolutely so.
The outflows have been substantial from many small cap funds.
The further down the list you get in the "Market Cap", the lower the liquidity.
And then you also get large rashes on the courses.
And there is still a risk of buying shares in which there is not so much liquidity.
An advantage as a small private saver-
-That you can get into illicated shares in a different way.
-Yes, but you should also do the homework. -Yes, liquidity can die if you want to sell.
-Then the door is closed. -Yes.
We move on to individual shares. You have a list of the company-
-which expected to have good profit growth at ebit level 2024-
-and is a good distance from their "highs".
They are sorted by how far from their highs they are.
Just. You can find a lot of companies that are far from their previous highest levels-
-But the idea was to also show which ones could have a substantial profit growth in 2024.
Here are all kinds of companies. From cyclically to the right stable.
Companies within Medtech, building -related, many different types of companies.
Finding relevance between if you believe that EBIT growth will come in 2024-
-And the P/E figure is reasonable, it is important. You should also look at historical p/e ratios.
But the difference is very large, from Sectra who is traded continued-
-To 67 times p/e next year, down to Netel, which is traded to 3-4 times.
Here is the question what kind of risk you want to take, to believe in the estimates that exists ...
See it as a list where you can get ideas.
You can have different views. I myself have some strong perceptions.
We do not have surveillance on all corporate
-But quite stable business models are in all companies in principle.
One or two bad quarters can be enough to go down so much.
Starting to look from this list-
-And sets up an index of all those companies, you should be able to get a good performance 2024.
Loomis you have talked about here before. See-digit p/e ratio for 2024.
Securitas is whispered that Christer Gardell may have bought. We'll see.
A reputation in town. Interesting.
Many stable companies are here that should reasonably be able to ha-
-Both 2024 and 2025 as a good year. Then the question-
-How serious a possible recession will be in 2024.
Here, the same company is ranked according to how they have performed this year.
At the far right we see "Total Return", including dividends.
If you want to give any advice, it may be interesting to start with those who have gone the worst this year.
Start by watching if they will be able to deliver something in line with the ebit growth-
-Or which the market is priceing to today? And what is the potential from today's level?
There are also different types of companies here.
Everything with construction has been right plague-related-
-But building facts is an international company, for example.
Netel has been exposed in different ways.
The Q1 report was quite turbulent and led to the CEO having to go.
It has left its mark in that course.
Then we have Coor that I also talked about before. They have a stable business.
Similarly there: The market did not like the Q3 report at all.
They start a cost program. We'll see how fast they can come back.
But as I said, here it is up to everyone to try to find ...
You can have a preference for certain types of companies.
Fun. Here they have a candy bag to look in for next year.
-A Christmas gift. -Yes, that's fine. It came with the plot.
We go ahead and cave in a specific company: Autoliv.
Yes, it's a little bigger. One of the companies we think seems interesting for next year.
In 2022 and as many as 2023 ABB has been a major net buyer of own stock-
-So called repurchases, "buybacks".
They continue with it, but not at the same level as before.
The company that now takes over the baton as a large repurchaser of its own stocks-
-As autoliv. We will soon get a graph on it.
It was for a three-year period during pandemin-
-When no cars were delivered at all.
There is a pent -up need for new cars.
Although there would be some good years-
-To you barely return to the historical trend.
Underlying is an organic growth for autoliv to take care of.
They have a very large market share.
Over 50 % on airbags in the world.
All new car models coming out-
-As you with and deliver on. At least every other car.
There is proper underlying growth.
This in combination with starting a repurchase program.
It is $ 1.5 billion to be repurchased-
-Forf for next year.
Here we talk about 10-12 % of the company being repurchased.
How often do you see that so much should be repurchased in a short time?
It is very rare, I would say.
One can have a repurchase program of 10 % of the stock market
-But it is often difficult to get hold of.
In this case, it is combined with killing the share.
It will be a very big kick.
Because you remove 15 %...
I don't remember all percentages. They have come a long way.
As you remove these shares, EPS also increases: en-
-"Earnings per share", with the same number of shares as you remove.
We get profit growth that will be 10-15 % better from the repurchase.
The next table shows what the valuation looks like.
We have proper growth both on ebit-
-And profit per share that is over 30 %.
If you look a little further down at P/E you end up under 10 times.
If you look at history, it has been almost double in valuation.
There is a buyer in the share throughout 2024.
It is not noticeable when you start with the repurchases.
As you saw in the table, it has been quite a bit for so far.
The big lift will come next year.
Finally, there is a graph on the share.
It is very close to all time high.
It is only a matter of time before breaking through their old levels.
When you put new highs you see new highs again.
This is a share that you can buy and own in the next year-
-And both receive dividends and a good price reaction.
A terribly strong trend since the bottom 2022.
It has really followed this channel.
If you pull a line from the bottom 2022 and all the way up-
-To there is a trend channel that is interesting to look at.
It is really clear.
In the latest report, I saw that they were good at getting through price increases.
I think too ... Here's the fact that the market is a bit worried-
-That you will not get your margin.
They have guided that they will raise the margin a bit next year.
It will be a question at each quarterly report next year.
If you get through this and fall through the bottom ...
We shall see. It is up to the company to deliver.
I and we think they succeed.
Having such a large part of the market is usually a sign on-
-That the market is unable to do without the product.
Then it should be possible to get the margin a bit.
One can hope. But the automotive industry is stent.
Those who deliver to the car industry do not have margins at all ...
Autoliv is now a 10-12 percent margin.
If we look at Atlas Copco, Sandvik or Alfa Laval, it is double.
Being a subcontractor to the automotive industry is very challenging.
You should have respect for that. But airbags must have everyone.
Maybe you spend a little more money on it.
Mutter as a nut, but airbag you want to ...
That said, it is ... it will be exciting to see.
This is the first time you anyway ...
Given the underlying growth found on new models-
-As is on the way, this feels very good.
Very fun. Thank you for that case and for coming here.
-Thank you for this time. -It's been very nice.
Thanks to you who have looked.
It was all in today's section.
We have some sections left, so hang with us all the way into the tile.
Take care. Bye!