You must have 15 % of the value of the home as a cash contribution.
This means that you can borrow 85 % of the value of the home.
The higher the cash contribution you have, the better you get.
For example, lower interest rates and amortization.
This is how it is.
Generally, you can borrow 5 to 6 times your gross income.
Your annual gross income.
But the banks look at both your credit rating and your ability to pay-
-When they will decide how large a loan you can get.
To find out your credit rating, the banks take a credit report.
You usually call it a UC.
There they look at your income, if you have other debts-
-And if you have any payment notes at Kronofogden.
You can have a co -borrower for your mortgage if possible.
If you have other loans and credits you can collect them for a loan.
Then you often get a better credit rating.
If you can, avoid getting many credit information taken on you.
It can adversely affect your credit rating.