Sweden, we are in recession.
Yes, what do we mean by recession?
In this case we use the US definition: two on each other the following quarter-
-With negative GDP growth. So the outcome was after Q2 and yesterday we got figures for Q3.
But how dramatic is this? It is expected and the economy is quite divided.
The construction sector, especially housing construction falls strong-
-houses hold harder in the wallet, but the export sector goes well-
-And investment in business otherwise tough.
The economy is cooled. Is the Riksbank's job thus over? It's not certain.
Inflation indicators still point in the wrong direction.
Companies' price height plans have arrived. In spite of the recession-
-Plan companies to continue to raise prices more than have been historically done.
The inflation struggle is not over yet.
The inflation threat is not over, I say, but the market believes.
We see broad, large interest rates in the USA, Europe and Sweden. It also applies to expectations-
-At Central Banks' interest rate changes in the future. Now it is expected by the market-
-That Fed and ECB will lower before the summer and the Riksbank this summer.
What makes the decision becomes inflation development.
Should we look at the companies' price plans or do a cooled economy make the decision?