Fiction or facts? Yes, the interest rate market's pricing of what the central bank is to do-
-none year is, according to ECB, science fiction.
For now, the European interest rate market expects a good bit more-
-An 1 percentage point interest rate reductions in 2024 starting already in the spring.
And even for the Riksbank, the market has tightened the arch considerably. A good bit below 3 % policy rate-
-In the end of 2024 is priced in the interest rate market.
We get more facts already tomorrow, Friday. Then comes the US employment data-
-For November. It is likely to show an upturn in employment-
-As a result of American car workers being back at work after the strike.
The underlying trend should be weaker. We see signs from vacant places-
-But also ADP figures a week, which shows that the labor market is cooled off.
The question is at what rate.
More facts next week: inflation figures, also for November-
-And them gets the Fed with them to the meeting where you have to put your foot down.
What happens to the interest rate now, unchanged everyone believes, but how to signal before 2024?
The market has tensioned the bow, pricing lots of interest rate cuts-
-and Fed must fight against.