Are you looking for stability in troubled times?
Then the key figure "solvency" can be something for you.
Solidity measures how much of a company is financed with equity.
Why is it interesting? The part that does not consist of equity consists of debts.
In other words, the higher the equity ratio, the more stable company.
How do you calculate solidity? Yes, like this ...
Take the company's adjusted equity and share with the company's total capital.
Multiply by 100 and you have your percentage.
If you are wondering what “adjusted equity” is-
-To it is usually the sum of the company's reported equity-
-PLUS 79.4 % of untaxed reserves.
What is a good solvency? Here you see Statistics Sweden's median values.
Among other things, you see that education, healthcare and other services are at the top.
While hotels, bar and restaurant are in the bottom-
-Together with real estate companies and property management.
Hope it was helpful. Feel free to share the clip with a friend.