What does the investment climate look like for unlisted companies?
And how do it go-
-Klar CEO Sebastian Siemiatkowski's investment company Flat Capital-
-which, among other things, invested in Open AI where it has been messy lately.
We will talk about that in today's EFN market. Welcome.
-Welcome Hanna Wachtmeister. -Thanks. Fun to be here.
Fun to have you here. You are CEO of the investment company Flat Capital.
Today we will talk about trends and the investment climate for mainly unlisted companies.
But also about flat capital, of course. We start there.
What is Flat Capital for companies?
Flat Capital is listed since 2021. A small investment company-
-What is checked and owned mainly by Sebastian and Nina Siemiatkowski.
-It started ... -klar -founder and CEO.
Good. You get stuck in who they are ...
Nina and Sebastian with their entrepreneurial travel were given the opportunity to invest-
-In other entrepreneurs around 2013, when Flat Capital saw their first light.
They began to invest in, among other things, budbee, or today Instabe, and Truecaller.
Can you tell us a little more about your strategy and why are you focusing on unlisted companies?
Our strategy has its basis very much in mainly Sebastian's experiences-
-When I was in. Brief
-They we believe that an interesting return profile is-
-In the opportunity to be long -term. Being a long -term investor in companies.
Because it takes time to build companies. Not four years.
Klarna ... Sebastian has been holding on for 18 years. And will last for another 18 years.
Building good companies takes time.
And do you have a fund structure that is common in the unlisted world-
-If the funds often have a lifetime, they are built up.
And there is a possible conflict in how you build companies and maximize value-
-Man between if you are a "venture capital"-investor-
-or if you can be with the whole trip.
We try to be long -term. We do not take a lot of charges-