The US economy is tough, but not so much that the Fed must slow down further.
Fed left as expected interest rate unchanged.
And there is no new course switching from Fed when listening to Powell & Company.
The next temperature meter for the US economy will be the country's employment data on Friday.
American "PayRolls" that in September grew significantly faster than expected-
-All await figures showing a slightly clearer cooling off the US economy.
And it is needed, still wage growth is for high-
-To be compatible with the inflation target of 2 %.
And we probably also need a rising unemployment over time.
It is not expected from Friday's figures.
We'll see what's coming.
We do not expect more interest rate hikes from Fed, ECB, Bank of England or Norway's bank.
But we still expect the Riksbank to raise 25 points in connection with the November meeting-
-To because of too high inflation and too weak crown.