Our vision is to be able to buy a plot-
-Sodate a house by a house designer, and press "Buy".
Then a self -driving printer prints the house and fixes everything.
Then you can move in within 30 days.
I think it was Gudrun who flew past and my roof was about to roll off.
I lay and glued the roofing cardboards with hot air gun.
I felt it was terribly hard to build.
Everything takes a long time. There must be a more effective way to do it.
In order for the Western world not to be over -exploited, we must develop a technology.
It is about creating a construction method that minimizes the amount of material-
-and at the same time build enough accommodation-
-For the large mass of the earth's population.
The view of this technology from the large construction companies-
-Is that they are very interested. Many have been here and looked.
But the technology is not really mature yet.
The entire industry needs to change.
I think we need to help create new opportunities.
We would need help from companies to participate and drive the development.
The next goal for us as a company is to build a real villa.
We want to buy a plot, print a house, furnish it-
-And sell it to someone who wants to buy it. Make all the way.
You test the whole process.