Great to have a lot of money, right?
Tog to be able to feel safe and free. I have no control.
How good do you have money and finances? Between one and ten.
Ten.
I have to keep track of my finances now.
Mia Ingelström is not only an economist, she is also a personal trainer in economics.
Yes, you hear. Should we start this?
Hi, my name is Jonas. Time for passport two in our Economic School.
I'm a little split for money.
Great to have a lot of money, right?
Tog to be able to feel safe and free.
But I'm still uninterested. I think it's complicated.
I have no control. How good are you, Mia?
-Between one and ten. On money and finances. -Time on the scale.
-You know what? -It's max. Only Ingves has it.
I don't know everything, but have control over what I need to be able to.
-Eight. -There I have ten on the scale.
Eight, what fun. I have zero.
-What should we learn today? -The most important.
To dream. Where do I want to come? What do I want to reach?
We're running. I'm not completely uninterested in money ...
... but I don't have to care that much, because it works out.
And it has, actually. It always does.
-In some way, it works out. -Yes, usually it works out.
But we tend to forget what has been difficult.
When you were young and didn't know where to live ...
When you didn't have money to pay the bills ...
Those who are going to retire often feel stress and anxiety:
-"Will it even work?" -You have suppressed the boring.
Unfortunately, many feel anxiety, stress and anxiety ... Sometimes it is unnecessary.
-An can not be millionaires? -It's not about it.
Money can simplify, but they do not create happiness.
Happiness comes when you use the money-
-and can live your life as you want it.
That you have the opportunity. And for that, money plays a pretty big role.
Not how much you earn ...
No matter how much or little you earn, you can be happy.
That the money helps you do what you want in life.
-How do you know, then? -You have to set aside time ...
... to find out. As for everything else, you have to focus and think.
-A dream exercise. -Just.
Okay, now let's see ... a dream exercise, see now ...
I want a sailboat, I've always dreamed of that.
And I want to travel more. I want to go to Capri, Japan, Finland ...
No, Capri. And I want a bigger apartment.
I'm so tired of working from home. A new apartment. Yuk...
I want to divorce too, it feels like. I'm so tired of Micke. A new man. Yes.
Will you sometime? What are you doing?
Nothing, honey.
-Yeah, it got a little drastic. -Absolutely.
-Is it good, do you think? -Yes, great.
To take the time to think through what you want in life.
Getting from one situation to another is a little difficult.
You have to break down the dream and see what it takes to reach the different goals.
Small steps. The same thing if you are going to leave a relationship ...
Nor is anything done like this ...
But you take yourself seriously and investigate if it is possible.
-If you are completely satisfied, then? -Fantastic. Congratulations.
My dreams are met.
If your feelings and your life in sync, it is fantastic.
-Well then. -You don't have to look for problems.
-And also see this program series. -But then you can show others.
-How did you do so you would get it like that? -Lecture?
Sure, why not? So you can spread the knowledge or feeling to other generations.
Quite a few are not happy with their lives, unfortunately.
A viewer question.
"I work at an insurance company, but want to become a gardener."
How nice. You understand that.
"But we can't afford that." Or how can you get there?
Oh ... This person must not write off his dream right away.
You have to break down the bigger dream into smaller parts.
What is needed for me to become a gardener? Do I have to school about me?
How long will it take? What salary do I get in the new job?
You divide the dream into smaller parts. First you look at costs today.
Can I lower my living expenses? Maybe i have to opt out of something i have-
-To be able to choose for the dream instead. Usually it goes if you turn on all stones.
But I also think this person should test.
Maybe she doesn't want to work as a gardener. You can do internships.
What have we learned today? Tell me if I say wrong.
Do the dream exercise. Take time to it.
And when you do it, don't be afraid to dream big.
-"Take yourself seriously," you said. -Giant weighing.
And no matter what you earn, you can ...
You can become a gardener or whatever you want to be ...
-Formula 1 driver. Right? -Absolutely.
Just take some time and break it down ... - Thanks for today. Have a good time.
-Mia. What did you dream about? -I dreamed of becoming a tour guide.
-Not me. -But do you know? I have tried.