If you keep track of your finances, you get more money. A "quick fix".
I have to keep track of my finances now.
Mia Ingelström is not only an economist, she is also a personal trainer in economics.
Yes, you hear. Should we start this?
Welcome to this series that will make you financially stronger-
-The gear and maybe freer.
If you keep track of your finances, you get more money. A "quick fix".
-Does it agree, Mia? -Absolutely. You can't afford not to keep track.
You need to do the things you want in life.
Here is Mia. How can you so much, so you can make such statements?
I love finances. I'm economic p. Personal trainer in finance.
What should we learn today?
Where you have to start to take control of your finances.
-And where is it? -You have to keep track of where you are today. The current situation.
Then we run. We can skip this section. I already know what I earn.
I know how much dog food costs ... and lunch.
-To the ear? -A crown here or there ...
-How exactly should it be? -The exactly. The risk exists ...
... that we forget things we have paid. Do you keep track of all streaming services ...
... you subscribe to? Do you keep track of all the dinners you have paid?
-All presents you bought? -No, stop ... I don't have it.
-No, exactly. -How do you do then?
You take the help of an app. Either the bank or any other economy app.
They help us get all the expenses of the year, but also the income.
An indescribable help for this job. Because you have to go back a year in time.
For the months, differ. Sometimes comes an annual invoice, another time it's Christmas ...
... or birthdays. You need to get the rub in one year and then share with twelve-
-To get one average per month. Then you can use it-
-To see if what comes in is enough for what goes out, on average per month.
—Tocking, right? -Here you just do it once?
Yes, we will find out the current situation.
And it then sets the bar for what we want to do in the future.
-Then we'll do it. Easy, now we take a cup. -We'll do that.
Mia, like this can be a little difficult.
To cave in old bad choices. Rice loans and a payroll negotiation you just satisfied with ...
-It's not so fun. -You aren't the only one ...
The most important thing is not to evaluate.
When we find out the current situation you should just check out the fact-
-Not value what you've done. You can choose to do differently in the future.
-So do not value. — Like a robot running down the numbers ...
Turn off the emotions. Look up facts.
Hello. Viewing question. Funny.
"Hello 'got in shape financially'. I have iron check on my money"-
-"But not on my partner and we have a common economy."
-How do you do then? -You need access to information ...
... about what the household has done with.
But you don't have to do the job together. But if you do, it is fantastic.
Sit down jointly if you can and do the job.
Otherwise, you need to access information about what the other has paid.
Hope the viewer was satisfied with the answer. What have I learned today?
What have we learned? Do not evaluate. Keep the facts and emotions apart.
Use app. Smooth. Think of the entire household, not just your part.
-Just right. Good. -Well then. Then we have learned it.
Thanks for today.
-A financial tip for you. -Exciting.
Do not use soap. After all, there will be a few bucks.
I thought I knew something ...