Saving should be about. Some have 0 when the month is over.
I have to keep track of my finances - now.
Mia Ingelström is not only an economist, she is also a personal trainer in economics.
You hear. Should we start?
-Yeah, Mia, look here… -What nicely.
Don't think about this. It is nothing.
Hello and welcome to the section "Let the money work for you".
Is it about leaning back, the money is working and you are becoming richer?
That's how it is. Once you have put your strategy and started doing after this, it feels that way.
Excellent. We will talk about how to make a strategy for their savings.
We will talk about fund fees and something called Fondrobot.
Have you heard of it? I don't have that.
Saving should be about. Not everyone can save.
When the month is over, it's 0.
I claim that most of us can save.
But on the basis of one's own conditions.
Not everyone can save several thousand, but a few hundred most people can put away.
We have previously learned to increase income and reduce expenditure.
-There is quite a lot to work with. -It doesn't have to be that much.
Now we will start saving. You cannot do that in a payroll account.
There it is SEK 0. Then you have to enter the stock exchange and so there.
It depends on when to use what you save.
When you are going to use the money ... we look at these buckets a bit.
-No, what's this ...? -The certainly are they good? Fun buckets.
Krishink - buffer. If anything really shits ...
Something happens. You become unemployed or ill. You have to pay the bills.
-Then you don't want to take an SMS loan. -Hund gets sick ...
You also do not want to sell fund shares that may have gone down a lot.
This money should be in a savings account.
-No stock exchange for that money. -Okay.
The one -year bucket is what to do extra for a year.
You have decided to go on vacation and really want it to happen.
Then you need money in that bucket. They should also be in savings account.
You want it to get rid of and want that money to be there.
In the five -year bucket you can start to take some risk for the money.
The higher the risk you take, the greater the opportunity for higher returns you have.
Higher risk - higher interest rates.
Five years are quite a short time interval anyway.
It may be an apartment effort, that you should study or have children.
You can't afford to take too high risk. Middle high risk for the money in the five -year bucket.
Then comes the pension and future bucket.
It is probably quite a long way to retire.
Not in your case, then ... but long time for the socket.
This is extra money for retirement. It's not the same as the orange envelope.
You need to save extra for your pension. Most of us need to do that.
In the future bucket there are over. Once you have started filling up the other-
-Can there be money left that you can spend in the longer term.
-I will not be able to fill up everyone. -No. Not from the beginning.
You should always start with this bucket. You should try to fill it up.
Preferably money for three months of expenses. It helps you sleep well.
You should start thinking about the future as well.
A couple of hundreds in this one month is probably enough if you start early-
-To to save good capital.
Then you can start decorating in the different based on your time horizon and what you want to do.
This is a strategy. You will not fill all of them.
But it gives you a clue about how to invest the money.
-This are regular accounts only? -Spark account.
-This I can't ... -Here you can take help from the bank ...
… To find out how to invest the money.
This is money that is going into the stock exchange, but at different risk.
Either you hear from your bank and ask what types of funds you should have-
-Which fits the buckets, or you use a fund robot.
-A Fondrobot is… -The thing we're talking about it we'll sit down.
This seems to be a lot ... I'm retired.
Mia ...
-Fondrobot? -Exciting.
I haven't heard about that until today. Tell us what it is.
It is a shortcut so that you do not have to choose which funds to buy.
It helps you get started. It is a lower threshold to enter the stock exchange.
-Is it a website? -The banks have their own fund robots.
Other institutes also offer fund robots.
You say: "I want to invest this money for such a long time."
Then you get suggestions on what to buy. The fees are clear.
-But ... -it's getting easier. A shortcut.
-Now we are in on fees. -It is important.
Each fund costs money.
If it is actively managed, someone is sitting and buying and selling-
-To it often costs more. If it is passively managed, it follows an index-
-Is it often lower fee. The fee is of great importance for how much money you receive.
It eats a fairly large part of the return.
-What are we talking for percentage? -Allting below 0.5 %...
… Are pretty low fees. When it starts ticking up over-
-Do you know why you want to own that fund.
You can choose it, but you should know why.
"Hello Mia! I'm eager to start saving on the stock exchange. When is the good place to start?"
Now, if you are craving. It is always good to start saving on the stock exchange.
Now is a good location on the stock exchange if you know your strategy
-So what money you can save in the long term.
If you can afford to delay money-
-And know how much you can put in, it is good to insert them per month.
You can save monthly. Then you buy funds both when they are a little more expensive and cheaper.
Why not start saving for your extra pension.
Get started and take a few hundred a month. Start now.
Start stock market already today. If you want.
What a tasty section. I have learned that you have to have a strategy with savings.
Some should have a regular savings account.
The money you should have in a little longer term, have them in funds.
Take the help of a fund robot, I have learned.
If the fees are a little higher, you should know why they are.
-Super good! -I can do this now. Bye!
-I could do well, right? -Super good.
-I'm proud. -I can hold it. You don't have to come.