The news has probably reached us all.
Some of Sweden's most important nodes disappear:
The paddle halls.
That's right. More than half of the country's paddle halls are expected to go bankrupt.
We will see how the Swedish people will survive this.
- Did you know what paddle is? -Yes, I know that.
- One you have when paddling. - No, no, not that paddle.
- Do you play paddle? - under Covid, but I quit.
It was a trend instead of sports.
Which are you worried about to die first, the paddle hall or you?
What do you think they will use for apologies when they have been unfaithful -
- Now when they can't use paddle?
Are you from SVT?
Yes.
Oh!
Did you learn Swedish by playing paddle?
Yes ... or, I knew Swedish before too.
- But it helped, like? - Yes, you can say that.
- Do you play paddle? - No, fuck!
- Is it a shit sport? -Yes.
- Are you glad it dies out? -Yes.
Do you think gang crime is now increasing when so many paddle halls are closed?
But are you worried about all Sweden's middle managers?
Middle managers? Yes, that was another issue.
How does it feel now that you need to spend more time with your family?
–Wa? - For the paddle halls close.
No, people do not seem to care about this extensive change in society.
No, and what it can have for consequences can only be time.
Back to you, Messiah.