Hello, Elza here from Elza's Bookshelf. It's October, which is kind of Halloween horror month and I'm really into horror books.
I thought I'd... On Goodreads, they've listed like 66 of the most beloved horror books in the last three years.
I've been going through that list and thought I'd let you know which books I'm very curious to read.
Because I'm a bit in the mood for horror, I feel. So we'll go through that list, I think, and then you'll hear some of those books.
I have... I saw in that I have kind of... the majority of those books are in my Goodreads list that I want to read.
So we're not going to go through all of them, but maybe top five, top six? Yes, which I really want to read. And of course I want to hear your thoughts on those books.
The first one that comes to mind and has several books on this list is T. Kingfisher. She has books such as A House with Good Bones,
The Twisted Ones, The Hollow Places are just three of the books I know I really want to read by her.
And I know they're supposed to be mild, horror, a lot of atmosphere and the one I think I'll start with, The House of Good Bones I think,
where it's about a mother... Yes, a daughter whose mother says there are ghosts in my house and that's how they find out a lot of things.
Yes, with some mild, atmospheric horror, that's what I like. So here we have a book that I have on my TBR too, that I really want to read for a long time,
and it is The Sundown Motel of St. James, Simone St. James. I have read two other books by her and liked her very much.
And she also has this kind of atmospheric horror, where you kind of take mysterious ghost stories, but you never really know, are they really ghosts or what am I reading,
and this one should be really good. Another author that I'm really curious about and one of whose books I'm about to start, and that's Grady Hendrix.
I just started How to Sell a Haunted House. It's the next book we're going to read in the book club and I'm so excited.
He is the one who wrote Horrorstör. It's this book anyway, which is kind of like the Ikea catalogue, it feels like.
He has several books that I have on my TBR that I really want to read, and as I said, I'm finally starting my first Hendrix, so I'm so excited for that.
Then we have a sci-fi horror, Dead Silence, Barnes something, and look at the cover, I just love it and it's on this list too,
and I am super happy when I saw this. So that one, I don't really know what it's about except that you're out in space simply,
and sci-fi mostly, so I'm bad at reading even though I like it. So, this combination I think is perfect for me.
Hidden pictures, a horror like this that was on this list which is also a book I want to read.
So, I don't really know what it's about other than that it's a child, a boy, it's pictures, not so...
It's supposed to be unpleasant, it's pretty cover and it seems to be very, very good.
Just the cover and the feeling it gives me seems like a book to me. So we'll see.
I have heard very good things about The Only Good Indians by Stephen Graham Jones, and it is also supposed to be such a book that is unpleasant.
Like this, atmospheric horror. Should it be a bit disgusting too, perhaps? I don't know, but I've heard great things about this one.
And it's also a book like this that just climbed up on my TBR that is getting closer and closer that I really want to read and grab it.
I don't know who has read it, but I think I have heard several who have read it and liked it.
So now we have two. In this list, I found two books that have a Latin American feel.
And one of them that I have had for a long time is Mexican Gothic. Look how beautiful it is.
Yes, I very much like the cover. You know how I am. I like covers. Scary covers, nice covers.
And here we have a really, really nice cover that really attracts me.
And that it's this kind of Mexican, South American horror or mysticism that I like. And this seems great.
And another one that was in this one that I hadn't seen before and that makes me very excited.
House of Hunger. And so vampire books.
A book that I also found here that I had forgotten that I had put in my TBR last year.
And that's The Book of Accidents by Chuck Wending. It must also be some kind of dysfunctional family.
Past present. Yes, but it must be unpleasant.
That said, I added it last year, April 2022, and had totally forgotten it was there.
So now I saw this and it seems very, very interesting. And check out the cover as well.
And of course, all Stephen King that is on this list is of course an absolute must.
So that goes without saying. So I don't have to say anything.
And this book, The Last House on Needles Street by Katrina Ward.
I have it when I saw it on the list. But I've heard and seen it just about everywhere.
But it's like this serial killer, Revenge, Death, A Stolen Child, all that.
I just, wow, this sounds very, very, very good.
I have to say, overall, this list is incredibly, incredibly good.
I've found quite a few new favorites that way. Or not new favorites, but books that I really want to read.
And all the Kingfishers are there, almost everything I want to read is on this one too.
So were new acquaintances that I hadn't really seen like that and I'm incredibly, incredibly curious about it.
One that, a book that I want to talk about is Sundial Katrina Ward again.
And this was also a book that I added last year and had forgotten about.
Check out the cover. I mean, how unpleasant and beautiful is it?
This is what made me fall for this book.
Twisty Psychological Horror. So psychological, twisted.
It's just, I have to read it at once.
And it has received quite good and high ratings anyway.
So Katrina Ward might be an author to keep an eye out for.
Have you read anything by her?
I think this list was so good. Really, really good list overall.
Because especially me who kind of likes horror but doesn't really know where to start.
But I'm very glad I'm going to start Hendrix books now.
Then I think I'll go get some of the Kingfisher books.
But I thought this list was so amazing and I just wanted us to go through it a little bit.
And talk about some books that I'm curious about.
I'm looking at the list, that's why I'm looking down and not at you.
I don't know, what do you think about horror? Do you get extra hungry now that it's October or do you hate horror in general?
I'm the kind of person who loves horror and can read horror in April or March, it doesn't really matter.
But I feel that this year, October, I've had this spooky feeling and I've had a strong craving.
So when I saw this list I was like, thank you so much Goodreads, now I'm going to go through it.
And look, and there were a lot of them that I liked, it's crazy, I don't know if you can see, so many of them is in my
want to read, want to read, that I've put it on my Goodreads list.
I'm so curious as to what you think about horror in general.
The books I have talked about, have you read any of them or are you also curious about them?
Talk to me in the comments section and I'll see you there. See you next week. Take care bye!