Hello, Elza here from Elzas Bokhylla. It's time to show you the books I hope and want to read during October.
I'll be honest, I think I'm going into a reading slump.
September has been hard. I haven't had as much desire to read or been in a reading mood.
When I do read, the books I thought were good have been sort of…
I get stuck, and I pause a lot more than I usually do.
I actually put down 2-3 books in September.
So I'm cautiously optimistic when planning my read for October, so you know.
But there are a couple of books. We'll go through them and see what happens when it's time to do a wrap-up later.
We start with the books that are in my book  challenge "Dust off".
Where I read my unread books that I own.
A book that will be included is one from my September's TBR.
I've started it, I've paused it several times.
I still want to read it, because I think about it and think it seems good and exciting so I haven't given up on it.
So it will come along in October as well.
And that's Our Tragic Universe by Scarlett Thomas.
I still don't really know what it's about.
It should be about some kind of time lapse, perhaps, if you can live forever.
I haven't really grasped what the plot is.
I'll be honest, but it starts out really good.
As I said, you see, I have started, I have read a couple of pages and will check how many I have read.
I have read 38 pages.
I haven't given up on it, I'm still curious.
So I'm hoping to give it another chance this October.
I feel like I have a bit of a craving for classics actually.
A classic that I really want to read is A Tale of Two Cities by Charles Dickens.
I'm a Charles Dickens fan.
If you heard a motorcycle driving by, apologies.
I'm a Charles Dickens fan anyway.
And I think this is available as an audiobook.
This is still a pocket, quite nice.
I don't know, but maybe I listen, read, listen and read. We'll see.
But I would love to read this one.
Give it a chance because I have been curious about it for a very long time.
World literature of the month.
I was thinking of going to Japan.
Last month I was in South America.
So I've been to India, I've been to Asia, I've been to Africa a lot over the summer.
But now I'm going back to Japan.
I thought I would read The Nakano Thrift Shop by Hiromi Kawakami.
I thought I would listen to it.
She's the one who made The Briefcase.
I like it very much.
And I want to give this one a chance too.
I want to listen and read it.
So it must be World Literature of the Month.
Japan. Yes, you know, I love Japan.
In my book club, we're going to read a horror story, since it's October and Halloween and stuff like that.
Then we will read How to sell a haunted house by Grady Hendrix.
I have it as an e-book.
I'm not sure what it's really about.
But it must be a girl whose parents die.
She goes back to her hometown and the house she grew up in and will try to sell it.
Is it something like spooky and scary and stuff like that?
I don't know more than that.
I don't want to know more than that.
And I think this seems so exciting.
I'm a bit curious about his writing in general.
I actually have many of Hendrix books on my tbr overall.
So it will be fun and get to know him a little.
And in the book circle, I go to two different ones.
One that I call the book club and one that I call the book circle.
In the book club we will read a horror story.
And in the book circle we will read On Earth We're Briefly Gorgeous by Ocean Vuong.
Are we beautiful on earth, yes.
I'm just unsure.
Here you have it.
I also have it as an audiobook, I think.
I'll give it a go as an audiobook.
So it will be very exciting to read it.
This is about a person who writes letters to his illiterates.
to his mother who is illiterate.
About his childhood, about the escape, about life in the United States, about the memories.
So it will be, I've heard it's beautifully written.
And I have heard that it is very difficult, but still important and wonderful.
It is a very blissful mixture.
It should hurt, but it should still be damn good.
So I've been looking forward to this and reading it a lot.
So there we have it. I have the book circle, I have the book club.
I have "dust off" times two and then we have world literature.
There is only one book challenge left and that is where I let chance choose which book I will read.
I have the phone here.
We'll get started right away.
Lets see.
Okay, 370.
Totally okay because I'm getting close to 800 books on my TBR on Goodreads.
370, Let us see which book it will be.
Listen, this is amazing.
Testament of Nina Wähä.
And listen, this is actually a "dusty book".
I have this one here, in a second we'll see.
Here I have it, I have it.
I bought it a couple of years ago second hand.
That was two, two years ago, two years ago maybe.
Second hand, so I have this one.
It's supposed to be a family drama.
These are nothing but murder stories, right?
Or yes, by all means.
It is much more than just that.
I actually don't really know what it's about.
All I know is that I saw it everywhere.
People loved it.
It was insanely hyped.
It is a very popular book.
And I'm finally going to read it.
Wait let me check when I put it in my tbr.
On the first of April 2020.
April 1st 2020, so three years ago.
So this is really a "dusty" book.
It's quite a shelf warmer.
So nice, then I have three "dusty" books this month.
How fun that it ended up on this one.
Which I own and don't have to think about.
Book that I actually feel a little craving for.
It's like pretty and stuff.
We'll see what I think.
If I think like everyone else.
Or if I think otherwise.
So there we have the books I hope to read during October.
Like I said, I'm a little cautious.
Optimistic.
I'm not trying to…
It will be as it will be.
I'm not sure if there will be these books at all.
Because I think I'm getting into a reading slump.
I don't have the same urge.
What I want to do is to sit and watch something.
Very good TV series.
Devour TV series.
I'm actually very keen on that.
For some reason.
So maybe I should take a break from reading.
And let things rest.
I do not know.
I'm still craving these books.
I do not know what to do.
We take one day at a time, we take one book at a time.
And then we'll see how October turns out.
I am of course curious about which books you plan to read in October.
tell me in the comments section and I'll see you there
Please give me a thumbs up and subscribe to my channel.
if you don't already
See you next week.
Take care bye!