Hi, Elza here from Elzas Bookshelf. I've been to the book fair and I've gone bananas. I have bought, I don't know, let me check, nine books.
It's been a long time since I bought this many books. I think it's to compensate for being in a reading slump, because I console myself by buying books.
You know that buying books and reading books are two completely different hobbies and I love them both equally and I have them equally.
But now I'm going to show you the books I found at the book fair and it's a lot, so we'll get started at once.
The first book is a non-fiction that I have wanted to read for a long time and the author was standing there, I said hello and asked if I could have it signed and of course she did.
I'm talking about Mammorna by Alexandra Pascalidou. Very nice like that, the whole page. It was really nice to talk to her, really cool.
She just came out with Papporna but I haven't read Mammorna yet so I thought I would.
I know it's available as an audiobook too but this is a paperback so it can be quite nice but it feels very good to own it.
I feel like I'm in a period where I'm starting to get hungry and glances at non-fiction.
So the second book I'm going to show is a book that I got because I bought the gold card and then you got a goody bag and in it there was a book.
It's a book that I've seen a bit everywhere, Songbirds by Christy Leftery nominated in 2022 for Årets Bok.
I don't really know what it's about. It's super nice anyway.
I haven't read, I know she has another book too which was pretty popular too. I have seen it here and there on bookstagram and on booktube.
But I haven't read anything by her. I think this is so pretty so I was pleasantly surprised when I saw it in the bag.
I've said that I've kind of finished with Swedish detective story, but it's a writer that I...
I don't follow many authors on Instagram, but I do follow her and I'm very curious about her books.
So I saw this and thought, okay, I'll give it a shot.
I'm talking about Anna Bågstam, Eyewitness.
This is the first book in her series. I don't know, Brutal murder, Öresund.
It is a fast-paced and exciting detective story that takes place in the Öresund region.
Harriet.
Honestly, this sounds like a classic Swedish detective story that I'm done with.
Like I don't want anything more and read anything more.
But, but, I like the author and I've only heard good things about this one.
So me and Swedish detective story are on a break but we are starting to flirting with each other again.
Yes, me and Anna.
Then a book that I was overjoyed to see.
And there was no doubt that it would come home with me.
A short one, which I have seen a little here and there.
But as my favorite booktuber Books with Emily Fox.
She raves about this book, she thinks it's amazing.
And I'm really curious about it.
I Who Have Never Known Men by Jacqueline Harpman.
Harpman maybe.
And this is apparently supposed to be some kind of dystopia, perhaps.
There are several women who are locked in the basement.
And then a lot of things happen.
Apparently you shouldn't know much more about this book than that.
That it should perhaps have some feminist touch, as socially critical in that way.
In addition to being insanely good-looking, it's cool.
And I've heard her rave about this book.
So I think I have to give her a chance.
And it sounds like a book I would like.
And I love it when people say they "you shouldn't know much about this book, Just know this and read".
Then I immediately become curious and gladly pick it up.
So this one had to come home with me.
I have a relatively new favorite author and horror.
And I've read a book by her, which I raved about a lot on this channel.
And then I read a collection of short stories.
And then I found another collection of short stories that I haven't read.
I'm talking about Mariana Enriquez and The Danger of Smoking in Bed.
A small collection of short stories.
Maria Enriquez is the one who wrote Our share night.
I love that book.
The horror that is so fantastic.
Oh how good it is.
Oh my god it's so good.
I recommend everyone to read it, of course.
Although those who don't like horror can probably appreciate this one.
But it is incredibly unpleasant.
Trigger warning for a little most of the time.
But it is so, so well written and so good.
And I have read a collection of short stories by her.
And now I own this one too.
The one I read was Things We Lost in the Fire.
And it is available in Swedish.
Things we lose in the fire, I think it's called in Swedish.
I don't know if this one is available in Swedish.
But I have it in English and I probably want to buy the other one as well.
The other short story collection that looks a bit like this one.
Fantastic.
I'm so excited for this one.
A bit nervous.
But I love Mariana Enriquez's way of writing.
And her way of setting the mood for things.
It's an incredibly unpleasant atmosphere.
I love her.
The second book I bought was also a bit of a gamble.
But I've seen it everywhere and want to read it.
But I've been like this, should I, shouldn't I, shouldn't I.
But of course I will.
We are talking about The Seven Moons by Maali Almeida.
Shall we see.
I apologize so terribly for butchering this name.
Fantastic name.
I apologize so terribly.
At least this one.
Look how beautiful it is.
And this is such a typical trope that I like.
We get to go with Maali.
I imagine this person dies pretty brutally.
But ends up in the afterlife.
And there this person has, Maali has seven months.
Seven days, seven months to go.
To sort of get along with the people she loves the most.
He loves the most, I even think.
And yes, it is vague.
As you know, vaguely.
I think that's what it's about.
I read the back a little quickly.
Got such a good feeling.
Magic realism.
The afterlife.
Feeling.
And thought that this was a book for me.
I'll take a chances.
And then it says here that it's a book.
The Book Pricer 2022.
So this one won.
Book Pricer.
The price until 2022.
So why.
So why not anyway.
And then check.
I mean check.
Another gamble
A book that I thought sounded so funny.
And I don't know.
I've said that I don't like cozy books.
But I have started to like them, a little.
At least this year.
So I found a book that seemed really cozy and great fun.
And it's called
The Cat Who Caught a Killer.
By LT Shearer.
I don't know much more than that.
We are allowed to accompany a woman.
In all cases.
A cat helps a woman solve a murder.
I mean the title says it all doesn't it.
So I think so.
I think it looks so cozy.
And I enjoy reading.
Books with animals that.
Which has like one.
At least animals I like.
And cats are cozy, I think.
I am both a cat and dog person.
And of course.
Must try.
Okay next book.
I bought for two reasons.
I like the idea itself.
The title itself.
You will understand.
And.
The cover.
Look.
at this cover.
I died.
That's how pretty it is.
The Girl Who Fell Beneath the Sea.
Axie Oh.
Oh maybe.
Perhaps.
Sorry.
Okay, I don't know anything about this book.
It's fantasy.
I hope it.
You see some fish and whales.
Here are some whales.
another whale
I mean, I'm already lost there.
It feels like she's going to fall into the sea.
About the sea.
I do not know.
It sounds like that.
I'll take a chance.
Look how beautiful it is.
It's at that level.
I actually don't really know what this is about.
More than that it is very stylish and I think it attracts me.
A thing I don't like is that, Back text.
When it's just lots of quotes from people who like it. But what is it about? I do not know.
It says beautiful, she says this. Enchanting says this one.Tale of blah blah says this one.
But for me...What does it mean? And that's all it says. Don't chase fate. Let fate chase you.
What does it mean? Where are we anywhere in this story? Who is it about?
Who is it about? What happens? What should we solve? I do not know anything.
And it says nothing.
It says nothing.
And then you have to browse somewhere.
And find either the back or the front.
It says a lot of things.
But like I said, I don't know.
And I do not care.
It is good looking.
The look attracts me.
It had to come home with me.
So.
Why do I have to explain myself?
Why do I buy books?
I bought it. It was nice. Let me be.
I have a another non-fiction that I really want to read and am curious about.
It is the Kurdspåret by Joakim Medin.
Sweden, Turkey and the price of NATO membership.
This whole NATO process when Sweden wants to join NATO and Turkey makes demands and says they have to extradite some of our citizens.
And what happens there.
I am very curious about this.
How could we do that?
I thought better of us.
Sweden.
I just think this seems so interesting.
There is so much going on.
And I haven't heard much about this.
And he's dug into this.
The journalist.
So I got curious and thought I'd learn a little.
Just a little general education.
So listen.
There were quite a few books.
I am super excited to read all of these and also very curious to read them.
And of course I'm curious about which of these books you like.
Which ones are you curious about?
Which ones have you read?
And what do you think of them?
Help me somehow find a way in.
Which one should I start.
Figured I might show them off too.
So here you have them.
I am of course, as usual, very curious about what you think of them here.
And if you have read any of them.
See you in the comments section.
See you next Monday.
Don't forget to give me a thumbs up and feel free to subscribe to my channel.
If you don't already.
Farewell.
Bye!