Apparently this powder should be able to replace our future ..
Is this our future?
When I see something like this, I get skeptical.
Is this bulls * it or not?
There is only one way to find out.
I will live on this powder only, for a full 30 days.
We'll see if I survive.
I really have the worst eating habits right now.
You know ... when you really neglect everything.
I have ended up in a phase, so that it always feels like I am behind and do not have time to cook.
So in other words that solves my problems with eating fast things.
Candy.
Chips.
Junk food, yes you get it. Sugar and fat.
And sometimes I completely forgot to eat at all.
So I started talking to Emma (girlfriend) about my food problem.
Hin put it up quite simply. "Control it up they make lunch box, make meal schedule" A normal person would probably have thought it was a good idea.
But I think the step further.
I start thinking: "why is there not a pill"
Future food that solves that I get full.
It's useful and good, no shit.
Kind of like Kalle and Chokladfabriken where Willy Wonka makes a chewing gum that simulates a three-course meal.
How brilliant is that idea and why does it not exist?
So with that idea in mind, I go to Google and start searching.
I scroll and scroll, find nothing.
Google
Facebook they are sick in the head
Then you will come up ads just for this.
Chocolate taste.
We will live on this for a whole month.
Now we start, cheers.
Not bad.
I had expected it to be worse.
The taste is perfectly okay.
Tastes a little gruel ..
A little coconut, a little flour and chocolate.
Porridge-mushy texture: D
Thought it would be much worse.
I think I made mine a little too thick ...
The funny thing is, I'm full now.
How fast did I not get a whole meal in me now ?!
I'm done there!
I have been recording for 4 minutes.
I guess 2-3 minutes went to a lot of shabbing when I talk ..
I easily think you can eat a whole meal in under a minute.
It's crazy to be able to eat a meal so fast!
At the same time, I feel very useful, as I get everything I need.
Now I'm Fit for fight.
I thought you should say this but I am pleasantly surprised, you are actually measured
I have been driving for four days now and I thought it would be much harder than it actually is.
But wait a minute now !!
You have no idea if that is useful or not, you can not say that straight up and down.
Blood test day.
We need an expert too, so it's not just "what I think".
Now she has chosen to focus on functional medicine, ie that she knows much more than you and I do.
Is this the future? You avoid all the cows, the meat and the environmental impact.
You solve everything with a powder instead.
So my own personal opinion, I do not think so.
Maybe a shorter period.
I do not think it's the future, do not skip it.
Good food is what we should live on.
You have looked at the contents of the bags, what do I get in me?
I see that they contain the necessary vitamins and minerals we need.
..So you survive ..
Okay * haha ​​*, so I survive ?!
So we take a blood sample now and then an experiment is done.
But how will you feel ..
You may go on your ketones.
So you burn fat instead of sugar and I can do that a little "high"
Clear-minded :)
I feel even, nothing up or down. It is very stable.
All levels are stable and I feel happy.
Andreas is sitting here eating pizza.
This is so good.
What do you have on the pizza?
A Vesuvius with bacon.
It's ham from the beginning, right?
Yes, I added bacon.
So what?
Right, it's the same thing: D!
Andreas: That's why I looked at you..when you said bacon
But I thought..yes..yes..it will probably be good anyway.
I will continue and not give up.
I do not know why I felt as bad as I did.
We're past it anyway.
Then you can be prepared that when you run out of sugar, an abstinence situation can arise.
Headache, you get low.
Which can be quite difficult to get through.
But it happens because the body gets rid of the sugar.
Now I have found something bad with the powder.
It feels clear with the mask ... the breath.
I forgot to brush my teeth and it's not nice ...
But I talked to a polar bear about it, and he said that protein powder could give the same effect.
What do you think I've been doing this for a while now?
You smell too damn good :)
Rotten ... his breath ..
Will we see you test this?
Have no hopes.
Thumbs up if you want Emma to taste.
Do you think it's healthy to live like this?
No, not for a long period.
If you are going out camping or the like, I think it can be convenient.
I hope that many people like the video now, as he spent more than a month getting it together :)
Stop
I sleep next to him and the breath ..
Continues with the shake, there are 2 weeks left.
I regret doing this in the summer. I am very hungry for real food.
It will probably go well anyway.
The worst thing is to be around "regular food".
Had I not seen it would probably have been a minor problem.
We would just back off with the car ..
I do not know whose car it is..it just stood here ..
J **** bang
You kind of get a perfect energy level.
Another disadvantage is that you get crazy hungry quickly.
Quickly
If you eat ordinary food, you first get hungry, more hungry, crazy hungry.
Here you are next a little cheated, then it is PANIC.
You're hungry now
So my stomach screams at me ..
Today I still ate exactly as I should do ..
Would pick up some things for Emma and see the chocolate ..
MY brain immediately says, "We have to take that one!"
But we did not..I was just pulled here ..
When my brain says something now..then I will do just the opposite.
I've not been in this fridge in about 2 weeks now .. thanks to this one!
I sit and make a menu that I will eat when I'm done!
Here you have the dish, I think I saw a common thread in it all.
There is flour in everything I apparently miss.
I'm so hungry for natchos..OMG
Am I bitter or am I bitter?
7 days left ..
It smells so good in here.
How crazy is it that I have not had to think or cook for so long.
It's so nice to get rid of it.
Cook then "yes what should I cook today ..."
God what fun
In the end, you fix the same s * it anyway (: Uninspiring!
I'm feeling very well!
It's not long now
Instead of you just seeing me with a shake every day, you should see my friends taste instead.
What is that?
Dinner!
Strawberry!
It was not so dangerous, it was good!
Porridge..type: D
OATMEAL!
JERRE: NEEEJ! - VA ??
There are a few lumps in..but that is the case with protein powder and the like.
It's his food ... not protein powder.
I liked it.
What do you think if you have different opinions and thoughts
That is, everyone who does not eat the ones you eat.
A bite, does it not look nice or?
I can not!
The brain wants to take the easy way out.
You train your discipline reached unbelievably.
3 more days
It's really nice to not have to cook.
Some of that money and over a month
Even if you drink Cola Zero?
It's not good for the liver, then everyone knows that at home. Instead of sugar, it's some other shit instead.
Exactly, so it actually got a little better.
Also
And then I saw that it went down a bit
Finally get to eat
Who how good does not this look
Tack
Wow