He has previously been convicted.
I found him in the criminal record.
That's why I call and it was even more.
How should we act in this situation?
I talk about Emma and Konrad who two months ago disappeared from ..
The crime should be judged as serious as the injury was then taken place through an uncontrolled fire.
And the injury was extremely noticeable.
We just disappeared and the situation is still serious.
But we have to tell the truth and we have missed Youtube and you above all, so much heaven.
So we have been commented daily on what has happened.
Everything from having children, something has been unfaithful.
Or, what you wonder, we have ended.
Watch the whole video because you really don't want to miss this.
What has happened to us is really sick.
Although we have a wonderful job, there is a dark side as many
Creators choose not to talk about it for it to get worse.
What we will tell you about now is one of the absolute worst LVI has been through.
And it all started in 2020.
We started getting messages and mails from a man who said he was religious.
He talked a lot about God, but was kind.
Because he said he liked our videos and my livestream.
At the same time, he began to say that he was talking directly to God.
That he was like a speaker for God.
Here I feel quite guilty because I did not know who where the person was.
But I responded to one of his messages and it opened a total door to a Madröm that became so damn unpleasant.
Our journey with this channel began in October 2016.
A jealousy filled with laughter, creativity and lots of love.
But as you noticed in the summer of 2021, it became quiet.
We just disappeared without a word and without any explanation.
Youtube means so much to us.
I've been watching Youtube for as long as I can remember.
Already in 2008 I uploaded my first clip.
It is now that you realize that I have gotten rid of my absolute greatest interest, to tell stories.
After several years of streaming, I realized that something important was missing.
I wanted to create videos that were always there for you.
Even when I wasn't live.
I moved to Stockholm to learn all about Youtube.
That's where I met Konrad.
We decided to start this channel.
When our channel was silenced, it felt like we lost a bit of ourselves.
We became compelling.
In his mean, he began to focus more and more on Emma.
He claimed that God had created her to him.
Like I was some thing for him. An object.
He saw our entire relationship as an evil sin.
She was unfaithful to him.
At first it was so sick. I just wanted to laugh it away.
Ignore it.
But now I started to get really worried.
It only got worse and worse.
Happens enough that the situation had become extremely more serious.
To shop for a video.
In this video he sits. He seems completely drugged.
Someone seriously wrong with this person.
He sits and talks about all extremely s*xuel*a stuff.
As I have to do with him because he owns me.
He will make sure we will not be with each other anymore.
If that's the last thing he does. It was so extremely unpleasant and so eerie.
And just hear the voice of this crazy man.
Just give me shivers, only I talk about it.
Here we start by registering the clip.
But of course it gets worse after that. What do you think this person did?
He sits down for ten hours in a car to Stockholm.
Not just that. He lives in a hotel.
Share on the corner. Right close to where we live.
We are starting to be planned when we got to watch this video.
We felt chasing it. You did not feel safe in your own home.
It's sick don't end there.
He starts filming our house.
He even gets into our gate.
And to then get into our floor.
When it does not succeed, he walks around the house and films straight in through our bedroom windows.
It felt completely insane that this happened.
It was like being stuck in a nightmare that you couldn't wake up from.
Of course, I became terrified. We both got this huge and did not know what to do.
He could be every fan at this time.
And at the same time we had our dogs.
After all, we had to go out to the apartment.
I just wanted to lock myself inside and at the same time I'm really scared something happens to be Konrad.
Konrad, if you go out and I know what he would do if he finds you.
What is still scary is that this person does not even hide who he is.
He is completely open and you realize that he has no boundaries at all.
No, he is totally splashing crazy.
So, something is seriously wrong.
We couldn't even sleep at night. After all, we were just awake at night.
And every damn sound we heard we thought it's this one
The madman standing outside us with the ax hand or something.
All the more thoughts that come into your head that you just can't shut it out.
We had probably had enough by this time and just like this what the hell should we get to?
No, so we simply called the police.
Now I have had a clip send to me where a person is looking for me and my girlfriend.
This person is in our gate and looks and looks for our names, he tells us in this video.
So that's why I call too. For it was up to me even more,
Otherwise, just thought it was a strange fan.
- What does he say then?
What is heard is that he is looking for us and he is looking for us for three, four days in the area where we live.
And, as I said, we had called the police and they took this seriously.
Thankfully.
But here comes the next bomb.
This man has been sentenced several times since before.
So not only the disgusting videos and s*xuel*a messages and crazy god stuff.
So now our safety was really in danger because he
In fact, did the crazy things he had also talked about.
The police told us.
To block him, ban him everywhere.
Give him no attention do not respond to any messages at all.
And whatever you do, don't talk about this out in your social media.
Because we do not know how to react if he would get angry.
And if he were to get angry, what to do then.
After all, we had to sit there and just pretend, be happy that everything was peaceful and delighted.
It was great, very busy.
And at the same time, it was a lot on our relationship between us.
Because we walked around and was nerve wreck and worried.
And we could not sleep at night, and the smallest sound like we
Heard or movement felt like he would break into our apartment.
And I think you noticed it more and more, because
Videos are getting smaller and smaller and my streams as well.
And guess if we had a bad conscience after this. We were forced to lie to you.
Or it felt so, at least, even though we did not make sense.
But being loosened that everything was just as usual when it really wasn't.
Above all, it was extremely difficult for me as a live streamer in the days.
I am a live stream on Tiktok and on Twitch.
And have lots of people every day who ask why we don't post as many videos anymore.
From the beginning, people start asking why I have not included in the videos as much.
And it is also because not triggering him, seems as little as possible.
I had no answers to any of the several questions. We just sat there trying to pretend like nothing.
And this man was since previously criminals and was convicted
Several times for, among other things, serious violent crimes and murder.
So now this idiot was then obsessed with my girlfriend.
- Emma !!
*Censored*
XXXX ... I know where you live.
Through the police we got in touch with a person at the personal protection group.
They work with people who are exposed and who are in such situations.
We were asked by them. Do you want to move to protective accommodation, because we can fix this for you?
Until the situation has resolved.
The problem was only that if we had stopped doing so, we would have had to stop all our social media.
And basically go below the ground. Which is the last thing we wanted because we actually love our job.
So it was extremely difficult and it really was something we
Had to think through. It was no easy decision.
After much if and but then we finally decided to
Move to your own apartment themselves without the help of the police.
Maybe not the best choice because since we did, we have had to move three times.
Because we wanted to be able to continue with our job that we loved.
We had to do something to feel money and pay the rent.
We really tried to keep up but the motivation and
The love for creating was completely wiped out after everything that has happened.
And he did not give up.
I just felt that in the end I was not wrong and I was depressed.
And videos came up more and more rarely.
I just felt such incredible stress and pressure.
I didn't have the whole energy to keep up both Youtube and stream.
If we think about that he seems more focusing on Youtube
Than Twitch I chose okay but I continue with Twitch.
Then at least we have some income.
There I can sit and sit down like I don't understand anything or try.
I modder in this point so incredibly bad.
I just felt that I was betraying you and I betrayed myself when I can't cope anymore.
YouTube was your life.
Hard to talk about?
Very hard to talk about.
Youtube has been my life for so long.
Yes.
It's all Konrad talks about.
Youtube, Youtube, Youtube all the time.
It was in the summer of 2021 that we finally made the difficult decision to okay.
He still hadn't stopped by this time and as I said we moved around like just that.
A lot of shit it happened.
Now we take a break, a real break to see if it can make him quit.
We just hoped that he could lose interest in Emma.
Then the time went more and more and we have managed to heal, build ourselves and focus on our lives again.
We realized it well so that is enough.
Now we want to live and do what we want.
I refuse to let someone j*vla ganning once again control what we do and do not do or get.
It has taken therapy for us to arrive at the point we are now.
I feel so ready to continue with Youtube.
It's all Konrad talks about.
I'm legit.
I am the world's largest Youtube nerd.
I cure holes in her head with video ideas.
Look at this.
I love this.
Or we both love this but I'm extremely nerd.
You are extremely nerd.
Yes, he is really extreme.
Every day there are new videos here.
At this point, you have thought that hundreds of video ideas are what you want to do.
I just know what fun when we post a video.
Yes, imagine what good it will be and God what fun we will have.
I'm just glad we are sitting here now and can tell you the truth.
It has been such a sick thing over our heads for so long.
I've been able to sit here now and do this.
I'm just so damn happy.
Yes, 100%
Now we really hope that you want to accompany us on our trip back.
And you are finally humming at the truth.
To the big question that everyone has wondered.
Are we still together?
Yes.
I didn't know what JI would do ...
Yes, we are still together. *Laughter attack*
And you probably wonder what happened to this madman.
And apparently he should not even be in Sweden anymore.
We have not been able to confirm it.
But at least that's what his relative says
It ended with, unfortunately..I get to say that I am not surprised.
That the case is laid down.