Oh, sh't there are a lot of people who want more mysterious videos!
So I thought we were awakening that segment again!
But how can you have missed this?
The United States released lots of secretly stamped UFO movies, they have released a UFO report and lots of other things.
Is aliens for real?
It is probably a question many have asked, but as you brush away in the lack of evidence.
But gets a year ago came the shock.
USA's headquarters Pentagon admitted that they had a secret UFO program to investigate close contact.
It has been funded by money hidden in the budget
There are very many people who are surprised that they have gone out with this public.
When you already said in 2012 that you closed all UFO operations.
And based on the closure on the fact that there was not enough evidence to be able to motivate more money into the project.
The project but now instead this business under C.I.A. and
Jonas No.
Do you get with pretty smart for purely theoretically, they do yes
She has dismissed the business in 2012 with divided the group and infects and paint them under new instances on
Flag
Strange the whole situation is that one has total waiting
In question
Previously have always rejected that resources have been put down on UFON UFO observations have me
May we see a completely different page
But I wonder where the turn came
Next time the US recognizes UFO
Where are real
In Delphi
Fine
Real the Last Airbender
Other
Switch to Historical US government go out and confirm
A video there
Is genuine
They say it's totally sick
Not called but out of which
I want
How does a cat sound
The defense
The technology is moving forward so more is filming even they
Sweet
It will be very exciting to see what they get on film
On May 20, Hangar Ship was a USS Nimitz and Prince
Very important training assignment just sent up the combat pilot
The air
Something very much
Strange on its radar identified object
10 minutes of flying
David work
Now we'll finally get to see the pictures Davidsjort
Unfortunately, David dropped objects
But luckily
Operator on the swish ship
These pictures
David describes this item
Called sometimes resemble the form of tablet
Booked a new approximately 12 m
Adult can change direction at any time
Put in 34 seconds in Kungsör
100 meters
Candy and likely is that we never
Any technology
Who is Alice
Gaming chair
Backcity
Eniro
What are you just seen
But their reaction
US military combat pilots they don't even know what they experienced almost
Unreal event
About it or not I don't know but that's something
As I really like to know what it is for
Watch as they talk about how unreal this
Is
The technology compares to one we possess they possess in their plan mixed
Canary
Where is Hugo
How does a cartoon look
Are you
Other military films
Pentagon confirms is
It was carbon dark night at
California
USA
Set Ship
Find an unknown item in the sky
I have absolutely no idea what that might be
But if you have it write a comment now
All of a sudden from nowhere
Only down into the water and
Disappear
This video is recorded in July 2019 by the American
ISS
Sea
San Diego
It was not exactly less question marks after here as you understand
Without
The US Minister in Congress was not
Am happy about sitting in the dark and not knowing anything
Starting price
The Military personnel pronounces with
Former president
Now we want answers from the security service and this mentioned
The thing Doris hard to meander as an authority
The security service had to report every case then
Since 2004
Normal people
Curious
Of course
Fixed that the report
2004 to 2020
The first story big gate is
They do not have enough high quality reporting or material which makes it difficult
Conclusions in the report
The reason for these should be that does not have enough good reporting systems but they best implement the controller
System for two years
18 cases in 21 different reports
So describes the same movement pattern as we got to see Davids
There is no explanation
Not in the normal way that one can expect an object to move it to go to the wind
I can explain 18
Similar events with Sven Reports
She also writes that they do not find anything to indicate that this would be another nation's has received a new
China Russia Under You Could It Be Being Without They Can't Find They WOULD BE
Has control technology
Turn it off
The information
144 cases
How many did they really resolve
Battle Fallen
Is proven is a balloon that drops the air very large balloon to the only case