Hello all legends!
Hi everyone!
Today it's a new reaction video
where we react to what you said
last time: near-death experiences.
Shall we do this darling?
-Jump?
-Parachute jump.
Yes, or...
What just happened? Lord...
Oh, shit. I thought they
were going to do a trick.
They're flying into a plane.
Oh, what? He's on the other plane.
Oh, shit. I didn't realize it was
that serious with the balloon.
It just crashes. Then you wonder
what's happening with the pilot right now.
Yes. Look, there you got
to see it from a different angle.
Oh, wow. It's burning and stuff.
-There are like seven people in the air.
-It was the plane they were in that broke.
I think it's what they
collide with that breaks.
Okay, is this a car, or?
It's an airplane, I think.
I mean, how can one be so stupid?!
-I mean, I'm getting angry.
-Oh, my God!
Imagine if he gets hit in the head by that.
-I mean, how can the other one not see it?
-What an idiot, really.
-But how lucky he is.
-Yes, that luck, guardian angel.
This is just crazy.
But okay.
No sharks please. I think it's so scary.
Oh, it's a shark.
I would have been so scared!
How cool he is.
He just knocked the shark. He hit it.
Yes, but who wouldn't have done that?
I mean, what a legend!
I mean, he just "Bam"!
I've read somewhere that you
should hit so it feels that it's not...
-It's a hammerhead shark, right?
-Yes, it is.
I've heard they're quite aggressive.
It doesn't want to eat him, does it?
But he might have caught its baby
in the line.
No! He must think it was a turtle.
They often think that.
-But if he hit it hard...
-A big yellow banana boat is a turtle?
He fights this thing for a long time.
Yes, it doesn't give up.
It could easily tip his boat.
-Do you think so?
-Yes.
Imagine being the one
sitting alone out on the sea.
I would have been so scared.
I think this is cool but so scary. Shit.
What's he doing?
Throwing himself off a mountain?
Yes, probably.
-Go go, dude.
-Okay. Can you just, like...
Oh, no, man!
Oh, my God! Poor guy. My God.
What? How did he survive?
I don't understand.
But it's the fall that slows down.
But still.
That must have hurt so freaking much.
Why is that dude just filming?
Oh! What's happening there? Oh, what?!
I didn't even see.
Was someone flying into a sign?
We'll try to understand what's happening.
-Something is coming flying.
-Oh, wow!
It's one of those squirrel suits, I think.
Oh, one of those with a flying thing?
I've never understood those.
How do you fly those?
Shit, I mean. What a freaking...
Oh, my freaking God!
-I mean, that guy!
-Did you see how lucky?!
No, ugh, how scary.
Can we rewind and watch again?
That was just insane.
-Oh, my God.
-That's inches, really. Wow.
Inches? He probably hit the car,
but made it really well.
Ouch. What? What's happening?!
He's on fire!
No, put out the fire!
I just want to put out the fire on him.
I love that he is just
"Shit, I'm outta here!"
First, he went out and then he just bailed.
Maybe he saw that the others
were coming up to him.
-No, that was cowardly of him.
-Yes, I think it was cowardly.
I mean, imagine how lucky you must be
for such a thing.
What now? This wall won't...
Oh, no.
No no, it's going to collapse!
This feels like a game with blocks.
-Oh, no, no, no. Please.
-So stupid.
Don't do this, please.
Look at all the things above him now.
Why? Oh.
I mean, I'm kind of angry.
You're so stupid!
Stop!
Really?! What did he think would happen?
Oh my God. Did he die? No, okay.
Oh, is he going to be robbed?
-No, how cool!
-What's he doing?
-He has this...
-...hairspray and lighter or something.
I mean, how cool!
-But how smart that he just...
-That was a legend move.
They didn't even get in
before he did that. Brilliant.
Pure legend thing, really.
-GTA.
-No! Oh...
No, animals shouldn't be harmed. It's
just like that. It's something special.
-He just walks away then.
-Ouch, ouch, ouch...
Yes, he's totally in shock. Shit, really.
Oh. No!
I mean, that's just insane.
Oh, no!
I mean...
Oh my God, how close that was.
Did you see that?
No, no, no. Wow.
Goodbye.
No, God, what a freaking drop there was.
-Hey hey, Skye?!
-I'm good!
Okay, sorry that I said goodbye, perhaps.
But wow.
Oh, my God. Run!
You flew!
I flew? I felt sorry for those
who stood there. He flew.
Ouch, ouch, ouch, ouch, ouch, ouch!
He made it.
All guys are breathing out.
I mean, I thought it was a nut shot
on that one. Wow.
God.
What's happening? Oh!
...deserves it but I mean...
yes, you shouldn't walk by on...
Ah but... wow.
It looks like Sweden. It could be Sweden.
-This is you, darling.
-Yes, it could be.
Wow, how freaking lucky...
-It could have been me.
-Is it the lady?
Oh!
Talking on the phone
and crossing the road at the same time.
-Did she walk into the bus?
-Yes, yes, yes. She was so close.
That's why you shouldn't talk
on the phone if you're not focused.
It's life-threatening.
But you have to look to the left.
And she's not even crossing at the
crosswalk, so she's in the middle of...
Damn how scary, really.
I would have just died.
But I felt sorry for the snake at first.
But then... can't just leave the snake.
Oh, no, no, no. Watch out,
watch out! You're in the way. Hello!
Wow, did you see
how he just threw that kid away?
-That was also a legend move.
-Yes, what a hero.
See, he was hanging on the hood.
This is just a total fail, really.
-What are they doing?
-No, no, no! Oh.
Oh, Lord... Wonder how much that weighs.
Maybe it's not that heavy.
I would guess 100 kilos,
but I'm just guessing.
-It's just...
-Now it's bombs.
-Ouch! Ouch, ouch. Was he really shot?
-But, like, what?
No, he probably wasn't shot because then
he would have screamed a lot, but shit.
Take the weapon from him!
-People like that shouldn't have guns.
-But why does he turn around?
And then just "Ah, but hey! Bam!"
Okay, a bit louder, please.
That was all the videos we had for today.
Good Lord, my heart just pounds.
And it doesn't stop.
You're just "Uh, uh, uh!" all the time.
You're just up here.
You get such an adrenaline rush.
You just don't get a quiet moment.
But hopefully no one died
or got excessively injured, I hope.
I felt most sorry for that snake.
And those little sheep. No, Lord.
It was really fun making this video.
Thanks so much to those who suggested
reacting to near-death experiences.
A really good suggestion.
So more comments,
spam with suggestions.
Don't forget, if you like these videos,
give a thumbs up, it will make us happy.
-Write a comment and...
-...subscribe.
-So, I hope you have a really great day.
-We'll see you soon again. Goodbye.