A shareholder agreement is a legal document where the shareholders in a limited company agree on the company's structure and how the company's operations are to be controlled.
When running a company with several other partners, it is always highly recommended to establish a shareholder agreement.
The reason is that it wants to agree on how the company and the partners should act in different situations that may arise in the future.
The main purpose of this is that you want to avoid future conflicts that can harm the company or you as a shareholder.
The most important thing about shareholder agreements can be divided into 3 parts:
1. That the agreement is clear and exhaustive.
2. That you have agreed on what is happening in unexpected incidents.
3. How you regulate the transfer of shares
Regarding the 1st paragraph, it is important for you to think about formulating the shareholder agreement as clearly as possible.
This means that any requirements on the partners must be formulated with a simple language.
Any requirements for sales volume per partner or similar must be quantifiable.
This is especially true if these goals are linked to clauses for when you, as a partner, have to forcibly sell their holding.
In addition to clarity, it is very important that a shareholder agreement is exhaustive.
This means that the shareholder agreement will in principle affect all eventualities that may arise in the future.
Paragraph 2 is about regulating what happens in unexpected incidents with a major impact on the company.
Here are the most important issues that the agreement should regulate:
What if a partner goes away?
What happens to the shares if a partner would differ?
What happens if a partner becomes long -term sick leave?
And what happens if a partner neglects their obligations?
It is common to regulate these points by allowing the married partners to have a marriage order that exempts the shares from being included in a division of housing.
In the shareholder agreement, it is also possible to decide that the shares in the event of death or divorce have a certain price,
And that other shareholders have pre -emption rights on these shares.
A strong tip is to also write a clause for when you as a shareholder must forcibly sell their shares.
An example of such a criterion may be in case of long -term sick leave.
Or if the co -owner does not achieve a certain sales requirement for a given period.
Paragraph 3 is about regulating the transfer of shares.
It is common for you as a partner to do not want you to be able to sell their shares to anyone.
You can limit this right by bringing home the home delegation, pre-purchase, repurchase and consent clauses in the agreement.
These four different clauses regulate how any repurchases or sales of shares should go in favor of other shareholders.
Now we will go through what these different clauses mean.
A home messenger clause means that former owners of a certain share have pre -emption right on that share if an outsider has received it through, for example, inheritance or gift.
The right of pre -emption means that you give other partners the right to buy the shares before others can buy the shares.
In this way, you can avoid unwanted partners buying themselves into the company.
A repurchase clause regulates the right to buy back shares that have previously been sold for a certain period of a pre -stated amount.
This can be smart to do if you let in a partner who does not turn out to be a good match a little further ahead.
Consumption clauses stipulate that in some cases a shareholder must obtain the consent of the Board or Annual General Meeting before a transfer of shares takes place.
This further increases control over who can become part -owners.
The very last thing you should keep in mind is to ban the shareholders from being able to pledge the shares.
If you want help with writing a shareholder agreement, feel free to contact us at simple law.
Thanks for watching! Feel free to press the Like button if the video was useful.
Do you have questions? Do not hesitate to ask your question in the comments field on Youtube or contact us on our website simeljuridik.se