Hey, today I was going to clean a shower room at a public bathing facility.
So I was going to go through some basics, talk about what you need to have, to do a good job on walls and floors.
It is important that we have protective equipment.
Long gloves, goggles, there are slightly different variants, boots or protective shoes.
We will work with an alkaline agent and an acidic agent.
We will work out the agent with a foam cannon,
And we will work with brushes, soft brushes.
And we will use floor scraper.
The alkaline agent is an agent that removes organic dirt.
Organic dirt is, among other things, fat, what we have on the body, oils etc. and this will end up on the wall.
When you shower and soap your entire body, the dirt ends up in a radius around the body, a little bit on the side and down.
We have talked about the importance of goggles.
For example, when we have to fill the foam cannon, this is often where the accidents happen ...
It can splash in the eyes and then it is very important that we have goggles.
Should the accident occur, it is good to have eye shower, I have a portable eye shower.
Most often, the eye shower is in a storage room where we store the chem.
But great to have a portable if the accident should occur.
We're running
We will start by applying the alkaline agent and I take on the glasses.
Now I have prepared with alkaline agent in the foam cannon.
We will work with cold water, or barely lukewarm.
It is because the chemist works best with cold water.
If you don't have access to cold water in the taps, make sure you get it.
We will start by applying from the bottom and further up.
And why do we do that
Well, if we start from the top and go down, the agent can run down, and fat and oils penetrate joints and give discoloration.
So that's why we put from below and go up.
I show.
And here you do not have to put on every centimeter, have an even flow upwards.
Let's go
I put the chemical out to the shower head.
I also put a string at the bottom.
Important, put down the cannon because if it falls, they often break.
We will work with soft, or medium -hard brushes.
And when we put out the chem, we let it work for five minutes.
Like that, now five minutes have passed and it's time to start working on the surfaces.
I know many people enjoy working with scurry blocks,
But for best results we use brushes.
If we use scrubblock now I hold it with a handle but there is also for rod,
Then you do not get into the joints, does not matter how hard I press, I do not get into the joint.
And then we get a bad result.
Work with brushes.
And, here it is important that you do not push the brush so hard, now we just have to work out the drug.
If we press too hard, then you see what happens to the hair on the brush,
they bend aside and then we will not ate the joints
Without now, we will work back and forth, important that we work in the corners.
We work in one direction first and then we take the next direction.
As you can see, I don't take much.
We work with the floor as well, and here we have special floors, with a lot of structure so we should not slip,
So here it is extra important that we access every millimeter.
Work back and forth, do not press with the brush but let the chemistry and the brush work.
So now that we have worked with the chemistry and of course with the whole wall, I disconnect the foam cannon.
Now we will rinse off.
It is important to find a beam that is adequate.
Rinse plenty of water.
As I said before: Important to work with cold water or barely lukewarm.
If you work with warm water you get an aerosol formation, and we do not want that.
So then we have run the alkaline agent.
Now we will take the sour agent.
The acidic agent removes inorganic dirt.
Such as salt, urine, sweat, lime etc.
Goggles on
We dose in the same way, from the bottom up.
The agent flows about 30 cm, and this is because it is gel -based agents.
I post
Do you now see on the surface that the chem is flowing down, but only a short distance, because it is gel -based.
While it is running down, the agent works with the dirt and we let it work for five minutes.
Now it's been five minutes and it's time to work.
We do the same way.
Then, when we run the entire surface, we rinse.
Remember to put the cannon on the floor.
We rinse off.
This is how we have worked with the sour drug.
When working with shower walls and floors, we work with the alkaline agent 2 days.
So only the alkaline agent and then for example Monday and Tuesday
Then, the third day, on Wednesday, you take the sour agent
So two days alkaline and one day sour.
Then you get the best out of the funds and you get a nice and clean plant.
After every time you have run chemistry and when you are done with the flushing you should work with the surface disinfection.
Now we have flushed away the chem and we have scraped dry.
Then it's time to put out surface disinfection.
And the surface disinfection removes bacteria, viruses and algae.
It goes down about a few cm in the joint.
Normally you lay it out with a low pressure syringe.
There are slightly different variants on low -pressure syringes.
Now I have already dosed clearly and this is done with water and chemistry.
I start it.
We post.
You don't have to spray the entire surface.
You see it becomes a spray fog
Such more than that you don't have to do
Now you let the agent work for 15 minutes after that you can go in and shower.
So you don't flush this.
This kills bacteria and viruses.
Ok a small summary of what we have done here today.
We have used an alkaline agent.
A gel -based agent that removes the organic dirt eg shampoo, oil fat etc.
We have used an acidic agent that removes sweat, salt, urine, lime etc.
The inorganic dirt.
We have used a surface disinfection that removes bacteria, viruses and algae.
To my help I have used a foam cannon, a low -pressure syringe, soft and medium -hard brushes and a scraper.
When you have done this, you will have a brilliant fine facility and your customers will come back to your bath.