Good morning everyone, then.
Those of you who watched our last vlog saw that Hailey was going to have a little party.
So listen now Definition party! But she has girl friends at home and sleep downstairs
in the little house.
The headline read Hailey is moving to the little house and this was a little test to see
if we could live in the little house.
So, she is 13 years old.
It is clear that she will live by herself in a purple house, but then,
she will never solve it.
First of all, it's like this When you live alone or live in a house, then
you have to keep some order, some order and things like that.
Alina Knapgök! Stop running! But when I came down this morning that I didn't panic
and think about I can cut in.
I'm cutting in here next to me now.
A film sequence that I filmed when I came in and just to the point, I hear that
today my parents are coming home again and then I have to make sure that it's kind of
nice here.
So yes, we have a bit of work to do, one might say.
But they have started and that is good.
And I have started the dishwasher.
But now I'm going to do the washing because it's necessary to say the least.
And I will also fill up so we can get.
When mom comes home, they just go Oh my God, how did you manage to get it this
nice.
Well, I'll tell you that.
We've cleaned for a living, but
even in here they haven't been like that.
In here, it's quite nice to turn on the underfloor heating a bit because it's a bit half raw
outside.
But I'm going to start the dishwasher, the washing machine and clean up a bit and
this croft will be in order in time too.
Even if it takes a little time, I can imagine so it can be there.
So now it is.
Pretty tidy here again anyway.
But yes, you could say it was an experience.
Now I have a severe cleaning obsession, so I've said you can clean up after yourselves.
Now I mean a little cleaning.
This one needs some lubrication 5:56.
But now we must go and fix the horses anyway.
We are going for a walk with all the horses.
Oh No, it's hug snow.
Oh shit! Wondering if it is possible to walk up the hill without getting stilts?
We have to try.
Maybe it will work.
I get to bring the hoof scraper and scratch the hooves.
It is quite soft in the forest.
I wonder what that sound is, but it's my phone. But you feel that it is plus degrees or it is
zero and plus.
But it was so damn good for their bodies to go climbing the round and sometimes
it's actually good not to ride without walking alongside because then they kind of get to
use their whole body.
But to work in a free way.
If you understand what i mean.
So we go round the climbs.
We hope it works.
Here I am waiting for the children to go and get the horses so we can go out and
the vafas never finished but got the horses.
We're going out for a walk in the woods and I'll leave the camera at home because it wo
n't be fun to film anyway so I'll see you later.
Now me and Robin are going down to the car shop.
I'm going down, stop there to
the car dealer because my car has been inside.
It has been sick.
No, it's been in for service so I'll pick it up now and then we'll go to
KC and buy some more Valentine's Day stuff or more.
I have bought a few and now I think I have to tie the sack and get
it sorted.
Because it actually is.
Hello! There aren't that many here.
Well, so it will be.
there at Beckis? Yes, it's small, but it's actually a bit bad with sledding slopes here
And there aren't that many people down here.
No, it isn't.
Yes, so now I have collected the key to the car and am going home again.
It's a bit cloudy outside, but I think.
Because now the snow is going away and I think that hopefully there won't be any more
snow now because I'm moderately tired of snow, God knows.
But back home again and now the car is serviced and fine.
Good God, then you can drive a couple more miles with a clear conscience.
What a thing! Let's see when you drive away.
Perfect.
I think you have to grab and pull it by hand.
Hey sweetie! E so cuddly, so cuddly.
Oh, you're going to have lunch soon, so now I'm going to take it and drive home again.
It's very fun! Now it's the perfect surface for kicking because the snow
is so packed and I'm so happy.
I bought that kick last year and we just loved the little Calypso.
Big and when you.
No, very, very good.
Those of you who know me know that I never cook, and Robin does all
the cooking here at home, which I am so grateful for.
But now I have his girlfriends here and Robin is doing lots of important
things that I don't know what.
And then I got to be the one responsible for the cooking and it can be fun.
Said myself very funny that I'm standing here
Yes, I understand that.
But I'm now making chicken.
I can't decide if that's enough chicken, but I
think so.
So there will be chicken, rice and then I will make my own sauce which is very, very
tasty.
It's
creme fraiche and chilli sauce.
Then if you want.
If you feel this way that you don't like creme fraiche, there is also
béarnaise sauce and it may not be the best combo in the world, but it's still an
okay combo.
But it's a chili sauce like this and it's super super tasty and it's also a very
quick lunch and you're a little hip like this
Type like that.
Is it.
is there water flowing anywhere?
Boiling.
Chicken fried chicken Cook rice.
running No water.
you shouldn't be worried while I stand here
And wait.
Yes I know.
They are.
Four pers.
Four a little less.
But these are food-loving children, I think.
They are gymnasts, they have to eat properly.
Yes, as long as I'm going to eat too.
So there are five of us then.
You can also eat.
It's chicken.
I'll make a little extra and we can take what's left over,
I think.
We're going.
What is it called? Clams yesterday? Makes you not so full of it.
But you will be gratefully full.
But you're not like when you eat tacos and are full for four days.
So it's done.
I think I'll add some more chicken.
This is Rose's chicken
that we got from my brother-in-law.
To test.
This is frozen through because I want Hectare Robin's tractor boiler because then
you could sort of let it sit and simmer so it gets heat from above as well, but I couldn't
borrow it.
So now it will be this instead.
Will take a while.
Oh how it boils here so
I season with salt, garlic and pepper.
There are three spices that I like very much myself.
It's about seasoning with what you like.
Then I also like chili, but I think we shouldn't
make too much of it.
And now I came up with something.
She was allergic to nuts.
Now we don't have any nuts here, but
it might be good to keep an eye on the fact that one of the girls can't stand nuts.
But otherwise so.
Yes.
Let's get meaty here.
So now we're starting to show up here.
It's still very cozy when you set the table and usually we always take our food
in the kitchen.
It's not like it's super long in between, but it happens.
So the food is getting ready anyway.
Which feels good.
kokelikok
I just got a bid on the post that was also opened, but that's, I think
from.
Prime
which is.
Super fun.
I haven't ordered anything from Prime, but I have received.
A lid with Prime.
You see what this was then.
Prime energy drink ice pop.
The children must not taste this.
We got Prime the other day but then there was no energy.
So this one.
If you have tasted this please comment on it and comment on what you like
which prime you like.
I've never really tasted them.
Oh, it tastes like a mix of probably the red and the blue.
I probably only taste the red, but very sweet.
I rarely drink energy drinks, but thank you so much Prime! Mmmmm.
Yes, can drink a little or so.
Give it away to someone I know likes Prime very much.
But I think it's fun to get these things because it's fun to try new
things.
But then, as I said, I don't drink very much.
Or not energy drinks at all because I don't think that's what I experience when
I myself drink energy drinks that I get very energetic then of course.
But then I also get very, very tired.
So the question is whether you become like that.
That it will have a negative effect.
But then there was another delivery here.
But I think it was for Robin because it was an
electric car charger.
Our company has both in both my company and also Robin's company.
After all, we have the company together, among other things, and what it looks like here.
I go crazy and then there may be deliveries of things that are not for me.
It's boring enough without him.
But that's how it is.
I'm going to go into Haley's room and sneak something.
After all, I have been the world's opponent of snail slime.
I think it's so disgusting.
So just the thought of sticking killer slugs in my face makes
me want to start crying.
Type.
Now I say hello.
Ah but then I'm having a mental breakdown
This Then we have Hailey's solution to all the world's problems and that is to
throw everything away.
Maybe I should get dressed, but you see here, I'm panicking.
However, I think I might have to take a little bit of responsibility for looking the way it does in
her room because I called her, can you go out to Chloe's and hang out with
her? And then I think she dropped everything and left.
But this is no exception and something she uses far
too much.
It's pads like these makeup pads and it's because she.
So for real huh? I will buy this.
So really lose it.
And that's because she.
I kind of can't bear to talk anymore because I get so irritated.
She is so careless.
What's up with kids today? To be so extremely careless? Or is it just my
child? Because now I'm losing it.
Hard huh? So parenthood.
Help me please.
I'm so tired.
What I would say about snail slime.
Now that I've trudged out of Hailey's bedroom, I'm going to try that
the other day.
Because in my feed everywhere it shows up how good.
Snail slime is here.
Or this snail it is this one.
So I had to try it and I kind of liked it.
Which the character in me.
Went in and ordered three more products like this.
I'll feature them in another video because they haven't come home yet.
But feel free to comment if you have tried snail slime in any form.
And feel free to comment!
What did you think of it, because as I said I have been against it because I think
it is so gross to think of getting snail slime on my face considering that
I hate, no hate, loathe snails.
At least the slime.
But if you think they could have named it something else they could have named it Super
Power Serum, I wouldn't have thought of that.
But is it so? Snail in.
But feel free to comment what you think and
if you have any products.
I have understood that there are slightly different products like this, because there is
this one that is like this.
And then is there any face cream, any eye cream? I think what I
ordered was the face cream and eye cream.
But then I saw.
There is another brand of this too.
So yes, there is little to choose from.
But go ahead with comments because it feels like I said many who follow us are a bit
in the same generation with tik tok and other things
So yes.
I also have to say I am now using the Charlotte Tilbury Flawless filter.
I really like that foundation, or it's more like a serum foundation
But it is yes.
I like a lot and also Huda's baking powder also superb! Lots of fun,
lots of fun.
That's a lot, I can say.
But tik tok that you have learned or received a lot of tips about some fun products
to use.
Above all, as my make-up routine has become completely different, which is super fun.
As a surprise.
You haven't filmed Robin Robban's kitchen?
It's a little dark in Robban's kitchen today.
But then thought.
I not so much.
So then it will be at Robban's kitchen today.
Since it's so much like pork, stew etc.
Not so advanced, just with mushrooms and shallots and cream and ghee.
What are you going to eat then?
I'm going to eat like.
I'm going to eat chili sin carne.
And it will be.
Yes, it's chili without the meat.
Chili con carne, without minced meat.
Without minced meat, mince and.
Beans too.
Or I'll start, me
and.
Böna and I will perhaps see what is available.
Kidney beans and white beans.
Yes, and I would hectare with a small one so it will be easy like this.
And do I have crushed tomatoes?
And paprika?
Shall I share it for you? I can run it in my blender.
No I do not know.
Got something I missed.
Yes, Janne.
I like my pieces.
You are boring.
Greece is a success.
I didn't say it was bad.
I said I like my pieces.
Now my father is finally coming home again and they are coming up here to eat so I
am setting the table
a bit.
Hello! We have one friend left.
There will be as many of us as the table.
Yes, the table is full, seven.
It will be cozy.
I still think it's nice.
And now it's time for us who live on the west coast but who live in Västra Götaland.
But it was so strange because no, only Kungsbacka but not Varberg.
It's weird.
Gothenburgers.
And also Skövde and Trollhättan and these.
But the strange thing is that not Orust, they were sort of deported from LOV.
They follow through on the promise the week after that.
But yes, then you have to take care and have a little fun, I think.
Yes, so very cozy.
What dinner do you know? Fantastic! We go clams.
Clams yesterday.
Yeah, do you like it? Can you taste Robins here.
And dad doesn't like clams.
Not salmon anyway.
I don't know mussels.
It's not salmon.
Was it good? It was swinging.
Robin is great at cooking and the other side.
Now it's food.
I'm walking around looking for my cell phone and wondering where did I put it? And then
it is next to the coffee cup.
Good point.
God, my eyes are watering so much and I look very tanned again.
But I'm not.
Or yes, on cheating.
It's time to end today's vlog and I've kind of had a reaction to
something so I've kind of swollen up one eye during the night.
I don't know if you can see it, but it is like that.
Or the eyelid is completely swollen.
But thank you so much for watching this blog and thanks also
to everything else you've watched on our channel.
And one thing for this vlog we did before this blog which was about
we've been to a funeral and we were going to do a video where we pay tribute to
everyone, everyone, everyone or someone we know or someone we miss or if we've
lost does not necessarily have to be a person.
That video really has the East on with such amazingly nice comments.
Feel free to go in and look at it and just be filled with love because it was so nice.
And even though sometimes I said oh that was fun and you wrote something, everyone
really took the opportunity and did it, which I thought was incredibly beautiful.
So thanks for that! But now we have to finish this video and now
our sports holiday also begins.
We are not going to do anything special other than to go and compete, probably this
weekend at Grevagården, Thursday to Sunday.
So we are really looking forward to that.
But hope you are having a great time and that you are well! And if you have a sports holiday,
I hope you have a great holiday! Take care and we'll see you again soon.
Bye!