Hello philosophers, my name is Joakim and welcome to the second and closing video
Where we investigate Friedrich Nietzsche's philosophical ideas.
If you haven't seen some, click here.
With the pointed wording "God is dead!" meant Nietzsche that time is coming to see
The old interpretations - especially the belief in God - for what they are, myths and fairy tales.
But he also realized that many would be despairing of the realization that we are nothing but
meaningless animals in a meaningless universe.
This newly acquired insight risked leading to a state of nihilism, the belief that everything has no meaning.
If life is without goals, meaning or purpose, then it easily follows the perception that all the suffering of life is in vain.
“Nihilism arises now, not because the plagues of life have become greater, but because you have lost the belief that there is someone
'Meaning' with suffering ... it now seems that no meaning exists, like everything is in vain. ”
Nietzsche wrestled himself with nihilism for much of his life
when he claimed that life lacked objective meaning.
He even meant that it was not only life that lacked objective meaning,
But that "truth" in itself does not exist.
Thus, objective knowledge becomes impossible and as a consequence thereof
cannot be objective meaning with anything.
Instead, the individual is always limited by his own interpretation.
“The work of painting the image of life, however often poets and philosophers is given on it,
is nevertheless meaningless: even in the hands of the largest painting benches
Is everything that comes from a thumbnail from a life, one's own life - nothing else is possible. "
Because one cannot possibly flee one's interpretation or perspective on life, Nietzsche meant that one should
Give up all attempts to find objective truth and instead interpret the existence in a life -promoting way.
Because if there are no truths in the world now, it is not a truth
That life must be meaningless to the individual.
The road from nihilism thus goes by creating subjective meaning.
He called for a change in which people - inspired by the crisis that arises when the objective values die -
would fill the void after religion with philosophy and art.
According to Nietzsche, the deepest questions you can ask in life are "Why do I live" and "Why do I suffer".
He meant that these two issues were actually one and the same.
Man seeking a meaning or purpose of life precisely because life is a torment
And she wants to believe that this suffering has a purpose.
"Man, the brave of animals and used to suffering, does not reject the suffering as such; he desires that,
Seeking it, provided he is shown a sentence for it, a purpose of suffering. The pointless suffering,
Not the suffering itself, is the curse that has so far been over humanity. "
By pondering his own suffering, he concluded that pain is not something negative.
Instead, he claimed that a life without suffering and misery would be a miserable life.
The suffering is instead a prerequisite for self -realization.
From the pain and suffering one always comes out stronger than before,
Something Nietzsche formulated as "what doesn't kill me makes me stronger".
“You want, if possible - which it is not - abolish the suffering. And we? We want to suffer more and more intensely
than ever ... because it is suffering that underlies all human development. "
For this reason he also hated alcohol.
It relieves and assures us that life is good as it is and that change is not necessary.
Nietzsche himself only drank water.
On solemn occasions milk.
Based on the fact that suffering is a prerequisite for progress, Nietzsche believed that we are in need of an ideal
To keep us motivated in our pursuit of greatness even in the darkest of hours.
His answer to such an ideal was the superhuman, "das übermensch".
In English, the term is often translated into "Superman" and is the inspiration behind the cartoon character with the same name
- But the similarities in general are few.
“I teach you superhuman. Man is something to be overcome. What have you done to overcome him? ”
Superhuman as ideal was a perfect and powerful creature that has overcome
all their inner fears, weaknesses and flaws.
One who floats over the rest of humanity.
The superhuman ideal is only accessible to us in short moments.
It is impossible to maintain this perfection.
After these ecstatic moments, one must always return to "being human, too human".
By comparing himself to the superhuman, Nietzsche meant that we could be aware of our shortcomings
And weaknesses, and are ashamed of the large gap that separates us from the ideal.
In the pursuit of this perfection, we will start hating our non-perfect self.
This soul hatred, Nietzsche claimed, be the beginning of the Supreme man's self -realization.
For only when we realized our internal flaws, and welcomed our disgust for them,
Are we motivated to grow and overcome ourselves.
In the book "So Zarathustra" Nietzsche describes in a parable how flaws and suffering
are necessary for self -realization.
“I met a young shepherd with suffocation, spasms and a distorted face.
Out of his mouth hung a heavy black snake.
I had never seen so much nausea and fear in someone's face.
I did what I could to tear the snake out of his throat, but in vain.
'Bit! Bit of its head! Bit! ', I screamed ...
The shepherd bit, and he bit well.
He spit out the snake's head and jumped up.
No longer shepherd, no longer man - changed, brilliant, laughing!
Never have I heard a man laugh like he laughed!
O my brothers, what I heard was no human laugh. "
Here the shepherd represents a man in his darkest moments and the black snake
is the despair and fear that plagues him in life.
But when he bites the snake's head, he overcomes his demons
and appears for a moment as the superhuman himself.
His laughter symbolizes power, perfectionism and an affirmation to life.
There is somewhat unclear if Nietzsche imagined the superior as the next evolutionary phase
(After all, he was inspired by Charles Darwin and Evolution Theory)
Or if he rather referred to an individual moral development.
To affirm life was the highest state a man could achieve, and Nietzsche presented two concepts
To describe this: Amor Fati (love for fate) and eternal repetition.
To affirm life, we must first accept it just as it is, live in harmony with fate.
Amor Fati is an approach characterized by fearlessness, sadness and power of action.
Where the weak passively waits to be loved, the strong unconditionally loves from his inner power.
Amor Fati is a characteristic of the superhuman,
"My formula for greatness in a human being is Amor Fati," Nietzsche writes.
But in order to love fate, one must first affirm life and it is among the most difficult there is.
The difficulty lies in the fact that existence contains so much evil, pain, suffering and tragedy.
So how can you affirm life in the presence of so much ugliness?
As we have seen, Nietzsche claims that large amounts of suffering and pain are needed to develop.
"It is from the deepest of depth that the highest comes to its height".
With this insight, the strong understand that the evil, painful and tragic
In fact, has an inherent beauty.
In these aspects of existence there is the potential for growth and self -realization.
Only when a black snake crawls down your neck can you bite off its head
And laugh like no man has laughed before.
“I want to learn more and more to see the beautiful in the necessary;
Then I will become one of those who make things beautiful.
Amor Fati: Let it be my love from now on!
I don't want to wage war against the ugly ...
And everything and on the whole. One day I want to be a yes-sayer. "
To determine if you are a yes-sayer, that is, in a state of complete life-affirming,
Nietzsche created a psychological test which he called eternal repetition.
“What if a demon suddenly seeks you in your loneliness and says:
'The life you are now alive, and have lived, you will be allowed to live through and countless times;
It will contain nothing new, every moment of pain and joy, every thought and every sight,
All the small and all the great things in your life comes again - in the same consequence ... '
Do you want to throw yourself down and squeeze your teeth and curse the demon? Or have you ever experienced such a large
moment that you answer him: "You are a god and never have I heard anything more divine". "
The superhuman confirms life and realizes that his greatest moments are born out of his darkest experiences,
And therefore perceives the inherent beauty in suffering, tragedy and evil.
With this insight, he does not condemn life like a pessimist, despite the suffering he has endured.
Instead, he celebrates the tragedy as a happy yes-sayer.
When he then approaches his death, the superhuman does not want to rest.
Instead, he wishes for eternal repetition and to live about his life again forever.
On his deathbed, should you say “Was it life? Once again, death! ”
Concepts such as "übermensch" and "the will to power" were used extensively by Hitler and the Nazis
To describe his idea of a biologically superior Aryan or Germanic gentleman.
Nietzsche's thoughts thus came to be regarded as a philosophical basis for the national socialist ideas.
This connection is largely due to Nietzsche's sister Elisabeth, who was a dedicated Nazi,
counterfeit a number of texts to suit Nazism's ideology.
Nietzsche himself was very critical of both anti -Semitism and German nationalism during its lifetime.
According to him, the superhuman was something that could occur in all cultures.
He, on the other hand, was an elitist and said that some people were better than others.
But this had nothing to do with race or nationality.
His questioning of "old truths" has influenced both existentialism
as the descendant postmodernism.