Thales from the city of Miletos in present Turkey (at that time belonging to Greece)
is usually considered the first Western philosopher.
This means that he wanted to find an alternative to the prevailing mythological explanation for the origin of everything.
Like many other natural philosophers, Thales was mainly employed by the question of what kind of material the world consisted of.
He searched for the origin of everything, a common building block or a watch - something he called Arche.
His response came to be 'water' because he could see that water at very low temperature
Was hard as stone (ice) and at high temperatures like air (steam).
When it was raining, plants penetrated from the soil, something he interpreted as being water in some form.
Everything living needed a large and constant intake of water to continue to live.
(Our bodies actually consist of about 60 percent water.)
Each land mass ended at the water's edge, something that Thales interpreted as the soil surface floating on the water.
It is the first known attempt to set up a general theory based on observations of reality.
Thale's greatness lies in the fact that with the help of reason he tried to draw conclusions about the world he lived in.
The fact that this was not quite right is less important in this context.
In addition to physics (which would be the modern definition of Thales theory), he also devoted himself to astronomy.
He must have calculated the size of the sun to 720 times larger than the moon (today we mean that the sun is about 400 times larger than the moon),
And it was he who divided the year into four seasons, the month for 30 days and estimated the days of the year at 365.
In addition, he must have been the person who introduced mathematics in Greece, something he must have learned in Egypt.
He has also contributed his own discoveries in the subject, mainly through what we today feel like Thales theorem
- That the strip angle to a semi -circle is always 90 °.
Unfortunately, none of Thale's writings are preserved (he must have written two philosophical works),
Without everything we know about him comes from other historical renovations.
He must have died at the age of 78, exhausted by heat, age and thirst, as a spectator during the 58th Olympiad in Athens.