The Taoist monk Zhuang Zi was always happy, positive and energetic.
But one day his disciples found him sitting in his room, crying with confusion.
They asked him what had happened, after which he told me he was dreaming he was a butterfly.
He had known the wind, the smells and how he flew around - just as if he had been there.
The disciples looked surprised, wondering what was the problem?
The monk replied, “Now I don't know if I'm a monk who dreams I'm a butterfly,
Or a butterfly that dreams that I am a monk. "
Even in ancient Greece, philosophers were wondering if the world was perhaps only an illusion,
And Plato claimed that everything we perceived was only shadow pictures of reality.
Enlightenment philosopher René Descartes questioned whether it is possible to trust our senses,
And Arthur Schopenhauer concluded that we do not really exist as human beings.
Swedish philosopher Nick Bostrom claims in a modern theory on the same theme that the world we live in is only one
Computer simulation, and thus nothing is for real.
We will take a closer look at the so -called simulation argument.
Theory is based on statistical probability, and is based on the assumption
that computer technology will continue to develop.
Bostrom believes that technological developments within, for example, artificial intelligence in the future can lead to
Computer simulations that are so real that the simulations themselves think they are real.
We are far from the technical possibilities today,
But who knows what we have the opportunity for 1,000, 100,000 or millions of years.
Bostrom sees three future scenario:
The first means that the human species die out before we have developed the possibility of simulating
human consciousness. Everything is peace and joy, and no simulation will happen.
The second alternative means that technology can develop, but that, for example, it moral
or legal reasons will never be tested.
This scenario sees Bostrom himself as the least likely when a technology like this would be interesting for
humanity. But that is, after all, an opportunity.
The third alternative means that the technology will be developed and actually used as well.
The number of simulated worlds will probably be large, you would not have been attracted by running one
Simulation on your computer and see how the "people" develop and ponder the mysteries of life?
Which of the above options do you see as most likely?
If you have answered option three, you have also just "proven" that we are all in such a simulation.
For what would the probability be that we belong to the real world, when there may be thousands,
Not to say millions of simulated worlds?
Statistically, it is almost non -existent, which is why we are a simulation.
Perhaps every simulation in turn can develop so far that it creates its own simulations, and that it thus
may be several levels of reality.
Maybe this is the meaning of life,
Maybe they are met by us who have lived "right" by a "welcome to level 2" after we died.
Maybe God is just a teenager in front of his computer.
In fact, some researchers believe that we are no further than a few decades from being able to simulate conscious life.
But to simulate a whole world would of course require huge capacity,
But maybe not as much as we first expect.
Instead of simulating the world in detail, you only need to simulate what can actually be perceived.
Other galaxies and planets need not be simulated in greater detail than light flashes are perceived from the earth,
And the microscopic world only needs to be simulated in detail when someone actually looks at it.