The ancient philosophy, with its questioning of old truths,
Come during the Middle Ages on collision with the teachings of Christianity.
Where philosophy emphasized rational and free thinking
emphasized Christianity and the inadequacy of human reason.
Because of the great power and influence of the church during the period
Most philosophers also came to be clearly linked to the church.
Therefore, the philosophy came to deal mainly in the Middle Ages to address issues of religious nature
- for example the theodicé problem (how can God be good and almighty
when there is evil and suffering in the world).
An example we find in Bishop Augustinus, born in the present Algeria, at that time part of the Roman Empire.
Inspired by what is called newly plated, an interpretation of Plato's idea theory, he came to bring together
Philosophy and religion by considering the Platonic ideas as thoughts in God's consciousness.
Just as Plato adds greater value to the world of ideas than the world of mind, Augustine will influence
Medieval Christianity to exalting the soul and downplaying the physical and material.
When the woman in the Middle Ages (and perhaps even today) came to be more associated with physicality than man,
came this depreciation of the bodily indirectly to become a dismissal of the woman.
Another medieval philosopher, and like one of Christianity's great theologians, was Thomas by Aquino.
From a philosophical perspective, he is best known for adapting Aristotle's theories to the Christian faith.
Aristotle's writings had been forgotten in Europe for 1000 years,
But in the Middle East, his writings had been managed by Arab philosophers.
During the 13th century, these books had begun to find their way back to Europe in the form of war changes from crusades,
And Thomas of Aquino came to integrate the Christian worldview with the Aristotelian system.
Christianity would be built on reason and logic,
And the literal Bible interpretation was allowed to be problematized.
Thus, Aristotle came to contribute to the resurrecting of the classic ideas
And the historical period called the Renaissance.
This new era, which lasted from the early 1400s to about 1600,
is usually considered a rebirth of the ancient ideals.
The power of the church decreased and science, literature and art thrived.
Economic, social and political changes occur in society as a result of inventions
Like the gun, the compass and the printing print art.
A clearer dividing line between theology (the doctrine of God) and philosophy is restored.
The English philosopher Francis Bacon is considered one of the precursors to the modern philosophy
when he breaks with the ideals of the Middle Ages and requires philosophy to be based on experiences
And scientific conclusions, so -called induction.
Thus, he also became a precursor to the knowledge theoretical school called empirism.
According to this, all knowledge is ultimately based on the experience of senses
- So they experience we get through our minds.
Now the puzzle pieces were in place for a new generation of philosophers.
Where the Renaissance thinkers were mainly inspired by the story
Wanted the intellectuals of the 17th century to find new ways forward.
And with the enlightenment time, modern philosophy was born.