Throughout history, many major issues have been dealt with in philosophy.
In the name of honesty there are few of those who received a final response
But in any case we have the second best - a number of exciting theories!
One of the questions that man has asked at all times is what the meaning of life is.
Here we will take a closer look at some of the most common answers that can be given to that question.
These are far from comprehensive but are examples of how to reason.
The interesting thing is what you think!
Maybe the meaning of the life of everyone is to achieve their personal potential?
This is a thought that (consciously or unconsciously) shaped the lives of many people
And is probably what drives our foremost athletes, musicians, artists and others.
According to theory, the meaning of life is subjective
And examples of such views of life are humanism and existentialism.
Existentialists such as Jean-Paul Sartre have built its entire philosophy on this starting point.
He believes that man must create his own meaning because there is not
some congenital purpose with human existence.
A theory related to the previous one is about the meaning of life to be
to develop the human species.
Here you highlight the meaning of the individual and believe that together we strive for a larger goal,
to achieve the potential of the human species.
One philosophy that partly represented this focus was Friedrich Nietzsche with his idea of the superhuman.
A theory reminiscent of the previous one finds in Charles Darwin's theory of evolution.
According to this, the meaning of life is survival.
But since we all have limited life length, this leads us to the meaning of life
Will reproduce, to pass on their genes and their species.
But even though Darwin felt that this was the meaning of life, he claimed with determination
that there was no purpose behind this.
It was just so it had happened to slump.
Sometimes it is claimed that all theories referring to a subjective meaning of life have one thing in common
- That we feel good when we reach our goals.
Instead of formulating several different theories, such as the meaning of life is love or to have their
Wishes fulfilled, maybe the meaning of life is simply to achieve happiness.
The theory is called hedonism and has its roots in ancient Greece and philosopher epicurosis with a
Modern variant in utilitarianism and the principle greatest possible happiness for the greatest possible number.
Hedonism (and variants thereof) is relatively common as a view of life in today's society,
But there are objections.
One such is Robert Nozick's thought experiment "The experience machine".
He thinks of a large machine you can connect
against, a machine that feeds the brain with experiences and happiness, all while your body is still.
A hedonist should then reasonably think that a life linked to such a machine would be the perfect life
Since it is only the experience of happiness that is important.
But this is contrary to most people's intuition for a good life;
For example, we do not just want to experience love, we want to love and be really loved.
An answer to the meaning of life is to live in accordance with God's will.
This religious answer is compatible with all the great religions
And has had a huge significance for our history.
Even today, in many places in the world, laws are based on religious beliefs.
The view is based on the fact that some kind of God is in the objective truth.
Life is then based on understanding this truth and as far as possible to follow it.
To their aid, you have sacred writings such as the Bible, the Qur'an or the Tora.
Often, this view of life is associated with the belief in an afterlife, either in heaven, hell or over again on earth.
Many are attracted by the call of religion to live a morally good life,
But have a hard time accepting the idea of a God.
Then the meaning of life may be to live morally right - to be a good person.
To their aid, you have a number of theories about what right is, such as mindset ethics, consequence ethics and rule ethics.
A pessimistic response to the meaning of life could be that it
Mainly consists of suffering and misery.
One representative of this view was Arthur Schopenhauer who believed that life is defined by just suffering.
Life is bad because it is the final proof that our lives are completely meaningless.
Only the knowledge that we will one day die makes us stand out with life.
In the same way, we stand out with the idea that we should die because life is still a torment.
Sometimes one encounters people who not only mean that life is meaningless
But which also distance himself from the question itself.
This view is called nihilism after the Latin word "nihil" which means "nothing"
And its foremost representative is Friedrich Nietzsche with his theory that God is dead.
Without God, all significance and the answers and the truth that existed when God "lived" is now gone.
There are no moral values or any meaning to life, which is why everything becomes meaningless.
There is a measure of nihilism in all the theories that dismiss an objective meaning with life,
That is, most of the theories we have raised here.
Some people are annoyed for various reasons on the question of the meaning of life
And mean that there is nothing we humans should think about.
Instead of taking a stand on the issue, you ignore it.
Such a person was the famous psychologist Sigmund Freud who meant that all the thoughts about this
Be unnecessary and only a sign of man's willingness to rise above nature.
He even went so far that he felt that thoughts about the meaning of life
was a sign of a sick mind.