We all have an experience that we are free in our actions.
We choose what we say, we choose what we do.
We can choose to act on our impulses or choose not to live them out.
Despite this, many philosophers ask themselves, and have done so for a long time,
If we are really as free as we feel.
Many even mean that our experience of influence over our actions is a mental
post -construction of an act that was inevitable or even predetermined.
They thus mean that you could not do anything else at this moment but to look at this.
We will look more closely at the problem of free will.
The free will can be defined as the possibility that you could have acted differently.
The problem is based on the fact that we live in a determinated world,
That is, a world where nature is caused.
An apple does not fall to the ground because it decided to leave the branch,
but because of a complex amount of causal effect.
Some of the variables that affect when the apple falls are;
the size and mass of the apple, the size and age of the tree,
the thickness of the branch, possible genetic defects, height above the ground, temperature, rainfall, winds,
Time of year, external influence in the form of animals, and so on ...
What finally causes an apple to fall at exactly a certain time is too complex for a human being
Be able to figure out - we can't possibly know all variables.
Despite this, most people agree that if we knew all the conditions
So we could figure out exactly when the apple would fall.
The fate of the apple is thus determined.
Sometimes in these discussions the term "predetermined" is used in these discussions,
Often thought as synonymous with determinated.
You may say that it is therefore predetermined when the apple will fall.
However, there is a point in not using this term as the term "predetermined" suggests that someone,
Often interpreted as God, in advance has decided when things will happen.
This is usually not what we mean, although there are of course theories
About all events takes place according to God's predetermined plan.
Nature is thus determined, it can theoretically predict if you can all parameters.
This also applies, for example, to physical or economic systems.
If you have knowledge of a projectile's exit speed, output direction, form, the strength of the wind,
Humidity, height above sea level, etc. can be determined exactly where it will land.
Why then would man differ from the basic conditions
That seems to apply to everything else in the universe?
Should we and our brain not obey the same causal effect as anything else,
After all, we are made up of the same matter?
Each time you make a decision on something,
So you make this decision based on past experiences and the current conditions.
Imagine now a hypothetical creature (in philosophy often called Laplace's demon) that has knowledge
About each particle and every event in the universe and has the ability to analyze all this.
Should not then this creature, with one hundred percent insight into how your brain looks and works,
Able to figure out what decision you will make the next moment?
The problem with free will is illustrated when making the comparison between a human brain and a computer.
One accepts the claim that a human is basically to be regarded as an advanced biological
Machine (that is, there is no "magic ingredient", such as a soul) you can ask the question
If a computer will ever be able to make completely free and independent decisions?
Many people spontaneously answer no to that question with reference to a computer always
follows the rules we have set up for its thinking, and that a computer despite its
Huge capacity is always and remains a glorified calculator.
The computer can give us seemingly intelligent and independent answers but behind this lies a
strictly the following by routines created by a program or programmer.
It could never have given us another answer under the exact same circumstances.
Certainly there are great differences between a human being and a computer,
This includes that we are made of meat and blood while the computer is a machine.
But is it really a relevant difference?
Isn't it the function of the brain, what it achieves or leads to that is the interesting?
There is currently not much to indicate that we in the future
could not have the same functionality based on other material.
For example, no one would claim that mathematics was not as true just because the answer came from a computer,
a calculator or a culmin and not from a human brain.
The fact that a computer is designed by people is also not a counter -argument.
Say the person who is not.
The fact that the computer's "thinking" is based on routines and algorithms is of course true,
But it does not necessarily disqualify the computer.
Computers can already learn things on their own today and go beyond what was initially taught them.
In addition, the human brain is full of corresponding "routines and algorithms",
structured as a neural network in our brain.
That is why we can learn things and think.
An example of a "thinking" computer capable of making your own decisions is IBMS Watson,
an artificial intelligence that interprets natural language.
In 2011, Watson won the American version of Jeopardy!
against the human finalists.
Watson is not a regular computer but consists of 90 interconnected servers.
No one claims that Watson has any free will, but the performance illustrates the technological development well.
So do you mean that a computer will never be able to enjoy genuine free will
So you have a challenge in explaining how man can do it.
In a survey from the Max Planck Institute in Leipzig and Bernstein Center for Computational Neuroscience
In Berlin from 2008, 14 healthy subjects were examined with the help of a brain scanner.
Random letters were shown on a screen, a new letter every half -second.
The people had to press a button whenever they felt it during the trial.
The subjects were then allowed to indicate which letter had been shown at that moment
as they decided to press the button.
In this way, the researchers knew when the subjects felt they made the decision.
On average, it took a second between conscious thought and action.
The interesting thing is that an area in the subject's decision area in the brain began to work
Seven seconds before the conscious thought, all according to the brain scanner.
Thus, the unconscious decision process begins first, then our consciousness is "informed" about the decision.
Only at this moment do we also think we make the decision itself.
Of course, this does not apply to situations that require a quick action on our part,
For example, when we drive or face a life -threatening situation.
Maybe, on the other hand, when we change channels on the TV or choose which book to read.
The statement that the brain makes a decision before we know if it is not new.
It is based on research from the 1980s with neurophysiologist Benjamin Libet at the forefront.
Even then it was about subjects to press a button and Libet then discovered as now
that changes in brain activity arose just before we consider us to make a free choice.
Although this is not necessarily the same as the fact that the subjects' decisions about when
They would press the button was determined, so it is still a hard blow to the free will.
For if your brain on your own and completely without your conscious intervention makes a decision
This can hardly be counted as your free choice.
It should be added that in all cases the subjects considered themselves completely free
to press the button when they so desired.
They felt that they made the decision at the same time as they performed the action.
One can ask what it matters whether we actually have a free will or not.
So longer we have the experience of a free will, everything flows as usual in any case.
This is in itself absolutely true, but if there is no free will, this would get
Extreme consequences for, among other things, morality, for right and wrong.
Ethics and morals are about choosing the right or wrong.
Documents that violate our ethics vary from inappropriate (for example, downloading a
copyrighted file) to gross criminal (murder and rape).
Criminis then receives their penalty based on how much they violated our laws and regulations,
which in turn is based on our perception of ethics and morals (right and wrong).
But if our actions are determined, it means that a criminal could never have acted differently.
The person had as much impact on his action as the apple falling from the tree.
But how can one justify the person to be punished?
But we can also turn to the reasoning and claim that it is problematic to punish criminals,
Although they could not affect the crime themselves.
We can easily point out that the punishment in the same way as the crime is determined.
So we had never been able to choose not to punish them.
One problem with determinism is that you easily end up in an “you could not act differently,
I could not act differently ”discussion.
It is easy to point out that whatever is said, it is determined
And nothing else could ever have been said or imagined.
One answer to what enables our "exception" from the otherwise determinated world is that God has given us free will.
In this way, Christianity seems to have been able to effectively solve the problem, but everyone does not agree.
What happens if you are an atheist, if you do not believe in God now?
Until relatively recently, this was a troublesome problem for both philosophy and science.
One had managed to explain how our world works so to the mild degree
that the free will seemed impossible to include.
Then we discovered quantum physics, which gives us a theoretical opportunity to "violate" the laws of nature.
Maybe it is that the true random and non-deported world of quantum physics
Does man's free decision enable?
We do not know how this would work, but it is not an unreasonable hope.
If nothing else, quantum physics puts a complaint for the aforementioned Laplaces demon,
Thus, the hypothetical creature that could predict your actions with insight into everything.
Heisenberg's principle of uncertainty shows that it is not possible with accuracy
know both the position of a particle and its movement.
So it is not as one could easily think that every particle has a definite position
and a definite movement at any given time.
Finally, it can be added that there are different levels of determinism.
Not all determinists mean we have no free choices at all,
But rather points out that the elections may not be as many as we experience them.
In any case, the question of whether we have a free will is interesting and worth considering.