The most insightful of the natural philosophers are the so -called atomists,
A term aimed primarily on democritos (Ca \ H460-370 \ HF \ HKR) and his teacher Leukippos.
They meant that everything is made up of small building blocks they called atoms (Ãtomon is Greek for indivisible).
They had noted that everything is slowly due.
Over time, even mountains and stones are worn out of wind and water
- Thus, seemingly solid objects must consist of less invisible constituents.
The basic question, meant democritos,
Is how does it come to the same material, plants and animals over and over again?
Take an oak tree as an example; Each individual tree is perishable,
But it consists of the same material as all other oaks that ever exist.
The properties of the material oak must therefore be descended from something eternal and unchanging,
Something that comes from within the material itself.
He thought that everything is made up of microscopic atoms
which hooks into each other purely mechanically through small hooks.
A material gets its properties from the shape, size and movement of the atoms.
Iron atoms are hard while water atoms are slippery.
Salt atoms are sharp and pointed while aerable atoms are light and swirling.
What properties a thing has been determined by the atoms that build up the object.
Even the soul consists according to democitosis of atoms, especially smooth, light and rounded,
which are scattered over the body and dissolved in death.
These atoms are eternal and unchanging, and exist in an infinite number.
When a thing is dissolved, the atoms will form new things and materials.
But Democritos realized that this is not enough to explain the world.
Had atoms been the only thing that existed, change would not have been possible
- This is because the atoms did not then have the opportunity to move.
Therefore, the void between the atoms also plays an important role in theory.
This void is something Aristotle would later call "vacuum".
Today's modern atomic theory originates from British chemist John Dalton and the beginning of the 19th century.
Democritos atoms are most recently reminiscent of what we today call molecules
- Thus, a set of atoms that together create a Ting's characteristics.