Every year, twenty thousand people move to Stockholm
Many of them can feel that it's difficult fitting in
That is why we have created The Stockholm Course
Hi, I'm gonna be your teacher for this course. Im gonna teach you how to fit in.
We teach you to alter your behaviour with different exercises
What you do you for a living?
Stop! Why are you turning the attention away from yourself?
Because it's pleasant?
Sit down!
And teach you how to communicate correctly
You are either from south of Stockholm or from north of Stockholm
You will also get to learn how to talk in the Stockholm accent
For example, "Excuse me, could you please move? is "Move!"
How do you translate "I was wrong"?
What does that mean?
On our trips you get to learn from real life situations
As you can see, it's harder for someone to get through if you're blocking the way
It's easier if we're not standing in the way
..yeah kinda
So, what do we do when someone is passed out like this?
You ignore it and continue on your way?
No, were not heartless.
Obviously we move the person off the bicycle lane so people can get past.
We also have time for questions
Do people from Stockholm think they're better than everyone else?
No, of course not. We know we are.
Isn't that kind of arrogant?
Coming from the girl with the ugly shirt.
Apply now and begin your future as a successful Stockholmer
Man, they're so fucking retarded
I cant stand teaching this course anymore
You can go home now,  the time is up.
Shit, its like an herd of sheep.