"Nazi Wants A Wife"
During this season, we'll be following the nazi Johan
I begin this adventure by heading to him in Stockholm
The dream would be to find someone with whom I can share my hatred
Hello Johan!
Hi
What have you been up to recently?
Resisting
Yeah? I've brought three letters for you
I don't really have any specific requirements
As long as she's an Aryan, submissive, Holocaust-denying girl-
that takes care of the household
She seems like a good choice, right?
NOTE: "The image got way darker when I scanned it"
Well, I sure hope so...
She has not been charged with hate speech
Smells a bit PC, doesn't it?
You think so?
It's difficult; you don't want to get too madly in love-
and lose focus on the fight against the traitors and the Jewish conspiracy
What do you think about her?
Tall, a beautiful, wide skull
I'm interested
I'm looking for someone with whom I can develop my nazism
"Mein Kampf" is to meet you. Hell Lisbet
She may actually be the one
Is that true? -*Nods*
Exciting! -Yeah
I'm pleased with the girls I selected
I rate them 8/8
It's time for a speed-date, and the girls have arrived in Stockholm
I truly hope I'll be able to show Johan how nazi-like I can be
Hi
Thank you. -You're welcome
I appreciate the gift. Adde was given a similar one by Eve
You wrote a good letter
But you didn't attach a family tree.
Oh...I'm sorry
And you wrote that you're not a nazi, but is interested in it?
Yes, I got extremely inspired when I heard you talking about the persecution of homosexuals
And the cleansing of racial strangers and people with opposing views
She's probably got a little bit of nazism in her, that girl.
So, would you be prepared to move into my place and start doing some nazi shenanigans?
Yeah, I think that'd suit me
Johan makes me feel like I'm in the Third Reich
I want to see Johan because he seems agressive and hostile
And I hope I'll be getting the chance of passing on his violent genes
So, do you think this body will be able to birth four children?
Yes, I think so
That'll be needed in the fight for the survival of our race
Absolutely!
Are your period cycles normal?
It was kind of awkward in the beginning. You don't want to be too pushy
You want to give them some Lebensraum
But have you been in many relationships before?
What is this? The Nürnberg Trials?
*Mutual Laughter*
Then sparks started to fly. For sure
I think time's up now.
Nooooooo, I want to continue talking
We'll have to do that later
Ja, Mein Fürher ;)
There was truly a flirty atmosphere
And we were arguing a little too
He thinks that we should deport every adopted child-
while I'm of the opinion that it depends on a case-to-case basis
So that spices up our relationship a bit
But, like, I strongly like that he's more filled with hatred in real life
Yeah, right?
And those Aryan arms, man I just want to squeeze those!
Eh, yes please!
In next week's episode: Sara's sad because Johan brings Lisbet to the Goebbels festival
And Johan and Lisbet fight for the first time
We were going to have a cozy evening and see the first half of Schindler's List!
Do you think bombings plan themselves?