Every year some move to Gothenburg
Where it is easy to fit in
But it can be nice with an introduction
So that's why we've created the Gothenburg course
Hello or!?
Welcome to the Gothenburg course
So j*vla tense and see where you come from
You can start
Stockholm
Tighten whole*ete!
J*vla tidy, they think they are something
We listen to your needs, to constantly get better
I'm sober alcoholic, so I wonder if there are any AA meetings?
I don't actually know, they are so damn secretive
I think it's super that you go there
But there is probably no wine-wine situation
We punch holes on some old prejudices
Not everyone is called Glenn in Gothenburg
Not me, for example.
What's your name then?
Jocke
Glennsson
Then also learn a little Gothenburg
Yes, you want some translation on the following:
Hello.
How é the situation?
What fun OSE you, it was a long time!
And it will be in Gothenburg
Hello or!?
How do you translate '' what are you doing? ''
Yes it will be completely different.
It becomes
Hello orne!?
The course also includes a nice tour
Broken water: Completely J*VLA useless
It is called the best-coast for some reason huh?
Hey, what are you doing?!
When you look like this you have to intervene
Hello, so you can't keep up there!
You pie your back, I can help here!
Oh yeah, I have it.
I have it.
Have a good time now then old men
Wasn't there any burglary?
No for f*n, it was good guys
Just like the nice guys we helped down to Syria last week
They would sell ice apparently
Now we are on Avenyn, which shows that Gothenburg is a real big city
Because here is always full of people
Except on Saturday afternoons, Sundays, everyday evenings ...
Saturday before pay ...
And when nothing happens at Ullevi ...
When they happen something at Ullevi ...
When it rains outside ..
Some summer weeks ...
And we provide important information about local traffic
This is the tram
And that is by far the fastest way to get ahead
If one does not go then we say
The tour ends on our fine island Hissingen
Oh then we are at the hissing
There is a lot to see, you get to duck a little
One can look quickly
So
There is Hjalmar Branting eg.
So sign up for the Gothenburg course today