Hello! Here you who are employed with sick pay can get help to apply for sickness benefit.
Your employer must have been reported sick in order for you to make your application.
To be able to do your cases digitally, you need to have BankID -
And have logged in to My pages on insurance fund.se.
You can choose whether you want to apply for sickness benefit via computer, mobile phone or tablet.
The film describes how to do in eight steps that take about three minutes.
Your application for sickness benefit is divided into three fields -
My tasks, illness and medical certificates and scope and period.
Click "Complete" to change the details in each field.
Click "Go On" to confirm your changes.
Here you can see your personal and contact details. Make sure the information is correct.
Here you can see employer information, information about income and work and account details.
You need to provide current information about your work and your income.
You can find these in your employment contract.
You can also contact your employer for the right information.
Fill in if you are back at work or if you are still on sick leave.
If you or your doctor has not already submitted a medical certificate, you can choose to connect it now.
Here you describe what illness you have, what your work tasks look like -
And how you would have worked if you had been healthy.
Specify the extent to which you apply for sickness benefit.
Now all three fields are filled and green marked.
Click in the check and approve box by signing with your BankID.
Once you have approved the application, you will receive a message that confirms that we have received your information.
Now you can follow your case on my pages.
Thank you for applying for sickness benefit via My pages!