We were, so to speak, a cocktail battalion,
Thus, a reduced battalion.
They did your job. When you were free you went down to the beach
And sunbathed.
Then we were out in town in the evenings and then you worked again.
It was such a life actually.
It was sunbathed and it was drank a lot.
It was a friend of me like
Called and asked if I would keep up with Cyprus.
And then I hung on.
Of course.
My biggest wish was to become an officer.
So I moved in to P 2 in Hässleholm.
But then I was involved
in a difficult car accident.
He who was driving fell asleep
at the steering wheel.
It was facial injuries, jaw injuries
And everything.
So I was engaged for a year.
In order to continue the education I started
Should I redo the military service from the beginning.
I can feel even today
That I did not get the chance to continue.
But
I couldn't do anything about it.
It was just moving on.
So when I got the chance to do UN service
It was clear, 100 percent.
I'm going!
For me it was
no challenge, without that
Would be wonderful to serve down here.
Although they went to "Tjotahejti"
So I had followed.
But I had the wrong idea of Cyprus.
I thought Cyprus was a flat island
With just sand.
So you got a shock when you landed in Nicosia
And got to see the high mountains and nature.
I know that Cyprus has a very long
history.
But I think you should start in 1974,
Before we got here.
Now the Greek Cypriots want
together with national grave
make a coup and incorporate
Cyprus with Greece.
And the battalion that we
resolved
They probably had it pretty quiet.
It was a so -called cocktail battalion,
But I don't want to sense their job down here.
And it was the same when we came down in April.
We didn't have much to do.
It was pretty smooth,
It actually was.
But
It changed quickly.
"Turkish troops invaded Cyprus earlier today."
“It announced Turkey's Prime Minister Ecevit who said
that troops have arrived in Cyprus early this morning. "
You were a little prepared.
One went and pondered what would happen
With me and the weapon I have.
On July 20, the Turks went ashore at Kyrenia.
They stayed there for a week
And there were fierce battles at Kyrenia.
There were parachute troops, warships and everything possible.
Then you walked slowly towards Famagusta
And it took a month for the troops to get there.
They thus first first received Greeks in front of them
because they would get rid of everyone.
It was ethnic erection.
They would get rid of all Greeks and set a limit.
We were seven man on an observation site
And as a sergeant, I was group manager.
We had a guarding task to take care of.
All that moved in the terrain
Written on a list
and reported on.
It was such information we had at all observational sites.
“The most sensitive point in the entire Famagusta area
is the harbor. ”
“The Greek Cypriots have fortified the harbor
of the fear of invasion from Turkey. "
The first observation site I was at
was called Othello Tower.
There we looked at the harbor
to see if it was shipped in weapons or
If military vehicles came in.
I was not allowed to sit guard
Because I was group manager.
I was responsible for radio traffic
and i cooked breakfast and lunch
In order for the guys to rest.
It was a lot of card games,
It was very sunbathing.
It was wonderful to be in such places.
We had a great time at the observation sites.
- How does it feel to go back to the camp?
What does it arouse within you?
- Yes, it raises great thoughts.
It will be amazingly exciting
Because inside there is part of my life.
These months before the war
Is probably among the best I've been to.
In here lay the officers' fairs.
A bit in there.
We lived four guys here.
The beds so. One there, here and there.
This was not then.
We lived here.
We were sergeants all four.
As I get into the camp now
then i will come back to this one
The stress we call it.
But I also feel a satisfaction
of entering the camp.
And a joy.
For I have had many nice moments
of my life here.
And horrible moments too. Of course.
July 20th when
The Greeks walked towards the Turks.
That was then
The real war began.
There was almost panic on the camp for
get to be in shelter.
You took your weapon, then down a pit.
That was what mattered.
Fort as the phase down into a pit to protect itself.
They shot through the camp.
So you couldn't go, you had to crawl in the ditches,
Because it small everywhere.
And some ridges looked like Tesils.
It was terrible.
I never thought I would experience it.
Because it was
an incredible fire at the camp
And all around.
You thought
Survive!
So this goes to the forest.
There came tanks that turned the tower toward us
And towards the camp.
I see and hear it in front of me now,
screams, cries,
And gunfire.
Bullets that come all over
And rattles in the sand.
When we had rushed out of
The protection pits
So I ended up in a covered guard.
The hole was roughly here.
Then it went away here.
Here was a whole group.
And I stand like this.
I can imagine that
Down where the guys sat.
There it was certainly 60 degrees hot,
Because it was 40 degrees outside.
Rune thought it was too hot so he wanted to get up
And look he too.
So I backed back as much as I could.
So he pushed himself up in front of me.
Just as he came up, he sank down again.
So I got hold of him like this.
I thought he just fainted
But then I saw that he was bleeding.
He had received a shot in his right eye.
Which went in and stopped four centimeters from the back of the head.
I told Rune once
that you saved my life.
Hadn't you stood there
So I had the ball in my head.
So I actually felt
And I am grateful for that.
I feel sorry for Rune,
that he would get it in the skull.
But it's war
And you know what can happen.
Unfortunately, it is.
It was heavy.
You get some goose bumps when you look at this.
Imagine I have been involved in this.
We had an observation site inside Old City,
Othello Tower.
Below was a small restaurant.
There were many turches and drank coffee.
Then there was a guy there.
He was Turkish Cypriot
and introduced himself as Mr. Mûnûr.
He was often there.
Me and he began to talk
And he was very nice.
He told us about his family, among other things
And we met down there quite often.
We exchanged many thoughts
About Cyprus and everything.
Then it was calm and peaceful.
“Swedish UN soldiers go by mail
at the multi -hundred -year -old fortifications. ”
"As today should be only tourist attractions."
“But that still matters,
just like fortifications. ”
The Turks were not allowed to be on the wall
in Old City.
Because then the Greeks shot and threw grenades.
So we would remove them there.
Then I got as a mission
to become the head of that strength.
We were a group that loaded a KP car
and would make a temporary observation site up there.
Then I told my driver: Don't stop for anything.
If there is a roadblock. Drive through!
We're going up there now.
Then a lot of soldiers came up.
Turkish Cypriots.
They were of course cursed.
But then came Mûnûr.
So he and I
stood opposite each other.
With each weapon.
I was snooped but not afraid.
I thought he couldn't shoot me.
Then I told Mr. Mûnûr that you know what applies.
You may not be up here,
You have to take away your guys and go down.
But then when it got dark, at midnight.
Then he came.
Without weapons.
Then we sat on the wall and talked,
in shelter.
It was nice.
We are now on our way
to Famagusta.
Old City.
And hopefully we will meet my old friend.
Turken Mr. Mûnûr.
- Hey what's up?
Do you know this man? Mr. Mûnûr.
- So you know him?
- Yes.
- He was here ten minutes ago.
Ask for him over there.
–Ok. Thanks!
- Hi mr. Mûnûr!
Mûnûr: - Welcome!
Jan-Olov:-How are you?
Mûnûr: - Thanks so much!
Jan-Olov:-Fun to see you again.
Mûnûr: - Is everything good?
- Hey you!
Mûnûr: - Is that me?
Jan-Olov:-Yes, and me.
- It's been many years ago.
Mûnûr: - Is it my house?
Jan-Olov:-Yes.
- I was there once with my girlfriend.
- Do you remember?
It was fantastic, a lovely feeling actually.
It was fun.
And he was probably a little moved too.
It's a lovely man.
I have a lot of friends there
And it's easy to make friends down here.
Have you got a Cypriot friend
So it is forever.
There is so much to enjoy in Cyprus.
I love the people who live here.
It is fantastic to live here.
It's not that complicated, you take it as it is.
It is not like in Sweden
Where it is a bit strict.
Without here it is a little mañana.
After all, I can't get 35 pensioners together at the age of 75
to a pub and throwing arrow
Every Wednesday in Sweden.
It is completely impossible.
But down here it goes.
It's a completely different life down here.
- Do you see yourself as a veteran?
- Yes.
I do it.
Absolutely.
I bear that with honor.
Not many people get that chance.
And as I said before so
would I be happy to continue and do more battalions
But the age took its right.
Texting: Joakim Gustafsson