An ordinary day at work starts about half past eight in the morning
with a morning briefing where we go through today's weather,
What the systems look like and what kind of business we should have.
Then we have four to five passes in the combat management center.
For example, a pass for us may be a four against four
Where there are four own aircraft and four opposing planes.
My task then is to inform my aircraft
About how the opponents behave, how they fly,
what speed, what height, because my pilots
in the best way should be able to act on it.
The more aircraft it is on the screen, the more that happens
the more tagged you will be to solve it
And give the best possible you can.
My name is Emelie and I work as a flight combat leader.
The best thing about being air combat leaders is clearly my colleagues.
I always have fun at work.
To feel that I am contributing to Sweden's defense and
The development of Sweden's defense makes me proud.