Arctic, gray zone, AI and soldiers on the ground.
But civil society then, how prepared are we?
When the war comes.
As a model railway nerd, you are very impressed by this railway bridge.
This is a model of our modern society.
It is used by the Swedish Defense Research Institute to easily and pedagogically show cyber threats.
I have lectured to many pedantic and critical people.
Here you show how our through -digitized society can be disturbed and what consequences it can have.
Cyber attacks ... You have a computer, I have a computer.
I want to influence you in any way or your business-
—with my computer asks your computer to do something you don't want it to do-
-or that you don't know it will do.
Quite small bus can have disastrous consequences.
Chopped water purification becomes the entire block of stomach ailment.
If someone goes on the traffic lights, the hospital's emergency clinics can be quickly filled.
And what happens if a bridge gets stuck in a raised position due to malicious code?
We believe that cyber attacks will be used as a complement.
You do this to make it easier for other types of operations.
There is nothing that is used completely isolated and separately.
Cyber attacks will not only affect the Armed Forces but also civil society.
Toward all or part of the country.
There are several ways to destroy, weaken and make a public really bad.
Damage a civilian population can be done in many different ways-
-Not only with weapons power, but it can be about basic things.
Nothing to eat, no heat, no communication opportunities, no information.
Precisely the lack of the basal is believed to be able to cause great problem-
-In our future scenarios on which this series is based.
There is especially a sensitive point that can change more than you first think.
You call it "just in time", that is, minimal storage of goods.
Everything should instead be on the road, between producer and consumer.
Thus, if the transport is broken, there are no goods available.
Everything will end, and it quickly.
Very many supply chains are "just in time".
In "Just in Time" concept you see stock, storage and reserves and extra resources as an unnecessary cost.
This means that everything should preferably be directly in production or truck between different units.
It is clear that a small tuva often steals a large load.
It is a risk of crisis preparedness.
During the initial phase of the Corona crisis, we saw that everyone wanted the same type of supplies.
That private individuals hamstrade goods are a thing-
-But political cooperation across borders, did it work?
You probably know that several EU countries, including Germany, France, Italy and Bulgaria-
-As a result of the pandemic has introduced export restrictions on medical protective equipment.
Something that we have been very critical of from the Swedish side.
Of course, we understand that there is a concern, but also in this serious situation we should have a solidarity between EU countries.
Trade in medical protective equipment must work.
Would this escalate into an even more serious social crisis or armed attack-
-To this will mean even greater stress and consequences for society.
Lack of healthcare materials and lack of imported food is a matter-
-But what we have ourselves then?
What we are self -sufficient at?
We have plenty of resources within the country.
Cultivable soil and animals.
We are self -sufficient in principle when it comes to cereals, eggs and chickens, and some more.
On the other hand, these products are dependent on the fact that tractors have diesel, that we have fertilizers and other inputs for agriculture.
Actually, we are not self -sufficient on anything.
In domestic production, we are also entirely dependent on electricity working.
Sure, farmers have reserve plants, but fuel is needed for them.
What happens if electricity and fuel are gone for a longer period-
-As, among other things, that large animal herds are suffocated because the fans do not work in the animal stables.
If the central electricity grid is extinguished in a sufficiently large area, basically nothing works anymore.
We lose the lighting, we lose the heat. We lose telecommunications.
We lose health care, we lose agriculture.
We lose all types of bank transmission systems.
Without the electricity, we no longer have a functioning society.
A country that is struggling just to survive is easy to get where one will-
-How competent defense force you have.
When one cannot, want or can defend themselves further-
-So all offers for a conditional peace are probably easy to accept.
There are many parts of society that are important in order to live a normal life under decent forms that we are used to.
What is ultimately important from my perspective is the desire to defend the country.
Our freedom and the right to live as we choose ourselves.
When you break that willingness to defense you have defeated the Swedish people.
That's what we want to avoid.
The Armed Forces alone can only stand for part of the total defense.
Civil society must also be robust.
Add to that a high defense will in everyone.
Then it becomes a good so -called threshold effect.
Military threshold effect is something that Sweden as a nation should provide.
It is a total defense affair to have this.
The threshold effect prevents an opponent from conducting business that he would like to do-
-To the cost and price becomes too great.
When we talk about the threshold effect, we connect it before the war starts.
That is, we will make sure that the war does not come, and that is the best defense.
We shall carry out operations daily to reject violations-
-But we will also discover various abuse and attack in the gray zone.
We will also make sure that we practice with others.
We must ensure that we meet any threats and attacks directly.
In this way we show that we have a desire to defend ourselves and thus abstains an attack.
In the next section:
What is really worth defending?