SGI for entrepreneurs,
that's how it works
SGI, or sickness benefit -based income,
is an amount that is calculated
by the Social Insurance Office.
It is the basis of how much money
You can get if you get sick,
wobble or should be parental.
Your compensation from us becomes approximately
80 percent of your SGI.
How your SGI is calculated
depends on how long you
have had your business
And what kind of company you have.
If you have a business
as you registered
for less than
36 months ago,
can you, regardless of corporate form
be entitled to a so -called
structure.
It means we
Calculating your SGI
based on what an employee
with the same tasks,
education and experience
would have received in income.
Keep in mind that you must have
started working in your business
In order to be entitled to
A structure.
After the build -up phase
SGI counts out different
depending on the type
by companies you have.
Do you work in your own limited company
are you counted as an employee
in your business.
Your SGI is calculated on that salary
As you take out
from your business.
If you have a very low pay
or no pay at all,
So do you have a low SGI
Or no SGI at all.
If you have an individual company,
trading company or limited liability company,
So we calculate your compensation
Based on your company's results
after deduction
And before tax.
It means that if your business
have a small surplus
or no excess at all,
So do you have a low SGI
Or no SGI at all.
If you both drive
private business
and have income from employment
So your SGI is calculated
both on your salary
and your company's results
after deduction and before tax.
The Social Insurance Office.
Read more about SGI
at fk.se/sgiguiden