The question is not why I chose to become an officer.
The question is why I remain as an officer.
It is because it is a varied profession.
I've been on a squad for ten years.
I've been in the staff for six months.
That's what is a bit funny about the Armed Forces, it's open.
You have the opportunity to focus on several different levels.
We want good managers. Then we have to give each other constructive feedback.
It is quite good at the Armed Forces.
Exercise is an important part, this is where we get wrong.
When it comes to the sharp part
Internationally and nationally that we should do right.
My name is Sofia and serve as a staff officer at Livgardet.