Sickness benefit and sickness benefit for preventive purposes.
In this film we will focus on the regulations around
sickness benefit and how the Social Insurance Office works with those who are on sick leave.
We also take up the compensation preventive sickness benefit.
It is sickness benefit
Compensation for illness that most people come into contact with.
Of those who live and work in Sweden.
The Mission of the Swedish Social Insurance Agency is partly to investigate and decide
about the right to compensation. But also to clarify the need for rehabilitation.
Work to make the efforts needed for effective rehabilitation
taken as soon as possible as well as
to coordinate rehabilitation efforts.
This is what is the Swedish Social Insurance Agency's coordination assignment.
Both of these parts are regulated in the Social Security Code
which is the legislation that governs the sickness benefit.
The Social Insurance Office does not carry out its own rehabilitation efforts.
However, we thus have an important coordinating role in the sick leave process.
Rehabilitation includes it
which takes place in health care, but also the one as the employer,
The social services or other actors are responsible for.
The Swedish Social Insurance Agency therefore needs to cooperate with all actors
In order for the sick person to receive adequate support
In order to return to work it is crucial that all actors in
The sick leave process actively contributes outside
their respective responsibilities.
What happens if man
cannot work due to illness.
When you are sick and cannot work because of the disease
as an employee, you should make a sickness report directly to your employer.
The employer is responsible for sick pay
the first 14 days of the sick period.
Anyone who is not employed but instead is self -employed,
unemployed or parental sick leave to report directly to the Social Insurance Office
and then apply for sickness benefit.
At the beginning of the sick period, a waiting deduction is made.
For employees it is deducted from sick pay by the employer and for others from the sickness benefit
by the Social Insurance Office.
From day eight of the sick period
Needs those who are ill and cannot work show a medical certificate.
This applies to both employees and others.
If the employee is still ill and cannot work
Due to the disease after the sick pay period in 14 days, reports sickness
The employer his employees to the Social Insurance Office.
The employee must then apply for sickness benefit himself.
Thus, both a notification is required,
an application and as a rule a medical certificate
In order for the Swedish Social Insurance Agency to be able to start the proceedings.
Most people who apply for sickness benefit do it digitally via fk.se.
When the Social Insurance Agency investigates the right to sickness benefit
and the need for support for return to work
If we first do a review of all the information contained in the case.
In addition to the application and medical certificate
May there be other important information we need to access.
Then we make an assessment
of if we have enough evidence to make decisions.
If any task is missing or needs to be clarified, the documentation is supplemented.
Usually through a contact with the person himself,
the employer or health care.
In conversation with the individual we pray among other things
about a more detailed description of what the work consists of.
What is the person having difficulty doing and in what situations?
What requirements do the tasks place
On physical, mental and mental ability?
The Social Insurance Office also asks for the person's own perception of
the ability to get back to work and what
which would be required in that case.
Maybe it has already been made adjustments to work or would it
Maybe it is possible to make adjustments to facilitate the return to work?
If the person is on sick leave part -time, the placement of working hours is also investigated.
We often also need to talk to the employer.
It is the employer who has a working environment and rehabilitation responsibility.
And know what is possible to do in the workplace.
Issues that often become relevant are, among other things;
Are there opportunities for work adaptation or other
appropriate tasks, either temporary or more permanent?
For example, work adaptation may be about changes in
tasks or working hours.
And if the person is on sick leave part -time it can also be
Current to ask about the organization of working hours.
The medical certificate is one of the most important surfaces
In the investigation and the main source of medical information
When the Social Insurance Office is to assess whether illness reduces work ability.
The Social Insurance Agency may therefore also
need to have contact with health care.
It may be partly clarified by
medical information linked to the right to compensation
Among other things, the rehabilitation chain's different assessment bases
the need for information.
But it can also be about the medical conditions that
Available for return to work.
For it to be right
For sickness benefit, there are a number of conditions that need to be met.
Both general and specific, and these are stated in the Social Security Code.
Most people who live and work in Sweden are covered by social insurance.
When applying for sickness benefit, the Swedish Social Insurance Agency needs first secure
that the person is insured in Sweden.
The work -based benefits, where the sickness benefit is counted
is based on the income loss principle.
It means that the income I go
Misten when I'm sick is the one I get compensation for.
Therefore, the Social Insurance Agency must always
investigate the sickness benefit -based income, SGI
Then it is the one on which the sickness benefit is based.
If any of these two basic conditions are not met
No sickness benefit is paid out no matter how sick and limited you are.
In order to be entitled to sickness benefit, the work capacity should also be
reduced by at least one quarter due to illness.
Here you start from the individual's regular working hours.
Sickness benefit is thus not
connected to a standard working time of 40 hours per week.
For example, if someone works 8 hours a day
the disease must limit work ability by at least 2 hours per day.
If the normal working hours are instead 4 hours, then the disease needs
Limit work ability at least one hour per day.
When assessing the right to sickness benefit, the Social Insurance Office receives
just take into account the disease and consequences of it.
According to the legislation, factors such as situation in the labor market, receive
social conditions or economic situation does not affect the decision.
If any of these factors have led to the disease it is thus only
The consequences of the disease valued, not the cause of it.
The information in the medical certificate is an important part of the decision basis at the Swedish Social Insurance Agency.
The certificate should describe what disease the person has and on
which way it is limiting and how the doctor has arrived at it.
For employees with
sick pay and self -employed we make the assessment based on the
The so -called rehabilitation chain, which is part of the Social Security Code.
Here are fixed time frames for assessing work ability.
The longer the sick leave is in progress
The more the assessment is widened.
The purpose of the rehabilitation chain is to take advantage of it
Work ability The individual has and, if necessary, promotes transition.
This assumes that the Swedish Social Insurance Agency together with other actors
And as soon as possible, the individual works actively for return to work.
In the first 90 days, work capacity should be assessed in relation to
regular work or other temporary work that the employer can offer.
Even for the needy employees where it can be assumed that
the individual would have worked in the first 90 days
the assessment must be made in relation to the regular work.
After 90 days the work capacity should also be assessed
in relation to work that the employer can offer
In the event of a relocation, both temporary and permanent.
In the case of own entrepreneurs, they are judged
in relation to the regular work up to and including day 180
and needs employees are assessed from day 91
as unemployed if they have not booked work passes.
After 180 days the assessment is expanded further
Here the Social Insurance Office will disregard what work the individual
have and instead evaluate the restrictions in relationship
to a normal occurring work in the labor market.
It means a work
which is not adapted or specially prepared for the individual.
The Social Insurance Office shall also indicate within
Which occupational group the individual can have a possible ability to work.
At day 180, the legislation has gradually been extended with several exceptions
from being assessed against normal work.
The basic idea with the exceptions is that the individual
should have more time in the health insurance for action
which aims to be able to come back to his regular employer.
Age can also be an exception.
The exceptions need to be investigated before the Social Insurance Office can
Make a decision on sickness benefit.
The Swedish Social Insurance Agency may need to supplement the decision basis with clarifications
or further information.
Even the one who does not work when
The need for sick leave arises can be granted sickness benefit.
Anyone who is unemployed is judged directly in relation to normal
existing work in the labor market.
Parental leave is assessed in relation to the ability to take care of the child.
Here, the Social Insurance Office investigates, among other things, who in that case takes care of the child
When the parent is ill and has a reduced ability to do so.
For those who study it is the study ability
that should be impaired due to illness.
If the Social Insurance Agency assesses that study
the ability is impaired approved the sick period and information is sent to CSN
so that the person is allowed to retain their study support.
Usually, this means that the study ability must be fully impaired.
Anyone studying needs a medical certificate from day 15.
In the cases that the sick person has
Various employment at the same time, the assessment is divided.
For example, the person who is is assessed
partly unemployed in relation to normal work.
For that part they are unemployed and in relation to the rehabilitation chain
for their employees.
Depending on the employment and situation of the sick leave, there may be one
several different actors who need to be involved in the person's
Rehabilitation and return to work.
All actors have different roles and responsibilities
in the sick and the rehabilitation process.
Anyone who is on sick leave has a responsibility to provide the information
as needed to clarify the need for rehabilitation
And to actively participate in rehabilitation to the best of their ability.
The employer is responsible
for the work -oriented rehabilitation.
If it can be assumed that sick leave will last for at least 60 days
shall the employer together with the employee draw up a plan
for return to work during the first 30 days of sick leave.
The plan must be continuously followed up and revised if necessary.
In the employer's work environment responsibility
also include reviewing which work adjustments you can do
And if necessary, conduct work -oriented rehabilitation.
As assistance and support there may be occupational health care
But also union representatives.
The doctor's task is to make a medical assessment,
make diagnosis and assess the need for care and treatment,
But also to decide on sick leave.
If the doctor concluded that the disease and its consequences
If the work ability puts down it should be described in the medical certificate.
The Employment Service is responsible for support to
The one as unemployed, but also support for transition.
If a person who employed cannot go back to work with his employer.
This includes being responsible for the individual's work -oriented rehabilitation.
The municipality is responsible for social efforts
and support to plan for self -sufficiency.
The Swedish Social Insurance Agency is responsible for investigating and assessing the work capacity
reduction due to illness in accordance with the provisions of the Social Security Code.
The Social Insurance Office should also coordinate others
actors' efforts.
Doctors may assess that there is a need for medical efforts
or rehabilitation, but that the disease does not put
Down work ability so that sick leave is needed.
Then a preventive sickness benefit may be relevant.
For example, it may trade
that there is a risk that illness will affect work ability.
It may also be the case that the work capacity is no longer impaired
Due to illness, but that the need for rehabilitation remains.
In order for preventive sickness benefit to be granted, one must just as for
Sickness benefit is both insured in Sweden and have a sickness benefit -based income, SGI.
The purpose of compensation is to prevent,
shorten or cancel a reduction in work capacity.
This means that it can be granted if the person, for example, has
or risks developing a disease that can lead to reduced work capacity.
The medical treatment or rehabilitation
shall be prescribed by a doctor and even included in a
The Försäkringskassan approved plan for the person to be granted the compensation.
In order for preventive sickness benefit to be up -to -date
Do you need to be gone due to treatment or rehabilitation
At least a quarter of the working hours on the day the treatment is performed.
This applies whether you work or are job seekers.
In addition to the treatment time itself also includes travel time
to and from the treatment if it needs to be done during working hours.
If treatment and or travel time occurs outside working hours
That time is not included.
One cannot receive preventive sickness benefit for single
Treatment sessions but only when recurring.
In case of preventive sickness benefit, no waiting deduction is made
And the employer pays no sick pay for the time granted.
It is not possible to make one
Full list of treatments that will give the right to compensation
Because it can vary and an individual assessment is made in each case.
But some examples of efforts that led to granting are
psychology conversation, pain treatment, physiotherapy,
vision and hearing rehabilitation, occupational therapy,
Osteoarthritis school and addiction treatment.
More information about Försäkringskassan can be found at fk.se.
There are pages that turn to you who work in healthcare,
But it is also possible to search freely on the website to search for answers to your questions.
You can also call the Customer Center for Partner.
There, for example, you can leave message if necessary
to insurance investigators in a specific case.
If you need to contact the Swedish Social Insurance Agency regarding a specific patient
Can you ask the patient for contact information for his insurance investigators.
Thank you for watching.
The Social Insurance Office.