Defender is a multinational exercise-
-Which aims to strengthen the defense of Europe.
During the exercise, ing 2 together with-
-flow bridge associations from the USA, Poland and France-
-Mobility over the rivers Wizla and Narew in Poland.
I am a platoon manager for the field work intelligence platoon.
Our main task is to obtain intelligence-
-To connected to field work for battalion and brigade staff.
We have conducted a tactical intelligence retrieval here
-The switched on against the liquid bridge system Tiresbro 300.
I am from the tire brushes and this is our final exercise in Poland.
For two weeks we have worked with both-
-Frenchmen, Americans and Poles.
It has been challenging but above all it has been incredibly cool-
-See how everyone works and how different but at the same time how we do things.
We have worked closely together with an American bridge company.
We have the same bromateriel and have among other things-
-Built a common 190 meter long bridge.
Our efforts have in an excellent way-
-Shere NATO's ability to cross watercourses.