We are moving towards a future where we will strengthen the cyber defense -
- And it is also pronounced at all levels.
As all parts of our everyday lives become more digitized -
- So cyber automatically becomes an integral part of all different domains.
You will not be able to defend themselves without cyber - in the future
- Over what it is you are doing within the Armed Forces.
Cyber defense is a military means of power that is most commonly used together -
- With other combat forces, when carrying out military operations.
Actually, anyone can search and become a cyber soldier -
- Just man is a Swedish citizen and is between 18-44 years.
We direct our application and the ones we take in -
- They are usually logically placed, so you want to solve problems.
One should be interested in IT.
One should have a basic technical background and understanding of computers in general.
One should have the ability to cooperate -
- And you should have the ability to give the little extra when needed.
Becoming a cyber soldier means that you will be tested in different ways -
–And in the end, when you have matched the requirements profile that we are looking for -
- So we do extra tests.
You are considered suitable at the duty and testing plant-
- Then you will have to make an extra pattern, as we call it, an extended pattern.
What we try, it is partly theoretical knowledge -
- And then we talk logic among other things.
The second is professional knowledge.
How much knowledge do you have about what is cyber before you start?
When one starts with your education to a cyber soldier -
- Then you carry out a general military part.
It is a big change to go from being a private individual-
- To a compound pluton.
The first thing that happens during GMU is that you have to step into a new world -
- In the military world.
And learn how to act at all stages as a military.
You learn to defend your place with weapons.
You learn to survive in the forest.
And you learn all the soldier skills -
- As everyone in the Armed Forces should have.
Honestly, this is a lot of fun, but I also long for -
- Get to put me with a computer and take it too.
It's "Best of Both World".
It's fun to shoot, it's fun to scream -
- And it's fun to be quiet in front of the computer too.
That works for me.
When this day is over, the military undergraduate training - ends
- And we are going into the next stage.
The next stage, is the job training.
As before, we work in groups.
It will require much of your group.
It will also require much of the platoon.
We do this in common.
You are here because you can.
As of having gone to living in tent-
–To be in the woods and shoot weapons -
-So you go into a high-intensity IT education--
with the foundation of one of Sweden's foremost university courses.
Cyber soldier training is an academic education.
It contains four KTH college courses-
- Which in itself corresponds to 30 higher education credits.
One starts with a basic understanding within computer networks as we call it
Then you move on to computer systems -
—While the second course - is
- And then it is data security.
In common with reading the three courses -
- So you will also read it, as many may recognize - -
- As is the ethical hacking.
Which is about getting into different systems.
It is extremely mentally demanding.
It's long days and there is a lot to take in.
By the fact that the community and then of course also the Armed Forces -
-Digitalized much more, so cyber domain - will
- To be a larger attack surface for a potential opponent.
Therefore, cyber defense is really needed everywhere.
Cyber defense is an actor or a nation's overall ability ...
... that through offensive and defensive methods -
- Defend a critical system.
Actually, you can say that basically very similar skills - are needed -
- For offensive and defensive cyber operations.
A defensive ability it is the -
- As we almost always use.
It's about monitoring -
- And discover intrusion into our systems.
Offensive cyber operations are about obtaining information -
–If the attacking system, or to make it difficult for the attacker -
- to use their systems, which in turn -
- is a defense measure, because it prevents these attacks.
The cyber defense is needed everywhere in the Armed Forces -
-And here we got the chance to deepen our knowledge a little -
- In how different associations work with their cyber defense.
What happens is that you are placed somewhere in the Armed Forces.
It could be, for example, in the Air Force.
And so the Air Force will further educate the cyber soldiers reading towards the Air Force -
–And really take what is general and do it specifically -
- Against their system, for example.
This competence to be cybers soldier -
- Is very important to the Armed Forces.
It allows us to expand our endurance and capacity.
We have the ability today and we have management bands -
-And IT defense associations, which know this ability very well today.
But with the cyber soldier training and the establishment -
- So we really increase our capacity.
When you finish your military duty, it's really two roads -
- If you want to continue your involvement in the Armed Forces.
One is if one is looking for employment as a soldier -
- In any of the organizational units, or within the Armed Forces.
The second it is if you want to become an officer.
There we have developed an education, which is focused on cyber.
If you have been completing the Cyber Soldier Training for Eleven Months -
- So you have a great opportunity both within the Armed Forces -
- Going on, but also out in the community.
You see it from the parliamentary and government decisions-
- Where you place great power and weight and point out the importance of the cyber defense.
Not least, you also see it in our immediate area.
If we look at what is happening in Europe -
- And if we look at what is happening in the world in general.
Cyber defense is an equally natural part of the war -
- As the other battlefields, that is, land, lake or air.