All people are extremely different and it is important to
try to get into what they see
And based on that make a good decision for the entire ship.
A well -trimmed crew is that
allows the ship to solve its task in the best way.
A good officer for me should be
Competent, humble but also demanding.
Just because i'm fanjunger doesn't mean i stand over
To band ammunition or clean a KSP.
It's an amazing feeling to see people
Clear a task they themselves do not think they will be able to do.
When you know that you have been a part of training and educating that person.
My name is Viktor and I work as an air defense officer aboard HMS Ven.