Welcome aboard a Visby Corvette. Up here from the dock is run the ship.
An officer navigates the ship and gives orders to a seaman about what course the vessel should hold.
In addition, there are lookouts that with binoculars look for things that are around the ship that can be dangerous.
The ship's manager is also often found here.
All of these work as a team and help to perform the ship for sure
-Os if it's sunshine, night or fog.
In the combat management center, information from Radar, Sonar and other sensors is presented.
It is thus from here the battle is led.
The radar can see aircraft, robots and other vessels.
The sonar shows what is below the water surface, such as mines or submarines.
The telecommunications staff can also discover other things that broadcast radar.
Like all other work on board, it is a teamwork where everyone is helped.
On board you live mostly in two- or four-man cabins.
When the ship is at sea, half the crew normally works while the other half rests.
Man works in six-hour guards, six hours of work followed by six hours-
-When you should eat, exercise, sleep, clean or do something else.
On weapons tires there are the sea -target robots. The ship may have up to eight robots on board at the same time.
Robot 15 is targeted, with a range of over 100 kilometers and is used against other vessels.
A RIB boat can also be found here, which in this case replaces four of the robots.
This can be used for the transport of staff or to save people from the water.
Here in the fair we eat and this is also where we watch TV or relax.
When the ship is at sea, you eat every six hours divided into two different guards.
The fairs also serve as a health care place at sea.
On board are two chefs who cook for the around 40 people in the crew.
At sea, they cook breakfast, lunch, dinner and night procurement.
In the engine room there are both diesel machines, if you want to run up to 15 knots-
-And gas turbines when you want to drive faster, just over 30 knots.
The vessel is powered by water heater that is quieter than ordinary propellers.
There are also generators that manufacture electricity, boilers that make hot water-
-And aggregate that manufactures drinking water from salt water and many other technical equipment.