The actual prerequisite for the officers to be able to do their jobs and because
Customers should be able to log in to “My Pages” on the web is that all
The systems work.
And this is where we system developers come in.
If there is a glitch in the systems, people may not get
money and can't buy food or pay the rent.
And then it is up to us to fix it.
It is a challenge to keep all technology modern and reliable without sacrificing quality.
We need to be able to update and clog Safety Hole
While we work in a system where it must not be wrong.
If an incident were to arise, we will release everything else that we have
For the hands and the entire team is helped to solve the problem.
It is something magical when everything flows on and the payouts run on.
We have a great responsibility and I feel proud of the job,
To feel that we make people's everyday life work and do good, for real.