Norrland's dragon regiment K 4 in Arvidsjaur.
Educates, develops and leads the hunter union-
-With qualified ability to work in particular subarctic terrain.
It is characterized by sparse infrastructure, rock, forest and is crossed by watercourses.
In winter it is cold, dark and plenty of snow.
The main task of the regiment is to deliver the Armed Forces' foremost association for combat-
-And scouting on the depths of areas controlled by the opponent.
The bandage operates in small, independent units.
Scattered over large areas.
Where they have the capacity to cause the opponent's boundary abilities-
-Thending losses.
To act as a hunter soldier is demanding both physically and mentally.
Our soldiers are therefore specially selected and specially trained.
The training to master the most extreme environments also creates conditions-
-To work throughout Sweden's territory, as well as outside the country's borders.
Our unique knowledge and conditions make us relevant to exchange-
-And exercise with both Swedish and foreign units.
At the regiment there are management and support functions.
As everyone together contributes to the final target image.
To educate soldiers and bandages who are dangerous to the opponent.
In direct connection with the regiment area there is an exercise field-
-optimized for training and practice of hunter associations.
We build an even stronger defense for tomorrow.
Our most important building block is and remains the high-performing individual-
-O which is motivated and grows with challenges.
Norrland's dragon regiment K 4 in Arvidsjaur.
Small units.
Difficult conditions.
Great effect.