The 51st edition of Baltops is over.
Baltops is a marine exercise initiated by USA-
-Where NATO participates in planning and implementation.
A large number of nations mainly from the Baltic Sea region-
-Have has participated since its inception in 1972.
The Swedish impression in this year's exercise has been greater than in a long time.
Several advanced exercises have been carried out on Swedish soil, Swedish water and in Swedish airspace.
Together with associations from our partner countries, including the American Navy and Finnish Amphibious Association-
-Have we have completed land rises on Gotland, amphibious ride in the Stockholm archipelago and mine clearance in Skåne.
We have strengthened our ability to both receive and provide military support.
This year's exercise has been implemented in new context:
Russia's illegal invasion of Ukraine.
We have clearly shown that Sweden will always take responsibility for the security of our immediate area.
The uncertain situation in our absolute proximity makes it even more important that we continue-
-Building security together with our partner countries, which we can soon call allies.