Welcome aboard a dietal class mining vessel.
Up here from the bridge, the ship is driven.
An officer navigates the ship and gives orders to a seaman about what course the vessel should hold.
In addition, there are lookouts that with binoculars look for things around the ship
The ship's manager is also often found here.
All of these work as a team and help to perform the ship for sure
-Oso if it is sunshine, night or fog
In the combat management center, information from Radar, Sonar and other sensors is presented.
It is thus from here the battle is led.
The radar can see aircraft and other vessels.
The sonar shows what is below the water surface, such as mines or submarines
In here, messages are also sent and received to other vessels.
Like all other work on board, it is a teamwork where everyone is helped.
On board a mine clearance vessel you live in two- or five years.
When the ship is at sea, half the crew normally works while the other half rests.
You work in six-hour guards-
-sex hours of work followed by six hours of rest
When to eat, exercise, sleep, clean or do something else.
Here in the Sweep Duk there are, among other things, our underwater vehicles.
They are remote-controlled unmanned underwater vessels-
-As used to film and harm minor found.
Here in the fair we eat and this is also where we watch TV or relax.
When the ship is at sea, you eat every six hours divided into two different guards.
The fairs also act as a health care location-
-And, for example, to lead firefighting on board.
On board are two chefs who cook for the more than 30 people in the crew.
At sea they cook food every six hours.
In the engine room there are four main engines that run Voith Schneider the propellers.
These allow the ship to maintain a speed of about 15 knots.
However, when looking for mines you drive a lot more slowly.
There are also generators that make electricity, boilers that make hot water-
And osmosis units that manufacture drinking water from salt water and many other technical equipment.