About the Social Insurance Office.
The Social Insurance Agency, one of Sweden's largest authorities
with just over 14 \ H000 employees and offices in 60 locations.
We are going on behalf of Parliament
and government manage social insurance.
We do this by investigating and deciding on the right to compensation
As well as coordinate rehabilitation efforts to help those who are on sick leave
to get back to working life.
Here is the state value base.
It describes how we who are employed at the Social Insurance Office should relate
ourselves to the power and responsibility we have as employees in the state.
The state value base originated in
The first chapter of the form of government and applies to all government employees.
To understand what this means
Should we briefly go through each concept.
Democracy is about everyone's equal rights and value
And about the possibility of being involved and decide.
It is we who vote who decide who should govern the country.
It is since the people elected in the parliament who understands
Decisions on laws, often based on proposals from the government.
State employees therefore need to have understanding
For citizens, the authority's client.
The activities of an authority
must have support in law or other constitution.
This means that the Social Insurance Agency may not take any action
Or make a decision if we do not support it in laws and regulations.
This is called the principle of legality and encompasses all forms of public
Power of power, including handling in cases at the Swedish Social Insurance Agency.
To understand how the rules should be applied in our business
Do we have the support of guidelines and processes
and other governing documents.
Citizens' right
to free opinion formation, freedom of expression and access to information
is crucial for democracy to work.
Everyone has the right to freely express themselves
in speech, writing, picture or otherwise.
This applies to both us as government employees
And the people we meet and whose cases we handle.
We must take into account that all people are different.
We shall respect their personal integrity
And we do not discriminate against anyone.
Respect for the equal value of everyone is basically about respecting the human
the rights that in itself form the basis of it
Democratic society.
Efficiency is about managing the state's funds,
But even about handling cases quickly and easy.
At the same time as the laws are followed.
Service means doing it
as simple as possible for the people we meet,
that we have flexible processes and good accessibility.
Good service simplifies for all
And make us save on our resources.
An authority is obliged to be factual
and impartial in their business.
Objectivity means that unkind circumstances do not
may form the basis for the assessments made and decisions that are made.
People should be able to trust that the handling or outcome of a decision
not affected by the arbitrar of an individual employee,
own perception or personal ideas.
The Social Insurance Office is governed by the Public Authority,
The instruction for the Social Insurance Office
and the government's annual regulatory letter where goals,
Budget and how the budget is to be distributed is evident.
It may also be added to special government assignments
Where the government gives the authority the task of investigating various issues.
As you have already heard, the Social Insurance Office must
Operations have support in the legal system.
Two laws that are good to know are the Administration Act
that form the basis of how one
Managing Authority shall act in relation to individuals
and the Social Security Code, which is the law that regulates
Most compensation paid by the Social Insurance Office.
The government must never control how the authority exercises the laws.
It is the courts that try this.
If there is scope for interpretation on how the legislation is to be applied is
it practice, that is, indicative decisive
from the Supreme Administrative Court, which becomes governing.
The decision becomes normative for how the legislation will later be interpreted.
Here is part of the insurance and remuneration such as social insurance
encompasses.
For example, there are compensation for families with children,
sick and people with disabilities.
In addition, the Social Insurance Agency pays out
Several of the remuneration decided by the Employment Service.
Every year, the Social Insurance Agency takes approximately
21 \ Hillillions decisions on grants and remuneration.
At fk.se you can read more about the
Various compensation.
Social insurance is
not linked to citizenship but what determines if you are insured
In Sweden, whether you live and work here or not.
Some of the insurance can be
Take part in by being registered in Sweden.
They are called settlement -based benefits.
Other Insurance assumes that you work or have
Worked in Sweden. These are the work -based benefits.
In addition to being insured in Sweden, one also needs to meet the conditions in question
for the compensation you applied for.
Each year pays the Social Insurance Office out
Over 4 \ h% of Sweden's gross domestic product, GDP.
Just over half of the payments go
to the sick and people with disabilities.
Just over a third to children and families and the remaining part
Goes to other remuneration in primarily the labor market area.
Here we see some of the insurance policies that can
become relevant if work ability is impaired due to illness.
It is sickness benefit, activity compensation and sickness benefit.
These remuneration can be obtained in the scope whole, three quarters
half and a quarter.
Sickness benefit should compensate
loss of income due to illness.
About 600 \ H000 people receive sickness benefit each year.
Most people are sick for a shorter period and then return to their work.
For some, there is a need for rehabilitation
action during sick leave.
We will delve into the rules on sickness benefit in the film called
Sickness benefit and preventive sickness benefit.
Activity compensation is one
time -limited compensation for those who are between 19 and 29 years old
And that will not be able to work for at least one year.
Activity compensation can be given between 1 and 3 years
And every year, approximately 6700 new activity allowances are granted.
As the name suggests, there should be some kind of activity.
It can be work -oriented, medical
Or of a leisure nature and it should have a positive impact on the person.
One can also receive activity compensation for extended schooling
If the disability you have makes you need longer
to complete their schooling in elementary school or high school.
Sickness benefit is granted so far and may be relevant
If you will not be able to work more or just be able to work part -time.
Sickness compensation can be granted from the age of 30
Until you can take out old -age pension.
There is an opportunity to receive sickness benefit from 19 years
If it is already clear then that the person will never be able to work.
Each year is granted approximately 5300
persons sickness benefit.
When the Swedish Social Insurance Agency assesses whether the individual is entitled to activity compensation
or sickness compensation we look at the ability to work
in relation to the entire labor market, also protected employment.
This applies to everyone under 61 years.
For those over 61 years there is a special rule that means that work ability
only tested against such work as the person has experience with
and worked with over the past 15 years.
The Swedish Social Insurance Agency meets citizens and partners
in digital meetings when appropriate.
Digital meetings make it easier for more people to participate
and thus increases accessibility.
If there is a need, we can have meetings where we meet physically.
On the Swedish Social Insurance Agency's website there is information about the different benefits
But also digital self -service around the clock.
For example, via My pages you can report sickness
themselves and follow status in their case.
For those who work in healthcare there are special pages
Which provides information about things that you often ask from healthcare.
You can also contact a partner customer center.
There it is possible to if necessary
Leave a message to insurance investigators in a specific case.