Today is a historic day, we have just re -inaugurated Västernorrland's regiment with Jämtland's field hunter corps.
This is a big day for many, it is a big and important day for the Armed Forces.
As we can grow with additional military associations in a strategically important area.
It is important for the army, today we have taken further steps to reintroduce the infantry.
For Sollefteå and Östersund it is also important. This growth allows opportunities for the resort. \hrs
It also allows the opportunity to contribute to strengthening society with the associations we are now setting.
Last but not least, it is a long-awaited day for so many of those who have worked on Västernorrland's regiment and-
-Jämtland's field hunter regiment now that we are inaugurating the two parts.
It feels fantastic. I have longed for this day since 2005, when the business was closed down in Östersund.
It feels great fun and we have very good conditions here locally, to train conscripts.
I look forward to training infantry associations in Norrland's inland and in the mountain terrain where we enjoy and feel at home
It is a big challenge but also something I look forward to doing.