Hello. Majken is my name, and I am a shooter and did my military duty as it -
- And it is very broad what a shooter is but for me it was that I had another weapon.
I had a shotgun, which is a slightly larger weapon.
Yes, my name is Birger and I did the military duty as a radar commander -
–And that means you have a large radar -
- A truck that drives around and then you set it up in a place -
- And so you stand with the help of radar and scout for airplanes.
Today we are here to answer some questions.
I have got an iPad here so it will probably show up something,
But I don't really know what questions we should answer.
So it gets exciting.
Yes, sounds exciting.
Yes, they do.
It is part of that that you do not make a difference in gender.
I thought it was good.
It really shows that you do not make a difference in gender.
Yes but exactly. And I think it would have become more we and them feeling -
- If you had slept separately.
Really.
Oh.
Yes, you are placed in war at the end of your conscripts -
- And should be prepared to solve the service you have been trained.
But then you can also take employment, if you would like to, you do not have to -
- And work within the Armed Forces.
There are good opportunities to do so.
You get salary, so to speak.
You get a full SEK 146 a day.
So that's nice money.
But you have no expenses either.
No. You get free accommodation and food.
Yes and all trips home on leave paid.
So I really had no expenses, it was a little candy type you buy on the weekends.
But otherwise it really is, most people save that money.
And then you get a lump sum.
What you have earned you get again when you have finished the education as well.
So if you do for nine months you have received 40 thousand -
- And so you get it again, so 80,000 then.
Tax -free.
Yeah.
And I did 15 months as KB, as it is called, company fäls -
- And 15 months times the four thousand you get a month will be a little more maybe.
It was a nice cling at the checkout when I got there, the day we finished.
Yes but a little this macho culture.
Everyone should be big, strong, tough ... endure a lot
But I noticed that pretty quickly -
- That no one was prepared for what was waiting in the beginning.
And then I ended up on a fairly technically oriented pluton then.
There was everyone like me. A little nature interested, or had this interest in plugging and so on.
Yes and a little similar, though, it is for me, because it was not very theory in my position -
- Out it was more out and pig in the forest type.
So I thought everyone would be this huge, strong man -
- But I fit in very well there and I'm not that stereotype.
So that I think it is very much wider than you think.
Then it is also an education, and that was perhaps not what I had mainly in my head -
- That it would still be a bit theory even though I had significantly less than I can imagine you had -
- So it was still some theoretical lessons and you talked a lot about how a group is and you should get to know each other.
And that's not what I had seen in front of me when I saw the lump in front of me.
Mental.
I would probably say a mixture, but the physical I think it will be psychic.
So you are out walking and wearing heavy, it is very busy physically.
But the hardest thing, I think, is the mental thing to constantly motivate oneself to continue walking or to cope a little longer.
So what is most difficult physically also gets the most difficult mentally, I think.
Oh.
I have so many memories, but I would probably say that both the best and the worst was probably the end of our group manager school.
We ate maybe one meal a day, and were under constant stress and then hunted by the enemy.
That's when you realized that shit I know so much more, I can live with very little food and with very little water -
- Because there was something I was very afraid of before ...
... when I go three hours without food so I start to get cheerful and dip together total -
- But it went well, because you were still prepared for it in some way.
And that was also the toughest.
I remember we went, and then we almost got back to where we had started the exercise.
So I thought now maybe we can go home ... but then we stayed for three more days.
Then you never get ... When you think you can go home so just no, it will not be so.
Ah. So I had many dips there.
But it was also what made it feel so good afterwards, that you managed it.
For me a little the same, the worst memories are also the best in some way because they are the ones you learn most from I think.
Mine was probably ... we had a soldier's test so we had done this and tested without food and such ...
... how do you manage for a few days. And it would have been shit.
But after that we had a job training ...
... and then I would have the shotgun for the first time,
Also, we would have a march to learn to go with it and pall the packing -
- And then I wore the charging bag, ie where you have all the bullets to shoot -
- And it gets pretty heavy because there is a lot to shoot.
So I thought it was ... It's my worst memory, but there I really learned ...
... it was probably the first time during the entire undergraduate education, then I had been in for a while -
- As I really felt that shit what I pallets more than I think.
Because then it really was this one, find more motivation to keep going even though I just want to lie down and scream on the ground.
But it went.
And I took that with me then, all other times I needed to carry all that equipment.
But the best thing, if I do not say a specific memory, then this is probably around.
So it's not just being out in the woods and walking and wearing heavy, or like -
- Lodest in some clay so, but it is a lot of community too.
So we went away and sometimes bathed in our spare time.
We played a fireball tournament.
All the things, the community you have, it is fantastic.
Yes indeed.
So that these are probably my best memories too. Leisure.
Nah. -No.
I thought it was very nice that there is no difference between women and men.
Then you may notice as a woman that like this, you are a minority -
- But I would say that the commanders, ie the teachers I had during my education - -
- They were very good that if we were out in the field we also got five minutes to pee -
- That every time you like this, I request more time, so I can't pee in five minutes -
- You may have had menstruation or so, then they were very very understanding.
And I only had male commanders, so for me it was a bit of a shock in the beginning that they were so understanding.
I thought it would be much harder than it was.
And what are fields? Should we start there?
We can start with fields. I have a little control over.
When you are out in the woods simply and practice or do different things, you are in the field, then it is called.
And you can live in the forest then. So, sleep over.
All the guys who were in combat pairs with a woman had to have some tampons in her pocket always or some kind of menswear -
- To be out in the field, maybe they would end or so.
So that there was always someone extra that wore.
I could always go to my combat companion and then he could pick out some tampons.
But if you have menstruation in the field, that is, the only thing is to bring the type of wet wipes out so you can wash your hands properly.
Yes. -Yes.
After all, there is no weapon -free military service today.
Nah.
So we had a job training as it is called when you start to focus on their different branches -
- I suspect you were out and shot a lot then.
We were.
Pig and had a hard time, in my world.
While I was sitting in a lesson room, had a cup of coffee, took a little break from time to time, taught us ...
... Like sitting in the school bench and plugging.
I thought it was much more difficult than what I did.
Because it is very theory and technically so.
I thought ... Obviously it's hard sometimes if you are out and going with packing and sowing, for example -
- But a lot when you shoot a shotgun, you might lie down, shoot at different goals in different places sow -
- So it is not always very physically and I do not think it is so hard because you do not have to think that much.
Of course you have to think about safety and everything like that but otherwise ...
- No, it is usually nice to go to the shooting range one day and just lie down, Panga a little.
Yes, it really is not hard all the time.
Yes, you have to do that. It is always possible to have a map in your pocket.
So I really didn't see myself as a typical military and still don't do it -
—The far from the stereotypical image I had before I did my military duty -
- That it would be very macho and you would be very big, strong and you would have an interest in being out in the woods -
- And maybe different weapons systems that some find interesting.
I was like this, I liked to hang out with friends, make up, I liked clothes ...
... So, it was really as far away as I could imagine that you could be from the Armed Forces and the military.
But I enjoy it very well and have found something that I really like.
So even though I really didn't see myself as the stereotypical military, I'm a military now.
Yes but exactly. And I recognize myself a lot in it because I saw myself pretty much like ...
... I am not strong enough and not enough on and forward, and I like to joke about it a little and so -
- And be a little lattjo, and it doesn't fit in because there it should be strict and "up oppos".
I'm a little more in the geeky direction maybe.
You are actually needed there, even if you think you are a reading head that may not have sports as a favorite subject.
And it has boosted my self -esteem so much because I thought a little about myself before the military service.
Yes but that was for me too. You get a bigger perspective, I would say, on things.
Although I might like to make up, or still do -
- So I can live in the forest without doing it, so I do not die from it.
So that you learn a lot about yourself and you learn to appreciate things a lot.
I think we can appreciate a hot shower, more than many who have not done military service can, for example.
Or a bed.
A bed!
Food.
There are many who are perhaps a little nervous about this, yes, but the bed is very narrow and hard and boring JU -
- But after being out in the field for a week, it is the best bed you could wish for.
To just ... a bed.
Yes, it is difficult sometimes.
It is difficult to beat.
Should we say thank you?
Yes.
It was probably.