2021 has been a year that has gone very well-
- True that the pandemic characterized both society and us.
We have expanded our business in terms of staff, equipment and new associations.
And the most important thing: we build stronger war associations.
We have welcomed 5,000 new recruits to our conscription training.
Many of our soldiers have chosen to apply for our vocational and specialist officer training.
We have gained more civilian competence and expanded by about 1,000 people.
The trend remains that the proportion of women will increase.
A strong staff supply strengthens our ability and endurance.
We have re -established three regiments and an aircraft fleet.
K 4 in Arvidsjaur.
AMF 4 in Gothenburg.
In 13 in Falun.
And F 16 in Uppsala.
The bandages will contribute to a more sustainable organization -
- Where we will continue to train more conscripts.
And we get a clear geographical presence in strategically important areas.
We have received new equipment but also renewed existing.
Among other things, we have received the Robot System Patriot-
- A brand new ability that meets the threat development in our immediate area.
With the introduction, Sweden has an opportunity to coordinate the air defense -
- With other nations that also have the system in order to increase the operational effect.
With our new recruits, re -established regiments and new equipment -
- We actively actively actively actively in 2021 to build the defense of the future.
The army has had good exercise activities during the year.
During the southern front, a reduced brigade was practiced under a division's leadership.
Thus, we showed our partners and potential opponents -
- That we build a stronger army and thus a safer Sweden.
Through exercises like Swenex, the foundation is laid for safety in the immediate area.
The Navy also practices with others, such as the Air Force and the Coast Guard -
- And has several important international collaborations, especially with the Finnish Navy.
During the year, the Navy strengthened the sea surveillance -
- And also increased the presence on Gotland for a period, in response to increased activity in the Baltic Sea.
The Air Force has protected and monitored Swedish airspace around the clock.
The number of conscripts during undergraduate education increases -
And the Air Force grows in abilities through education and exercises.
Such as the recently implemented air defense exercise.
During the autumn, the special associations have been together with American special associations in Sweden.
Autumn also meant a historical manager's change -
- In the large multinational special associations Task Force Takuba in Mali.
The strength is now led by a Swedish colonel from the special associations.
The Battle Power Home Guard has now resumed its educational activities after the pandemin -
- And started work on the supply of new equipment and new abilities.
ÖB has decided to introduce a new central management in 2023
- which will provide a clearer and simpler management of operations and operations.
Our important international collaborations have continued with full force.
So does our collaborations with other Nordic countries.
Similarly, our operational planning with countries such as the UK, the United States and NATO has developed.
With our international collaborations, our exercise operations and ÖB's decision on a new central management -
- We have collaborated in a very good way for a stronger defense force in 2021.
Our international efforts are important for the defense of Sweden.
Our efforts in Mali are difficult and demanding, but of great importance to Africa and Europe.
The effort for several years in Afghanistan has also made a difference.
Our part in the evacuation from Afghanistan was an operation of the ultimate class.
The Armed Forces play a central role in total defense development.
How the total defense is to be developed has been made clear in action:
The document that ÖB and DG MSB have agreed.
We must never lose focus on our culture.
How we are against each other, and with each other, is important for our ability.
With clarifications on the development of the total defense and our central role -
- In 2021 we have shown samples of foresight.
So that Sweden is better equipped for tomorrow's threat.