In my job
Do I make sure that air combat leaders and pilots
can talk to each other.
During a flight, information must be able to flow between
us in the combat management center and the aircraft.
Through Data Link we send mode updates to the pilot
And with radio, the air combat leaders lead the air battle.
My job is to make sure all systems work.
In order to do that I need to understand both
the tactical and the technical.
I get an insight into everyone's details
And we become a welded team.
The special thing about my job is that I am where it happens.
On my screens I have constant surveillance over our technical systems
And I see the air situation throughout Sweden.
My name is Hampus
And I'm a management system officer.