The Armed Forces defend Sweden-
-The country's interest, our freedom and our right to live as we choose ourselves.
The world we live in, our immediate area, is more uncertain than in a long time.
Therefore, the Riksdag has decided that our military ability should increase.
If Sweden is subjected to an armed attack, the Armed Forces' war federation is mobilized
-To be able to ward off the attack.
Everyone must know their role, and what to do if we are attacked.
Therefore, we carry out Armed Forces exercise Aurora 23-
-Together with Sweden's international partners.
In mid-April, by mid-May, the army, the Navy, the Air Force and the Home Guard-
-To defend Sweden with each other.
Together with other parts of society and together with international partners.
We increase our ability to lead our bandages on the ground, at sea, and in the air-
-S and our ability to collaborate with the civil defense.
We practice our training fields and we practice in the community we will defend.
Together we defend Sweden.