Welcome to the bridge - from here the ship is performed
An officer navigates and maneuvers and has a sailor to look out for his support.
Together, they have supervision and control over the business on board and around the ship.
The ship's manager is often on the dock and always in place when Belos throws loose or moor-
-Or is inserted or when it is impaired.
Together we work as a team and help to perform the ship in a secure manner-
-Ofort of business, time of day or weather.
Belos is equipped with a dynamic positioning system; DP-
-What is a system for keeping the ship still with the vessel's trusers and propellers.
The system is used to belos to lie still over a position-
-There underwater jobs must be performed with divers or underwater vehicles.
Here is the dining room where we eat the three and sometimes four meals served during the day -
-Breakfast, lunch, dinner and when we are at sea even night acquisition.
The dining room can accommodate about 50 people.
Here we have the gun where our three chefs cook the four goals of the day to the approximately 40 people in the crew.
Often we have with extra staff that make it significantly more portions to be served, but it always fixes our chefs.
Here we have the Chamber Hall that houses three large pressure chambers that are for treatment-
-As different forms of pressure disease or diving sickness.
Here we can treat a whole submarine crew or divers that show symptoms of pressure drop disease.
The chamber system can be pushed down to the corresponding 350 meter deep
-And is served by staff on the outside and the inside who ensure that the staff in the chamber system has a good environment.
Here we are inside the chamber center wall to wall with the chamber hall.
From here we take care of pressure increase and pressure reduction and other monitoring of the chamber system.
The business is led by chamberwear leaders who have a number of chamber operators to their help-
-On the outside and chamber caretaker on the inside.
After about the Chamber Center is Belos Gym, decorated on two floors.
Here on the upper are workout bikes and treadmills for fitness training-
-And downstairs is the actual gym with equipment for strength and agility training.
Here we see a seaman's cabin located at the bottom of the ship on the tires where it actually swings least and is the quietest.
The sailors live in single cabins with a common toilet and shower department.
A tire up is also a sauna where you can warm up after a cold working day on deck or after a diving assignment
Here we are down in the engine room.
Belos is a vessel with diesel electrical progress-
-What means that we have generators that produce power that then operate the ship's propellers.
Machine staff continuously control the various technical systems on board
-To ensure progress.
In the space next door is the control room from where the engine room's input system is monitored.
During a guard, machine and control rooms are staffed by an officer and a motor.
Here we are inside the fair where we can have a cup of coffee and unwind after the work session.
There is also the opportunity for crew collections and meetings as well as a little finer dinner sitting.
There is also a TV corner and a small library in the fair.
The fair also serves as a medical place where our doctor and our healthcare providers take care of any injury cases.
Here we see Belo's wet dive clock that is housed in a container on deck.
The clock is staffed by two divers who are raised with relatively heavy equipment down to the dive object.
The clock's umbilical cord supplies the divers with respiratory gas, hot water to the costumes and power to cameras and lights.
Belo's dive system can use both air and mixed gas depending on dive depth and can be used down to 90 meters depth.
Welcome to the diving center.
From the dive center, all underwater activities that Belos can perform.
In here, the diving leader is for the wet clock diving.
The dive leader has control at times for downs and ascent and leads the divers' jobs on the dive object.
In the dive center also sits the supervisor for the operations with our underwater vessels or prey: er
The prey pilots here have their operator sites from which they control our various underwater vehicles.