Welcome aboard a Gävlekorvett.
Up here on the dock, the ship is run.
An officer navigates the ship and gives orders to a seaman about what course the vessel should hold.
There are also lookouts on the ship who, with the help of binoculars, support the operating officer-
-With what is around the ship, and supports the combat management center.
Often there is the ship's manager here.
All of these work as a team and help to perform the ship for sure
-Os if it's sunshine, night or fog.
Welcome to the combat management center
From here the battle is led.
In the combat management system, information is presented from radar, sonar and other sensors.
The radar can see aircraft, robots and other vessels.
The sonar shows what is below the water surface, such as submarines.
The telecommunications staff can also discover other things that broadcast.
Like all other work on board, it is a teamwork where everyone is helped.
The ship is equipped with a 57 millimeter alms cannon-
-And eight sea -target robots of model robot 15, but can also wear torpedo, sinking bombs and mines.
On board, officers live in two, three or four years.
The sailors live in a cabin with 18 bing sites.
When the ship is at sea, half the crew normally works while the other half rests.
You work in six-hour guards-
-Sex hours work followed by six hours when eating, exercising, sleeping, cleaning or doing something else.
Here in the fair we eat and this is also where we watch TV or relax.
When the ship is at sea, you eat every six hours divided into two different guards.
The fairs also serve as a healthcare site and, for example, to lead firefighting on board.
On board are two chefs who cook for the more than 40 people in the crew.
At sea, they cook breakfast, lunch, dinner and night procurement.
In connection with the gun there is also fair one, it is the sailors' fair-
-There they eat, relax and spend time on freelance.
In the engine room there are main engines and generators powered by diesel.
The vessel is powered by water levels that are quieter than propellers.
The vessel has three main engines that together with the waterjaggaten-
-GOs the ship a speed of over 30 knots
There are also generators that make electricity, boilers that make hot water-
-and osmosis units that manufacture drinking water of salt water-
-and much other technical equipment.