After all, we have talked about this with quality of different cars.
And now I'm going to pull a little anecdote for you.
It is so that, besides Grufman car, I also have a small side business
called Grufman Gräv.
We are digging.
We have done some jobs where we have found things under the customer's old garage entrance.
And this I think illustrates what is quality or not.
You who drive German cars understand ...
When you see it, you're know it.
I mean, it's totally self -clear
On American quality instead.
Look here.
Here we have perfect lacquer, those who sit in the car are happy.
The dog is happy.
The wheels remain, they even rotate.
This is all that was needed on an American car.
We have learned that American cars are of good quality.
While German cars are of inferior quality.