Back!
Now we keep track of how the high school choice goes to
But how should I know which program
that is best for me?
Should i take it my friends take
Or should I go based on my own interests?
I have invited a person
Who will give us knowledge about this.
What's your name?
My name is Jessica
And I work as a study and career counselor.
There are 18 different national high school programs,
Is there any big difference between them?
The biggest difference is between
the college preparatory programs
And vocational programs.
On a college preparation program
Is the idea that after high school you will study further.
The vocational programs prepare you for the labor market
So that you start working after high school.
What is it required to be adopted
to a national high school program?
A foundation of a portion of the requirements is in any case
Grades in Swedish, math and English.
You can read more about which permissions
As needed for each program here in the articles
at high school.se.
Good there, high school!
What program do you go?
I go to the IT program.
Why did you just choose that program?
I've always had a great interest in games and such.
That's probably why I chose the IT program.
Once I got into it it was wow!
Since then, interest has only grown and plant.
What program do you go?
I go the aesthetic program with a focus on interior design.
Why did you just choose that program?
I wanted three fun years ahead of me
and I wanted to do something practical
Because I liked the picture when I attended elementary school.
Can you only attend high school programs in Swedish?
No, there is also an alternative called IB.
Where you read college preparation programs
With all courses except the Swedish lessons in English.
Because there are so many different programs,
What to think about when making your choice?
The most important thing to think about
is what you are motivated by and are interested in.
And what you think is fun!
If you are reading something that you are
interested and motivated by
So it often generates good results.
That you get better results in the courses you read
gives you the opportunity to reach higher ratings.
Then it is also important to think about
If you already know a profession that you want to work with.
Gives this program the permission
Or eligibility for further studies to that profession?
Thank you so much for all the info,
Now I feel that I have a great look!
We have barely had coffee.
What fun I could be helpful!
Why did you just choose your program?
I personally was pretty sure of my choice,
I have long wanted to work with something in finance or law.
So for me the choice was pretty obvious!
You see,
Choose what you want!
Another step closer to high school!