Many programs can usually be read at several different schools.
Have you decided to read the community program but do not really know which school you want to attend?
Absolutely understandable. I will meet some high school students to ask why they chose their school.
Come along!
Why did you just choose your school? Was it something that was extra important to you?
I chose the design gymnasium because I want to plug in design.
Then the design gymnasium feels almost like the obvious choice.
And then I thought the situation very well at Kungsholmen.
I come from a school with over 1000 students. So coming to a small school felt very nice.
I chose my school because I heard about it through other friends.
And I thought it was nice to go into town and leave the schools where I have lived before.
What is important here and the thing for me is that I see several cultures as well as from different countries.
And you can learn a lot from cultures and nationality.
And in the language you can develop further.
Why did you just choose your school? Was it something that was especially important to you?
I chose Queen Blanka Kungsholmen because it is close to me.
They have the direction that I am most interested in.
And I wanted to go to a small school.
So that you ...
You get community and you do not feel alone.
The most important thing for me was probably both the teaching and what I read.
It was not much about where school was low or the food or so without it was the most
That I wanted to attend a good technology school.
As you understand.
It is very individual what you choose to appreciate yourself.
Try to think about what is important to you.
The situation, recommendations or how the teachers are.
One step closer to high school!