Environmental policy risks stopping Swedish cement production.
Expresses this a progressive climate responsibility,
or is it an idealistic decision with system -threatening consequences
The Hardest Choices Require The Strongest Wills
Sentences go apart, like a misunderstood block concrete
My name is Henrik Jönsson, and I am an independent, libertarian entrepreneur and social debater.
Recently, cement manufacturer Cementa's application for continued lime mining permit was rejected in Slite on Gotland.
As a consequence, Sweden risks standing without cement at the end of October,
We are all out
With major consequences for both the construction industry, mining and for Swedish industrial exports.
According to the construction industry's calculations, up to 400,000 jobs are threatened,
And Sweden risks suffering an investment loss of SEK 20 billion a month as long as cement deficiency prevails.
Why is this type of acute crisis situation constantly arises in modern Sweden
Is it reasonable to regard this conflict as a choice between environment or cement
And what happens to a society such as institutionalized emotional and ideological reactions to a greater extent than rational and long -term decision -making processes
Feelings are action
I address these questions in this week's video.
If you like my movies, you will help me continue to make them if you support me through one of the payment options out here on the left.
It is only thanks to your generous support that I can continue to make new ones,
Current videos every week.
So a big big thank you to those of you who make this possible
If you are new here on the channel, you can advantageously subscribe below.
Also make sure to cement your notes from me,
By clicking on that concrete-heavy clock icon-but subscribe mainly to my free weekly letter,
So you never miss out when I release new movies, which I do with stiff discipline,
Every Saturday morning at 0800 Swedish time
Today I talk about cement, central control and cerebral processes.
come along
A cow we will drive in bet on our meadow ”and bolster of down we will have in our bed
And nice postelin and glazed barrels ”you admit!
Mayo you!
So we should not have!
But, you, you, you, where should we not take it.
I'm too poor and you're too lazy
You go on the root, and I go on state you admit!
Mayo you!
Where should we take no?
So is the last two verses in Gustaf Fröding's economic satiric "marriage issue" from 1891.
The discrepancy between the wishes of the in love and their economic reality illustrates in humor mirror the human nature's
Duala nature, where the rapid, emotional feeling anticipates the slower rational thought process's skull reality.
Honey, don't think I don't know how you feel.
The award -winning Israeli psychologist and economist Daniel Kahneman describes in his book "Think quickly and slowly"
These two parallel human attitudes.
The first reaction system is fast, intuitive and emotionally
Which in Fröding's poem is expressed with the exclamation "so we should not"
The second system is slow, logical and requires mental effort to reach its answers, which is emphasized in the poem's questioning final clamp
"Where are we going to take out"
Properly applied, both of these systems are useful and helpful, but the slow system works poorly in acute crisis situations
And the fast system risks making disastrous decisions regarding long -term and complex issues.
Do Not Press the Core Destruct Button
The environmental issue and its packaging in the debate often express a conflict between these two ways of thinking,
Where the rapid reactions stand for climate anxiety, airbags and emotionally embossed symbolic measures,
In a situation that really requires a pragmatic and well -founded reality anchoring so as not to risk becoming destructive and counterproductive.
It is therefore important to avoid emotional reactions to problems that require rational solutions.
Your highly emotional reaction is most illogical.
In particular, it is important to avoid the temptation to play on voters 'rapid emotional reactions on complex issues as politicians to play the temptation of voters' rapid emotional reactions
Which is a political approach that is sometimes called "populism".
Libations for everybody
A concrete example of how wrong thought systems on idealistic, and probably even emotional basis
has permeated the Swedish administration is land and the Environmental Court's sudden rejection of the cement producer Cementa's right to break lime in Slite on Gotland.
Cementa produces 85% of Sweden's cement, and had already applied four years ago for the extension of its lime mining rights,
An request that was initially also approved by the Land and the Environmental Court.
After the judgment was appealed by, among other things, the state authority the Swedish Environmental Protection Agency,
The County Administrative Board of Gotland and a climate activist group called the Urberg group, so Cementa's application was rejected last week
With the result that their cement production will be forced to cease by October last year.
The reason why the application was rejected is that the court found the investigation into the consequences of the lime mining for the groundwater unsatisfactory.
That the court chooses to reject Cementa's request so close to renewal date,
Although the application was made four years ago, it makes it impossible for the company to supplement its application
And they have now appealed to the Supreme Court with the hope that the case will be handled with priority.
Responsibility for the crisis arising falls on the Löfven government and then Minister of the Environment Åsa Romson,
As in 2018, the decision to expand the nature conservation areas around Cementa's limestone quarry in Slite.
The Environmental Court's failure to Cementa's permit application specifically refers to the area hejnum Kallgate
an area that the government extended.
Cementa warned in 2017 in a statement that these changes meant that cement production
"is considerably difficult/risked to cease, in the near future and in the long run."
Cementa has produced cement for 100 years without operational disruptions.
The current cement crisis is thus a direct consequence of an active government decision by the Löfven government, headed for by the Environment Party.
But the consequences of a seemingly kind -hearted and ideologically embossed climate decision
Can now prove to destabilize large parts of Sweden's infrastructure.
The domino effect is the cumulative effect created when an event triggers a chain reaction of similar events.
These types of chain reactions are at risk of becoming very large -scale and can be triggered through careless manipulation of seemingly insignificant details in a complex system.
Within the climate activist movement, the understanding of this is relatively good,
And you are therefore very keen to protect the ecosystem from different types of disorders.
Fewer, however, extend the same understanding to the complex system of human civilization,
whose productive work is expressed in the form of a global and self -regulating trading system
Which is so complex that no human being has the capacity to overlook its whole.
An entertaining illustration of this production system's breathtaking complexity was made in 2015 by an ambitious young Youtuber,
Who set to make your own chicken sandwich.
So, to really make their own chicken sandwich from scratch
From growing own wheat and your own vegetables to breeding a chicken and extracting their own salt from the sea.
Making a chicken sandwich that you can buy at the Press Office for under the hundredths
Took him over half a year to do, and cost the equivalent of close to SEK 15,000.
It is only through myriads of trade relations, specialist competencies and service exchanges
As the fruits of modern civilization are available and it is very easy to take them for granted.
Therefore, if one wants to limit the extraction of certain types of raw materials on a political basis, it is very important that you first implement
in -depth impact assessments, as it very easily arises unforeseen imbalances in the trading system when the availability of different types of raw materials changes.
Which, such as the availability of lime.
It may with the way of the emotional, intuitive system of thinking appear both reasonable and sensible to slow down the interventions in nature,
At the same time as the long -term, and slower thinking reveal secondary consequences that not only create
Comprehensive societal problems, without who also risk being significantly worse for the environment.
If you limit the availability of lime, it is not only a presumed greedy commodity company that becomes the battle on the fingers in favor of the environment
Because by abruptly strangling the lime mining, a chain reaction is triggered throughout the Swedish trading system.
Lime is needed to produce cement.
If there is no cement, you cannot build any houses.
Nor can one build any roads or renovate Sweden's rail systems
And infrastructure projects such as the West Link and Stockholm's new lock will not be completed.
In the next stage, Swedish mining also stops, as this is dependent on cement to strengthen the rock after blasting.
The state mining group LKAB's forecasts indicates a loss of production of around 80% of all iron ore if you are deprived of access to cement.
Without iron ore, in turn, the manufacturing industry stops, and Swedish exports collapse.
The construction industry, which has already requested a crisis meeting with the government now warns that a construction stop of this type
threatens between 200,000 and 400,000 jobs, while 3 out of 4 building projects will not be able to take place.
According to the construction companies, this will in turn lead to an investment loss of approximately SEK 20 billion per month
And then you do not include the investment loss that will affect an industry that stands without the iron, steel, the plate welfare.
From the mine came the iron, steel, plate and welfare.
In the next stage, logistics and the transport industry are affected.
Without guaranteed deliveries of cement, iron ore and industrial products after October 31st, the drivers must be notified already in August.
A lost logistics industry means longer delivery times on all types of goods, which in turn increases the pressure on fairways and public transport
which cannot be renovated and maintained without cement, concrete and iron ore.
The consequences quickly become irresponsible.
For everything is connected: Whether it is something as simple as a sandwich or a bridge foundation in reinforced concrete,
So all existing products are dependent on sensitive supply chains.
The possibility of compensating for the ideologically established cement deficiency through procurement in the international market
is limited due to delivery times and high international demand for cement.
And even if Swedish companies would succeed in buying parties of overseas cement, this would be both considerably expensive
And worse for the environment due to the low environmental requirements of the production countries, and because of the long transport from, for example, Algeria and Turkey.
Notwithstanding if you, as Dagens Nyheter, choose to present the cement crisis as something you "should bring a pinch of salt"
and as a battle between market forces and the environment,
So the central problem is the constantly so careless approach to issues related to Sweden's basic infrastructure.
It is perfectly legitimate that different social interests test their respective claims in court
But when it comes to socially important functions such as raw material extraction and energy production, these issues must be handled in good time,
With the necessary impact assessments and with pre -implemented new solutions for the maintenance of Swedish society.
No God Damn Plan B. With the necessary impact assessments and with pre -implemented new solutions for the maintenance of Swedish society.
No good damn plan B.
For the clueless and emotionally colored arbitrariness that has long characterized Sweden's relationship with system -critical functions such as preparedness,
Raw material and energy production testify to an idealistic ignorance that is characteristic of Kahneman's quick,
emotional and in this case environment
with potentially disastrous results.
For without the long -term and rational anchoring of the sowing system, ignorant and activist ideologists' choice -handed manipulation risks manipulation
by systems they neither understand nor have the skills to recreate to cause Swedish infrastructure irreparable damage
But that prices are so high that paper mills close, it can be good for the environment.
I do not criticize the ambition to care for nature, the ambition to streamline production or the intention to develop new and more sustainable technology.
I criticize the fast, emotional and counterproductive approach that can be rightly called environmental urgent.
Because it is very easy to house strong emotions, while reality -based decisions place high demands on knowledge and reflection.
I now allow myself to paraphrase Gustaf Fröding's "marriage issue" in contemporary political context,
With the extremely relevant environmental reformist question: where should you take not
With emotion we shall defend our power so everyone can see our moral splendor
With gender doctrine and protected climate “Stefan you!
Märta you!
So we should not have!
But, Märta you, Märta you, where should we take it.
I am too Velig and you psychopath
The goals we discuss, they just get talk Stefan you!
Märta you!
Where should we go!
And since Sweden's left has recently become unreasonably inclined to hang up on deliberate misinterpretations, here comes a fireplace:
So I do not accuse the Environmental Party's speech tube Märta Stenevi of psychopathy.
This is just a satirizing word that rhymes on "where should we take not" and that plays on her recurring and half -attempted attempts
to opportunistic virtue signaling.
Thus, there is no reason to cry out in the press and demand an excuse for my word choice.
And then I hope that the Ledarfot finds someone else to discuss Marxist power theory.
I can recommend Henrik Jönsson.
Thank you Mrs. President.
Thank you in advance for applying a rational cognitive process instead of an emotional cognitive process.
To get foreign -born women, then, then white domestic women will also have to move.
Do you think it is more important to make long -term and thoughtful decisions, than to react emotionally when it comes to complex issues
In that case I think you should share this video with your friends
And why not subscribe to my Youtube channel when you're still on the move?
If you have your own experiences with environmental populism, please share your experiences in the comments section below
I appreciate all respectful communication.
However, remember to always be polite.
I do not accept aggression, person assembly or racism in my idea -driven comment fields.
Thank you for commenting on this.
My name is Henrik Jönsson, and I recommend a rational and more time -consuming thought work over rapid emotional reactions.
Thanks for me, and thank you for listening to