Meet Marie Mattsson
Professor of Environmental Science
My name is Marie Mattsson-
-and I am a Professor of Environmental Science
here at the University.
What is your research about?
My research is very much about climate,
environment and important societal challenges-
-and how we can learn more about them, understand them
and maybe do something about them.
The concrete example is the research we conduct on biogas.
How to use biogas, how agriculture can produce biogas
and how it can replace fossil fuels-
-and what you can use the biogas for which
it is produced for example in agriculture.
It can be used for heavy transport if we liquefy the biogas.
Then I am also involved in other projects-
-linked to agriculture and eutrophication problems.
It is a LOVA project-
-where we look at the concerns that agriculture poses-
-in the form of emissions of fertilizers and
if we can avoid it in different ways.
When it comes to these eutrophication
substances, there is a whole-
-a whole battery of different measures that you can take.
Then we have looked at this with peatlands-
-for peatlands have proven to be a very
large emitter of greenhouse gases.
If we can re-wet these peatlands so
that they become wetlands again-
-and then harvest the material
that grows up, for example reeds-
-and use it for biogas,
then we get a double climate benefit.
Why have you become interested in environmental issues?
I have been working with plants-
-and I have been dealing with environmental
issues in various places-
-at the Swedish University of Agricultural Sciences and the Danish University of Agricultural Sciences for ten years.
You can see that agriculture is a very important industry.
We need food that agriculture produces-
-but agriculture is also an environmental culprit in some areas.
There we need to find solutions.
What is the significance of your research?
It can be important both locally and in general.
We may be looking at what it looks like here in Halland-
-with farmers who want to invest in starting
to produce biogas and so on.
But there are also things that can be followed-
-both in other places in Sweden but also abroad.
What is most important in your role as a Professor?
I think it is very important to teach-
-make the students aware and increase
their knowledge in these subjects.
So that they can then go out and
maybe get leading positions in society
-where they can really make a difference.