-Hello.
- Want to show me around?
-I can do that.
Where are we now?
Right now we are in the health lab.
What to do here?
Here, students can practice care in a more real environment.
For example, you will find nurses in here who practice knitting needles in a fake.
Okay.
Do you work with real blood then?
No we do not.
The blood is also fake.
How do you celebrate a exam?
I do not celebrate my exams until I have received the grade, but ...
... a big glass of O'boy, maybe.
Is the great love of your life here at college?
You never know.
Can you describe Halmstad University in three words?
If I were to describe the college in three words, it would be: best in Sweden.
We were actually voted on the best student city.
Do you have any extra jobs alongside?
I have.
I work as a treatment educator and housing support.
Do you need an extra job?
I think so.
If you waste a little more money, it is good to have an extra job aside.
What is your favorite place on campus?
My favorite place is the library.
There are many who sit there and plug, and you get easier into a plug-flow.
What is the most unexpected thing about student life?
The most unexpected is enough-
-That there are so many who are involved in student life outside the plug.
And if you come here as new in town you get many friends quite quickly.
- Hi, where do you come from?
- Hi, I come from Iran.
Where are we and what can you do here?
We are in the electronics center in Halmstad.
It is an innovation arena-
-For local companies and a testing room for EMC tests.
What is the best thing about Halmstad?
Sunny Tylösand and cozy winter nights.
What is unique about Halmstad University?
You can always find at least one person listening to your ideas, even if they are completely crazy.
Excuse me, I have to change shoes.
-Can you any Swedish?
- Well!
- What can you say?
- I am called Fujan and I like chocolate.
How do you live?
I live in student corridors with a huge kitchen and a large family.
Was it difficult to find accommodation?
Not at all.
I got my accommodation the same day I came here.
Cinnamon buns or meatballs?
A cinnamon bun after meatballs.
Have you found friends for life?
Yes, I was lucky enough to find some.
Was it so cold here as you expected?
Not at all.
There is colder and more snow in my hometown.
What is the weirdest thing about Swedes?
Lingon jam for the meatballs.
Come on.
Zlatan or ABBA?
ABBA.
Describe Halmstad University in three words.
Innovation, future and community.
Hi, where are we and what can you do here?
Right now we are in the digital laboratory center.
Here you can meet researchers, students and teachers at the university-
-And learn all about new technology and digitalisation.
Which students usually hang out here?
In here it is usually students from the teacher programs, the community programs-
-and the humanities.
How do you live?
I live in one via Willhem, which is a private housing company.
Was it difficult to find accommodation?
Yes, it is difficult if you are not out in good time.
I lived in the second place the first half-year-
-And it was via a Facebook ad.
Do you choose gas or movie night?
Movie night.
Which one is the favorite movie?
I have to say that is when the lambs are silent.
How much do you have to plug?
You plug about 40 hours a week.
But it is different depending on the course it is - but usually 40 hours.
Do everyone bike in Halmstad?
Yes.
What do you always have with you to an exam?
I always carry the track and Red Bull.
It's my two stuff.
What do you always have to do before an exam?
I never plug in the same day but sit at home and take it calmly
-So I will be rested and prepared.
Can you train on campus?
Yes, you can work out at the sports center, which is a gym with slightly different premises.
What do you prefer to exercise?
I prefer to practice paddle, but now I'm going to go and gym.
Hi, what is the best thing about life as a student?
The social, I think.
You meet many new friends - I like that.
Where are we now?
Now we are at the Sports Center, which is part of Campus-
-And they also have a large gymnasium in here that you can train in.
How is the atmosphere on campus?
A little calmer than usual, because much is remotely because of Corona.
But it works well.
It's a good atmosphere.
What do you do when you are not plugging?
I practice Thai boxing and other activities with friends - paddle and such.
Are any of your courses digital now?
They are both and.
There are lectures and at distance-
-And some are both -ie lecturers filmed at Zoom.
How does it work do you think?
It works well.
Zoom is nice.
You can be anywhere and see it.
But the lectures give the most and you learn most from being in place.
- Do you drive a lunch box or do you buy lunch?
-Lunch box.
What is the go-to food box?
It is probably some lens in the moment.
What is Common Core?
Common Core is that many different programs go together and mix their knowledge-
-And together solves some societal challenge.
How often do you bathe in the sea?
Maybe two to three times a year-
-But it might be more now that you live here.
What is the best plug rack?
I like the City Library.
If you go down one floor, they have a quiet floor there that works very well.
There I feel that I am most effective.
Where is the best coffee on campus?
I think that is home.
Yes.
But now I'm going to train, so we'll see you.
Hey, where are we now?
Hello, now we are in Fab Lab.
Why is it called Fab Lab?
It stands for Fabrication Laboratory and it comes from MIT.
Here you can 3D printing things-
-You can laser things -kind of a little bit of everything possible.
What is the coolest thing that has been 3d-printed here?
Oops there are a lot of cool stuff-
-But I would say a bust in several different colors.
Do you sometimes feel like a genius?
Just a crazy one.
Why did you choose Halmstad University?
They had a very interesting education-
-And it's a place I've never been to before.
Salstatta or home tent?
Salstatta.
Why?
Much better focus.
Were you on the zero?
Yes.
How was it?
Among the most fun I've done.
Where are you sitting on campus if you want to look for people?
A little odd question, but trade center, at the top with binoculars.
What do you want to work on after graduation?
I hope.
Tell us something that you think most people do not know about college.
They have a very nice sauna at the sports center.
Now my questions are over.
Do you have something you want to add?
No.
Should we say hello then?
Yes good bye.