My name is Simon Andersson and I read-
-Froofessional sports career and working life (PICK) at Halmstad-
-And right now we are in one of our elite environments.
I chose to study because I am an elite golfer-
-and have wanted to study further at college but not know-
-Richly what I want to do. So this opportunity showed up.
I found out that you can read sports science at Halmstad University
-At the same time you can conduct a golf venture alongside.
The best thing about studying here is that everyone who comes to the program is-
-otally interested in sports in general and perhaps primarily-
-The sport they are doing.
This means that we as students both learn to take part of-
-Howing history within the sports and thus can learn-
-To work on our own sports. Although the sports differ
-If especially the mental part is very similar in most sports.
We have a lot of like -minded people to bump ideas and the like with.
It also makes it very positive in the study-
-What you have many like -minded people to spend a lot of time with.
The arrangement on the Pika is that we read at 75 percent study act-
-and that is because one besides their studies-
-As to be able to conduct their sports investment.
A regular school week for a pika student consists of we have two to three days-
-In the school and two days, roughly, for golf training or physical training.
There are extremely good conditions-
-be able to fully conduct their sports investment.
In the future, I feel that I first and foremost want to continue to conduct-
-My own golf venture. My dreams are to become a professional golfer.
If I would not succeed in that I am sure I want to work-
-with something in sports and this program has made me see that it-
-There are opportunities to work in sports in other ways other than just practicing it.
A tip that I think many of us pika students would agree
-Is to take hold of the studies on time. To do with their sport is fun-
-I think so too.
To grab the studies on time and get clear everything fast and in a good way-
-make you can do your sport significantly more-
-And with greater freedom as well.