Hello! My name is Julia Andersson-
-And I study work science at Halmstad University.
Right now I'm sitting in house S.
I chose to read this program as it is one-
-Bred education that provides many job opportunities.
There are also great choices after graduation-
-So that you can work with a lot of different things.
The best thing about my program is that we read many different courses-
-If both people and theoretical things.
We read, among other things, law and financial
-What is very sought after knowledge in the labor market.
This is a whole new program at Halmstad University.
It has been around before, but are now-
-More specialized and a little more niche in work science.
In the third year we get the chance to choose intermediate-
-to study abroad, practice or choose your own courses so that man-
-Can form the education a little according to how you want it yourself.
In the future, I would have liked to work with recruitment or other HR issues-
-In that I like to work in groups and meeting new people.
Something unique about this program is that man-
-Directly after graduation can be given a leading role.
One can become manager or leader directly, because it is something-
-We plug in to become.
One tip is to be on the zero before school start-
-To you get to meet all the new friends with whom you should go to the same class.
Then it will not be as scary to start school later.