This year's alumni is praised for its ability to create good relationships with both the past, the present and the future.
Hello! My name is Rebecka Larsson and I am this year's alumni.
I feel incredibly happy and honored to receive this award as this year's alumni.
I think it's great fun that after my study time -
- Keep to inspire students at Halmstad University and the health pedagogical program.
I work today as a supervisor at the individual cooperation team Halmstad/Hylte -
–And works with long -term sick leave and long -term unemployed persons -
-As is in need of pre-rehabilitation efforts to be able to approach work.
Linked to my studies I have been given good use of my educational knowledge -
- For example, my knowledge in the health promotion area.
The health pedagogical program has given me good conditions -
- To actually be able to take on all the challenges I have met and will face in working life.
I want to continue to be an inspiration for the students at Halmstad University -
- And get the chance to continue to share my experiences.
I think the key words as a health educator are to dare, to be curious -
- And to challenge when you get into working life.
Because then you come a long way.