- Hi, my name is Lisa Närenborn and I sit here at the Halmstad University
-In DLC, which stands for digital laboratory center.
I plugged language, text processing and digital communication.
Now I work as Business Development representative-
that is a nice word for selling at an IT security company-
-while is called Proofpoint.
It is an American company with offices all over the world-
Including Stockholm, but also in the UK-
-When I will belong to.
My job is very fun-
-Very much relate to digital communication.
I write a lot of e -mails and I am in the sales process in the beginning.
Much of my job is to communicate with potential customers-
-To, and this is very often digital.
Before I worked with marketing and there is a lot of text and communications-
-But in another way.
A girl who plugged in the program works more with-
-The shop communication and also it is text processing and how to get in ...
... the message in a good and clear manner.
Once you have read this-
-The program so you have it, that's what you have to learn.
Something I thought a lot about when I read the program was that I compared me-
-Very with my classmates.
Everyone we had chosen the program because we like text and digital communication.
And then it is clear that everyone is good at it.
Only after I had taken my exam-
-in I saw that "no but god I'm really good at this too".
I have a special competence that not other have-
-But compared to those who are also good at it.
When you come out into the world where others have read something else-
-To you notice what advantage this program has-
-And how much you use it.
I also think it's good that you can choose either-
-Swedish or English.
I chose English because I knew that I-
-Ville work and live abroad.
I didn't know exactly what I wanted to work like or with.
But at least I had it clear to me and-
-Then I thought that English will always be a competence that is in demand.
Whatever I work with.
One of the reasons I chose the program where-
-That it had an exchange term.
You could choose to study abroad.
I studied a semester in Missouri in the United States.
It's really so fun, because you meet so many people.
There was another girl from Halmstad University who went with me-
-And we became great friends.
You get so much experience.
Studying at a college is not just about studies.
Sure, largely, but it's also about experiences, get friends
-and all the extra around.
If I am going to give a tip to someone who is thinking about searching, I would say-
-If you have an interest in writing, for communication and text-
-But do not know exactly how to apply it to a professional role.
So I recommend this program.
I didn't know what I wanted to work with either.
But this program provides a broad competence, so that it goes-
-To apply on so much.
You don't need to know what you want to become.
If you know the area: "Text and communication".
Then I really recommend this program.