Research, University of Halmstad Professor portrait
My research is very much about digitization and-
-The school's digitalisation but also teacher education digitization.
My name is Pernilla Nilsson and I am Professor I-
-The Didactics here at Halmstad University.
I have previously worked extensively with teacher education and-
-The Natural Science Teaching, even in the classrooms.
But in recent years, there has been increasingly focusing on that-
-Take on digitization.
What happens when teaching using digital tools-
-What manner is the teaching affected and in what way is affected-
-The students' learning or commitment to the subject.
It is especially fun that the University of Halmstad's first research program-
-Soping on learning in digital society.
I have the privilege of being a research program manager for-
-This program and together with colleagues-
-Detrap the research around this area.
Leads we shorten our research program and it is about-
-Bae from a critical perspective but also see what benefit digitization-
-Can do when working with different learning processes in society.
These different research areas are very interesting because to-
-We know that the government in 2017 came up with a strategy for to-
-The whole Swedish school system will be digitized.
It will be a political question of working with digitalisation.
If one is thinking a little bit around the effects from the research
So I think it is important that the results we arrive in research-
-So need to be applied both in school and education.
If we notice that some methods we use in school-
-To example when we sometimes force on digital tools-
-Bae on students and teachers and then see that the effects on -
-learning as we expect perhaps not really fulfilled
So we also need to reflect on why we use digital tools.
The result of the research is to be able to be implemented in society-
-And then in school and in higher education.
As a professor, you are a bit of an all -artist.
I supervise five doctoral students today which is an important part of the teaching-
-But it is also important that as a professor join and support other-
-And contributes to other people's career development.
What I have always tried to do as a professor is to create-
-conditions for others to grow.
The role of professor is both supportive but there is also a great deal-
-time expectations of us professors to be able to seek different forms of contribution-
-But also as in this case being able to lead research-
-and develop research at the university.
There "learning in a digital society", that is, leads a good example-
-To how we can collaborate within the framework of interesting common research issues-
-and develop research together.
I think that is a very important role for a professor-
-To be able to participate in and lead such work.
Research where different perspectives meet