Hello and welcome to Halmstad University!
Fun to see you! Come on and I'll show you around a bit.
We start with a little detour right away, come here!
Hi Victoria, fun to see you!
Hi Timmie, the same!
Can't you tell those who watch. Who are you and what do you do?
Absolutely
Victoria is my name, and works as a study and career counselor here at the university.
I often have guidance calls with students who are interested in-
-To Start studying here at Halmstad University.
But also with students who are already reading here with us.
There will be a lot of questions about admission, eligibility-
-and what you can do after reading a program-
-If the labor market and career and such issues.
You sit with some others who are also sitting in here.
Can you tell us a little more what you all do?
Exactly, it's not just us, study counselors sitting here-
-It is also student health and educational support.
So, for example, if you need support and help with your health-
-And your feeling so you can book a conversation with Student Health.
If you have a disability then you can get educational support-
-During your study time here, which can facilitate the studies.
What good that you are here on campus, it is an asset I think.
But we shall move on through the glass aisle-
-So let's see if we can meet some more people.
Now we move on here in the glass aisle and we'll see ...
As you can see here, we have a service center.
We'll go in and check if anyone can tell you a little-
-If what they do here at the service center.
Hi Ida!
Hello Timmie!
How's it going?
That's good, thank you!
Can you tell us a little what you do here at the service center?
Absolutely!
As a student you are welcome here if you have questions about-
-Studies, college or your education.
If we can't answer, we will help you further.
Here you can arrange access cards, study certificates or pick up your exam-
-When you wrote your first exam.
Perfect!
This is exactly what you do here at the service center.
I have picked up a number of exams here, I can announce.
But come, now we'll move on.
Hello then Ida, thank you for being able to join.
Hello then, thank you!
Next in turn is the student union and they make sure we have-
-Good and functioning education here at the university.
And above all the study social.
And it's something you will see more of in autumn-
-The zero, above all!
Come on and we'll see what they say.
Hello!
Fun to see you, what is the best thing about the student union?
All engaged students, of course!
It's the most fun, when the students come here and say-
-Heah I have an idea, can we test this? And then we say "Yes, we look at that!"
So we look at whether it can be implemented.
But it is the best, committed students, like yourself.
Yes but I agree. Awesome male. Thanks so much!
Being engaged during their studies is one of the most important things.
Now we will move on, so come along and we will see what we find at the library.
Now we go to the university library so come along here.
At the college library you will spend much of your time.
We will meet Elizabeth here.
Hello!
Nice to see you.
Can you tell us a little what students do here and what they get help with?
You can get help with most things here actually.
There is room to sit here and plug both individually and in groups.
We have some group rooms.
We have a lot of books but most of us have-
-Very much of what we have, that's digital too.
So then you can get help from finding in all that material-
-So you find what you need.
Then we also have some machines if you want something to chew on-
-When you sit here, and some water and such.
Nice working environment and access to find help.
A place where you spend a lot of time as a student, can you say?
Do not you agree?
Yes! Now during the last period has been a bit empty here-
-So we have missed all students.
Usually, it is usually very full.
Especially certain times of the day.
Yes but really, and to you this fall we look forward to-
-To have you all in place here.
But we will move on. Thanks so much Elizabeth!
Now move on and take us to House R.
Now we are back the glass aisle because of course we should not miss any things-
-White we go to house R.
We will now go into house E and F.
And there, among other things, the design studio will be-
-And electronic lab and electronic center Halland.
To my right side we have the restaurant found here at Campus-
-Som have good food.
But come now we will go and look at the lab.
Now we are in the electronic lab.
Students who are here are in the process of that-
-Test and create circuit boards.
And the circuit boards can look like this.
Students also program these.
So do you want to become a student and work with them-
-It's really the big thing that was about here.
There is a lot of activity here in the lab.
But with that said, we will move on to the Electronics Center Halland.
Now we go into the electronics center and there you have to wear other shoes.
Now we will change shoes a little quickly.
These are special shoes for getting-
-Go into this lab.
So come along now.
This then Electronics Center Halland.
Here we have two pieces of chambers where you measure-
-Electromagnetic fields in different ways.
And we will now go into a chamber called Maxwell.
This is what it looks like in this chamber-
-And here students can measure, wireless, electronics structures.
And as you can see, there are plates on the walls and roof-
-In ordinary cases should students close the door to measure-
-The constructions in here.
This is something very unique to Halmstad-
-And Halmstad University, that we have something like this.
In both this chamber and in the other chamber-
-which is here next to you can see-
-To in there, you measure electronics magnetist fields in a different way.
Among other things, through how it can affect the electricity grid.
Here, several students may be able to do-
-Among other things their degree projects.
May be allowed to go in and test different constructions.
So if there is something you want to do and study at Halmstad University.
This is the second chamber.
In this little box you can measure and connect electronics products-
-And see how they can affect the electricity grid.
This chamber is called the noisy chamber.
Compared to the chamber we were in before where it is more quiet.
Here happens and a little more stuff that can ...
... then tests and measures how ...
... electricity products and the fields then affect other things.
Incredibly awesome.
Now we go past the design studio and here are students-
-Which reads digital design and innovation.
This is their project room.
Here they work with real cases, with business-
-In otherwise for their degree projects or the like.
This really happens.
Join us, now we move on.
Now we are finally in houses and now you should look at the health lab.
At the Health Lab is: Clinical Exercise Center-
-The behavioral science lab, apartment and media lab.
Join us and we will see what it looks like.
Then we will see here, now we are in the health lab.
The first thing to visit is what we call the apartment.
Join us and we will see if we enter the apartment.
You did not do here, but we test the other door-
-So it will probably work better.
We didn't do that either.
But wait a bit and we'll see if we can't get in anyway-
-Yes but, look now it was open.
Let's see.
This is the apartment-
-Here can students who, among other things, read to Socionom-
-Fa experience what it is like to have conversations in the home.
You can create a simulation in here.
As you can see up here, there is then a camera-
-So that other students can follow what is happening here-
-In in apartment.
The apartment is equipped with what one can find in a home-
-There is a living room, a bedroom in there.
To the right we have a large mirror and that is in there-
-When the observer room is located.
Now we will move on to the next part.
Then we'll see, now we're going to the clinical training center-
-It's in here.
Follow.
Here we have ...
.. where the nurses can simulate what it is like to work-
-On real patients.
There are dolls in the beds-
-And, among other things, can the nursing students-
-Test what it is like to take blood tests, and other types of method-
-To save a patient or to help a patient, of course.
They can useful everything that is here, to simulate reality.
Join us and we go out in the open part of the health lab-
-and here there is everything from study places to group room-
-To sofas and even a kitchen that the students can use.
It is so wonderful that we have these types of labs.
But we will now go into the media lab. So hang with it.
Now let's go into the media lab, come!
But first, we will of course start "recording in progress".
Come and we go into the studio.
Here we have the media lab and the studio.
Here, among other things, Media and Communications Student-
-Make your own shows, ie record real television programs and other things.
Maybe a small talk show if you wish.
This is how they can really test what it is like to work.
It is not only in front of the camera that one is working-
-What also behind, about what it is like to stand and film-
-It's about lighting-
-And how to get the message you work with in different ways.
Come on and we'll move on.
Now we will go out of the media lab and go to the e-sports lab.
Now we are at the e-sports lab and we have a collaboration with-
-Movemented children and adolescents in Halland.
This is among the newest we have here at Halmstad University.
Join us for now we will go into the new cafe.
Now we are in the cafe. The newest cafe we have here in Hus S.
Here you as a student can buy both moderate lunches-
-To some good snacks in the afternoon.
They have incredibly beautiful and study -friendly environments here.
Now we will go into Fab Lab.
So now we are in Fab Lab here.
Hi Tim.
Hey Hey.
How's it going?
Yes, it's just good thanks.
I was going to ask if you could tell us what you are doing here?
Fab Lab is the university's prototype manufacturing lab.
Fab Lab as in Fabrication Laboratory as it stands for.
Fab Lab comes in originally from Mit Boston-
-So we are not the only ones in the world there are-
-Or we are one of over 2000 labs around the world.
But here we create opportunities for the students to-
-working practically in both courses but also research-
-And help in such a vis-
-But also private projects.
If we look at the 3D printer who stands here next to us-
-The students can make a case a prototype in education.
But also make new curtains or whatever you want in the apartment-
-Eximes.
How exiting.
Fab Lab is one of all our labs.
But now we will move on, so follow along.
So now we are in Hus S and Hus S is one of the newest house-
-As we have here on campus.
It is completely renovated from very old premises.
The house was clearly in the middle of the pandemic.
So it is still very unused premises.
Incredibly beautiful environments.
Come on and we'll go in and look a little more about what it looks like in house S.
Now we go into the big hall.
Come on and let's see what it looks like.
Here we have from smaller group rooms to project room-
-We have universities that are interactive-
-We also have large hearing rooms.
And now we will go into what is called the movement lab.
Join here now and we will get to the finish line.
Now let's see what it looks like in here.
Now we are in the movement lab and here students get to test-
-How it is to work with training physiological principles.
This is about testing strength, condition-
-And other, and be able to analyze them with measuring instruments available.
In order to be able to see how to perform better-
-or if someone is performing a little worse-
-How they can work on getting a normal function.
It is something that one both research-
-And that students can work a lot with in here.
But that said that we will move on so follow here and we will go.
Okay now we go to DLC.
Now we are in digital laboratory center DLC.
Now let's look at what it looks like.
And here you as a student can work with your digital skills.
Here are everything from different types of equipment to-
-Strengthen digital development.
From a blackbox to smaller meeting room-
-To we have small studios to work with physical products-
-which can be digital.
Also how to teach as a teacher student in digital environments.
We have a nice pod studio that was recently inaugurated.
This is how you as a student can also join in and play-
-A real pod.
This is something we need even more here at the university.
Then we will move on to something completely different.
Come.
Now we are somewhere completely else and where we are now is on-
-The sports center like a gym located on campus.
It is Eleiko certified and is located in the university's premises.
A great opportunity for you as a student-
-Exercising close to your studies.
One floor up here is one for a cafe.
We have several cafes here on campus, to buy some snacks.
Come and we will end this hike.
Now we have made a proper tour here at Campus-
-I hope you've got to see what it looks like here-
-But there is of course so much more to discover.
I look forward to you looking for an education here-
-At Halmstad University.
So maybe we will even be seen this fall.
Thanks for this hike! Bye.