Hi, I am Vaike Fors-
-I'm a Professor of Design Ethnography
here at Halmstad University.
I'm going to tell you a bit more
about the project GREEN-LOG.
Come with me into the elevator
and I will tell you more.
Have you ever purchased anything online?
Imagine all the logistics
behind getting that product-
-from the producer to your kitchen table.
In Project GREEN-LOG we are 29 partners
in ten countries-
-and with a 6.3 million EU contribution
we are going to implement-
-really innovative
last mile delivery solutions-
-that are completely sustainable.
Halmstad University researchers
are in this project-
-to help five cities
to establish living labs.
And those living labs will also do
co-creation activities together-
-with stakeholders
and citizens in these areas.
And we are also going
to facilitate trading zones between those.
We are designing with people,
not only for them.