Hello! My name is Ying Fu and\h
I am a Professor of Applied\h\h
Electromagnetism at the School\h
of Information Technology.
Mostly, I do 50 percent at least,\h
research and technical development\h\h
in the field of quantum technologies\h
and communication technologies.
The quantum technology part is\h\h
kind of advanced in a sense that we try to work\h
with photonics technology to pick up signals.
The simplest cases these today's\h
infrared camera that we can use\h\h
to detect temperature. Instead\h
of getting the patients closely\h\h
using thermal meter now we can do it remotely\h
actively, so like a quite quick screening.
So this is mostly the quantum technic\h
technologies, photo detectors, advanced ones.
Another part is the communication. So we need a\h
fast communication, like in the field operations\h\h
you don't carry a big machine into\h
the field, like driving big cars.
In most cases talking about remote areas like\h
a health care system in the remote areas.\h\h
So one point of this remote area\h
is of course people live there.\h\h
Not all the people live in the big cities. So we\h
need to provide all the people with proper care.
The second issue is in the big cities, you\h
have a some disease and you go to the hospital.\h\h
But there are a lot of patients around the cities\h
and in the hospitals so you get cross infected.
So it's like today's issues of this virus,\h
you're already sick you get extra virus and\h\h
then the chance of getting worse is very\h
very big. So don't go to the hospital.
We try to provide such kind of diagnostic\h
small device with fast communication.\h\h
So to try to find solutions for the smart city\h
and smart home. We live healthy and longer.
So one most important task is to disseminate\h
information. The real information about\h\h
the education for example, knowledge, that we are\h
doing research and obtained with so much money\h\h
from the society so we are trying to give back\h
the society the right information and education.
So this knowledge dissemination is very\h
critical. And at the school level I also\h\h
do a lot of coaching for the junior researchers\h
and for junior colleagues, PhD students.
And then also at the teaching levels for the\h
young people, for the future job markets, so\h\h
we are looking at the possibilities of what will\h
the future job look like with today's technology.
So we are moving into a new society with a lot\h
of new technology hallway. Adjust ourselves\h\h
with proper knowledges, so\h
that kids and young people\h\h
after education they can get\h
a good job and a good living.
So we have this role as a duty to\h
the society to provide information.
So mostly, the research activities of mine\h
are collaborating with the companies. Like\h\h
the biomedical sensor is with AstraZeneca, so\h
they're developing a lot of this new technique\h\h
of medicines like inhalations for asthma. So they\h
need to access the effectivity of these drugs.
So I'm trying to develop\h
some master technical things\h\h
to see how fast to access the\h
effect of these medicines.
So a lot of funny things! I built some small\h
machines, early on we built a small portable\h\h
machine for 'svenska vägverket' to try\h
to detect this road in the springtime.
In the winter time we have a lot of snow,\h
so we spread a lot of salt to melt the snow.\h\h
But these are corrosive material,\h
not good for the for the bridges.
Now we need to test the\h\h
viabilities and corrosion of the bridge to\h
see how long it can survive, another 50 years.
So these small machines are needed\h
everywhere. We see the results quite clearly.
And more or less that I'm trying to\h
develop a lot of small devices into\h\h
products with some companies.
Mostly it's kind of a hobby partly.\h
Another thing is about the social\h\h
development that is needed. So this is the\h
challenge for sustainable development of society.
We are living in the big issue a world now.\h\h
We have the energy issue, we\h
have the health care issue.
We are also living longer so\h
it's aging, with social demands.
And then I've talked about this hobby. I like\h
this technology part so from the very beginning\h\h
when i was a kid and later in the University,\h\h
I always like play with these electronic\h
things, photonic things, photos, cameras.
So I'm doing a lot of these hobby\h
imaging or capturing, like the moon\h\h
in the evening. I can do it using my mobile\h
phone. So I play at home say like 24–7.
But then I get paid to play with these things\h
I love like 24–7. So that's the best thing!