Hello!
Today I speak English, and that's because I have a guest with me.
When you look at this, I'm actually in Greece.
Doesn't really look like it, but I am, I promise.
The girl next to me is called:
Antonia: Antonia.
Clara: an ... Andonia?
Antonia: Mjjaaaaa, something like that.
Clara: And that's why she's here, because I'm sucking in Greece.
In Greek, I mean.
I suck in English too, apparently.
How are you today?
Antonia: Good, how are you?
Clara: I'm fine thanks!
So the reason I sit here with Antonia is for her to teach me a little Greek for my holiday.
If you could rank yourself, how Greek are you on a scale from one to ten?
Do you love feta cheese?
Antonia: Yes, of course !!!
Clara: Okay, she's very Greek.
Antonia: Ten out of ten.
Clara: Perfect! That's the spirit!
Before I came here, I searched a little quick on Google for Greek words.
So okay, how does a "yes" say in Greek?
Antonia: "NE".
Clara: And how does a "no" say in Greek?
Antonia: "ande".
Clara: Yes is no and no is okay?!
Huh? Huh ???
What are you Greeks doing ??
But now it's time for you to learn Greek.
Antonia: Yes.
Clara: Maybe I can start with something simple?
I see in front of me how I get off the plane, get into the terminal,
Jumps on the bus and goes to the hotel,
And the first thing I will say is:
Where the hell is the beach?
Antonia: Without the swear word, you say:
Poú Eínai I̱ Paralía?
Poú ..?
Eínai ..?
.. I̱ Paralía?
Clara: Para ... Lea?
Antonia: Ne. [= yes (hehe)]
Clara: Po inside e Paralea!
Antonia: Okay, so if you want to use the swearword it is called:
Poú Sto Diáolo Eínai I̱ Paralía?
Clara: Thiallo?
Antonia: Diá-Olo
Clara: Thia -ollo
Antonia: Yes! But you can also say:
[Found no translation but NOTE NOTE FUL WORDS !!!]
Antonia: It's such a ugly word ...!
You actually have that word here! "Clean".
Clara: Clean?
Antonia: It actually means "cock" in Greek.
Clara: Clean ...
Antonia: Yes, but it is one of the very worst swearing.
But you can say "#!? &%* Eínai in Paralía?" And that means "where the hell is the beach?".
Clara: Puston Potso Ill Paralea!
But give me your meaning now! I am super -tagged and a little nervous.
Antonia: ????
Clara: Exactly.
Antonia: What do you think it means?
Clara: Help! I am from Sweden and I ..
Antonia: Wait, huh! You..? No, go on!
Clara: Help, I am from Sweden and have no pants so where is the nearest place where I can buy pants?
Antonia: Aha.
But you actually got some right, Soui̱día means Sweden.
Clara: Yes! That's what I thought.
Antonia: It means “I need sun protection factor 50,
Because I am from Sweden and if I burn
Then I will look like a chicken that just came out of the oven. ”
Clara: I am! I am in Greece!
That is still good to be able to.
Suecia.
Antonia: Souidía.
Clara: Sueecia.
Antonia: Español?
Clara: So when I'm on the beach, and when I asked someone ... where ... polish ... the beach
Then my next question is: Do you sell pink flip flops?
Antonia: Pouláte Roz Sagionáres?
Clara: Polas Pink Sayonares!
!
Sayonares?
That was easy!
Antonia: Should I continue? Okay.
If you are out and see someone nice, you will say this.
???????
Clara: That guy is so good looking that I want him to ...
... read Fifty Shades of Gray for me.
Antonia: But you have to be more "Popotimanarinafto"
Clara: Popotidanarinado
Antonia: It actually means "you are so stylish - five out of five nasal spray".
Clara: ooooohhhhhhhh !!!!! 1!
So how does one "five out of five nasal sprays" say?
Antonia: ?? !!!!!!!!
Clara: That is so cool
I think I'm ready for Greece!
I am so tagged and we will see as usual next week.
Thank you very much for teaching me Greek.
Antonia: Oh, thanks for coming!
Both: Hello!