The first scientific journal was published in 1665.
Before that, research results spread mostly through personal communication-
-and handwritten material.
To disseminate research results through scientific journals-
-Haves come to become an important part of the scientific system-
-And over the years, tens of thousands of scientific journals have been started.
Until digitalisation needed publishers and printing companies-
-For everything for packaging and dissemination of the magazines.
Researchers' need to spread and quality assure their results-
-eventually come to become a market.
In the 1960s, large stock marketed publishers began to buy up less-
-And the market has increasingly become an oligopoly dominated by a few publishers.
At the end of the 1990s, digitization began.
Scientific publications are now mainly e-resources-
— As the reader has access to by being enrolled or employed-
-In a higher education institution that subscribes to these magazines.
The dominant system for publishing and available research-
-Is researchers send in their articles to publisher-
-As responsible for editing and publication in scientific journals.
Usually the publishers do not pay out any financial compensation-
-To either the article authors or the researchers who are responsible-
-For the scientific review, so -called peer review.
The publishers have then sold access to the magazines-
-To libraries and higher education institutions through subscriptions.
At the same time as the market has evolved into an oligopol-
-And the publication has been digitized, prices for subscriptions have increased.
The profit margin can in some cases be as high as 40 %.
This development has led to many universities no longer being adopted-
-To pay the high subscription fees.
The consequence of this is that researchers in different parts of the world-
-Not gain access to the information that they need-
-And that knowledge does not reach out into society.
It is with this background that the need for a new system-
-For publishing research results has emerged.