Right at the Malmö School of Music is a lot of focus on one's own expression.
There is always a very open atmosphere when you enter the cafe and you can sit with anyone and talk.
I enjoy being very, great at the School of Music.
I would say that the most fun thing about studying at the Malmö School of Music
is to be in an environment where you get to meet so many other musicians.
Also to get to know the experience that our teachers have and try to practice it on their instrument.
One can expect great freedom which also comes with a great responsibility.
There are endless opportunities to do an incredible amount.
When I have gone here I have developed in a lot of ways that not only have to do with my instrument,
Without a lot, I think I have to do with my maturity as a musician.
My ability to tackle things that I might not before thought that I would be able to do in the way I do now.
An ordinary week is that you come here in the morning and then you go home late at night.
Because you have been here all day and played and practiced.
That is what is mostly.