I'll just make a good intro.
Shabla!
Shabla Shabla!
Ohh, good transition.
We stand here outside Berlin Airport.
-Guten Morgen!
Right next to a vibrant pikachu, check out there!
Gotta catch'em all!
What has not happened before in a "on the space" section is that Niklas has escaped.
There are several who commented on it, and your comments are our team!
We do what you say!
Well, our next plan is really to go to the United States, -
-Asia or something.
But we thought we squeeze one when Niklas can run like hell!
It's not so fun to do it himself, so he has his friend Oskar with him.
Here we have.
- Applause!
Applause.
Niklas and Oskar!
Versus jlc,
That's what is fun.
The entire JLC against Niklas and Oskar.
The rules are clear, as they always are.
There is new info every half hour.
You have to stay on the spot for five minutes.
Every other time it is picture and then pin location.
And you must not go to ******-club without calling us first.
No, goalkeeper.
- Ah ... ah.
Set timer in 30 minutes.
So!
Stick away, stick away!
Shall we jump in there?
- No, it's a person in there.
Shall we jump in?
We jump in.
This is how: I have read German in high school and there is a bit left.
Order, yes I can actually do that.
We'll take it over there.
Cheers guys!
- Cheers.
How long do you think it takes to find them?
I think an hour and a half from they go.
For four hours I can guarantee.
Niklas will fight as hell I think.
At least we are now on our way towards the very core that we should be around.
Where we go now we are about 500 meters away, I do not know.
It looks very close anyway.
And we saw a hotel there that seemed fun and that is something that the guys may not appreciate ...
I don't know, we'll see, we'll see ...
Can I take a selfie with you?
Thank you so much!
Now Sent Niklas Photo!
It's a taxis driver!
- They became more polished with him!
Yes but we can be polar with ours too.
But then we just chance and go right in.
I think it was when we checked the map Jonas, what was it?
36 minutes type.
So we will have 6 minutes left when he sends location, that's good!
Then we just say: Drive there instead!
I really want this caravan room ... - we may need to look further?
The plan was that we would have a caravan holiday stuck in Germany.
In the middle of Berlin!
- In the middle of Berlin yes!
And then I had found these, you can see the picture here:
So I swap like this:
You see, you see, yes.
Yes anyway, you take.
Then we go inward towards the State Care.
It's a bit risky, we are ... - We're out on the outskirts after all.
Ah that's us.
- We have to get inward.
We currently shared the place info.
I first happened to share live, but I don't know so I wrote to them.
"Check so it's not live".
Then they cheat if they always see where I am.
We'll wait here for five minutes now.
We just have to go on!
I saw the pendulum going up here.
So we just have to take something like that and move on, because they can take a taxi.
They can be here anywhere.
This is so damn good.
Niklas has sent a pin now.
Do you think they sat in taxi when he sent it there?
- Nah.
It's a hotel somewhere there.
We are sitting in a taxi now, we are going there now, now now.
Yes, say he goes there.
We have fourteen minutes.
Is it so far?
- Ah.
Now it has been five minutes.
And we're going to move away now.
We take the commute!
It's Berghein and the football arena here.
I promise to Calle and they think I will go there.
There and pave it as well.
But no, I'll take the commute.
What the hell is Niklas doing here?
Why right here?
Here you have, here you have the Döner.
Should we drive a dunner?
We drive a dunner.
- It's good Döner here huh?
Type all the dousies are good here I think.
Yes we drive a dunner.
There is a bus 14:12 from here I saw, I forgot to check before.
It is 15:08 and we will send location in 12 minutes.
We will send a picture on the bus if we do not notice that we will be off the map.
Then we jump off before.
We must also find a place to jaw, we have not done that today.
I am swine hungry, I just cooked a sandwich this morning and a cup of coffee.
Do you get it?
Bread!
Mmm.
What if you could buy one like this at home?
40 bucks.
Ah fuck what good.
I have never tested this before.
Döner-Kebab.
Don't have it?
- No.
Is it a special type of kebab or?
- Much better than the one we jaw at home.
Oh!
It's any other sauce?
- Yes.
This was good.
- Spring Spring!
You're joking!
- No!
!
What the hell are we doing?
There is a bus too?
We'll take it then?
We take the one we take it!
Jump!
Yes yes!
- Thank you!
Aahh, my ass.
Where do we go?
Should I ask someone or?
Ok, we're on the map where this bus is going.
Okay so this is going like further?
So it's not going anywhere soon to the center?
- No.
We have to jump off here.
- We have gone in the wrong direction.
Yeah.
So we have to take the next bus the other way.
It's a bus in that direction!
I'll send a picture in a minute so I'll take a selfie right now.
So damn asshole.
Check.
He stuck right away.
That is smart.
- He sits on a bus.
He has waited five minutes, he takes a bus.
That's how they will work all day.
So we have to be the step ahead.
Do you know what, there are two options here:
Either you go upwards across the bridge or whatever it was, or downwards.
We take a taxi and then we chance.
So we hope it will be right.
I think they will move towards town, or the chain.
So we are in the middle of town?
No we have a bit into the main street itself.
- Okay.
Imagine: We would move here, now we're here.
Now he sent a picture, next it will be Pin Location.
Then we should be done with each means of transport.
We sit in the taxi then.
- Yes we can do that.
Do you understand what I mean?
We have to chance first.
Yes.
- Otherwise we will not be able to five.
To chance in one direction yes.
- I think we should chance inward towards the batter.
Yes but then we do.
Two beers and eh ... do you have any like ... snacks?
Like Chestnuts or ..?
- No.
No like ... Lringla?
Fries?
- No Never Mind, I Can Take Two Beers.
We go up and watch!
We go up and check!
Come come.
What is this place?
We sit here and take a beer!
We see if they come here.
We are standing outside the Döner place now.
We will see if we get a taxi or something now and move towards the very core.
We chance!
He will be nearby and then we just take him.
Hallo!
Damn, check out what the street is called.
No!
The Biggest Shopping Street.
?
You can't say it so Calle.
Who the hell did it down now?
Now it smells of ass in the car.
After all, he has fed and smoked as hell in this car.
Just smoke smell.
- We have looked up hotels.
But unfortunately it was fully booked, and Lucas called me precisely-
-And: "Where's the hotel?"
Because they want to leave their bags.
What a shame we couldn't take that hotel.
- Yes.
It would have been so damn perfect.
But!
Then I thought we were moving in with the bus.
- Yes.
We find something, we google around a bit.
- Either the bus or the subway.
So we just have to try to find a hotel.
You hear the music, it's the pure party here.
They call this busheim.
We are not ready with the beer, or I am not at least.
Oskar has little left too.
It takes to leave the bus, but we almost have to.
Bowl!
We are sending location now anyway.
It's too damn here Kitkatclub is located!
What everyone sent to me at DMS.
- Is it?
Are you kidding, is it Kitkat Club?
- It's a sex club?
It's kitkat!
He's Kitkat!
Kitkat.
Are they naked?
It's this.
Kitkat.
How far was it?
- Seven minutes!
Are you kidding!
It's so close.
Perfect!
He must stand there five minutes after all.
- Yes Yes!
Damn, we can take him now.
We will catch our friend at the strip club.
I sent to my Polar in Berlin and asked what I said in this Translator thing.
That voice said we would meet our friend at a strip club.
Here it is somewhere.
You are here like that republic place.
Check!
We have to go in here.
- I'm watching, I'm watching.
I'm coming.
Oh damn.
What a damn place!
One hundred percent that they have been here or?
They are probably damn here.
We go in and check.
Excuse me?
Have you see Two Guys with a camera here?
- Yes.
They were just here.
- Oh, they left?
They were here?
- They were just here.
Really?
Okay, Thank you.
What is the subway called?
We are Swedes, we speak Swedish.
- Well!
Well.
But which one is inward towards town?
Not anyone here ...
In such cases, it's over there.
That way?
- Yes.
They have taken a subway!
No, we go down.
They will take the subway.
Absolutely sure!
Now it comes!
We'll take it then!
- Yes!
So!
- Let's go!
We missed them with type two minutes.
We have to go back.
Or?
- During?
It's under the houses and everything huh?
- Yes.
Here they are not like.
Now I have lost Jonas and Lucas.
I paid the taxi and jumped out, so they are gone.
Where the hell am I somewhere?
This wasn't good.
What the hell...
There they are!
What the hell, you can't call you!
We thought they went the subway.
It is at the strip club, that is where he is.
We asked at the beer place if they saw two guys with camera and then they had just left.
Then we thought they had taken the subway.
Yes exactly.
A minute ago.
The strip club is the only thing they talked about.
It is located here.
But he has not gone in there or?
- Yes!
That's the only thing he talked about.
At the airport he said:
"Kitkat is here"
Yes we have to go in and check.
Can you go in?
- May go in?
Yes?
- Clearly you have to go in.
I promise you, he has entered.
- Should we go in here?
Yes yes, we will find him.
Well!
You rush on.
You have to ping on.
Oh!
We ask if Niklas is there.
- Keep the camera a little discreet then.
Hello We Are From Swedish Television ...
Have you see (inaudible)?
Horny, Blonde Short Guy?
When does it open?
Tonight 22-07: 00.
- 22 tonight.
Okay then we have to take Niklas here tonight then.
He must have been aware that it was not open and drunk was carried at this place then.
He might think he should film when he is outside.
Hello!
That's what I said from the beginning!
Shall shall--
Should he go in ...?
- Don't you know how it smelled?
Damn what it smells.
They have easily been on the bus.
Well, he hadn't dared.
He had never dared to hide there.
- No no no.
Not a chance.
It had been so stupid so ...
Ok i'll send a picture now.
- That is too obvious.
Yes that is too obvious, then they take 110%.
Should we send a picture, wait 5 minutes and then go towards a eatery a little further away anyway?
We can't take this.
Should I send a picture on that eateries?
Do you want to take a picture with me?
Very good!
Thank you my friend.
- Thank you!
He sends where he is.
Do you film Lucas?
He sent a picture huh?
- Yes, Alibabas.
One and a half kilometers.
- Ah but what the hell!
Yes but one and a half kilometers, we take a voi!
Do you know what is there?
TV-Tower.
It's a view tower.
But we won't get there in five minutes?
We have to drink the beer too.
It tasted a little special, this beer huh?
- Yes.
A little bit?
I have not been very impressed with the beer.
Damn what you are picky then.
What is the plan then?
It's 9 minutes there by car.
Oh damn!
Check out the building.
We don't go there.
Wait a little huh?
It's nine minutes ... - Yes but then we have to sit down now.
On a voi.
So it is already late.
We would have done it right away.
It has already been two minutes now.
It says beer and "for Sale" or "Beer Sale".
They may have a small tingle here or a small schnitzel as well.
Can we drink beer in here?
There's a Restaurant in that Direction.
That's a bottom shop.
Where are we?
That's why they looked like MC people ...
We didn't dare to film them.
But they stood there shit.
One of them had a gun in the belt.
Or it was just his gloves but it looked scary.
We didn't dare to film him.
But here is a restaurant!
From Location, they also see this place if they go aside a bit.
What do you recommend for food?
(inaudible) Meatballs ...
Can you make it in 10 minutes?
Perfect!
- But?
Did he even understand what we wanted?
I thought we would choose after!
They took the subway!
The stop is right there!
- You are joking!
They took it!
- Yes they did!
I think they will do it all day.
Then we have to be in the ass on them.
So it must have been fanemey seconds!
There was no one in the subway when we were down there.
- No.
It just must have gone a bastard.
At the TV tower they have gone there.
What a damn ... yes you can still give them.
They are pretty good.
Nikla's tactics are movement all the time.
That he even dares to have a beer here is totally sick.
Cheers guys!
- Cheers.
Damn what was good.
(?)
Snase?
It is 16:35 and we are completely fucked.
We will send location in five minutes.
We sit here with a beer-
-And we have ordered a damn sausage plate for three people.
And we'll push it in five minutes.
We are going to his PIN location and we are a little late on the ball.
Or to his picture he sent.
Soon his PIN location will come and then we pull there immediately.
I don't think he can flush anymore now.
I think he is hiding somewhere.
So we go there now.
- Now is 50 o'clock huh?
Just when we arrive at the old address, it's time to get a new pin so we think we are still there.
He should send now.
So we give it immediately and go there right away.
Now we send to him.
Here we have it.
If they are left at the same, we have them close.
We have to push us fast as hell, come on now.
We just chew the damn sausage now then we stick.
Five minutes left.
Okay, we go to (street name) Five.
It's right here!
Okay, go go go go go!
Sorry Sorry Sorry!
But you...
Damn, it's super close!
- Go go go!
So it's really 200 m ... - Now we have him!
But you are a jazz club!
It's a jazz club!
Now we have him guys!
- It's a jazz club!
Excuse me?
- No he doesn't work here, he doesn't work here ...
No no ... nothing, nothing.
No, he doesn't work here ...
It's here, it's here that he has sent.
I thought we would have him then!
But it says over there?
Shouldn't we just go back again?
Should we talk to some people over there if they have seen them?
Have you been sitting here for a long time?
You have seen two guys in white t-shirt sitting here with a camera?
No?
Okay, okay.
Thank you.
If we do not take Niklas now you will hear it.
Yes.
- You want to take him just because.
I think he is doing something or is on this street somewhere.
It feels like things are happening.
He is guaranteed to be somewhere up here as well.
Up.
So I believe in this direction.
I think they are inside the shops here.
Oskar and I talked about it behind the camera here but,
Here is the water and I see some yellow boats.
Should you take a boat or?
I didn't know you could do it in Berlin but,
There may be a small toad as in Gothenburg.
Look there!
Check!
There's no alcohol on the boat right?
- Yes.
Is it?
- Yes, yes.
Aaah!
We should send a picture and I was going to ask her but I don't think she wants to be in the picture.
But now they will realize that we are on a boat.
What should I send?
- Can't you send on a building?
Well I can do that!
I'll send on this one.
It is very in zoomy anyway.
That's it, yes.
Yes it is, do you see the top of it somewhere?
No, into a taxi fast as hell.
We are as close there.
Asbelled.
Checkpoint Charlie.
When I pressed it, a picture came up on that building.
Yes it is just because you see it from there.
Ass sex.
I go in and check.
I have it, I have it!
I have it!
A museum or?
- Yes here is.
Berlin Cathedral is called it.
No, museum.
- Museum Island is it.
Museum Island.
- Berlin Cathedral stands here.
Is he on something else then or?
It is the.
6 minutes.
It's the church.
6 minutes to take a car, yes.
And go then?
A quarter to go.
- There we have a voi, should we take it?
Yes we do.
Excuse me?
I don't have to movie if you want to but how long is this bus going for?
An hour.
- An hour, Oskar.
We may send location into the water then.
Where is it going?
I'm Not Sure.
Should I ask her to the left if she wants to film us when we take one?
Should I do it?
Excuse me?
Can you movie us when we take the shot?
Was it good?
- Yes.
Ok, thank you so much.
We realized that scooters are the best option.
Is it the right path?
How far is Calle left?
200?
Have you put in wrong?
I have pressed the wrong button I think.
- No?
Thought where the hell are we on our way now ... - I've put in the wrong button.
What are we taking now?
You're joking Calle?
- No?
Well for hell!
How far is it now?
- Not so far.
- I can not take it.
Cheers again!
We have been drinking our Aperol Spritz here.
Not ready.
And shots down.
But we have been going for 20 minutes now.
It takes an hour.
Now in 10 minutes I'll send location.
Then I think we will turn around.
Or what do you think Oskar?
Yes it feels so.
Then it will be perfect because then we will send location and-
-We can't stand still on that location.
After all, we can't help we go a boat as well.
There is the police.
It looks like the police are following Carl and Jonas.
Well they don't do that?
Well it does!
Check out Vettu.
The cop is coming.
If you look at the Traffic Light ...
So sorry.
We will just fine you 200 euros.
If you are not from Germany you have to pay now.
We did not see that.
If you promise you don't do it again ... - we promise you!
Then go for it.
Have a great day.
- Thank you!
Damn what a go 'police.
- He was absolutely wonderful.
You drove towards red, I said that the cop was after.
Did you see that he held up a sign like that?
Jonas just: Stay it's cops!
Did you hear what I said then?
"What the hell do you want now then your fucking snap pig?"
Do you know what I said?
You can go to hell, I still go.
It wasn't the point but it was such a damn big intersection ...
Red Light?
I HAVE NOT SEEN RED LIGHT!
For Real?
No?
Is it for real?
Did you get it?
"So Sorry We Didn't See That" - Do you know what I was thinking?
"Don't you drive to red Calle?"
Yes, shit the same!
We have looked here now, there are several options.
One is over there.
One is there.
Where the hell have you led us?
You led us wrong, then you were taken by the cop.
We get a pin in 10 minutes.
We are in the right area, we go to Waynes Coffee.
Yes a coffee yes!
Wine and coffee it says!
Here we have Wayne Coffee!
Such fucking Swedish tourists ...
Wines Coffee ...
Wine and coffee!
Jamen Waynes Coffee is a chain!
Yes I know that but it's so fun, Wayne Coffee ... Wine and Coffee.
Thank you!
He sends location in three minutes.
Can in Also have a cappucino?
A cappucino?
- Yeah it's okay.
He is sending three minutes now, what the hell are you doing?
We are going to pull now?
After you have been out and traveled a scooter, it is good with a small beer.
We're really bad now.
Why are we sitting here drinking coffee?
Transition.
Then I send here ... wait.
- And we are turning to turn so it's perfect.
Send location here and we're on our way back.
I have sent now.
Jonas has read it a minute ago.
But he sees that we are in the water.
Do you see that we are outside then?
Fuck!
He sees it.
He's in a boat.
Check this out.
There you see.
Niklas is exactly on such a boat.
Check.
It is an entimat ride, it is the only thing that goes.
If it is an hour turn, then we can stand there when he is back.
Right?
Then we take the voi there.
Check out his ass.
But what in hell ... does he have string?
Gosh!
He had string!
But what the hell?
What is happening here?
He goes with the jeans in the knee and has a string on?
What the hell...
Now we are close to land and Jonas wrote that they are waiting for us on land.
So I'm not sure how to solve that situation.
We have to hide down there I think because I have to pee too.
Should we pee and wait down there?
The first activity I go boat and they know where you go off and off.
It's so damn hard.
It is much more difficult than you think.
You hear how the police come after Lucas now, he has been in ... riots.
We have taken the wrong cathedral first.
They have been farthest farthest over there.
The station is located just as well.
He has been here very much you can say.
- Yes.
He has been in this area.
The best thing about this boat trip is that it comes back in the same place.
If that is true, we have type 10 minutes to go there and catch him.
Then we take him when he comes back with the boat.
It is no more difficult than that.
There it is Lucas!
It is the!
Here they have been yes.
- And here's the boat.
Jonas wrote that they know that we are on a boat.
So we'll try to wait here and see if they even find us.
They can just as well sit under deck there.
Niklas can easily sit under there as well.
It will go there in the same place.
So it might as well be it.
- Yes exactly.
They will try to catch us up there.
Yes...
Listen what she says ...
Yes, she says "Jonas is over there".
No you are kidding me!
Hello brother!
Hello!
But you are not all together!
The two stay.
They stand there.
Come!
- He has found them.
He has them.
They were there!
Does he film or?
- Yes!
Oh hell what good.
Damn what a good thing!
They were there!
We went to that boat over there and: it went just!
And so: Here comes a boat too!
And then I saw your white ... - I saw you when you got up there!
I would go by and so I saw-
I saw you go with a fucking goopro ...
Here we have them!
- You, the sick was ...
Damn what a good thing!
- Do you know what we were talking about?
More boats came in and we thought: There are as many boats here!
I saw the white sweater and some black stuff on, and that was just before I would go to you!
And then I saw Niklas coming ...
We only heard "Faaan!"
He has 40 minutes left.
Then time had been out.
Holy shit.
But you were great!
Ah!
Damn what boring!
But do you know what ... - were you there at the strip club?
We rang.
- You've been there?
Swedish subtitles: Alice Skårbratt alice@skarbratt.se