You, I say like this: Cheers the brother! -
Cheers, brother!
Bowl! - Good morning!
Good morning!
Here's how: Liseberg turns 100 ...
... and they celebrate it by running a club carousel.
We are here at the premiere.
Today plays Nause, some attractions are open-
-It's bars, it's music, it's age limit.
We must say this, it's big!
For the first time ever, Liseberg opens a nightclub in the area.
You did it powerfully there.
We are first in place!
Yes! - You can fuck that.
I have my reporter on site!
Dududududu! - I'm a bit drunk...
We should not stick under the chair with taking any unit before or so ...
Well but we did.
We have our two friends with us too, the corne and Bissen.
They are here as a backup, bodyguard and backpack carrier for Niklas.
We will test Liseberg by nighttime. - Yes!
What happens at Liseberg at night? - What happens?
It's DJ's. - Is it DJ's?
It's bars. - Is it bars?
These are attractions. - Are these attractions?
It's oily lighting. - Is it good lighting?
These are good dancers. - Is it good looking ... dancers?
And we're here. - We are here!
We'll test everything. Liseberg by night!
Bowl. Here we go!
We went in there.
And getting in here at night is almost a bit like Halloween at Liseberg though more alcohol.
And do you know what the fun is? Basketball and stuff is open!
Please, can't we drive one before? I promise I put it!