- Welcome to the research circle in the skeptic track.
The skeptic track is a track within "Digitally first with the user in focus".
It is a competence lift for library staff in the country.
At the beginning of the project, one of the development leaders came to me and said:
"Have you thought that we would have a skeptic track?"
We had all possible tracks, but no skeptic track.
What a good idea, right? That you have to ask the shaky questions.
It ended in a research circle together with Södertörn University.
There are four groups that will discuss this.
It will be a book for the Book Fair this fall.
Not everyone has to disclose their texts, but you have to do it.
It will also be a pod, which is already on Digiteket.
Those who do not attend the course can follow the course aisle. You can work in small groups on your own.
If you dare not work together with supervisors.
But then you miss the whole supervision.
It is there so you know what we have for us.
The courses themselves will be in group rooms in Digiteket.
Now we will start with our first lecturer.
Jonna Bornemark, well -known speaker. Professor of philosophy, associate professor at Södertörn University.
You will talk about the immatable library.
Welcome forward. - Thanks.
Great fun that we do this, and to start the skeptic track.
What I will talk about is based on my book, "The Renaissance Renaissance".
It is in many ways a skeptics' look at the contemporary.
I try to formulate a contemporary and cultural criticism.
The criticism that I perform there, and will place the libraries in,
Had I not been able to do without empirical material.
A contact with the contemporary similar to what you will do.
That is, to be in close contact with practices and core business.
For us at the Center for Practical Knowledge, it is about school, care and culture.
People from there are our education.
What is interesting about that material is that we are looking for concrete stories.
We want to start in concrete and shaky situations.
Like here and now. Now I do not know how much you are driving.
I try to describe the material in the book, not exactly what you should do.
We want first person, singularis, present, to stay here and now.
I teach so too many different groups.
At one point I had under and nurses in the group.
The nurses were recent graduates and had their education in the body.
They had a hard time writing "I".
It became "man", and hovered away in abstractions.
The nurses had no problems with it.
However, they spelled as rakes, but it was easy to do something about it.
It is interesting to see what our education does to us,
And what perspectives we get worse at.
But that does not mean that it is uneducable.
I will talk more about why it is important to get close to the concrete.
You can get better at that. It is not in contrast to education.
All these stories told me a lot about our time.
The problem with our time is that there is so much that is obvious.
It is difficult to be critical when you are in the middle of something.
The fish find it difficult to see the water. You have to contrast it.
The second source of the book is the Renaissance philosophers.
Nicolaus Cusanus from the 15th century, Bruno from the 16th century, and Descartes from the 17th century.
The whole point is what we are going to do with such memories.
Why should we read historical texts? Well, to be able to relate to our time.
At Cusanus I find things that are very different to the contemporary.
This meant that I could see things that are otherwise forgiven.
The function of being able to throw a critical look at the time needs a distance.
We try to work explicitly with the relationship between proximity and distance.
To be close in concrete situations and then be able to distance themselves.
Read their own text as if someone else has written it.
See what it really is about, and take the help of philosophical scientists.
I'm not going to delve into it now, but it had to do with it.
Just so I have worked when I formulated this social criticism.
What I discovered at Cusanus was our relationship with not knowing.
When I talk about it you wonder "Why shouldn't we know?"
Modernity is about creating knowledge. It is knowledge that is the whole point.
Cusanus says that knowledge is important, but we do not understand it unless we have a relationship with non-science.
There I began to think about how we think about not knowing in our time.
We rarely have relationships with a large non-science.
Instead, we have something we do not yet know.
It becomes clear when writing a research application.
Then you have to talk about everything you know, and extensive what we do not know.
And then I'll talk about exactly how to find out.
I have acquaintances who got the noble because they did not talk about
Exactly in which magazines to publish what they do not yet know.
I have to know a lot for not knowing exactly that.
Few researchers feel comfortable with it, because this is not possible.
It would not be research if it went so.
Here Cusanus becomes extremely liberating to think with.
It is from this perspective that non-knowing becomes relevant.
What is non-knowing for Cusanus?
It is the horizons around all human existence.
Here a philosopher starts to feel at home.
These are the five -year -old's questions.
Where does the universe end? What happens after death?
What is the meaning of life? All infinity issues are here.
What was interesting was that there was also at Cusanus in the least.
Here I want to talk about concrete situations.
In the Middle Ages there was a vocabulary to talk about the concrete, the least.
Here you can endure a philosophical turn.
It is easy to understand that with the biggest, the words are not enough.
The concept of God in a medieval understanding is what man cannot encompass.
We can't define it, because we can't say what it is not.
It is "be", which is one of our biggest concepts.
It is a word that does not mean anything in the end, because it is boundless.
It is easy in relation to the biggest issues.
In the Middle Ages there was a relationship with the smallest,
Where the language is similar in a similar way.
Language is always based on generalities. On what is the same.
Blue yesterday, today, for you and me. So we have the concept of "blue".
Cusanus we mean missing something if we only live in the generalites.
We also live in the situation unique.
It is perhaps easiest to understand if we talk about love.
Vascular to a child, who is just this child.
My child may be worse than yours, but it doesn't matter.
I love this child, and cannot formulate how it differs from yours.
But I love this. There is a specificity that words do not reach.
If I want to write a list, it will be too general.
There is something here where we must have another responsiveness.
When we talk about professional judgment, there are situations unique in a different way.
There are situations and groups.
If I as a teacher come into a class that I know well
May I have a responsiveness for where they are now.
If the conflict between you has escalated, I must meet it.
How is the situation with the child with anxiety that has it tangled at home?
What we should talk about today, how does it fall into this group?
That's what we call judged, being able to feel here and now.
Everyone who works in interpersonal professions knows what it is.
Some of you certainly have administrative tasks, and others meet visitors.
What do you have? User.
Attention is a topic that never ends.
How do I do with this person? With the category "Fylo" I do exactly like this.
In this particular situation, I have to face this way.
Here are horizons of non-knowing.
I cannot create a complete manual with concepts.
It is to be in relation to horizons of non-scientific,
For every situation is always richer than the generalites that describe them.
Somewhere is Cusanus.
The point of the horizons is that they do not exclude knowledge.
Knowledge always inserts that we can find out things in relation to the horizons.
The horizon concept is great here.
There may be an island over there on the horizon.
I can get to that island, and create knowledge about it.
But at the horizon there is a new island.
Then I can row there and create knowledge about it.
But the horizon is still there.
So Cusanus thinks. It is horizons of non-knowing.
It never excludes knowledge.
This is the situation we can create knowledge in.
I have some medieval and mystic interest.
Science is focused on the fact that there is an island where you can create knowledge.
In the next application I want to write I see an island that I want to investigate.
The mystery is interested in what it means to live in relation to horizons of non-science.
That the horizon is never exhausted. What does it mean for human life?
Science and mystery are not in conflict with each other.
Modernity is good at creating opposites. Magic or science.
Cusanus shows how they are connected.
They are two sides of human knowledge process.
I hope I come to the libraries.
In relation to the horizons of non-science, we can create knowledge.
For that matter, we have reason.
By reason I mean what we use when creating knowledge.
With Cusanus I have a greater concept of reason.
Cusanus talks about two concepts.
One is "Intellectus" and the other is "Ratio".
"Intellectus" is the ability to stand in relation to horizons of non-scientific
And there capture what is important.
In that classroom, for example.
What is important here? What do I need to face?
A lot happens in a class, but everything is not important to deal with.
What do I need to catch up?
Then I deliver down what-the-races to a ratio
that organizes, systematizes, arranges, measures, counts.
The point for Cusanus is that we cannot have an order without knowing what is important.
We could always measure and count more.
There are infinitely things to measure in this room.
But what is relevant to measure?
These are different types of abilities.
Catching what is important requires judgment.
In art and literature it is about knowing what is important.
You are not passive, but also not active and just capture things that are important.
This is a long discussion. If it is incomprehensible, then ignore it.
Pactivity means I take over something and make it mine.
You have to be passive and active at the same time.
I capture things and systematize and arrange.
Here we can measure, because there is objectivity.
This is the big example.
When Trump said there were more on his installation than on Obamas.
There began the discussion about alternative facts.
Journalists showed photos of insight. There were more at Obama's installation.
The Trump administration said it was alternative facts.
Intellectus is a subjectivity.
Only a subjectivity can capture what is important.
No computer can, I want to claim that.
But it does not exclude objectivity.
That doesn't mean Trump can say there were more.
And for a very simple reason.
We agree on the time.
We agree on the site.
And we agree on how to count heads.
It does not matter if we have different definitions of what a person is.
I would have been impressed if they had said that everyone at Trump's installation was pregnant.
So there are twice as many as you can see.
At least it had been an argument.
Once we have defined our concepts, there is an objectivity.
We are good at creating dichotomies, and say that you should be objective.
So we put them in conflict with each other.
The point is that they can only work together.
Through subjectivity we can know if it is important to measure.
But that does not mean that there is no objective measuring.
Objectivity means that when we have defined our concepts, we can count.
It doesn't matter who counts.
Background, sexual laying, skin color.
It doesn't matter as long as we have the same definitions.
I take this up because they are so often put into conflict with each other.
One of Cusanus's main points is that this does not happen once.
In a healthy culture, it happens all the time.
We have to capture democracy.
Do we know what democracy is today?
It is a concept that we structure our world around.
We have a definition of citizens, what the media does and so on.
But I don't know if we know what democracy is today.
It is a concept we would have to capture.
For a while not know what it is, to capture what is important.
What we need to recapture, and new dimensions that we need to formulate.
And what may have passed.
It is an intellectus work.
When we take it down, maybe democracy, citizens and media become something else.
So it gets a little messy.
I hope you understand that people always have to have a ratio.
We have an order, a language, a culture. It is included in the ratio formation.
But it is always a bit messy as long as it is healthy.
Here I release Cusanus and do a contemporary criticism.
I mainly use Max Weber.
Modernity carries this movement with it.
In modernity, we do not perceive horizons of non-science, but see it as a wall.
Christianity is not without the advancement here.
On the other side of the wall we have a god and a heavenly.
A lot of things we can't know anything about.
On this page we have the world, which we can create knowledge about.
The modern man says: “Why should I relate to what we can't know?
I stand with my back against the horizons and look at knowledge production.
In this world - nature, what can be measured.
Weber says that modernity is the time where we do not care about non-scientific.
The relationship between the wall and a horizon can be considered for a long time.
When we focus on ratio, intellectus does not disappear.
In our privacy, we have to think about what is important.
But we no longer understand that kind of practitioner.
There will be a ranking between activities with more ratio character
And less of those with intellectus character.
Here we see the ranking between objectivity and subjectivity.
This will be reason, that becomes a feeling.
This is faith, here is knowing.
Culture is society's foremost practice to think about what is important.
Today when we are in a collective crisis to the environmental issue, the art is there and pondering.
What is it to be human?
It is there and examines at once.
The culture becomes incomprehensible.
After we arrange the world, it is nice with flute games.
Or it becomes culture for health.
There is always a risk that culture will be an instrument for something else.
We do not understand the Intellectus activities.
It is the same with the relationship between science and the humanities.
The science has the intellectus practice. You think about what is important to measure.
But I get a little dark when I meet some scientists
Who does not ask the question, but looks at what is best measured.
What kind of measuring material do we have? Then we ask questions about it.
Then there will be very little intellectus business.
I was shocked that so many people think so.
Among other things, the economy.
Now I dissected a whole discipline.
The most flimsy of sciences have their focus here.
To capture a concept.
We have a doctoral student who raised the patient concept.
What is it when dialysis care for kidney disease looks like this?
Then the concept of patient does not work anymore.
Then we have to examine the word and then bake.
We can see a ranking in relation to this.
This has a lot of consequences. Things happen to the intellectus.
One thing that happens is that hedgehogs are created.
Hedgehogs are those who have the intellectus practice, but where it gets stuck in those rooms.
I got it illustrated to me when I was at the Royal Academy and talked.
They described how the male professors looked at the students' works.
So everyone else rangs a week to interpret the humming.
So they thought the practice looked.
It's a hedgehog.
It is a person who has competence, but it is stuck there.
It is high status groups that have the opportunity to be hedgehogs.
Nurses cannot talk about their judgment without being overrun.
Doctors are also criticized for having a trapped intellectus business.
They feel that they must be hedgehogs, otherwise they will be overrun.
What happens to the ratio is that when we cut off we strive for a simpler, pure ratio.
There we can measure and have simple relationships between the different parts.
All totalitarian states start by cutting away the intellectus operations.
The artists, the journalists, the intellectuals, because they tangle for it.
They are skeptics, argue and think new.
It is uncontrollable with Intellectus operations.
We never know where it goes. That's the whole point.
If you remove it, we have pure, simple ration.
When making something into a market, there is a built -in professional skepice.
A criticism for perceiving doctors as hedgehogs.
Other professions have no status to begin with.
They do not understand the rational way of organizing care.
You have not brought with you the professionals when organizing New Karolinska.
We do not have time to go through exactly what is happening.
One problem is that we think that knowledge should be in paper and not in reviews.
In manuals, guidelines and routines.
When one thinks the knowledge should be in the papers
And every situation is new, it will be a fantastic administration.
The "documentation monster" they talk about at the Teachers' Union.
The criticism has begun to be formulated seriously.
This is completely measurable. That's right, but we'll know why.
We can measure how much administration has grown during the 2000s.
The administrative class is getting bigger and bigger.
The administration has gone about the dear business in healthcare.
How much administration can we have on how little core business?
At New Karolinska, they discovered that you had more managers than care places.
Is this effective resource use?
It was sold as financially and efficiently.
How effective is it to believe that all knowledge should be in the papers?
No knowledge should be found with the professional business.
It is not effective, and what is worse is the core business's professional remote controlled.
They should only do as it says in the papers.
It has a variety of unpleasant consequences, and we end in a banal evil.
I can't take responsibility, because I have done as it says in the papers.
The focus has been shifted from the core business to doing as it says in the papers.
A colleague of us was the manager in the elderly care when this was introduced.
She was at a conference where they went through the quality registers.
The last powerpoint said: "Whatever you do, care for your quality registers."
And that was exactly what happened.
The quality registers are there for the care of the elderly to be better.
But we have seen that the purpose of the purpose carries more with it.
It has become more important to care for the quality registers than the elderly.
We care for the elderly to enter the right figures in the documentation monster.
It is a clear displacement that is harmful.
At the Health Care Association, they say that those who think the papers are important are those who can remain.
Those who focus on healthcare are moving from there.
It is a dangerous system.
Teachers and nurses are the shortcomings, and that is not because we educate too few.
That's because they don't want to stay.
What they trained for is not there. The job has been to feed the paper monster.
It is a concrete experience for many.
In this situation, something is haunting.
What is the reason when it is a ratio without intellectus?
That's exactly the reason the computer has.
Partly it is one and zeros - things either are or are not.
A computer is either or in the basic structure.
It fits well into manual thinking.
While a human being can think analogously in sliding scales.
With a sensitivity to another side of the language.
Imagine the poetic, which tries to be close to the concrete.
Computer logic has become an ideal.
People also have a ratio, because we have made the computers.
Where we have feelings and values, we try to get rid of it.
We want to get rid of the human factor so that we only have the objective ratio.
Computer reason has become the metaphor for a proper way to be human.
This is one of the central issues in AI research.
Have you heard of the stamp collector?
I have the best AI ever and I want the finest stamps.
I put in what is important: stamps.
So it manages to solve problems much better than me as a human being can.
In the end, I have the most valuable stamps in the world.
But the computer is not done, but starts gathering all the stamps.
Then it buys the paper industry and starts making stamps.
Finally, it starts to make pulp of my children.
The computer cannot see that what was important yesterday is not important today.
What is important? The computer has no judgment.
We try to make it more nuanced, so that the computer should be closer to reality.
You can take this as a quick picture from Cusanus.
If reality is like this, then our concepts are always hearing.
The computer is also always based on hearing.
This allows the computer to come close but it remains a hearing.
Therefore, the rationality of the computer is never fully enough.
Human language is hearing, but the intellectus's competence is to be in contact with the round.
I think it is clear why the concrete is important.
When we enter the concepts, it is easy to become pure fool production.
This school's key words - the student at the center, respect, learning.
We throw out clichés, and so it will be no more.
Teachers talk about respect, but not about who should have respect for what.
It just becomes a word you hit each other in their heads.
Floskel production becomes our way when we do not understand the intellectus business.
In the skeptical thought apparatus, one should lift yourself from the contemporary ration that exists.
If we know all the time, we can't see anything else.
Allow yourself not to know to capture something new and let it meet our ration.
Of course, this is also the role of libraries.
We have the libraries as memory, but also as resources for citizens.
In a democracy, everyone must have access to intellectus practitioners.
This is where you capture what is important.
Where are we going, and where do we come from? Who are we"?
If we do not have practices, we have no democracy.
If we think it is to submit alternatives in a ratio system, we have missed something.
We must investigate and develop, and then the libraries must be understood as a base.
There I quit, otherwise I will not be able to get comments.
I want comments, questions, protests.
- Questions from the audience.
If you want to look at your picture and see the role of the library.
Is the universe intellectus, the library Ratio, and "digitally first" the squares?
-I think the library carries intellectus practitioners.
- The skeptic track must be found in Intellectus. - Absolutely.
Being able to move in it.
The skeptic is the one who throws a new look at what is.
The step then is to redo what is, and that may not be the task of the skeptic.
- Everyone here has an important role in any case.
- Do you have any comment on the Library Act? Is it something you know?
The libraries should be responsible for opportunities, and there are expressions such as "cultural activities in general".
There are opportunities to link it to what you are talking about.
- A great comment. I have discovered that in several areas.
Often the legislation is good. It has an openness to this.
Pedantification has been done in recent decades, and the laws are older.
Everything was not better before. What we see today is answers to problems that existed.
When we catch up, can we ask "have we forgotten this?"
What does this mean today, and what are we not fulfilling?
If the libraries are depleted, we cannot carry out the core business.
Often the law can be used today.
You have a mick on the entrance.
-In the libraries we fight with the ratio requirements.
More and more of the business will be measured.
It will be the language we can use to be respected.
We are an intellectus business, but that language has lower status.
That is why we reduce a lot to numbers, and it goes very fast.
This was interesting and strengthening.
- I'm out talking a lot about this.
What you said says the entire non -profit sector, including the church.
Save the Children has gone a long way in such an idea.
They discovered that they had made a manual for how to help in a certain way,
And it sometimes worked and sometimes not.
It was the same manual, and should get the same results.
In care, school and care you say the same thing.
There is no neglect for existential issues because they cannot be measured.
What we should be able to measure is the well -defined.
Empathy, judgment, education are words that belong to the Intellectus activities.
They cannot be measured if we do not find indicators.
It makes us distort the phenomenon, and start chasing what can be measured.
We may miss the basic phenomenon altogether.
It is pseudoscience. It is not rational.
Catch the words that describe the core business, and think about how much you have to show.
Today we have to show everything up and out.
Is it the most important task of the business?
Or is the most important thing to do good core business?
We spend resources showing off, and forgetting the quality work.
We will show that much of what is being done is not about increasing the quality of the floor.
It's about showing off. It's something else.
Words like "ensure" I think we should dismay.
It's almost always a lie.
At Södertörn, they said they would ensure that no abuse happens again.
How should you do then? Lock everyone in each room?
Many things cannot be ensured, and then it becomes spasmodic.
We will work qualitatively with such issues.
It will be like a safety hub. The measurement becomes a cutting -edge.
We can measure, and we will measure, but in a wise way.
- It made me think a lot about the steering document concept.
As soon as there is something measurable and sent down, we end up in the ratio thinking.
Then there is no proximity to the reality for those who take it further.
Perhaps the best steering document is a number of questions.
The philosophical aspect disappears, and we are not encouraged to have a philosophical concept.
- I agree, and have seen it so many times.
At the Healthcare Association, they have provided that professional skill is important.
Then they mean judgment.
They tried to encourage an intellectus business, and we couldn't handle it.
We have grown this thinking as the only rational.
There is research that points to exactly the same movement in the Bologna process.
The Bologian documents are interesting, but at every step it becomes pedantified.
It is the way of our time to believe that we can do it in a rational way.
We have lost respect for the concepts that existed, and are starting to look for indicators.
Today, many people think about how we create environments for judgment.
These calls are located either at the fool production apparatus or the coffee apparatus.
Those that happen at the coffee apparatus are most interesting.
There you capture the shaky.
The structure you describe we must become aware of.
Only then can we respond to it, because people are wiser than that.
Computers are at a level very stupid.
We have to recycle what people can, and that is exactly this.
Without judged, we would not be able to live our lives.
- Thanks so much. You should get a small memory.
It is KB's own lla paper monster, which is found in all aspects.
- Thank you very much.