Hi, Julia is my name.
I am alumni from language, text processing and digital communication program-
-To University in Halmstad.
Right now I'm sitting in Gothenburg in my apartment and working from there.
I now work as a communicator at the construction companies in Gothenburg.
Thus in the construction industry.
The best thing about the education was to develop my writing.
I've always loved to write so it was a lot of fun.
Then it was also great fun to get more-
-The knowledge of text processing and communication.
Halmstad is a fantastic city to live and live in.
It is also a very good student city.
To you who are going to plug this program-
-or that is thinking about doing so, I would like to give tips on that-
-be curious about everything and absorb as much as possible-
-What the width offered by the program.
You can meanwhile find what you want to do then-
-or which direction you want to go.
It was especially good for me because I didn't really know-
-What I wanted to work with afterwards. I could come up with that in the meantime.
Something I brought with me from the education-
-Is that I have had to develop my writing.
It's something I do every day. I produce a lot of content-
-To various channels, social media and web, debate articles and more.
I have brought a lot of what we have read about communication-
-And digital concepts for example.
It is a big advantage for me in my job today.
I have always liked both Swedish and English as subjects in school.
But I chose the "Swedish language" as a focus because I experienced that-
-It was a more widespread labor market in Sweden.
I knew I wanted to live and live here in Sweden.
Therefore, I chose the "Swedish language" as a focus.
I didn't really know what I wanted to work on.
But thought it was a very wide focus.
So that I could come up with everything because, what I wanted to work on.
Something that I thought was extra good during the training was the practice.
I thought it was one of the most fun and most important things in the program.
There you really have to put your knowledge on the test-
-and do practical things.
Which is a great good stuff to know what you want to do later.
But also to make contacts for the future.
In the future, I want to continue working with communication in different ways.
I love to create content, to write above all. I think that is great fun.
But I also have a great interest in books and reading.
Which would have been a fun thing to work with in the future.
Either on a book publisher or as a writer.
We'll see what the future has to give.