-Cok, Edwin, I got him out! -Yes...
Edwin, how is it? You look so depressed.
It turned out that lots of my followers, my safaris, were fake.
I talked to my agency and they would check what had happened.
It may be fake followers. Purchased, scam, fake, like.
-When they bought. -Now I look at one of my followers.
-Yeah. -I am completely uncertain.
-On what? -If she even exists!
Is she a female? Imagine if it's a computer program that locks my stuff-
-or a hacker on any 'click farm' in some land-
-or a troll that sits and laughs at my amazing videos.
It is difficult to know who is hiding behind fake accounts.
Now this week, at SVT News, they had a company in Skåne-
-Which was revealed in a corruption.
It turned out that press officer at the company was an invented person.
Huh? So she wasn't at all?
No, they had used a page on the net where one can randomize faces-
-And it is generated a face that doesn't really exist.
You must probably accept the uncertainty that is on social media.
You do not know if the person you are talking to is there.
Many sites allow one to name themselves what you want.
On Facebook you should have your real name-
-But even there it is easy to create new accounts and hot something else.
On other social media or forums you can name yourself what you want.
"Leather62" or "lars the fat" or whatever seven.
That anonymity is there so we can use it.
-It's so on the internet. -You might not want to be himself.
No, and you shouldn't have to be. Anonymity is also good.
With it we can become whistleblower or alert about misconduct-
-And say when something is not right.
It gets lousy when many get afraid of not being able to tell things-
-When they experience. So anonymity is needed.
But remember that everything is not black and white.
Anonymity can lead to problems.
One who is hiding behind the anonym may breed, mock, hate or threaten.
-So there are problems with anonymity. -Oh...
All life is a lie. What else is not for real?
Right now you have a "pull away the carpet under your feet" -The moment-
-And it's hard, but this is what we do the "Källkoll" programs about.
What is fake online and what will be the consequences of it?
Now it's time for three important things:
Fresh air, coffee and some brainstorm.
Would you say you are good at discovering fake news?
No not really. I am not very pleased with fact -checking.
Yes, I would say.
-Oh yes. -Yes.
But some things are very difficult to say.
One should not be too confident.
No.
It depends well on what it comes to subject and how familiar you are in it.
I want to say yes, but you are often bad.
Yes, I'm pretty trained in it throughout the years.
No.
People do everything possible stupid when they are anonymous.
During the Melodifestivalen that Tusse won ...
96 points, which means Tusse has won the Melodifestivalen 2021!
Someone changed Tusses Wikipedia article so that it said he was cheating.
It wasn't out for so long and the one who did it was blocked.
Okay, but that doesn't sound very dangerous.
-No they wrote that he was dead. -Oh, it was pretty onejs.
Wikipedia is an encyclopedia everyone can edit.
That everyone can edit means that some can destroy-
-But at Wikipedia there is a strong community with serious editors-
-O which usually turns down hard on that type of scribble.
So you can trust them, then?
Actually, you should probably assume that you should check everything you see ...
-. in forums and comment fields. -Everything is always worth double checking.
Especially when it comes to unverified accounts.
Believing in what they say straight away is like believing in rumors.
We have said that we should talk about journalists-
-And how they work to confirm information.
Then when you see something, it's just as good to go out and check out news media-
-and see what is written.
If they talk about unconfirmed information then one should know-
— that an unconfirmed task must not be false-
-But you should wait and see how it develops.
These are the fake stuff with real consequences that we talk about here.
That someone sits behind an anonymous account-
-And writes a lot of stuff. It can grow and get out of control?
Yes, already in the Middle Ages ...
Not your ancient examples! Do we have anything a little more fresh?
The Instagram race in Gothenburg is a good example.
The brawl, which developed into something that can be likened to a riot-
-Have its origin in a large number of pictures published on Instagram.
It is a good example of something small that then becomes like a monster-
-What cannot be checked. It's a good example.
After all, this was some girls who started an Instagram account
-And then they started putting out gossip and rumors about other girls' sex life.
Oh my God! I remember that! I lived there then. But it was 2012.
Yes, but it's not like people don't hang each other online now.
The principles are the same. There is something small-
-Ny in a comment field or in some forum-
-And then people start to care in a wider circle and then it rolls on.
In this case it became calabal-
-When people would look for those who made the account.
Innocent were hung out.
Not to mention how it felt to the girls who were hanged.
Okay, but we jump to modern times. You are factorying things online.
Last year, fake stuff has had real consequences.
God, yes. It is enough to watch the Covid tests-
-When people realized that they do not work, are false.
We looked at the conspiracy theory-
-and it was based on the fact that people who did not have the right knowledge of the question-
-Hade found details in various scientific study-
-And then spun about it in, for example, Facebook groups.
Yes. The consequence of this was that doctors at Sahlgrenska Hospital Sa-
-people who were in for other refused to take covid-test-
-trot that it is good for them to know if they have it.
Then it was a cavalcade of completely wrong statements during the year.
Then I see the disinfection agent. It knocks it out in a minute.
One minute. And can we do something similar, by injection-
-or almost like cleaning.
That the vaccine changes your DNA.
Neither the MRNA vaccine nor the others that develop-
-Have the potential to change our DNA.
That you get oxygen deficiency from having masks.
Prolonged use of masks can be uncomfortable.
But it does not lead to carbon dioxide poisoning or oxygen deficiency.
That the vaccines are untested and dangerous.
More and more people are not going to take vaccines.
I don't want to inject anything like that.
That there is microchip in the vaccine.
Dr. Rose, first question: Is there microchip in the Covid vaccine?
No. There are no microchip in the vaccine.
Only vaccine and a bit of a chemical-
-As you react correctly to the vaccine.
That the 5G network, this one with mobile telephony
-Have something to do with Coronavirus, which it doesn't have.
I recognize this from the demonstration poster I have seen.
It was planned to hold a demonstration at Medborgarplatsen.
-It didn't have the police condition. -... against the order of order ...
It has created effects in reality.
The conspiracy theories around the vaccine and virus-
-Have created a smaller, but loud, group ...
-. who doesn't believe in Covid-19. -That it doesn't exist at all?
Some believe so, others maybe more that the vaccine and virus-
-Is part of some kind of diabolical plan-
-No an elite that they think controls in the shadows.
And that the world's rulers either dance to their pipe-
-or is included in the conspiracy.
Okay, but then it's a good example?
It is a colorful example, spectacular and maximum-
-But do you really want to shed light on that group of ideas?
How big is it really? How many people believe in it?
Isn't the risk that you just showcase the idea for new ones?
The question is how representative they are.
We will see that now when it is to be vaccinated on a large scale.
Several times, even healthcare professionals have refused to vaccinate.
-Yes. -Th the other side, you have to leave.
-It's totally okay. -Yes.
And you have to be critical of the restrictions and laws.
-This are opinions. -Time "on the one hand, on the other".
-It's getting bad TV. -It's so to be factor.
It is difficult to determine what to raise to give attention.
Do you risk spreading something, or is it good to disprove it?
-Sån we wrestle with every day. -Yes, and conspiracy theorists ...
-Folia hats. -To call them so ...
... just make you widen a gorge here.
It is difficult to approach each other when you call someone stupid in the head.
Yes, this has split more than one family.
Some have lost friends because of things like this.
It is a problematic consequence in real life-
-That it affects how we are against each other-
-And how we trust each other and community institutions.
-It's a consequence. -What is the worst ...
-.. with fake stuff online? -Where should you start?
Yes, it is a big area. We make it easier.
Which is the worst example you think-
-If something that has been false and had a real consequence?
It is, for example, I think, the movement around the vaccine resist-
-There you use parents in different ways whose children have died.
Anna Nordbeck, reviewing reporter on "Documents from within".
What is common to how the vaccine opponents handles-
-This the kind of stories about people who lost their child-
-In a preventable disease as a measles is to point out-
-It, regardless, the vaccine is more dangerous than the disease itself.
I have talked to people who say that measles is not a disease-
-and that measles cannot kill, which is completely wrong.
It's about trying to bring
-That it is not serious illnesses and that vaccine is dangerous.
But there are a lot of good tips here to give.
We can do this in our channel.
Okay, but uptempo this time. Remember where I taught you.
False claims on the web can cause substantial injury.
Here are some tips for not being part of it-
-When you share things in your flows.
Tip one: assume that something is wrong or fake.
Think like it's April 1st and you don't want to go on something-
-When you are out on social media.
Tip two: Check it out. If anything was interesting enough to share-
-Is it absolutely important enough to check if it is correct.
Even if it's just something you read, it may be well worth checking out too-
-Stheft it can affect your picture of reality.
Tip three: Think about the effects, for you, for the one you write about.
Can this cause harm to someone?
Tip four: Keep in mind that things can scale up.
This little, little you write-
-or posts in your feed-
-Lo pretty openly open, and if many begin to split something-
-And something goes viral, it can have consequences you have not imagined.
Oh. - Hello?
Yes. Okay. I get it.
Oh, do you want to? Yes, but absolutely.
-Okay! -What is going on?
Perfect Beautiful Amazing Digital Media AB!
They want to do a collaboration with me. The largest thing that happened-
-Sen Travis Scott's Fortnite concert.
-Do you lit on them still? -EVER this talk about "trust" ...
I choose happiness! It will be fantastic. Drive the car!
Yes Yes. Okay then.
Let's go! Perfect Beautiful Amazing Digital Media AB, here we come!
Swedish texting: A. Thorén/m. Karlsson Iyuno Media Group for UR