Wow, what a place! But ... Jack? Jack?
-Hello! Here I am! -Yeah, where did you end up?
It happens crazy stuff in my channel sometimes.
Do you have hundreds of thousands of followers?
YES! The trick is to go up at regular intervals at night-
-To cover different groups.
I am the third largest account in New Zealand after the bird Hector.
Wow!
You don't really understand social media. We go through them!
-But ... -listen, I like you.
But your channel is a bit ... So, you need a little more ...
So, weave it in ... with a little LA! A little music, young people.
It should be fun! A naj's background.
You are absolutely right, Edwin!
And some iconic outfits.
Anyway ...
And grind on your message. You talk about a hundred things at the same time.
But these are interesting things we are talking about.
Choose a thing and focus on it. It should be clear and easy.
You want more followers, huh? Who is following you now?
Yes ... we will see ... Ulla-Britt in Växjö, librarian.
Look, she has fun pictures of her cat!
After all, one's followers tend to be as one's self.
When adults try to be "down with the kids" it can be Cringe.
Social media is about being able to reflect sig-
-and relate to the one who becomes the sender.
It becomes a bit of an age issue.
Speaking of it, I get spinning here. Can we sit down somewhere else?
-We go out of here. -Okay.
-I don't get him out of the channel. -It does not matter.
Strange that you haven't heard of any business-
-As you want you to advertise some product.
Funny you should say that, Åsa!
I have received a contract with Perfect Beautiful Amazing Digital Media AB.
They take care of my social media.
Social media is a good thing to take up in "Källkoll".
They affect the information flow of our time.
Many get their information almost only from social media.
Just! You talk about social media platform-
-And then you may mean mainly the technology-
-The then, what it looks like under the hood on Youtube and so on.
But one also means the world that arises-
-When we interact with each other.
Type algorithms? They are scary accurate sometimes.
How do they work purely technically?
My name is Ania and I work in the magazine "New Technology".
Algorithms work a bit like a recipe.
If you think the information is the ingredients in a prescription-
-And then you will get a certain result.
A certain cake, if we are to take such a comparison.
In social media contexts you can say-
-Do the algorithms above all help to sort content-
-And determines what you as a user see first in your feed-
-or what kind of content you see more of.
It may be based on who you are and what you have liked and followed-
-But also what your friends have followed and commented, or where you live.
The important thing is that the algorithms are not created from nowhere.
People create them. They are not always perfect.
You think they make a perfectly individualized content for you.
But it can fail and I think many have noticed in ads.
One wonders: "Why do I get this one?"
Then it has collected a lot of different information and determined:
"This is probably the kind of cake that fits."
Okay!
But algorithms are made by humans and bring our prejudices with them.
How?
Close your eyes and imagine a shoe.
Okay. Did it look like this?
Like this? Or maybe like this?
We may not know why, but everyone prefers one shoe over another.
Imagine you should teach a computer what a shoe is.
You may teach it your own opinions.
So prejudice enters machine learning.
YouTube has been accused of their suggestions for the next video
-Have radicalized people.
People start with cooking and become conspiracy theorists.
Isn't it a way that technology interacts with our thoughts?
Exactly, it's hard to get to the bottom with such.
The technology companies are not so open with how the algorithms work.
You do not know the recipe for something to be virtually.
-For then would we take advantage of it? -The precise, gejma system.
But sometimes it has been obvious.
On Facebook, angry clicks have led to viral things.
What social media are there? Which ones are the biggest?
-Facebook. -If you're type 40.
I would say tictok.
Tiktok is on the rise, but they are not really there yet.
TikTok has, like all such apps, had problems with suspicions about security-
-And how they use the data and the connection to China.
In a country where mass surveillance is common, both on the street and internet-
-Can you assume that this also applies to the data tictoch collects.
It has been discovered that the app took advantage of a vulnerability in Apple's phones-
-As has been able to read everything that the user has copied.
Facebook has also had some about security and user data.
My friend made a quiz called "This is your digitial life".
It made them get hold of information about me-
-When was used by Cambridge Analytica.
This was a big betrayal. I apologize for happening.
It is our responsibility to protect people's data.
Russian hackers tried to influence the American election.
A Russian impact campaign approved at the highest level.
You say you can get into my Facebook account.
And there we have your Facebook.
Facebook and TikTok are not the only ones who have these problems.
Like Clubhouse, the new app where you talk to each other.
There you have wondered how the app uses your contacts.
The app is Invite Only.
To invite someone, you must give Clubhouse access to the phone book.
Clubhouse went out this week and said that you can take out your contacts now.
It is a generational issue. It depends on the platform you are on.
A survey on Swedes' internet habits was conducted last year.
40 % of those who answered, who were students had tested Tiktok.
Compare that with 12 % of those who work and 3 % of pensioners.
Big difference! Instagram and snapchat-
-As much more common than Facebook in the group 16- to 25-year-olds.
Then something else will come. Who is it old then?
-It's still us. -Do not worry.
There will be some social pedometers you can entertain with.
I checked with people.
Instagram, tiktok, snapchat about it likes.
It's Instagram and Snapchat. It's the ones I use.
It is not much. We are elderly.
Instagram I run a lot, both for work and privately.
I have also started with Tiktok, work -related.
-What do you know? -Facebook. Basically.
Social media is fantastic, but there are some problems.
Yes, the younger generation is tired of everything being screamed out.
Now you want to be in private rooms and share things with each other.
You can say this, social media companies have built system-
-O which are created to target advertising as accurately as possible.
Yes Yes. And we users, we are pretty much on our stuff.
We post pictures of what we are doing.
There is a risk that it will be exploited.
What is going on?
I'm big in New Zealand. The third largest account.
Or, I was the third largest account.
The account for the bird Hector has required a cleansing of bottoms.
Whatever? So?
This means that thousands of my safaris were bottoms!
It's a disaster! Why does this happen to me?
It may have to do with that company.
Perfect Beautiful Amazing Digital Media AB?
Have they boosted my followers so that I should seem like a bigger star?
So that they can use me as advertising, like their items girl? Oh my God!
It has happened before that followers have been revealed as fake.
You can make quite healthy if you want.
Buy tiktok-likes.
But they can be used for more everyday things.
In Uppsala, it was booking bottoms that stole and sold further training times.
What we see is private individuals-
-Or has built bottoms, "script", which monitors our site.
When new times are released, they are booked faster than a man can.
Bottar is a weapon with.
Countries that affect each other through propaganda can use them as weapons.
What has happened to you may have to do with purchased fake followers.
Purchased users? I have to go and crisis!
It can be a bug. Right?
Yes, like on Twitter when people were blocked because they used the word "Memphis"?
Accounts that used the word "Memphis" have been limited due to a bug.
It is something. Hope it is.
-Can you make a summary piece? -How are we going to do it? We solve it.
Bot comes from the word robot.
It is a computer program to do automated data-
-Att from chatting in a customer service to spreading propaganda.
It depends on what it is programmed for.
When trying to make it look like you have a lot of followers-
-Is, for example, purchased likes or bottom-
-So you want it to look like you naturally have those followers.
Then you deceive the algorithm that you are more interesting than you are.
What, then, is an algorithm?
An algorithm is like a recipe that has been created-
-To tell the computer how it should act in different situations.
If it is a matter of how your social media feed looks out-
-What will come at the top and prioritized-
-To it is based on an algorithm that is a recipe for you.
When it comes to your feed then it is a recipe that applies to you.
That recipe has been built up by what you have previously done on the platform.
How you have interacted and things you've liked.
The companies want your details-
-To be able to direct advertising but also other things.
We offer a lot of information.
We offer what we post, pictures, personal information ...
Basically, algorithms are programming and can be used for a lot of things.
-All right! It went well. -Yes, he may have points anyway.
Perhaps. Anyway, we must try to help him with his loss of loss.
You mean "bot-case"?
Swedish texting: Iyuno Media Group for UR