Traditionally, an essay or degree project usually consists of these main parts.
In this video I talk about the first part, introduction and purpose.
The introduction is usually about one to one and a half pages.
There you tell the reader what kind of relevant problem you have found when you have read previous research in the form of primary sources.
That is, examined articles published in scientific journals or dissertations.
To tell the reader what kind of problems you have found is also called problem formulation.
It means the same thing and just means describing a problem.
For example, there is previous research, but there is no knowledge of a special thing.
In other words, you have discovered a knowledge gap.
Here it is important that you underpake your arguments with the support of primary sources.
In this concrete example, the student initially describes the importance of good healthcare.
Then the role of pedagogy is focused.
Finally, the student argues that there is a need for a certain type of study in the field.
A common beginner error in the introductory text is to forget to motivate with support in previous research.
It is not enough to refer only to government reports, course literature and the like.
This is because there are secondary sources.
I recommend one or two scientific articles in the introduction.
In addition, you are welcome to use a current and relevant dissertation in the introduction.
In this example, references to the National Agency for Education are not enough, I think.
Although it is a relevant authority for this study.
I want to see something more.
Let's add some arguments substantiated by primary sources.
The introduction is getting better because the reader understands what is the study's problem area.
In addition, it becomes clear that this study is based on previously completed research in the area.
However, remember that the introduction must not be too long.
Briefly tell us about these sources but save the longer descriptions for the section on the purpose.
It is enough if you show that your study is based on a scientific basis and not on your own opinion.
Another error in the introduction is to describe the problem too broad and unclear.
It is not enough to only point out a general problem area.
You have to specify what your study is all about.
The reader should not be forced to guess what problems or lack of knowledge you have discovered when you have read in the area.
This example describes an appreciated business, but the reader may find it difficult to understand what is the study's real problem area.
By adding a precise text, with references to articles and/or dissertations, the study's research problems become much clearer.
We now see that the research problem is that there is a knowledge slot regarding open preschools' work to support parents.
Another error is to focus on yourself too much in the introduction.
Admittedly, it may be of interest to the reader to know something about you.
However, there is no reason that you write an introductory background story based on your personal experiences.
You can briefly mention that you have your own experience in the field of study.
However, your problem formulation, that is, the knowledge gap you have discovered, should be based on scientific primary sources.
Once the reader has taken note of your introduction, he or she should think:
"This is a relevant and important problem of public interest and someone should conduct a study to create knowledge that can help to solve this problem."
A perfect introduction creates this feeling in the reader :-)
For your purpose, tell the reader what you have for your essay or your degree project.
You may also have two or three issues to further clarify and specify your intentions.
The purpose and issues must be about the problem you describe in your introduction.
A common beginner error in the purpose is to write that the study's purpose is to conduct a survey.
The purpose is rather to create knowledge.
You want to help clog the knowledge gap regarding the problem you describe in your introduction.
Another error is that the student believes that the issues should look like interview questions.
It is a common mistake to believe that the issues should be addressed to individuals.
Instead, they should be designed more overall and addressed to what the study intends to investigate.