Qualitative analysis of interview transcripts
Step 1: Read the printouts.
Eye through all the prints.
Write down your first impressions.
Then read through the prints again, more carefully-row-by-line.
Step 2: Mark relevant parts.
Mark words, sentences or paragraphs in the printouts.
It can be about what is happening, ie.
Activities but it can also be about perceptions, processes or basically anything that you think is relevant.
This process is called to code or index.
Here is an example of an interview printing that I have coded.
"But Kent! How do I know what to cuddle?", You wonder.
My answer is that you can decide to encode something because:
It is repeated in a number of places, it is something that surprises you,
It is something that the interviewee himself says is important,
It may be something that reminds you of something that you have read about in previous research,
for example in scientific articles or dissertations
It is something that reminds you of a scientific theory or concept
Or it may be for any other reason that you think is relevant.
In your coding process you can start from specific previous research and definite theories and concepts.
Or work more openly and exploratory.
You can code to create a superficial description or to concept the underlying patterns.
How the process is implemented is up to you.
It is your study and your choice of methodology.
You are the one who interprets, summarizes and analyzes.
It is your study and it is you who highlight the phenomena that you think are important.
However, ensure that you tell the reader about your methodology and the choices you have made and you usually do this under the heading method.
When encoding, try to be as factual and neutral as possible.
Stay close to data ie
What is actually in the printouts.
Do not hesitate to encode many phenomena.
You can have lots of codes, even hundreds.
Step 3: Decide which codes are most important, group those who think are associated and create a number of categories or themes.
Go through all the codes you have created so far.
Have a pen in your hand as you read through everything.
If you want, you can create new codes by combining two or more codes.
You do not need to use all the codes you have created.
In fact, most people can be sorted away from now.
Keep the codes that you think are important and group them in the way you think fits well.
You create categories or themes, which they can also be called.
Here is an example.
I have grouped these codes together and created a category.
Here is a second example, and here a third.
You are open minded and creative as well as factual and neutral when you create your categories.
These categories or themes need not be of the same type.
They can be about objects, processes, differences, similarities, emotions or basically anything.
Your work process now, compared to previous steps, is more general and abstract.
The categories you create, which also become the main result of the study, must be of general interest to your future readers.
Step 4. Name your categories, determined which are most relevant and how they belong together.
Name the categories.
In my example, I have three categories or themes.
I call the first constant adaptation, the second information search and the third problem solving.
In my case there were three categories, but it could just as well have been two or four.
You should also describe how the categories and their content are interconnected.
That said, these categories, or themes, as well as the connections between them, are your study's main result.
It is new knowledge about the world seen from the participants' perspective that you reproduce under the heading Results.
Step 5. Here are some possible options.
If you want, you can decide and describe the hierarchy that you think you see between the categories.
You can also decide if any category is more central than the others.
It is also possible to draw a figure to show them and their relationships.
Here is an example that I have created.
Step 6: It's time to write everything together.
Under the heading Results you describe your categories and how they are connected.
Use a neutral voice and do no analyzes of your results.
Under the heading discussion or analysis, you do your interpretations and discuss your results.
You can do this in the light of, for example, similar results that have been presented in relevant scientific journals or dissertations in the current research area.
Or in the light of theories or concepts from the area.
Or other relevant aspects.
Part 2. Finishing notes.
My starting point for this video was that you had raw data in the form of interview prints and that you want to bring order into them.
It wants to saga, create a result chapter where you tell us what you have found as well as a discussion chapter where you interpret and analyze these results.
However, I would like to remind you that everything I said in this video also applies to qualitative analysis in general.
In other words, you can use the steps and the tips and advice found in this video to interpret and analyze notes from-
-Observation studies, contain in documents, texts and web pages or other types of qualitative data.
There is quite a lot written in this area, but here are at least four books that I recommend.
Thank you so much for watching the video.
Don't forget to subscribe so I get spurred on to make more movies.
Hello then and good luck with your writing!