Hello! My name is Helena Karlsson-
-And I plug my second semester at project -based master.
With a project -based master, I have more opportunities to influence my studies.
I can work with a company or an organizational-
-and help them with changes or problems they have.
I have much more flexibility in a project -based master.
I am studying what I am interested in and I get to do something-
-Or has a value for someone else.
Maybe a company that needs help with something.
That is positive about having a company or an organization in the back-
-Is that I get one-
-The feeling for what it looks like in real life and I gain experience.
What kind of benefit is the company?
They
-The high school
-And an innovative resource team and I am included there.
It is very exciting that together you influence and solve-
-A existing problems that exist at the organization or company.
One is continuously working on carrying a dialog-
-and as a student-
-Es you feedback and support-
-What applies to the process.
Halmstad University is one of the most innovative colleges in the entire country-
-And that's why I just chose Halmstad University.
Precisely the project-based master-
-I feel the right line.
University really works proactive-
-To get the student as much experience as possible.