Hello and welcome back to a new video
Today Lilly and I will tell you a bit how it goes with exams at KTH
It is because the academic year is divided into four periods
And after each period you have an exam period where you then have time to plug in for your exams and even write them
But the exams don't just have to be written
There are also oral exams
For example, I had an oral exam now in one of my courses
And besides that, I know that many programs,
or some anyway,
have project work or submissions instead
It is common on architecture, where they have no exams at all
And also other programs that have group work instead
But how is it really done on an exam
Good question
I had a written exam
And I think it's very similar to the college exam
One starts with identification control
You have to show ID or passport for the exams and then you get admitted
And then you get to put jackets and bags beside
Then you go to your designated place, or sometimes you are lucky and can choose a place yourself
And then paper is already placed on the table
And then you start writing the exam
What one can bring with you, except for the usual as a pencil and blur
Is that you can bring pencul, pen sharpener, food and drink
Which can be good as the exams usually get quite long
And then it is important to have energy to cope through the entire exam
Besides that, after a while, the teacher usually enters the classroom even
And then you get a great opportunity to ask questions if you do not understand the questions
If you need to get some more clarity about the
And it is basically how a written exam looks
Last but not least we also have
A little later inlet
Which is 30 minutes after the exam has started
If one happens to come late or have been sleeping off
Perfect
How did you plug in for your exam
A little different
I think it's very
One is very favored by sitting with your course friends
And discuss and learn and each other
Then you get much better understanding too for what one should be able to
Then it is also sometimes nice to sit yourself
Then maybe you are sitting in some silent hall in the library
And really caves down on all questions
But then there is also a lot recorded on Youtube and so
As exercises and lectures
It is above all in math courses
So there is a lot of material if you feel that you may not have learned enough from the lectures or in the course book
So it will probably go well
Yeah there was a bit about exams at KTH
It's a little different maybe
A little different from high school anyway
But you get into it quickly and get used to
If you have any questions, just write them in the comments field
Take care, bye!