In this movie we will take a closer look at qualities and entities.
We will go through to add properties, seek out entities,
Adding linked and local entities and managing entities.
We will return to our cookbook example.
Some properties are linked to works and others to the instance. There are also properties that are tied
to admin metadata or stock.
To add a property, go first to edit.
The button with the large plus sign in the tool menu is "Add Properties".
If you are in the instance, which we are now, then the plus sign means "add properties during instance".
Thus, properties specific to the edition.
We can try removing a property and adding it again.
We remove scope.
And we go to add properties.
We are looking for scope.
And to now add the property again so we can either click the plus sign
Or put us up to Plus and press Enter to add the property.
So we press Enter again to add an instance of the property and now you can enter
Number of pages again.
Then I use ESC to close the side window.
Some properties are instead linked to works.
The work information is under instance of works so far because we do not
have started to break out works. We expand the instance of works
And we try to remove a trait here as well. We remove the subject.
I click Remove.
And to now add topic again during instance of works
So we go to add properties under text, ie instance of works, text,
Add properties.
We are looking for the property again
And tabs us forward and press Enter to add it.
Then we press Enter again to get to the side window.
Here we can now find the entity again.
So we are looking for vegetarian food
And we enter that it should be from Swedish subject words, SAO.
When you search for entities in the side window, you have the opportunity to delineate
The search and you have some opportunities to sort the hit list.
We're Tabs up to Add and Press Enter
And now the property has been added again.
If you want to get an overview of the characteristics associated with works, instance, admin metadata or stock,
Go to help and look in the table of contents there.
We click on help, it opens in a new tab.
We go into works and we can see in the table of contents that subject
Located under works.
We go back to the form.
We try with the property involvement and function
under the instance of works.
We remove the property.
We go to add properties during the instance of works and we seek out participation and function again.
We use tab and enter to add the property. Then we come to a list
Where we can choose type. We choose primary participation because it was just a writer here.
Then we look for the entity again by clicking Add Entity and searching the side window.
We are stabbed to add and press Enter.
Then we do the same with function.
We go to Add Function, searching the side window for the entity writer,
We are stabbed and press Enter to add.
The principle is that we link to entities that already exist, such as a person.
If necessary, we can create new agents for new people and you can watch a movie about it.
The film Create new agent - person.
Sometimes there is no entity to link to, and we have no information as a basis for creating a new entity.
Then we may need to create a local entity.
I'll show what it looks like.
We remove the linked entity
and i now click Add Entity at Agent
And then I go to create local entity at the bottom of the side window. I choose person,
And then I enter the information I have.
This is then a fingered case that it may look like when you do not have all the information.
This is how you sometimes do with subject words.
There are films about linking to subject words and about subject words as a local entity.
We will look at another trait during instance.
We go to title.
We have a main title and other title information or subtitle.
If we want to add a cover title, we may add another title entrance.
We go to Add Entity and choose type
Cover title
I enter a cover title here, I find it.
If we here want to add other title information under the cover title we may go to
Add properties under cover title. Then we can seek out the property other title information
And put us forward and add it.
And then we can enter the other title information if there is one.
It is also possible to copy an entity to the clipboard and to duplicate it.
Click on the three dots that mean manage.
If you copy to the clipboard, the tool feels where the entity can be pasted.
A paste in icon then appears in the places where it is now possible to paste the clipboard.
For example, you can Copy an entity from one post and paste it into another.
You can also duplicate an entity which can be useful in some contexts
To delete a property or entity click the trash at the property or entity.