- My name is Michael Forsman and I am an associate professor of media and communication science.
I am also the leader of the circle south, something that I look forward to.
We'll see you this afternoon and talk about the texts.
I think they were excited, and are linked to what we have heard.
I will also do that, though in other words and in different form.
It doesn't feel okay, but I do it anyway.
In addition, I have a script that I was going to read from.
I can tell you that the self -test found in Digiteket,
the platform that is within the framework of digital first,
has been developed for you to develop digital skills in the profession.
I have done that test. I became a "beginner".
It may be good to know.
Through the test I also got to see what is expected of you.
The test is based on skills that you should have, and may need to develop more.
You should be able to handle information, but also source criticism and computer science.
It's not just about your skills, but also about helping others
Who comes and is a village in this.
It's something I see in some of the texts we're going to talk about.
You are part of a national project where we all join.
The government writes like this in its overall digitization strategy:
"Sweden will be the best in the world in utilizing the possibilities of digitalisation."
Here we enter the skeptic track.
It is a name that can be interpreted in different ways.
There is a book called "Skeptic School" that indicates that
It is important to be critically examined in issues of source criticism.
But we go more in the philosophical direction.
The skeptical method is about a kind of theoretical provocation
in relation to observations we make.
It's not just reviewing validity and truth,
Without also provoking our ways of thinking about facts.
We can do this with theories, but also by reflecting practical experience.
The goal is not to be for or against, but to induce underlying structures.
To become aware of how we think, because there is a limitation in our own thinking.
It is the credo's credo, according to Kant.
"Enlightenment is man's exit from her self -inflicted un carerion."
We need to think about concepts and our own thinking.
I will talk a little about that.
A few more words about the skeptic track.
One should watch out for cynicism, nihilism and dogmatics.
All of them can be linked to skepticism.
Being skeptical is about opening new perspectives and opportunities.
To be skeptical of the management culture that comes with digitalisation
is not about being a technology opponent.
Some kind of luddit, like those who gave up on textile factories
who were considered to threaten previous forms of knowledge and work.
However, I am inclined to agree with technology conservative media ecologists.
For example, Neil Postman, who urged us to switch on our "Bullshit Detecor"
When technology propagandists say: "The future is already here",
With the implied sentence: "You don't seem to have understood it".
Postman, and even contemporary critics of, for example, the school's digitization,
Know that technology is not neutral, that it is embedded in a historical context.
That it is always constructed and understood in a social, cultural context.
That it is always linked to questions about power.
As a skeptic should we ask the question: to what problem is this a solution?
What interests are pushing, and why?
What curricula do follow with the technology?
What is the price for implementing this? Could it have effects other than those intended?
In this way, the skeptical attitude becomes productive.
I can see that our skeptic track becomes technology progressive
And about how technology can better help the profession.
Alternatively, to have the technology redo the profession in a fruitful way.
The important thing is to see what the indispensable values in the librarian profession are.
After this introduction, I was thinking of linking to the "Floska apparatus".
Policy, concept formation, manuals, directives of various kinds.
I have previously researched different things.
Children and young people in media, popular culture, public service and other things.
I have also worked in teacher education for twenty years.
Currently I am finishing a project called
"Media citizen's education and the school's medialization - curricula, teaching materials, teacher education."
There I and a colleague look at the curriculum 62 and Lgr 11.
How to write about teaching technology there, but also about media society and media education.
There are no new questions about the need for this knowledge.
There we have coined the term "media citizen".
There is a thought about the good media citizen who is involved and reviews information.
I don't mind, but it's an interesting historical construction
made in curricula, teaching forms or food
which is given to the school from external players.
Today it is Apple, Google and Microsoft.
Previously, it has been the Swedish daily press, public service and the Swedish Film Institute.
Many people work against the school with new technology or media issues.
It is about raising media citizens for the deeply medialized society
Where media is everywhere, and it can be perceived as media being everything.
You can take the idea of ideal citizens and curriculum for what we should work with.
There is a kind of curriculum in the profession that is confronted with the management culture.
They do not fully meet each other.
Digitization in libraries is about many things.
Some are to digitize collections, and manage a lot of information.
Another is that the library gets a new function in society.
It seems that both processes are in motion.
"Digitally first - the user in focus" it says on the logo
which is an emblem for the national competence lift for library staff.
The logo is stylish, simple and fun. It is available with pink and light green background.
The circle expresses harmony and wholeness, but also movement, as a globe that rises.
A balloon that lifts, a ball that rolls.
“The user in focus”. We are all users in society.
That is why we are all in focus.
"Digitally first" is a call, a finding and a reminder.
It also indicates order. First comes digitization.
Here we have to ask ourselves what comes next.
In this context, other symbols are also used that will make us think right.
It is about tools, it is something to be created.
Magnifying glass, there are problems to be solved.
It is a kind of visual ability to be sharpened.
Digitally first began with what was called a mobilization phase,
Which leads the thoughts to citizenship and renovation.
Everyone is going, and maybe no one gets away.
But this is also a community that has a future.
Now it becomes a college talk with the concept of "digitization".
Above all this lies a top down process where the term digitization is used.
I have been to many fairs where new technology is presented.
Many teachers talk about their "best practice".
All respect for it, but one wonders where the concept begins and ends.
From the beginning it was about an idea of a technical transformation
Where you still think about the relationship digital -analog.
That question is about to be overplayed, except that robots will possibly replace people.
Otherwise, much of what we are doing is already digitized.
It is also a social transformation.
In English you distinguish on "Digitization", the technical change,
And "digitalization", which is the social transformation.
It is the one who does something with our work and everyday life.
Where the technology is involved and affects.
One can think of a concept from the literary scientist Fredric Jameson.
It is a kind of culturally dominant.
It is a concept that you have to include when you think about the contemporary and the future.
Questions about work and citizenship.
You can't think about it without thinking digitalization.
With the cultural dominant, norms and ideas follow.
You talk about sociotechnological notions about a future.
That technology will solve different types of problems.
For example, gaps or problems with inclusion in democracy.
We think the technology will do good things with this.
These pictures are often bright and problem -free.
There are other types of performances that are more alternative.
There may be another future that is connected.
There are very dystopian images of the technologized future.
Where the machines have taken over.
Jonna described how the children become pulp.
There is a concern, but also a learning process that we all have to go into.
I who are getting older think that sometimes it is a personal challenge to keep up.
The learning process is something that we must all be included in.
One can also think that digitalisation is about a national project
that has to do with citizenship.
A kind of education by us in a national community.
Sweden will be the best in the world in utilizing the possibilities of digitalisation.
One concept that recurs is "digital competence".
It is a key term in questions about learning processes.
There are several different definitions and descriptions.
This is how it says in the government's digitization strategy:
“Digital competence means that everyone should be familiar with digital tools and services
And have the ability to follow and participate in digital development based on their conditions. "
There is a feeling that we are different, but also a requirement to be involved.
Something similar is found in Lgr 11, where the school's digitization was made.
They have wanted to press to make more happen.
I have no objections, but it is interesting to look at.
There are other ways of describing.
Beyond this one can find endless amounts of documents
With definitions, descriptions, modules, indicators, dimensions of digital competence.
24 Competences in 5 different areas, and so on.
Digital skills can be all this, and there is a lot we should include.
It is almost a stress when looking at the concepts.
The term "digital competence" comes from "digital literacy",
Which was a word that came in academic circles in the 1990s.
Around the beginning of the 1990s, the EU and the OECD became fond of the concept of "digital competence",
And connected it to what is called "21st century skills".
An assumption of what people need to be able to do if they are to be in this century.
One of these skills is digital competence.
The concept is often linked to employability, innovation, competitiveness
And to the demand for lifelong learning.
We must never stop learning the things that are partly prescribed that we must learn.
It is also linked to a living democracy and dynamic cultural production.
The term "digital competence" and other terms are so -called "loose concepts".
A kind of liquid signal word, which means they lack a fixed definition.
At the same time, everyone can use them, and no one can help but use them.
They become points for policymakers in different contexts based on their interests.
They are not only descriptive, but also prescribing and regulating.
It is interesting when you meet this type of terminology.
The concept of competence may be worth a few more words.
The American concept of "Human Resource Management" came into Sweden in the 1980s.
On the one hand, there is the functional, requirements -oriented side that is linked to what Jonna talked about.
Competence is what can be measured.
Then there is a more dynamic side that you fish for in the steering documents
Which is more about judgmental ability.
What Eva Swartz writes about in the anthology Librarian's practical knowledge.
A kind of fronesis, judgment knowledge, even education.
I'll stop right away.
Another term that has been close to the libraries is "media and information expertise".
That term comes from UNESCO, which in the early 1980s began discussions about
What happens to children and young people in a medialized world.
How can we protect and empower them in relation to those
Risks and opportunities that new technologies bring.
Of course, these are important issues.
In 2011, a global curriculum was launched for all teachers in the UN Member States,
It is about teachers becoming more media and information experts.
The concepts "digital competence" and "media and information expertise" have been supported and wet.
They show up in different contexts, and the authorities have their favorites.
The concepts are overlapping. What sets them apart?
UNESCO presents five laws for media and information skills.
If you follow them, it will go well.
It brings me back to the idea of education by citizens.
I don't know about this conceptual outing and skeptical reflections
Around policy and logos are relevant to our meetings.
There we should be down to earth and concrete around everyday situations
And how they can be experienced and grow into new reviews.
I have certainly missed important aspects along the way.
Library is a new area of research for me.
My impression is that a library is on its way into a structural transformation that has been going on for a while.
Where the library's autonomy is under pressure.
Where the libraries are changing as a physical and cultural place.
Where the librarian profession is changing
And where different sociotechnological notions of the future are produced from different directions.
Here, concepts such as "Digital Competence," Mik "," Digitally first "will be signal words.
What do they signal, and is it red or green for me?
Everyone has to decide on it.