Welcome to this course on open access!
"Open access" has come to the forefront
of research and library communities
in recent years,
and will continue growing in importance
for our entire society.
Simply put, "open access" means
it should be possible for anyone,
free of charge, to access research results,
for example academic publications,
by searching the internet.
This may not seem remarkable,
but the fact is that open access
involves a major change
for the research and library communities
that make research results accessible.
"Open access" is part
of another current concept:
Open science.
An open science system
includes open access
to academic publications
and research data,
but it also includes open learning resources
and citizen participation in research.
The Swedish government has decided that academic
publications and research data
resulting from publicly-funded research
should be openly accessible.
Whether you work at a library such as NLS,
or another research library,
or if you are a researcher,
you will be affected by this movement
towards open access and open science.
The transition to open access
and open science
has been underway for nearly 20 years,
but is still evolving.
This means we do not yet
have all the answers
to how open access and open science
will work in the future.
In this course,
which takes about 30 minutes,
you will receive a broad introduction
on what open access is,
and how it may affect you in your work.
You will also meet colleagues
who share their views on open access
from varying perspectives.