In this movie we will take a tour of Libris cataloging tools.
We will go through the home page, the main menu, the tool menu and the structure in a description.
Libris cataloging is the name of the cataloging tool.
Libris cataloging is part of Libris XL
which is the name of Libri's new technical infrastructure and was launched in 2018.
Libris cataloging is a web tool.
It works in all browsers but has proven to work best in Google Chrome.
When learning Libris cataloging, use a test environment
And you see the address of the test environment in the address window.
The test environment contains a copy of the libris database.
Here you can freely practice cataloging.
What you save here will be cleared away at the next update of the test environment.
You will receive login information to the test environment at the basic course.
When you are logged in, you can see in the upper right corner which sigel you have active.
Sigel is a code designation for a library.
If you have access to multiple Sigler, you can change here if necessary.
We will look at the home page.
Here you will find links to news, introductory material and to Libris Supportforum.
You will find our instructional films found in a playlist on Youtube.
At the top of the page is a main menu.
Here are search that leads to search in libris and search in other sources.
It is important to seek carefully before creating something new so as not to create duplicates.
We will take a closer look at search in another movie.
The heading Create new leads to a page with templates for different material types.
Keep in mind that you very rarely need to create something new.
There is usually already an item or pre -information in Libris for what you should describe.
The next heading is catalog care.
Here you will find a feature for moving stocks between items.
Then we get helpful.
Through the helping heading you come to a page with help texts.
This page can be used in parallel with the cataloging tool.
Feel free to open it in a new tab and go to the help when you wonder about something.
We will look at the headlines in the help.
You will find, in the middle of the page, a list of links to further information.
Among other things, the important instructions for cataloging according to RDA, which are our catalog rules.
During the cataloging tool in the left menu there are some pages that explain how the tool works.
The page to use the tool contains many headings that you benefit from.
There is a list of shortcuts for PC and Mac.
Under general description there are help texts that are common to several types of materials.
Admin metadata is administrative metadata found in each entry.
The headings work and instance you recognize from previous films.
Under works you will find headings such as participation and function, genre/form, classification and subject.
These are characteristics that are common to several editions of a work.
During the instance there are headings such as publishing, identifier, such as ISBN, scope, dimensions.
This is what is specific to the edition.
Then we see in the left menu that there are pages for different material types.
There are pages about agents and subject words, stocks, terminology
And you will find the page with educational material here.
We go back to the home page.
We will take a closer look at an entry and see what it looks like in the tool.
I'm looking for a title, sheet metal food.
And choose a printed monograph here in the list.
This is a vegetarian cookbook.
There is a box that summarizes the information in the description.
We see that the book is called sheet metal - green in a long pan.
We see ISBN.
That there is a origin and information on publication.
It is published by Norstedts 2018.
If we click on "Show more" we will see the number of pages and more.
A little further up the right we see when the post is created and last changed and of which Sigel.
We see Posten's ID and we can copy it if needed.
A little further down there is information about stocks.
We can set stocks if we have not already done so.
We can see how many other libraries have set stocks and we can show all stock items.
The list of stock items is now displayed in a side panel.
To close the side panel, press ESC.
Let's move on.
The next headlines are instance and admin metadata.
There are two views that can be switched between.
We start by switching to admin metadata
by clicking on it.
Here is administrative information about the mail, such as the description level,
cataloging rules and information on mechanical changes that have been made.
Most of this is done automatically and you do not have to change a lot.
But in particular, note that it is important to choose the right description level.
Read more about it in the Help text for admin metadata.
We switch view back to instance.
The instance contains information that is specific to the edition.
The instance currently contains the work information embedded locally during the instance of works.
We start by expanding the mail.
We do this by pressing Alt and Plus at the same time.
You can expand and minimize each section also by clicking the arrow at the heading.
We first look at the work information during the instance of works.
As you know from previous films, the work information is not linked,
Without it locally embedded in each instance.
We see that this is a text.
We will look at what qualities are attached to the work here.
First we have the property involvement and function.
Here we have stated that primary participation is an agent with the writer function.
The agent is an entity.
We can right -click the entity and open it in a new tab.
Here we see the information about this person.
We can link to this entity several times if there are several works from her.
The writer function is also an entity that we can link to if needed.
In the same way, it works with language and genre/form.
Genre describes what something is and this is a cookbook.
We have linked to the entity for cookbooks.
Classification, on the other hand, does not contain linked entities.
Instead, classification lies as a local entity and the information is entered.
There is both dewey classification and SAB classification.
There are also subject words.
Subject words describe what the work is about, unlike genre that describes what it is.
This cookbook is about vegetarian food and we have linked to the entity for it.
Sometimes you describe agents and subject words without linking.
More about that in the movie qualities and entities.
There is also a link to the content type text.
Then we were done with the work information and we move on to the instance.
The body is about what is specific to the edition.
Here we enter the identifier as in this case is ISBN.
Title, publishing, e.g.
Place of publishing, publisher and publishing year.
And we also have scope and there we have the number of pages that the book has.
We will look at a tool menu that we see here.
There are three buttons.
First show as.
You can see the post in the storage format JSON-LD and a few other linked data formats.
During the tool icon there are several choices.
You can expand or minimize all properties.
You can copy the entire entry.
You can also download the mail in Marc format to import it into its local system.
You can also download it in JSON LD format or see the information in a Marc view.
Then a side panel comes out and to close it we press ESC.
Here you will also find the instance.
The last button is edit.
Here you now get some more choices under the tool menu.
You see that under tools you have now received enrich from template, enrich from mail and detailed enrichment
And we will go through them in the movie Edit, upgrade and enrich.
You can add properties with the plus button.
You can cancel and you have two savings buttons.
With the first you save and continue to be in editing mode.
With the other you save and leave edit mode.
When you save an entry, all empty properties disappear.
If something is pre -filled, you need to remove it manually if you have not used that property.
It was all for this movie.
There are more films about different elements in Libris cataloging.