Hello and welcome here
to the University of Borås
Here I sit, Malin Ögland together with Karin Nowe Hedvall
and we shall present some
First tentative results from our accompanying research
of the project digitally first with the user in focus
As in daily speech in the public library world, digitally is first called.
And this is very briefly an assignment that the Royal Library received from the government to -
And now I'm quoting directly from the Director of Culture - Directive -
That KB in 2018 to 2020 nationally coordinates and finances
an investment in regional library operations such as skills and development nodes
The investment in turn means that regional library operations coordinate an education
By the country's public librarians
For a digital knowledge increase.
And Karin and I have
Included in a research group earlier where we did a study
Where we followed that project
2018 to 2019
That resulted in the study
Users first with the digital in focus.
In this study identified at several gaps
As the gap between perceived local needs
Local demand and national assignment when it comes to support with the digital.
We also saw that you already work with many digital elements but you work slightly less with
The task of raising citizens' digital skills.
These results were so interesting and important so wanted to keep looking at
Some of them and therefore we have continued with follow -up research
Even during 2020.
And this time we would love to
Understand a little more about this excitement that you mentioned
Between local needs for digital skills development
And local expectations that the public librarian sees
That their users have.
And the tension between the national level
The national assignment at public libraries
And also wants to learn a little more about
Users and even local partners
at municipal level
and their expectations at the public library
When it comes to the digital.
This year we have posted it as three sub -studies.
The first where Malin as responsible looked at the regional coordinators
and how they can handle this gap that we saw
between what they perceived as the needs of the public library
and the demand for skills development
also within the framework of the national digital first project
And you have done an interview study, you will tell you more about it later.
I have gone back to these
The municipal libraries that we looked at in the first study.
This time I have immersed myself a little more in
How their choice of business and activities
As for the digital
can be seen to interact with
How they are perceived in the local community
thus their role, their legitimacy
in its municipality.
I have done some interviews, workshops.
Jenny Lindberg, who is not here today
will do a study on
Citizens of these local communities
And she wonders what expectations
Do you really have at the public library.
And partly she will do structured interviews
with residents, users
and also interview some local partners
in municipal administration.
Today we will report some preliminary results
From your study Malin and also from my part study.
I have then interviewed
19 regional coordinators and even the national coordinator
for digital first and that I was interested in
is how the regional library business handles this gap
As we found in the previous study, we see that it is also reflected at regional level.
and what is it that coordinators perceive that their local library needs
And what is it that the local libraries expect to receive support from the regional level
and what is it as the national level
have expectations of what is going to happen.
And what I can see, among other things, is
How the regional coordinators are tamped with the scope of action they have
and how complex it is
And that it is large, complex but limited by all different assignments and values
that goes into each other.
And that they must constantly define their own professional objects
In order to
In collaboration with the local level
Find the common professional object
So what is it to be achieved here together
In this project.
In digital first, they have been able to take the support of the national self -test that was made
The beginning of the project
And it looks a little different how you
Has been able to use this.
An example from here
Empirin so one says that the tour was initially made to discuss the result
from the self -assessment test
But
Instead, it became an anchoring discussion around
What does it really mean to be digitally competent.
Then there is also a dilemma in how itself
the assignment has been given, namely this that
that the regions should coordinate an education
for the country's public librarians, and it also records
In how you
Works with it.
It sounds rational and good but
They bump a little on patrol because there is no existing infrastructure
Or collaboration model
For all regions nationally
because this...
It is also not easy for regional coordinators to create it is national cooperation.
One can also say this is going
against what is the regional libraries
Strength, namely
to seem
Local
and also not be fully thought out but rather then bring in local library
When they create their projects
And work
in dialogue with them and then searching funds
and this project has then
added in a different way - here comes money and a mission straight down
And then you should do something.
We are not sure of whether this became
better or worse or if it just got different
But the ones you can see is that at the start of the project, it was included in the plan to build
a digital learning platform, the one called
Digiteket
And now during the past all over the past year, then have
The digitet or learning platform
been filled with a variety of courses and lectures and articles
Which has been created by these more regional coordinators but also by librarians locally
and in collaboration and even some
Researcher articles have been added
and so on. And then you can say that
Actually so have then
This national
Coordinated
The training it
is now available as a result of this whole project at Digiteket
And
But
Where there is still there
to
The local libraries can pick as well as to suit them according to their needs
And the regional ones
The libraries can also as well as
Recommend
from.
And I think so as you see on the third quote here that
That is true.
Then it is when we have been out in the library and showed the digitet and then maybe someone found a course where man
Realize that - yes this was great this we need.
It is really in the conversation with the library staff in smaller groups I would like to say when you can sit in peace and quiet
And they must tell you what they do and what needs they have, what you find I think.
I think that is very exciting and will
also good at
What was the starting point for my study then at the public library level to
Digiteket, that business, the activity, which eventually becomes the project
Or it becomes that governs. And in the same way I think that
At the level of public library, at the local level.
Then their choice of businesses, activities out toward users
Become
that that became
digital support
Regardless of which ones
strategies or goals or
Governance documents you have
Who says what to do so it is still on the floor
as
The projects will be.
I think that is important so we went out to these public libraries and asked what is it then you really do
As you call the digital
to understand
In which way you see
the role of its public library
In this whole digital
The digitization of society.
We already said that in 2019 we found a very rich selection
of activities like
Public library staff associate with
What they call the digital
and now as we followed this up again in 2020 through digital workshops
We notice that
the wealth it has
increased, it has really got a push up again
And it is probably partly that you have embraced
Digitally we understand
Also by digitalisation is something that governs in society
continuously
one sees the needs
And the third is, of course, that we had a very special spring with pandemic.
What you can see is that these public libraries we have talked to
that the essence of what you work with I call for support on site
that is when
people who come into the library with their questions
regarding
the digital and it can be anything from needing help with printing
to want to download an app
to want to use
Facebook
perhaps
any question that applies to the digital and then you try
Most often you try to help as much as possible
on site.
Another leg that is of course very
strongly as they talk a lot about are the digital resources
Man offers as a library
and it's e-books
It's e-journals, Press Reader
It's blogs, it's websites
all this
in the catalog.
And that can be said that
Several libraries tell them that they are increasing their range of, for example
E-books
so that one can borrow more
And better
E-books nowadays
and market them too
More and more and more and also see results in being used more.
A third leg that you always mention is that you see that the infrastructure and then I talk computers
printer
that there is Wi-Fi at the library
But also technology as a greenscreens
movie cameras
Makers Space
infrastructure
that you see that you provide it
for people who do not have
Access to them and they are seen as part of their mission and is very much used.
Then there is some program operations that target this with this with digital skills straight off
courses in source criticism for example, as one has
arranged and arranged out against its users
And that kind of program business. You have usually also had it in place and you have needed it
change
with Corona now so it has moved out to
the digital world.
With Corona, you have also started to interact digitally more and more
over social media for example
With recorded lectures, recorded book tips
What it may be
and this will be this
A fifth way, a fifth category to work with.
Why is this important to know what to do? I'm thinking that
the important thing is to think what will it be of it all
Why do you do this way and what effects do you think it may have
for the users
in the end
and this is something that is usually called a little fancy for program theory
It is an accepted concept in evaluation research.
It is based on the assumption of that
When one is part of a project
For example, as staff at public library
so you have a number of assumptions about
What the project might lead to
And so you have some activities that you organize
To make sure you end up there.
The effects they usually talk about being able to change an individual's
behavior in four ways just really, only four kinds of effects:
feelings
one can strive for people to feel more satisfied with something or that they have
better self -confidence for example
when it comes to the digital.
One can choose to have new sorts
skills
Most often skills in basic digital technology,
Office documents.
But also, for example, reading promotion activities
that you want them to be able to read more
May be such an effect that one mentions that one wants to achieve with the digital
the activities.
One also talks about the third level, about wanting
that people should have new knowledge
And then, for example, most often
Source criticism online that is such a knowledge that you strive for.
And in the end and perhaps most basic is that you want people to change their
behavior
And here, for example, you talk about wanting to
Start using the library
Thus, new user groups
that changes it.
All these
the purposes, all of these desired effects mention
Public library staff
when they talk about why they work with all their
digital activities as a mix.
What one can then look at and think about
In every public library is that you can take a step back and review then this one
Mix of all these businesses you have and think
Where is this business? Where is this just this that we offer support on site
To those who come in?
Where does it lead? We want it to have effects
As one can look at these arrows on powerpoint
That people are more satisfied, that they have self -confidence when they take on this digital world
That they learn
Basal technology
And so you can think of even more that we want to go there.
And so you can look at we have enough of that kind
Should we expand it, we will, as some tell about
out with this support in place to the place where people are actually
And so on and so you can look at all their businesses,
they recorded the book tips,
partners' integration business
Where you have this fun technology you buy, thinking what does it lead to?
Why do we want it to lead there and where
is there somewhere here we want
Change a little, screw a little on, take a little more off for us to have even better effect.
And that is what is program theory, that one looks back
on his own
We are in the process of analyzing this right now
We will also then I intend to look at which program theory you have at regional level then
which one has at national level,
How do they fit together?
But there we are not yet
We are in the middle of the project.
And there is also a third studies remaining then, Jenny's, but we thank you now and
We will return with a report later this fall.
Bye