An important aim of open access
is to make it possible, for anyone,
at no charge and in a simple way,
to find and reuse research results
by searching the internet.
There are a variety of methods
by which publications are made available.
The terms "golden road," "green road"
and "hybrid publishing"
are frequently used
to describe these various methods.
The "golden road" is where the researcher
publishes his or her article
in an open-access journal.
All articles published in the journal
are immediately accessible to,
and searchable by, everyone.
The publisher commonly bills
a publishing charge to the researcher,
referred to as an
"article processing charge," or APC.
In other words, this differs significantly
from the traditional system,
under which the publishing itself
is free of charge,
but the reader is required to pay
to access the article.
"Hybrid publishing" is where the researcher
publishes the article
in a traditional, subscription-based journal,
and the publisher bills a publishing charge
to the researcher,
in order to make the specific article
open access right away.
The "green road" is where the researcher
publishes the article
in a traditional, subscription-based journal.
After that, an earlier,
peer-reviewed version of the article
is published in a digital archive
for open access.
The publisher usually requires that the
open publication does not occur right away,
but that an interval of months must pass
between journal publication
and publication for open access.
This period is referred to
as the "embargo period,"
and is often between 6 and 12 months.
There is a trend toward
increasing embargo periods.
Within this method,
anyone who wants access
to the published version of the article
is still required to pay
high subscription fees to the publishers.