Open access affects me in the sense
that I see it as the future of our work.
It's strongly linked to digitalization.
Libraries will not be able to function
without addressing the issue of open
access in connection to digitalization.
Publicly-funded work
must be openly accessible online.
In my personal life,
if I need to search for medical information,
I don't have access to those articles
from home.
They are publicly funded.
I have friends who run startups
or who study.
They don't have access to what they need
to be effective in their studies or work.
For me, it's primarily about making books
and journals accessible
via link servers that connect to our local
directories and thereby also to LIBRIS.
It's about making databases accessible.
The databases we feel
are relevant to the work.
It's also about the projects
the Bibsam Consortium supports.
Most recently Open Book Publishers
and Knowledge Unlatched.
I'm helping make the titles which are part
of those content services accessible.
This raises the discussion
about how the collection is perceived,
what the collection will look like in the future.
NLS has a fairly large collection
of printed journals,
to which we continue to subscribe.
When journals transition
to an electronic-only format,
and in some cases
are made openly accessible,
it raises the question
of how to make the most of that material.
How do you preserve it?
Knowing how to use open access
is important,
because then you know
how to use the material.
If you know how it was created.
Open access material
comes in many forms.
It may have been peer-reviewed,
or it may not have been.
It's comparable to Wikipedia,
which is designed so everyone contributes.
In some cases,
Wikipedia articles aren't reviewed.
Controversial subjects
can cause differing opinions.
If you know how things work,
you can use them in the right way.
You can include unreviewed work
that's still interesting to discuss.
That's one reason why knowing
how to use open access is important.
If you write the material
which will be openly accessible,
if you know what that means,
you have power to shape the process.
For example, the copywrite issue.
For a long time, researchers signed away
their copywrite ownership,
the right to disseminate their material.
Now the plan is to set up licenses,
so researchers retain their copywrites.
This requires knowledge of which license
to use, which license suits the work?
It's important that the person creating
the resources or writing the material
knows what to do,
what choices are available.
The number of openly accessible
publications is increasing.
It will most likely continue to increase.
Since the issue is at the forefront,
it's good for the staff to stay current
on issues which affect the libraries.
NLS is a national library
which other libraries look to as an example.
So it's good to have a plan, a strategy,
about how to convey that knowledge.
Part of my job consists of work in the field,
where I meet users and visitors.
So far there hasn't been a lot of questions
concerning open access materials.
That may be because visitors and users
think they know
what the NLS collections consist of,
the printed collections or the archives
or the audiovisual collections.
But they may not know about open access.
In the long term that will certainly change,
because of the changing landscape.
It's good for the staff to have the knowledge
to guide users down the right path.