The first academic journal
was published in 1665.
Prior to that,
research results were mostly disseminated
through personal communication
and handwritten material.
Disseminating research results
through journals
has become an important part
of the academic system.
Over the years, tens of thousands
of academic journals have been started.
Until the advent of digitalization,
publishers and printing houses
were needed primarily for packaging
and distributing the journals.
Eventually, the researchers' need to
disseminate and quality-assure their results
grew into a market.
From the 1960s and onwards,
large publicly-listed companies
began buying up smaller publishers.
Since then, the market has increasingly
become an oligopoly,
dominated by a few large publishers.
The process of digitalization
began at the end of the 1990s.
Academic journals
are now primarily e-resources,
that readers can access by being enrolled
or employed at higher education institutes
that subscribe to these journals.
The prevailing system
for publishing research results
and making them available,
involves researchers
submitting their articles to publishers
who are responsible for editing them
and publishing them in academic journals.
Publishers generally do not pay any
financial compensation to the article authors
or to the researchers
in charge of peer-reviewing the articles.
The publishers have then
marketed access to the journals
to libraries and higher education institutions
through subscriptions.
Simultaneously, with the market's
development into an oligopoly,
and with the digitalization of publication,
the prices for subscriptions
have increased,
with profit margins as high as 40%
in some cases.
Owing to these developments,
many higher education institutions
can no longer afford to pay
the high subscription fees.
Consequently,
researchers in various parts of the world
lack access to the information they need,
and society is unable to benefit
from the knowledge produced.
This is the background to the emergence
of the need for a new system
for publishing research results.