Since the end of the 1990s, a development has been going on
-mot a digitized publishing system for research results.
The development has been driven by the deficiencies with the traditional system-
-For example, subscription prices increased and locked up research results-
-But also through the technical opportunities that the Internet entails.
An important milestone in the development towards open asset-
-We the manifesto  The Budapest Initiative in 2001-
-As as stated during a conference in Budapest.
The manifesto defines open access like this:
The Budapest Initiative  has been followed by several similar manifest-
-If example the Berlin Declaration from 2004:
The main reasons for the development towards open access are:
The need to be able to spread research results free-
-So that more people can access and use the research results in everyday life and work.
Both researchers, decision makers, professionals and the general public.
The high subscription prices in the traditional model for distribution.
From the beginning, open access to scientific publications-
-But nowadays also research data included-
-In the information that should be openly available.
By research data is meant, among other things, results from experiments, measurements-
-Observations, statistics and interview responses.
Thus, openness has come to include the entire science system-
-and the processes that deal with collaboration, communications-
-and spreading research results.
That scientific publications become more openly available-
-The led to the benefit of society.
The UN body UNESCO emphasizes that open access is of fundamental importance-
-To achieve at least ten of seventeen sustainability goals for 2030.
In hospitals and health centers, there is a great need for access to research.
With a subscription system, the cost becomes an obstacle.
There is a hope that open access will be able to change this.
Even business, non-profit organizations, politicians and a number of other actors-
-will benefit from being able to freely take part in research results.