We will go through the search function in Libris cataloging. We will look at the search box,
How to define the search and sorting of the hit list. The search box is included
Wherever you are in the tool. With the shortcut alt + s you come to Search.
You can search directly in the search box. You can also delineate your search in different ways.
As a default, the search is canceled at the instance.
This corresponds to searching for editions or similar.
You can change the boundary to works, agent, concept or all.
Since we have not yet started working with works as our own entities
If you do not get many hits when you search for works.
As a default, the search is also set to free text.
You can then define further here by selecting ISBN, ISSN or Main title.
If you delineate to ISBN, you can search for ISBN with or without a hyphen.
If you search for ISBN as a free text, search without a hyphen.
You can also click Search in the main menu.
Then you come to a view where you can search in Libris or other sources.
It is important to always seek carefully in Libris first to be sure that you do not create duplicates.
If you do not find what you are looking for in Libris, you can move on to other sources.
Here you can search other databases and import an entry.
See the movie "Search in other sources" for more information.
We are testing to do a search in Libris.
I search for the hypnotist of Lars Kepler.
You can delimit with different filters that you see in the left menu.
For example, I choose to delineate on work type text
And on publishing year 2009.
Then we see that the hit list became much shorter. You can remove the filters by clicking the cross.
You can also sort the hit list.
Sorting is set to relevance as a default and one can also choose
Main title, release year or last updated.
I choose to sort on release year (oldest first).
The hit list can also be set to detailed view, as here, or on compact view.
There are more opportunities to make your search more detailed.
Read in the assistance section under the heading Search for more information.