The Catalog Care function means that you can move your library's stock from one item to another.
This can be done, for example, if a duplicate has been created in Libris or if one's stock has ended up wrong when it has been added via Libri's acquisition routine.
I can only move stocks for the one (s) I have permission for.
To see what Sigler I have permission for, I click on my name in the right corner and look at the roller list with Sigler.
I can also go under Settings and look here under active sigel.
Under Settings there are also contact information for Libris customer service if I need rights other than the ones I have.
Under the heading Catalog Care is an instructional text for how to move stocks.
I start by searching the title in Libris.
In order for the items to appear in directory care, I must click on the flag at each post.
I do this either directly in the hit list or by going into each description.
Now the number 2 is visible in directory care and I can click there to move the stock.
Now I will choose the sender and recipient.
I click on Choose the sender and select the mail that I want to move from.
Now I see all Sigler who have stocks on the title.
If I happened to choose the wrong sender, I click on the cross in the corner and choose.
Then I choose the recipient.
I can only choose the entry that I have not already chosen as a sender.
Now I see the Sigler who have stocks on this post.
When I have chosen the recipient, I click on the sigel of my library and then on the "Move stock" button.
When I click on "Moving stock", a pop-up box comes up asking if I want to flag the sender.
Here I can do in different ways.
If it is so that my library is the only thing that has stocks on this post,
That it has been created a duplicate that I will delete, then I can print "no", so that it becomes easier to find the post and remove it, because the flag remains.
If only a stock item is wrong and not a duplicate I can print "yes".
When I have deleted a possible double and am finished and want to clear the flags, I click on my name again and choose "Clean flags".
If it is a duplicate, but it turns out that other libraries also have stocks on it, so that they also have to move their stock before it can be deleted,
Then I can send a CXZ message to them and ask them to move their stock.
Information on how to send and monitors CXZ messages can be found on KB's website under Libris and Breach lists.