Hi, my name is Lisa Olsson Dahlquist
and working as a teacher and researcher
In the Department of AVM and Digital Cultures at Lund University
at the Department of Cultural Sciences.
This recording is part of the research square's digital program at the Book Fair this year.
What I will present today is a research project that I have done
together with my colleague Ola Sundin
On behalf of digitally first with the user in focus
which focuses on algorithm consciousness in the meeting between generations.
Although algorithms today are a very central part of our increasingly connected everyday life
so we still know relatively little about people's experiences, attitudes and conscious actions
in relation to algorithms
and how algorithms affect our digital information flows
The purpose of this project is to develop
an in -depth knowledge of what algorithm consciousness can mean
In the meeting between children and adults
In order to better understand people digital action and thereby create the conditions for
Librarians' digital skills development
within the MIK area
ie the field of media and information skills
This means that
This is research project
which can be put into a larger context of the research that has been conducted by our research group in Lund for many years
that has a focus on just source and search criticism
and search in a digital everyday life
Algorithms
and media and information skills in relation to
public libraries in different ways
At the end of this presentation I will also give you a list
over publications if one is interested in taking part in other research that we have also conducted
But this particular project is based on
What algorithm consciousness can mean from a user perspective
When we talk about it, we see it as an important part of media and information expertise today.
Because we have been interested in that
investigate how children and adults together reason and reflect
About their digital everyday life we have done family interviews.
We have done 14 family interviews
With a total of 40 participants in the families' homes.
Long conversations that have been about their digital everyday life
In the conversations, we have focused on questions such as how the participants experience
that algorithms affect internet use
What does source criticism mean
For different generation, young and older
How to perceive one's information flows in social media
And how to look at the library in relation to media and information expertise
Among other things, we have assumed these issues in the talks.
A shorter summary of the results of the study
The results are presented in relation to the themes that appear in our report
It is clear in the study that Internet use characterizes both the children and the adults
everyday in a variety of ways
from morning to night
Computers and mobile phones are used for work
school, relaxation, news on different occasions during the day
As for the time that Internet use uses
In the study reflecting on in
significantly higher
than the younger participants do.
For several of the adults this is
Something they mean takes too much time
They would like to reduce their internet use and then in particular
when it comes to social media services like Facebook.
You also describe how, for example, the news reading on the Internet takes more time to
than one had thought from the beginning because one becomes
Recommended for new articles
continuously
and it can be hard to stop
Here appears that the algorithms and the various recommendation systems can contribute to
To create a sense of freedom.
They keep users
in the various services.
When it comes to algorithms, many of the participants are
feel that they have hardly knowledge of what algorithms are
But in the conversations, it turned out that you have knowledge of what algorithms do
their consequences
It is about understanding how
one's own internet behavior
affects what information and which ads
that becomes visible in one's flows
Here also a more critical and questioning view of
Internet's commercial business model
Among the adults than among the children.
This more critical view of the
adults are also reflected in the conversations in terms of questions about
integrity and monitoring online.
The adults in the study seems more reluctantly accepting
a lost privacy
While several of the younger ones are more benevolent to, for example, targeted advertising
It emerges
Still, there is a lot of uncertainty about how data tracks are stored
and handled
and that the services and technical infrastructure
lack of transparency
leads to a lot of speculation and guesses
And when it comes to the particular infrastructure, questions about how the Internet is controlled and controlled
Why certain information becomes visible and not another
So it appears that nothing has been discussed to a particularly high extent in the family.
It also becomes clear that it can be very difficult to put words on
And imagine the Internet's invisible information infrastructure and structure.
In many participants in the study, an interest in the questions is aroused
During the course of the conversation
More and easily accessible knowledge is asked for the subject.
In the conversations with the families, it also becomes clear
that there are major differences
between and within the families in how to relate to and reflect on
The information you get in different flows online.
What we call search criticism.
Like how source criticism can be understood.
It is clear that
Source criticism in meaning
What one can and cannot trust is something that is discussed to a much greater extent
than search criticism
that is, why information is presented to us
That way
as it does.
In terms of library
for all participants
Young as adults
is a library
to a large extent associated with that
borrow books
A challenge lies in the mission of public librarians
to educate in digital skills
towards users who are unconscious or
about the library's educational assignment
Or simply uninterested.
The adults in the study that I mentioned earlier call for more
Knowledge about the subject.
And preferably in the form of shorter
lecture activities.
Here we mean that the librarians' educational role as lecturer
could be made visible and extended further
The library can also help
Develop people's imagination
In relation to the invisible digital information infrastructure
that in so many ways affects how we perceive and understand our surroundings today
Based on these results and conclusions, we give the following recommendations
To give continuous space ate
and create conditions for extensive skills development so that libraries
And librarians can rightly claim that they have knowledge of algorithms, digital source criticism
and other effects of the information's
infrastructure that is so central to human life
today
It is not just about technical knowledge
Without a broader ability and critical knowledge
that includes cultural, social and political aspects
We also recommend that public libraries
developed into nodes for MIK issues in the local community
Here, librarians can work more with outward operations
primarily aimed at other workplaces and occupational groups
By conveying expertise to, for example, police, school, leisure activities, sports leaders
healthcare professionals and social services
so can the public library indirectly reach people
which they don't always reach.
But it is a role that must be credible and founded in expertise
It is a challenge to change the image of libraries and librarians
Collected expertise.
A way of working educational
In direct contact with users
may be to put a critical pedagogy into practice and thereby work
both reading promotion and with mik
Here we advocate reflective conversations, for example within the context of
circle business.
In this way, the focus may be to make aware
And critically reflect with each other.
Cultural forms of expression such as fiction
non -fiction or film could help make visible and act as
the basis for conversation about it many times
Invisible information infrastructure.
Finally
do we mean that in order to enable the librarian
to work more with outward-directed MIK operations
But also with this type of reflective conversation in circle business
So also needs educational ability to be included in the continuous skills development.
Both these recommendations and the report
Will soon be published on digitally first website.
But for those who are already interested in that
read and these and related questions
So I have here a list of related publications about searching in a digital everyday life
About search and source criticism at school,
If the invisible information infrastructure and need to make it visible,
algorithms,
And how libraries can work with folk education in a digital contemporary.
With these recommendations
Do I want to say thank you for listening
Feel free to go in and read our report on digitally first website.
Thanks!