Hello! My name is Fatima Klanco Al Mulki. I work at the Royal Library.
I will now show how to edit an imported post with non-Latin alphabet.
The described approach applies to version 1.19 of Libris cataloging and may change.
I have chosen a book that is in Arabic. I have searched for the Arabic translation of August Strindbergs a dream game.
I start by looking at admin metadata and review it.
You do not have to follow that order, it is different how you usually edit your items. My way is to start with admin metadata.
Here I check that the description level is included.
In import, the description level automatically ends up at the minimum level if the system does not recognize the code from the database post is imported from.
I change it to library level.
System technical note. There is already the property so I can duplicate that entity by clicking on these three dots
And manage and then duplicate the entity and replace that text with a note of transliteration schedule that we will use.
Within the Librian collective, we largely use the Library of Congress Romanization schedules when transferring
Text with non-Latin writing for Latin writing.
Exceptions to this are made for church writing. KB/LIBRIS practice is to Slavic and most non-Slavic works
With Cyrillic writing, it must be translit according to ISO 9: 1995.
The libraries that are in particular need it may instead choose to transcribe according to KR76 (Kjellberg)
And if necessary, supplement with AL-LC Romanization Table, Non-Slavic Languages (in Cyrillic Script) for the extra characters that may occur in non-Slavic languages.
Exceptions are made for Mongolian where the extra signs ө, ө are romanized as Swedish island, island and ү, ү as ü, ü.
In addition, we have exceptions for Greek writing.
Works with Greek writing follow two different principles. Old Greek texts and newly texts.
Old Greek (from before 1454) follows transliteration schedule set for scientific libraries in Swedish cataloging rules 1980 (SK).
Nygrecian texts (after 1453) follow transcription schedule stated for Swedish libraries following the library service practice for the public libraries.
You can find more detailed information including links to the various schedules in the Metadatabyrån.
The important thing is that in this field you specify which table you use.
This is how I write that we use the Library of Congress ... so there.
The importing library Sigel ends up at imports automatically in created by and we should not change that.
I see under cataloging rules that it is an RDA post and I will then remember to follow those rules as I continue with the editing.
Had the cataloging rules been others, I would not have had to change them to the RDA even though we primarily catalogize the RDA.
The reason is that there are other libraries in the world that use other rules and we have said that we accept it.
The cataloging language I see here that it is Arabic.
And since it is an imported post I would not have had to change it as long as it is true but
Here I know that the number of pages, for example, will stand in Arabic so to avoid
Transliterate it also I choose to change here to Swedish.
In imported items it says that the library that imports the mail is what has created the post. We do not change it but instead we put in
Upgraded or imported by.
Like this
So we write our library's sigel here.
So, now it's time to insert information about modifications.
You use the plus sign here to the right.
Like this
Add. And then you choose the one at the bottom: Non-Latin characters are available in both original and translated form.
But before I leave admin metadata, I need to add another property. Because I catalog for KB
And it is a translation of a Swedish work, I want it to be included in the Suecana collection,
Thus, the collection of foreign material with Swedish connection that KB preserves.
To do that, I will insert a new property by clicking on the plus sign in the right column and choosing bibliography.
So
And so I continue here.
Create local entity
Although it stands out here, I do not write my library's sigel but write Suec instead.
So the name of the bibliography it should be on.
And now I'm done with the admin meta and switch to the instance.
I start by turning off to have a better overview.
And starts with the instance.
And I start with the description and see that it is true.
Now we check that the ISBN is correct. Publishing method: Monographic resource. It should always be monographic resource because we catalog a monograph.
Media type, carrying type, that's correct. And there we see that they are in English. This means that when we save the mail they will be automatically linked
Right to the Swedish variant.
Now we are at the title and here we see that the title is in the original writing.
According to Libris practice, we will use the original writing. We put the original title as a variant title as follows:
So. And I choose to move the original title to this box.
In addition, because it is about a writing species written from right to left, I check that the direction of writing is correct by the
Right -click and choose the right one. So.
As the main title, we enter the romanized form of the main title.
In this case, because it is about Arabic, we use LC's transliteration schedule.
And when we have translated the main title, it looks like this.
When we look at the origin information, we see that it is non-Llatinous writing.
Since transliteration is primarily to help the user group that is librarians, we need to translite the origin information as well.
Here we write as it says on the title page fixed in transmitted form.
This is how it will look like this.
In imported items, the other title information may be incorrect in the capacity of the origin.
It can be extra difficult if you do not understand the language. A reminder only that you are attentive.
And to remedy it, you would move that information to other title information.
Like this. But that was not the case in my example.
Now we look at the release. We see that primary publication is correct
The country is correct.
We have to transmit a place and then we enter the translite form, and it will be like this.
I cling to the place because it is not in the publication but we know that this particular publisher is from this place.
Agent, ie the publisher, we also translabs.
During the publishing tasks, the year may be repeated very many times, which may seem confusing,
But it is because the data is retrieved from different fields in the Marc21 format.
More information about this can be found in the help texts.
Our publishing details are correct so we don't change it.
We check the number of page and see that it is correct, but standing in Arabic, and we have changed
The cataloging language in admin metadata for Swedish so we write here in Swedish.
We see that the manifestation is part of a series. So we put the right information here too.
For more information about serial membership, read in the help texts.
Now we are done with the instance and move on to the instance of works.
You can click the Home button to get at the top.
Now we go here.
The title in instance of works should be the preferred title for the work and since this is a translation it should be the original title
And we must therefore check that it is in line with Swedish practice.
We see that it is not correct. It should be a dream game.
And there is also no filing value.
It should be 4.
Now it follows translation of.
And this says that this is a translation from a Swedish original.
Then follows participation and function and we continue to check if there is an authorized and linked name form for the participating agents.
And I know here that it says August Strindberg so I check that there is a
Authorized mail, and it does, so I link to it instead of the Arabic form.
Function is in Arabic and I change ... it will not be linked to it but I have to choose
I remove it and convert to writers.
Here we have the translator. The second participation.
Now we're going to make the translator and the easiest for me in this case is to make a new participation
Because I have to translite his information and so I choose a person.
And then I pick his name from here in translated form and write down ...
So.
And the function is translator.
In this case, an authorized name form is missing and I choose not to "create and link entity"
Because it would create an entity where the content does not follow the instructions for authorized name form.
Instead, I do this way.
And links the right function.
Then follows a new language assignment that tells us that this is a book in Arabic.
And then we get the genre/form part.
Here we will add different codes as the literary genre, and genre/form terms.
And here I know we should choose drama.
And we should pay attention to lists. That we choose the right one.
I see here that we lack the subject so I will develop that property by clicking on ... here.
So there.
As for subject words, if they had already existed, we would have left them.
But here I produce Swedish subject words according to the Swedish original.
To get only Swedish subject words, I end my search with SAO.
And then I get fewer hits and partly only those who are SAO meetings.
And here I have content type and it is correct, too.
And it is in English so it will be linked to Swedish when we save the post.
Now we are done with the editing and can click Create Post after a final check, here.
It remains to be posted on the mail and to see how to see the movie about stock registration.