There is an old agricultural property outside Piteå, which is said to affect the family that lives there so much that they sometimes scream out loud in frustration that it should stop.
It is said that a man has hanged himself in the barn, in one of the beams. We are trying to find out who this man is.
Those who live here experience enormous discomfort when they try to stay in the barn.
And what's in there wants you to leave quickly.
The family reports seeing figures inside and outside the houses, watching them. And the feeling inside the dilapidated house is that it is children.
A boy and a girl.
Outside the house there is a man standing by the house knot watching them.
The boy in the family, whose room is on the ground floor closest to the kitchen, is talking to someone they can't see.
On this land there used to be an old Norrbotten farm, which unfortunately burned down.
And the flames took a woman and her child with them who never made it out.
Perhaps it is these unsavory spirits that still haunt the houses.
Then we made our way here in Piteå, to this agricultural property. Actually, there are three properties, it's this one, then the one that's a little more run down, and then we also have the barn.
Much to investigate.
There are specific things that happen, we must focus on them. We will see if we can make these phenomena happen, but we don't know.
It can happen now, it can happen anytime. But we have had little things that have happened before we started here.
I think we caught a shadow even, on the surveillance. And that got us all jumping.
It was very interesting to see that.
In fact, we have not previously been able to document that, not in this way.
We've seen it before, on the Safari investigation, but then it didn't record it. But now we had on the recording luckily.
This sequence shows what it looks like when the camera switches to Nightvision as we usually see.
So it was very, very special.
Absolutley. And I think like this, now there is quite a lot to investigate, many rooms. Then there are specific phenomena they say are happening here, so I think we should try to focus on the hot spots we have.
Shall we start in the kitchen?
I think we should start in the kitchen, but we should also focus on a special room. Where a little guy gets things to himself, he talks to something before he goes to bed.
And he also receives information, which is not so positive.
No.
So we're going to go in and try to address this, but they also think it's a little girl walking in, walking around..
but we'll see. Maybe it's something trying to show itself as a little girl. We'll check, I think we'll start with that room.
We bring some tools with us. I think if it's a younger energy, I think we put RemTeddy in there. See if it can push it down, you will run communication.
I think he receives a lot of messages that are not very pleasant. In case it wants to communicate with us, what is now here.
Exactly and it's only right through this door. It must be horrible as a parent to lie there and hear him talk about all sorts of things in there.
In the kitchen where we are now, we have a surveillance camera too, behind me. And here we have this box, above all, pulled out and these knives change position.
And ends up inside another cabinet. It's absolutely incredible.
If we can catch it, it will be absolutely wonderful. The Holy Grail of them all.
But as I said we have a lot of instruments, all the equipment is here so we can always go and get more.
It's not huge. We're going to pick up some instruments, we have to put on jackets, it's cold out there and cold inside the other house. Plus in the barn.
But right now we are in the heat. We go in here, I'm thinking if we should have a tool running. If you start it there and immediately open the door, we will see what is said.
I also think the PDA, Paranormal Direct Answer. It works if something comes to the right or to the left, so it lights up red or green.
Exactly. We prepare the whole room and see what happens.
Shit that scared me.
What?
When I look directly to the right...
Well, it looks like someone was standing there.
Yes, I thought there was someone standing there.
As if you hung a gallows over someone.
Like watching one of the worst horror movies, you only see a blanket and it looks like a human underneath.
As I said here he is sleeping, he hears a lot of stuff and he talks back to it.
We start with PRS, both static and rem function.
I wouldn't have done that.
What does it say?
I wouldn't have put it there.
Okay.
I will put more things here that you can touch and push away. Do you recognize this teddy bear?
If you want to push it away, do so.
Just push it.
Include.
Are you included in this family? Is that what you feel?
I have shivers behind...
I was just going to say, I have shivers behind here...
You are not included in this family. I don't know who you are..
you don't say positive things.
I'm going to put another thing here that you can..
put your hand against or pass by.
Then you will be able to reply with different colors to us.
Allows.
It's almost like it gives us...
You decide.
What shivers! It comes in waves.
It comes from behind.
Do you usually talk to the boy who usually sleeps here?
If you do, go to this blue pulsing light that is in front of us on the bed.
Is it the little girl who usually says things to him who is here?
I can say, we have surveillance now in most buildings, if something happens, Lennie will call us straight away.
He sits in the bus and watches the surveillance. If we get a name out, he will see if he can relate the name to this farm.
That way we might get a better understanding of what it is or who it is.
We mustn't forget, there was a Norrbotten farm which was roughly where the barn is and it burned down.
It is said that a woman and two children were on fire inside.
Right. And that's what we're thinking about, if this girl has gotten into this building, which is also affecting this boy.
We have to test everything here now. We haven't the faintest idea what we're dealing with here.
It could also be something very negative that has gotten in here. These shivers that come, they are interesting.
It comes in waves.
Love.
Because now I don't feel it, it kind of comes in spurts.
I'll try to go into the corner here I think.
I was the one who influenced it.
Now I would like you to come in here and show how strong you are.
Talk to us too.
Feel free to open a door in here or push something.
Can we get the name of whoever is here?
What are you?
Now there was a shiver again.
Here´s nothing now.
It felt here, right here.
Can we get a name?
Are those initials?
It's hard to say...
We have other things going on here. We have a curtain down in the basement for the shower, where they hear this little girl laughing and hitting the curtain.
We're going to test that theory and be one on the inside of the curtain and then some stand outside and then we're going to see if the little girl can get in there.
It's going to be one hell of a hum down there, because it has a... what's it called? Dehumidifier.
And we can't turn them off, they don't want to.
I'm going to try to get down on my knees here and see if we get anything, if it's the little girl that's here.
My name is Tony, this is Niclas and Johan is the one filming here.
We only want to talk to you who are here.
We mean no harm, we want to know why you're staying. If it is a girl who is here.
Did you die in this fire outside?
By the barn, this old farm. Together with your sibling and your mother.
I found a small teacup here.
I'll put this next to the teddy bear and you can touch it if you want.
Are you under the bed?
What does it mean?
No clue.
Play first...
Okay, do you want to play with us here?
If I stick this under, can you hold my hand?
You can touch me.
Wait, that was....
Do you have a lamp here?
No I do not have it.
Either it's some hair or something..
I got touch on my fingers. Shit...
What the hell is this?
Here I feel something.
Wait, I'll get an instrument.
I have a perfect instrument for that. Which can take static fields, if that's what Tony got. We take the handheld parascope to it
Either it's a static field or it's some kind of cobweb.
You can get around here Johan.
Are you down here? Where!
Where! It is a static field.
Are you under the bed now?
I felt your hand or something. Damn!
I'll try a spirit box and see if we can get her voice through.
It was as if something caressed my fingers here.
What did it say?
Time.
Did you just hear this?
Here.
It sounded like.. well it might have been.
Difficult.
"Working now"
Working now.
Are we going to shut this down for that long? Or should we have both running?
Run both.
The girl who is here can you say your name? Thanks! You are here.
There.
It's both ways here, both red and green
It was such a light touch over the fingers several times like this, back and forth. Think of a child's hand that with the fingertips runs over the fingers like this.
Never felt like that.
Are you still there?
You can do it one more time if you want.
You don't have to be afraid of us.
But still cool that this showed static, what I felt.
That was...
Put that by the bed and we'll see.
Is it on?
No, I've turned it off.
I put it here.
Now we have lots of tools here that can take different fields.
So if you're in here now, can you come and sit here on the bed please?
Get up from under the bed. You don't have to be afraid.
I run spiritbox again.
This was the sickest thing, it still feels like she's touching my hand.
Was it you who took Tony's hand?
*Breathe*
Someone breathing just..
"Beware"
Did it say beware or behind you? But now it's a man who's in here.
*Laughs*
Did you hear it?
"One"
"Girl"
A girl.
Now the shivers came again.
"Here now"
A woman.
It was like someone grabbed my hamstring when I'm standing with my foot on the bed here.
Or get pains.
Are you touching Tony now?
"We're waiting"
A woman, I don't know what she said.
"Go now"
It was dark, like it said Go.
Is it really a little girl here? Then I want the little girl to come in here now.
The man who took his own life..
out in the barn...
are you still here?
"He says..."
"Get up"
It sounded like Get up. Or Up.
"Exit"
Turn it off. This man, he is seen inside the house, but he also stands outside and just looks at them. He is wearing a sloka hat.
Right. And a coat. And boots. So he just stands still.
They have even yelled at him, what do you want?! And then he just walks away.
That was sick, that was an awesome feeling.
It's cool, while you get the touch, you get a static field that pops up under there.
It was like I was walking into it, but it kept wandering along my fingers.
You get to play with this teddy bear or with that coffee pot over there.
Throw them down if you want.
I think we put our PMA there as well. Paranormal Motion Alert. I will turn on a switch here and it will then lie and be activated
and it will sound. If I run this now, it will be like this.
And it continues.
Until we turn it off. Maybe we will hear it too.
You can also have it just on the move.
That it moves. So I put it on the bed in case something pushes it or sits on the bed.
So if you want you can sit there in bed. Then we will hear it.
Shall we go down to the basement? Or should we go up to this room where the wardrobe is said to open?
We'll go down to the basement first, I think.
Here we have where the family usually showers and this is where they belong, I'll show you, you know when it gets hot and cold the drapes usually go in and out, but when they stand in there they get this.
That someone hits. Really powerful. So there are no small movements and they think that it is the girl who runs here, that she makes them the phenomena.
Now we have the camera there so if something like that were to happen, it would be caught there.
I'm thinking if I put this down inside?
Can you come in here? You who usually hit here. On this curtain, if it's the little girl or whoever it is that's usually here fooling around and hitting the curtain.
Find.
Are you standing behind the curtain or can you come in here and turn on the curtain?
Actually, maybe someone should stand inside, just to illustrate that someone is behind. Are you going to try standing in there?
So it's like you're standing in the shower.
Play, I got now. Yes we are playing with you here.
I got Coming.
Yes come. I'm standing here. But hit the curtain first.
Now I'm standing here wasting water, if it's the man who doesn't like that you waste water.
Hit that curtain, if you're in here. You have done it several times before to those who live here.
Good, hit this now.
Niclas is in there, make sure he gets out.
We will check if we get any light phenomenon.
Time to pray, it says.
What do you want? Steam like you are talking about now, does it get hot in there Niclas?
Yes.
We're going to test something Nicke, Johan and I back out so you can stand there by yourself for a little while.
We back out, then we have that camera running.
Can you come and close this curtain now while I'm standing here?
Take all the power you can. Get the water turned off here, hit the curtain.
Take all the strength you have and pull the curtain now.
All power. In the drapery. Now.
Now we'll see if that's true because he's in there by himself now. If this girl or boy wants to hit the curtain.
Maybe it didn't want to when we were there. But we have a camera running, so it hits, it has to hit from the outside and in towards Niclas.
All power in the drapery, now.
The drapery moves but Niclas doesn't notice it, and that the surveillance camera is flashing.
Do you feel something there?
No.
Nothing?
Unfortunately, nothing came.
Now you have showered in the same way as the family. But we put the curtain back as it is, it rolls here all the time, so if something happens, we catch it with the camera.
Right. Now I've got the steam up so it got very hot in there. Then we'll see if it moves in any way.
We go up to the living room.
Boys?
Yes?
We just lost the kitchen camera.
Kitchen camera?
We are just on our way up.
Let me know when it comes back.
It's already back, it was gone for about thirty seconds.
Okay.
Wondering if something happened. We have to check, we have stuff on the bed.
Yes exactly.
Now the shivers came once more.
Shall we check the bed first then?
Everything looks normal but it smells strange in here.
There is a scent here..
Does it smell freshly baked?
Right?
It smells freshly baked.
We'll leave it at that, the alarm doesn't seem to have gone off on the bed either.
Shall we go out to the living room? There is the rocking horse that is said to move.
I'm bringing spirit vibes, I'll put it by the rocking horse. And also our PDA, Paranormal Direct Answers.
Green or red, answers questions.
I replace Polterscript and run Ovilus in there.
Here on the right...
This is where it says.
The rocking horse.
I put it up here, in case it moves then this will take the movements.
You see, if I stomp. And if this one starts rocking, hopefully it will fall off.
So if we have the girl or the boy here, who usually plays with this rocking horse, who has made it rock before, could you do it now?
I'm putting this down too.
I back off a bit.
Do we have someone with us in this room?
I've got the spirit box ready so I'll just have a little session here.
Can you walk up to this rocking horse?
"Oh no"
No, a man.
The man who is here, is it you who went out into the barn and took your life?
"Seriously ill"
Seriously ill.
Did you find out you were seriously ill and then you went out into the barn...
and took your life?
Is it you that people usually see standing outside in the yard, in windows and just about everywhere?
Did it say Eriksson or Fredriksson?
After all, we brought in an object from the other house, that lamp, and put it on the table.
That's when the family says even more things start to happen.
Don't you love that this lamp is there?
"Go now"
Go now.
It smells freshly baked all the time in here now.
Who makes this building smell so good?
Say your name, you who make it smell so good.
"People live here"
This is also interesting, I mean we have these phenomena happening and right now it feels like we are talking to quite a few people around here.
But I don't know, what we try to focus on when we are here is what he experiences. Is it really a little girl or is it something else that has been generated from something else entirely?
And we focus a lot on these phenomena, because they are the ones that stand out. It's the rocking horse, the bedroom there, the shower down there and we have another bedroom up there where a wardrobe door usually opens.
And objects are also moved there. These are caps that end up in completely different places.
I'll try Ovilus here and we'll see.
Anyone here? Angry I just got up..
Are you angry because we are here? Don't like us?
Can you make this rocking horse rock once for us?
You've made it rock several times before. When the family has been sitting here.
What I feel now with hot spots, it's just his room. There are shivers, everything is very focused in his room.
Shall we go up? We leave the horse alone, it is also in front of the camera. Shall we go up a floor? And feel what it's like up there with this closet door that opens.
Yes.
We try it. Should we let the spirit vibes stay?
Let´s leave it.
Okay, getting interesting now, I got.
It is this wardrobe that is said to open and close.
And these caps tend to move and change position.
Anyone up here who can open this closet?
Even these mirrors have fallen over.
Yes exactly.
I'm starting this one too.
That thing, I don't know what it was, it was something black, small like... I don't know if it was your shadow, can you do it once for Niclas?
Is that it?
Yes, that might have been the one I saw.
It could have been me.
Yes, it can be.
What Tony sees is a light phenomenon passing in front of him that the surveillance camera captures.
If you're in there, take all the strength you can and just push the door open for us, please.
Take all our energy, we who are in here. Drain the camera battery, take everything from all the tech to be able to open this door.
Could you do that for us?
If it's the little girl that's here, doing these things, would you like to play with us and open the closet and we'll play hide and seek with you and hide, and you can look.
I try to listen while you talk, to the whole house. We hear drops, something hitting out here, you hear a lot.
But it's recurring, it's the same thing all the time. So it's nothing paranormal.
No.
Can you move a cap hanging here on the wall?
Evp is recorded.
"Jugs"
It's not the same discomfort here either. That's his room down there, so far, right?
If you want to go for the instruments and what we feel, it's down there. But then if it moves throughout the house, the camera will catch it, if these phenomena occur.
But right in there, it seems like it's centered. I have a theory about the little energy that is there, uses him incredibly.
He sure has a lot of energy. So that's why it's in that room.
That he becomes like the battery for it.
I mean, doesn't it calm down, you have to do something completely different.
I'm going to put a PMB against this door.
So if you want you can go by here and it will play a tune for you. Or open the wardrobe there.
So we let that camera work. Lennie says it now too.
That's what gets interesting, there are so many phenomena in different places here now and I find them so fascinating, you want to document them.
If we can find a logical explanation for them that's even better, we've tried everything here during the day, but nothing. Nothing logical, that one has been closed since we closed it.
Okay, we're going down.
As I said before, in these stairs you can hear them running too. People running up and down at night.
It crunches a little when you walk, so you won't miss this.
No, exactly.
Here, it's a completely different feeling when you come down.
I agree.
You are drawn to that room.
Shall we go back in and test?
I'm testing Ghostbox in there.
I have Ovilus with me, which works in parallel. So we'll see.
Now we are back here again.
It was under the bed earlier that we found it.
Immediately! It was under the bed before.
Right when you said it!
And shivering. Good.
Can you get up and sit on the bed?
If it's a little girl, you don't have to be afraid of us. We're not going to hurt you or anything. You can just come up, sit on the bed, and you and I can talk.
I start Ghostbox here.
Ovilus can lie here.
Who are you?
Ghostbox works like Spiritbox, it's only digital.
The little girl that is under the bed, can you come up and sit.....
"Angry"
Did it say ouch?
I don't know if it said that or what it said.
So the little girl that's under the bed, come up to us here.
Do you see the teddy bear there?
See that teapot I set for you?
That noise, I put it here.
Can you tell us your name?
Look look!
Good! Go near it.
It glows on both.
Sit next to it and talk. So maybe we'll hear your voice.
Like it went.
Yeah, like it couldn't quite take it, did you see? It went away.
Strange, I usually don't get anything, but in my head all the time, it's a girl's name.
Which has been going on now for probably ten minutes. Now I have to say, Lisa, Lisa, Lisa...
Who just goes round, round, round. We haven't gotten through Lisa, have we?
No.
Lisa, if that's your name....
can you touch anything that's on the bed?
Shall we leave this?
I'll bring this.
We leave the Teddy Bear and that because hopefully the camera catches it. And the alarm will go off and it will stay on until we get back in that case
Shall we go out to the building behind? Let's see if we can see this man. And there are lots of other things in the windows there.
Yes exactly. And Lennie knows if things happen, if PMB starts playing or something else.
But it's cold outside, so we have to wear our jackets.
And then we go out. We are leaving, we have a lot of stuff in our pockets. We also bring the sls camera, the thermal camera. We will look at everything, the man who hanged himself in the barn
but we will also look at where he has been seen. Around here, so we'll see if we can get any mapping.
The instruments are still running here. Lennie has full control of it, so he shouts, Johan you have a walkie talkie, so we will hear it.
We run both sls camera and thermal camera at the same time.
And it is in this house where they see people standing in here.
Anyone here?
It's interesting, a candlestick is on.
Should I turn it off?
Do it.
Do we have anyone in here? Who usually stand by these windows and look out.
He has been seen standing here. And look straight at the person when they enter.
If you stand there Niclas, I'll see if I can get a mapping. See if we can get him with you.
You who usually stand here, this man.....
Can you come in here?
Probably you who built this house.
Stand with Niclas there.
The voice that Johan heard was not caught by the camera.
How disgusting it was, I heard a woman's voice.
What did it say?
A woman's voice, I didn't hear what it said. I heard a woman's voice in the headphones.
Only as a woman's voice I heard it was.
Is there a woman here?
As Johan just heard.
Can you side with Niclas in that case?
What degrees do you have?
I have zero degrees inside the building here.
That woman who was heard just now...
can you make a loud noise in this building where you please?
Where are you now?
I don't see any heat or cold or anything.
Wait, there! Now something appeared.
On that hand there, now it disappeared.
You hit it, but it was a little lower, like a child Niclas.
Okay, but then I bring up communication.
Did you get that?
Oh yes.
Good!
There was a shudder now as you say it, good.
Can you come back again? You don't have to be afraid of us.
What's your name?
Did you hear what it said?
Why do you want to hush us?
Are we talking too loud in here?
Then I raise this to max.
If you hear this noise...
then come and hush us one more time.
"Go!"
Go!!
Oh! Now it is, stand there!
A small child that is under your arm, touching your hand like.
Good! Use this..
It disappeared again.
"My spot/my place"
We are standing, or something..
How angry he sounded.
I want these kids here...
Now it's back! Stuck on the other side...
Yes, there! Behind your back now.
But that doesn't look like a child, it looks like something is climbing your back now.
Climb up! Take off my cap, knock off my cap, pull on my jacket.
"Naughty"
Naughty.
Cool, there's a chill up your back.
Yes, it wanders up further and further after down back. The hands touch your hand there.
It touches your hand there Niclas.
It stood up, it squatted huh?
Yes, it was squatting, now it's standing up.
*Thump in the building*
Oops, what a bang somewhere.
If it's you we see now...
the little child who is in the other house.....
do something. Pull my jacket.
It just stands behind you, it does nothing. It hits your leg or your hand a little.
And your knee.
There was another one..
I have to raise my hand..
Now it goes down, what the hell is it doing? Look...
Nicke, it's on the floor.
You see, it laid down and crawls along the floor. But now it's someone else who says...
"Hello"
It was a child.
Hey, we hear you.
Is your name Lisa?
Another one, though it's there now, on that side. It stands up on the bench. It also looks like a small child.
There are two kids here.
Are the children here now, you who passed away out here?
Do you see Johan?
Yes, I have full control.
One sitting on the floor, one standing on the bench behind you Niclas.
"Mother is coming"
Mother is coming.
"Yes!"
I thought there was a black shadow behind you Johan.
I have a light inlet there, it was checked out all of a sudden and it's not you.
Mom is coming, okay if mom is here come in here too and talk to us.
Sick. One that is still sitting and one that is there. And both are small.
Can we get your name? What's your name?
Can you stand up?
What happens if I go out of the picture? Will they remain?
Should I try?
Yes.
Yes, try exiting.
Yes, it remains. It's sitting down there on the bench. Come and see for yourself.
Sitting leaning...
Now I don´t know what the hell is going on...
That's not...
Now something happened. It crawls after...
Gone.
I go there again.
You who were here..
Go down towards the bench there. There.
Now is the time for you to show yourself to us.
We would love to see you. If it is this man who is here now...
"Yes!"
Although there were two people who said it at the same time.
I'm shivering like hell here.
Do you talk to a boy in the other house?
Now! One more. On the other side.
"Is there something wrong with us?"
The first sounded like Down.
Disappeared.
So, jump down.
Wow sick.
Is the man here? Which has been seen.
Go into that room too and we'll have a look.
Wait!
Bert.
A name.
"Stand there!"
Bert, someone said.
Is it the man who took his life in the barn?
Is that you that people usually see out here?
I would like to try something Tony. I'm closing this..
I'd like to try standing where that barn burned down. On the ground out there. See if anything pops up next to me there.
Shall we test it before we go into the barn? But it's interesting, we have two energies moving here.
They come through pretty well. But there are still too many questions. But it's like, there are still two children and the story is there. It's not far, we can just go there before entering the barn.
Lets go out.
So if it's you who passed away out there, come with us.
As you can see, we are standing right outside the bus, what you hear now is our heater for the bus. But we've got a good bit to go...
Damn, was anyone standing there?
Aim the kinect there.
Someone was standing on the balcony there.
On the balcony?
Yes. It was a full shadow of a human. Stand still there, look here...
So that was sick! Now I understand what they mean.
Where did you see it?
Like this.
Who stood there? Where! Wait, damn I got it...
Here was an old man looking at us.
Right where you were, someone was standing. It disappeared just as quickly.
I understand now. What I saw was just black, this posture, you're standing with your arms at your sides.
Just stood and watched?
Just stood there. I thought now someone has come here.
Look there.
Can you come back, the man who usually stands here?
I just saw you. Now I understand what they are talking about here.
We have experienced this many, many times when we do this. That you see it, you get it confirmed afterwards, but we never get it on film.
But now I think we actually got it. The sick thing is that you say we're going here and you stand, then it takes two seconds and then it just disappears.
When I stand there, I become like this, the owners are back.
Well, is that what you thought?
Yes, that's what I thought.
Was it that clear?
Yes, imagine a black shape that just stands and looks at us.
You didn't see if it was a man or a woman?
No, black guise. But precisely the posture, with the arms by the sides. just stands like this.
But this is what they have been talking about, they have said that they see this man, he is standing here in the yard. He looks around the corners, he is here in the house, he is in the window, he is everywhere here.
And now I understand what they are talking about. He was so clear over there.
So sick.
But it's cool that sls took it afterwards.
Show yourself out here! And it is said that this Norrbotten farm was located here next to the barn.
I start and scan.
These children, if you are with us now...
come here and talk to us.
I don't know what it said there.
If you can hear me now..
then come here and talk to me now.
"Coming"
This was the man.
This man that is here, that we just saw, can you come here and stand next to me?
Stand next to me here now.
If you stand there, we will see you too.
We stand outside in the yard and try to get in touch with the Ghostbox, while this is happening in the kitchen.
What we can see is that one of the hooks is pushed down, and that cables move in the bags, we mark with arrows where you should look.
The cover is then pushed back.
Okay, they won't get through here either. Shall we go to the barn and try, see if we can get in touch with them this man, maybe can see him too.
The energy memory of him if nothing else.
It is said that he has hanged himself here, from one of the beams. We aim the sls camera and see if we see anything.
The man who unfortunately chose to end his life here, are you still here?
Up there...
It's up there, on the right.
Where? That way?
On the contrary, yes, exactly.
Can you come back again?
Just for a brief second I saw.
If you took your life in here, can you show me which place?
Where was it?
I just got a quick one. I'll have a look between the caravans here.
Anyone hiding down here?
You are welcome to show yourself if you are here.
Throw something.
Did you see it?
Where! No..
Are you hiding behind here?
What is here, it appears only briefly. One second, then up on the wall, then gone.
I go on this site too. Are you here?
I start communication here behind.
Nothing.
This man, can we get your name? Is your name Bert?
Hermansson in the last name, is that correct?
"Not really"
Not really. Maybe I was wrong then.
We heard from previous owners that it might have been, or I may have confused it.
I get no mapping here, only on you, no one else.
Okay.
Can you make a bang somewhere so we know where you are.
Knock.
There was something here..
Was it at the caravan or?
Niclas, shall we try entering the main house again? And then we go to the room, with the kinect. There isn't much battery left on it.
We'll see if we get any mapping on it.
Everything shines here.
No alarm has been triggered.
We are back here again.
Are you still under the bed?
There is Niclas.
You who usually talk to that boy, who has his bedroom here..
could you show yourself to us just once?
A little time.
No mapping on the sls camera here.
I'll try once under the bed here.
Nothing.
We wait for Johan while he takes off his jacket before we continue, then this happens.
Damn, now he was there I think. Damn he was behind the car.
Huh?
Yes, hell!
You see a lot Niclas.
Damn I want to see this damn old man too.
But that's because I'm looking around, I'm looking out all the time. Now there was a black figure behind the car.
While we are fixing and taking off jackets, I look out at the same place, but now he is standing behind the car.
The people who live here have two cars and they left one behind. And now he was standing behind the car. Unfortunately, we don't have surveillance out here, I'm the one who sees it.
Now when Johan takes off his jacket so we can be back inside.
It's quite interesting, I don't know why he appears to me. It's like you said, you also want to see and I understand that.
But I'm a person who watches all the time, I might seem nonchalant, but I work on everything.
I let my body feel, but here I just turn my head, I see him standing there...
The same dark figure, straight out here.
So I think it's cool, he walks around here, but he doesn't come in here it seems. But what we have focused on all evening is more this with the child
and it seems that there are still children here.
Yes, everything the owners say here. There's two kids, we've got a woman through and you see this man out there in the yard walking around.
We do not know if it is the same man who has hanged himself. Or if it's two different men.
Because it's one that has a slightly more aggressive tone as well.
You also have to think that it's their land and we're trying to get a little more justice for those who live here.
What it is that can affect him. Because they also give him rather negative thoughts.
So it's very difficult for us, I can't put my finger on why that energy does that.
But I think we'll test a little more, we'll put out a pyramid that we have. The Pyramid of Truth. I'll put it in there and we won't be in the room.
We will stand here somewhere. And this one will then shoot out rays on each side. Which detects if something breaks it, then it will indicate with green or red.
And then that beep comes and has its own life in there.
Then I'll wait out here then.
As you can see, it will be green and red.
Two beeps.
So it will be on the bed here now, about this girl or whatever. So Johan will point the camera between us here now.
Now we have placed it here and it senses if there is any movement next to it.
So if the little girl is in there by the bed. We're not in there with you now, so you can come forward.
You can touch the flashing thing on the bed, it's nothing dangerous.
You can make it glow green if it's Yes and if it's red, it can be No.
Like I said, it's not dangerous, you can touch it as much as you want.
Do you know what we do?
We have a car that runs on static. If you take it and place it under the bed, see if it can roll out to us.
If she can get it out to us.
We test it.
We will put more toys for you there.
Then we have to consider that static fields are required for this car to start.
We will not be in the room ourselves. Tony will put it under the bed.
I put it where I had...
Now Tony passed by as you can see.
I put it here, where we had the static field.
Now it's under the bed. You can play with it if you want.
It was Tony again who walked by, so you can see how sensitive it is. It takes right away, so that's not why we're in the room.
So now we have posted a toy car for you too. You who are under the bed...
There were shivers when you came out.
Yes?
Good!
You don't need to be afraid of anything like I said.
Do you want to play with us? Play with this car that is under the bed and drive it out to us.
Play with it!
Play with that car.
Now we have addressed this with friendly voices, as if it were a child.
Shall we try something else then?
Try a little more like, that it's not a child.
You who are under the bed in this room, who are affecting the person who is in that bed..
can you make a sound from inside?
The negative that is in that room..
There it comes!
The negatives...
It pulled over the threshold and all.
That was unpleasant, the negative!
You made the car go out. The negativity that's in there, that's affecting this boy sleeping there...
now I'm talking to you.
There is no little girl in there.
It's something else.
Are you afraid of us?
If you are afraid of us, I will come in to you now.
Can you throw something at us in here?
You got the bus to leave.
It was sick when you said the negative. When you talked about it being something else.
We tried to address it as if it were a child, but it wouldn't listen.
The thing that's in here with me now, that made this bus go out..
can you close this door? Lock me in here with you.
Do you have the strength to slam this door shut?
Niclas hears a voice.
It sounds like a woman saying "Niclas"
There are shivers in here.
It sounded like someone said something...
Yeah, push me or push someone in here.
Push the door, push the bus.
The bus tries to drive again.
What was that?
That's it!
It´s that one..
I said push the bus.
It tries to push the bus.
There was a voice before Tony, out here.
Yes?
I heard that one too.
It lies there beating.
It wants to push it away.
We're not getting out of here...
until you say your name.
Who are you?
It starts vibrating more Tony, the bus.
Does it?
I put a PRS down on the floor next to it.
It could be that PMB starts up there too.
A bright light is caught by the surveillance in the room where the PMB is standing.
Show yourself as a mist here.
Play the melody up in the other room.
If you are there by the wardrobe.
I'm standing here thinking about something that feels quite macabre...
when we got here earlier today..
this door was closed. No one in there.
What's also on this door, it's a hasp.
Huh?
Top left.
Is it so negative in there that they even lock this door sometimes?
Shutting it in.
Do you understand?
It's pretty sick.
It's the bus.
It picked up speed when you talked about the hasp.
So those in the family sometimes choose to close and hasp. Maybe they forgot to tell you that this door...
What the hell was that?
It was the second latch on the bag to be lowered during the evening.
Something moved.
Something moved in the drawers here.
Or if there was any cover.
It was like someone hit something.
Is that you who did that?
So close one of the lids here. Unless you like that we're getting closer to the truth here...
that the family even tends to lock you up.
It sounds like the car is about to pop popcorn.
It answers when you talk.
Yes, it just gets more and more every time we mention it.
What's in there that makes them even have to bolt the door?
I haven't even thought about that.
No, I saw it now as I stand here thinking about what they have in there. That it is so...
I am the voice.
Who are you?
It is the voice, he hears the voice. Who says things to him.
Yes, but who is it?
Who are you?
Look. It just vibrates, the bus.
Guess, a slightly nonchalant answer.
I believe you are a dark energy that has been generated in this place, by something very, very negative.
I even think you told this man to go out in the barn and hang himself.
Am I right there?
And then it increases.
It vibrates even more.
And you try to act like you're a little kid.
So when the boy will be able to talk to you..
But we will tell those who live here, that what the boy is talking to, is not a little girl. So he should stop talking to you.
It just faded, the bus too.
Okay. If you want to do something big and strong, do it now.
Because you are not the voice of this house any more.
If you have that kind of strength...
I'll point one thing out here. If you can manifest without fear of me, then come in here.
Walk past this and make it blink, then I know you're out in the hall listening to everything I'm saying right now.
So if something goes past this pyramid, also a prototype that we're testing right now, if something breaks this beam, you see...
how it starts to light up. That there is something with density that moves.
What are you?
You can scratch us as much as you want.
But it will not affect what I will say to those who live here.
Then you might as well leave this place.
Crawling back to where you came from.
Sick, it feels like someone ran a finger...
It feels like someone ran a finger on the back of my neck.
I'll see if there are high emfs in here.
I stand behind you here Niclas.
Even if you say such words, you don't scare me.
It takes much, much more than that. Now this one is coming at you then.
Because I think you're hiding here, you don't dare go out of this room.
Throw the teddy down there then.
Now Niclas is there, lock him up.
Did you hear?
It increases.
I won't run..
It sounded like it made a noise.
Here behind.
1.3..
05..
Even higher.
Here it's louder, right where the sound came from.
05 down here.
And this is also a theory within the paranormal, that the electromagnetic field rises...
when the energies, or the entity wants to do something. Or wants to manifest.
Is there anything else you want to do before we leave?
Run upstairs, they've heard footsteps up there.
Knock on the walls.
Can you knock like this?
Think like this, from everything that happens here, we got something very, very good. We will tell the family that it is not a little girl. We have come to that conclusion.
And I think the man that we see here, he goes around protecting them.
That he stays on the outside..
He doesn't go in here because there is something negative here. But there is, as I said, a hasp on the door, you understand that it is something that they do not want to let out of there.
It may be that this door is about to slam because something wants to get out of here.
It's an interesting theory.
But we tell them. Then they find out what we have come up with.
Clearly.
Some investigations, nothing happens. And with some, everything happens.
The investigation in the north perhaps surprises us even more when we start analyzing the material than when we were there.
The family in the house talks about their experiences early on and we can now say in retrospect that we managed to document a lot of what the family experiences.
Early in the investigation, we manage to capture the energy that the family senses down at the shower. Which creates a shadow in our surveillance camera.
There was something special in one of the children's bedrooms down by the kitchen, where Tony senses a static field that our equipment also detected under the bed.
Is this the dark energy the son senses in his bedroom? Which also causes a bus that senses static fields to leave the bed.
Is the man Niclas saw the man who hanged himself in the barn? And is he also the one talking to the child in the bedroom?
Perhaps the most interesting phenomenon that happens, which we have never been able to document before, is a poltergeist phenomenon.
The energy has enough power to push down the latches on our equipment bags. Not just once, but twice. As well as moving the wiring upwards in bags.
This means that in retrospect we are now completely taken by what we actually managed to document that evening.
Our theory may be that the man who hanged himself in the barn is still in and around the house.
Our recommendation is that the family contact a medium who makes sure that the children in the family are calm and that the energy that is still left is allowed to go to the place where it belongs.