(The noise is coming from a baby downstairs)
This is how I closed the door
You have to turn the key
and release it, then it's locked
The door moves
stops here
Where are we right now?
We are at Ekenäs Castle
You have to turn the key. Come closer
(dog/baby in the background)
It has to go around the edge. You see?
It must be like this, otherwise I cannot close the door
This is what locks the door
And you closed it?
Like that
It's not possible to open
Closed
That makes this even better
Yeah
And it stays there...
It could easily have moved like this
if it's the wind...like this
The door stops right here, and then it closes
at full speed
You have to turn like this to open
And you turn it on the outside like that
And it gets stuck here, behind that iron thing
Check what it looks like when I close.
Do you see?
Yeah
Like that
Nice!