The one who is here, it knocks and hits the walls.
It was from under the bed, I thought it thumped back in my back.
It was so hard, it felt in the body.
And then he came after me.
We live in Säffle and we have lived here for, 13 years.
When did things happen in this apartment?
It is probably a year and a half ago.
The one who is now here, it knocks and hits the walls.
And it has made holes in the wall, both in the hall and in the bedroom.
It shakes and moves the bed.
Even when we are in it.
When you lie in bed?
You know how someone pulls it?
Yes.
When you lie in it ... It's a heavy bed.
Yes, it scratches on the floor.
Yes, it was under the bed I thought now.
Something scraped, polished as well.
It also moves the dining table.
Yes.
And roll over the chairs.
Throws things.
For example, a teaspoon.
It is so much that you have even written down a list, so you remember everything that has happened.
And it's not just a phenomenon, it's pretty much that has happened.
Opens the mirror in the bathroom.
The mirror cabinet.
One door.
When he thumps then the internet goes out.
It happened two, three days in succession.
And that paraffin lamp, it shook.
I even kept it and felt how it shook.
Then it was scary I think.
Yes.
And it turns on the TV at night.
Scratches on the floor.
Do you have any idea who this might be?
I think it is true to your brother, because he has had a hard time.
Can you tell us a little about your brother?
He drinks a lot, he is almost an alcoholic.
So that's why we don't have much contact.
He gets noisy when he drinks.
It will be exciting.
We will investigate here and see what we get and then we will bring here a medium that does not know anything about this apartment or about these phenomena.
So we'll see what she gets late tonight and tonight.
Yes, exciting.
Then we are in this residential building here in Säffle and it is an incredible story, what they say hands here.
This is the craziest we have been with, this is such a physical activity so there is even proof of the walls.
But this is crazy.
It is not the crashing location we have been on, but this is how it is, you never know what is happening.
It doesn't have to be the big castle from the 1200s
Without it can be just like here.
It is quite small, about 2.3 rooms, but then the phenomenon that happens here, they are incredible.
What do you say, should we start?
We fill the rooms with different instruments, we hear them, we are so close to everything.
It's like a big one about, so we will hear.
We know where these hot spots are somewhere.
And we will focus on very, very much.
And see if we can make any of the phenomena happen.
In here, where the most incredible has happened, a bed that is moved when two people are in it.
They lie and shake.
And then holes in the walls.
But what I think will be quite unique here too, it is that we will take a medium here.
And that medium will try to get it off or get what it is moving here.
But we must first look at what we can get.
On the one hand, document what they say hands here, then run with communication.
We will have as much info we can about the place when we are done here.
We will also test a theory, now we are here ourselves, then we will call back those who live here, to see if more things happen.
There was a sound behind the camera right now.
It snapped.
I don't know if you heard it Viktor, but it small.
Now Tony Viktor said, he is now filming.
We still have Lennie, who sits on the bus, he hears us, we have surveillance with sound.
If it comes through a name, Lennie can sit and search for it.
I imagine that if this energy moves here, it is enough that we just set the PMB.
Straight up here.
I start it straight up to the roof here.
So we'll see.
There is still sound out there.
There is no sound I've heard before.
It sounds like something is wandering around out there.
So the energy that can make these sounds in the walls and everything, can you go ahead and put your hand on that box there?
There was a discomfort when you said it.
Although it came from the wall here and moved forward.
This feels like a regular bedroom, but when you said it Niclas it was like something happened.
I also ripped when I said so.
So if you are with us here now and understand what we say ..
So you can knock in the wall ...
Check this out.
It's when you talk, I don't know what you trigger, something is.
It feels like you know we are here and we see what you can do.
You can move things, you can knock in the walls.
This is your chance to communicate with us and say what you want, for the family who is here wants to know who it is here and what you want.
So now you can communicate with us.
So if you are in this room now, could you go past that little black that is on the bench?
Wrap by or put your hand on it and we will notice that you are here.
You have made holes in the walls, can you make a new hole here for us?
Can you move on this bed?
We make sure we leave here now, you get a discomfort now.
It is cool that you feel it, that you shudder when you say the words.
This is the only room we have PMB in, so it starts playing so we know it is from here.
But we try it like this, then afterwards we will try to put it against the wall.
There was something here ...
The floor doesn't even sound.
There it is cracking a little.
It was something such a sound we heard.
We will post our paranormal Movement Alert, ie PMA.
We can put it on alarms that only indicate movement then.
We put it on the table, but we do not take the alarm but just that it should indicate in case something moves.
Because here they talk about chairs falling, tables being moved, everything vibrates, the lamp vibrates and it has also been kept.
It will be perfect.
And PRS next to it.
We can test when we stand here.
As we did in the bedroom.
If we have someone who can move on this table, move on the chairs that they have told about ..
Would you be able to do it for us now when we stand here?
Take our energy and then you do something.
We start any communication.
Should you test?
I start Ovilus.
Ovilus throws out lots of words, in English that we will interpret.
Try walking around.
I will go without disturbing the units, because they are quite sensitive.
These chairs here that you have moved on and pushed down on the floor even, could you be able to get them to move a little neighbor only when we stand here?
I have one thing in my hand that you can come up and talk ...
The man who is here, if I'm talking to you right now ...
Can you say your name to us?
We can test anyway, we know Arne, his brother perished in a fire a year and a half ago here in Säffle.
That's when these things started to happen.
And I think he mentioned that his name was Tommy.
Okay.
So Tommy, if you are in this apartment ...
And want to say something to Arne, greet him something.
So you have the opportunity to do it now.
If you are Tommy who is here, can you go to the table here and touch the antenna?
Or just go by and we'll see that you're here.
Scratch sound, she talked about that before.
It's in the bedroom.
Under the bed, they have heard it, like someone lying and crawling.
But we do so that we leave them two here, we learn to hear in case they get started.
So we put something out in the living room as well.
This one you recognize, says Hello Welcome.
I will direct it ..
Wait!
Here, the kitchen!
Can you do that again?
We heard that you were here in the kitchen.
Tommy?
Are you here?
If so, stir the iron stick.
We leave it, it may start again.
I go back here.
Can you touch it again again when we stand here?
You don't have to be afraid of us, whoever it is.
I don't know who it might be right now, but you who are here, or what's here, can you touch that antenna again?
We test some theories then, is there a woman who is here?
Is it a man who is here?
Is it a child who is here?
Now I get lots of words here Niclas.
Is there anything in the ground here under this apartment?
Can you touch any of our tools in here located on the table?
If there is something in the ground right here.
Now I have activated two PRS here, it is both static and strap function, so if something comes close ..
So if you do as I did now ..
Then you will make it sound.
Can you throw something in here?
Duns and sound in the building.
When you say throw it sounded from the floor.
It's no one above.
And these sounds that come are here somewhere ..
So it sounded type.
But there is so much that happens, TV is started by itself, the bathroom cabinet opens by itself.
I feel a little dizziness, but not much.
It comes and goes.
Try there.
We test go in here again then.
As you notice, it is not big here, but we can move pretty quickly through the rooms.
Try standing where I stood.
Can you do these things, make a hole in the wall?
Tap so high and hard that there are holes in the wall so we will see it.
So we know that you are here and that you really want to convey something here now.
Now I got up camera, we have to keep track of if something is happening with the technology now.
So the individual, the entity that makes these physical holes in the wall, now we challenge you to get to us here.
I think when we talk about camera, if it is intelligent, what comes through here now, we have cameras everywhere here ..
That it is so that you film this, that it does not want to be documented.
Duns and a knock in the room.
Now it was a knock somewhere.
It's just a tapping, it's hard to say where they come from.
It is really difficult.
Can you do this then?
PRS reacts in the living room.
Out!
I don't know if it was the living room ..
Was this out?
Yes, here.
Good!
Shiver..
You are .. I don't know what it is, where the shivers came from.
Check out what goose bumps when I go in here.
It's sick how the hair just rises straight up.
Can you knock for us?
Do you recognize that melody?
Reveal the master, what does it mean by that?
Say your name to us.
Come ...
Niclas hears something from the hall.
What is it that sounds here?
I have to check.
What kind of sound was that?
It sounds like there is someone outside the door.
Okay.
I bring a spirit box too, so we see.
Maybe we should test this Niclas.
I go in and knock on the wardrobe the door, right I did so it went on.
Try it again then.
Niclas gets a knock back.
Was that you?
Was it you who knocked?!
No, mine were hard, then something else came.
It was a dull ..
It sounded like it came in the wall here.
Try again.
A knock back.
What kind of sound comes afterwards?
What is here, now you have the chance to do everything here so we know who you are.
Do you have the power to be able to do something for us?
Sit on the couch if you want.
Throw a pillow.
Is it he who lives here, Arne, his brother who is here?
Is it something you want to say goodbye or say to Arne?
Is it Eva you want to talk to?
So make a loud sound somewhere.
They have a lot of watches here, you hear clock sounds everywhere.
It is interesting anyway, when we are not in the same room, an instrument starts.
Now there was nothing in the kitchen then, but now this was what it probably sounded.
Lennie here after all when we are here, because we have sound recording on surveillance.
So Lennie, if you hear us now ...
I hear you.
Would you be able to check this area if you find something about this area in Säffle.
If there was something in the ground or if this is known in Säffle, that things happen here.
I look at what I get.
Perfect, just come back if you find something.
Yes.
What we have been reaction to now, there are knocks.
When we knock in there, this one starts, we leave that room and then it went on.
I don't know how to meet this.
But we have driven Ovilus, should we test spirit box?
Now it said table.
We must have some control.
We wait a while with spirit box, otherwise we will not hear.
Is there anyone in the kitchen over there?
Can you touch what's on the table?
Do you know that you are dead?
Tappations are heard from the wall and ceiling.
Sound up from.
How can it be sound up from?
There is no one there.
Knocking and voice.
If you are angry with something, can you go to any of those things that don't usually be here?
Should we try a spirit box?
See if we get something through it.
Who is making them the holes in ...
"I"
I.
"Wall"
MAN.
Wake up or wall.
If you take all the power you have ..
Yes.
And then you hit a hole in the wall in here.
I challenge you to do it.
Should we go in and close the door here?
We have a lot of holes behind too.
"Are you standing there?"
Can you make one to the hole behind the door there?
Do you see the black box standing up there?
Can you push it down?
"Yes"
Say your first and last name to us.
What's your name?
Do you know the family who lives here?
"Yes."
It sounded like someone young.
Do you know who makes them the holes in the wall?
Not much is coming through.
We pause it a little.
Now we are here, can you do something for us?
Show your power to us.
Tap hard in any of these walls or do you have such power to move the bed once only?
Are you stuck here?
Want help from here?
Listen now if something goes on.
I knock again, in the wardrobe door.
You who have overturned these chairs, can you come in here and move them again?
I would like to document the phenomenon.
Because when we come to such a place where we have chairs that go out, holes in the walls, bankings ..
And it happens regularly.
It is hoped that it will happen when we are here now.
If you take all the power you can now, we invite you here.
Push this table.
Can you move a chair just a little neighbor.
Just like this ...
Do you have so much energy?
You have overturned these chairs.
I turn this off.
I put it over there.
Do you see the two lamps lying and pulsating here?
If you put your hand on one of these pages, it will shine a color.
So we can talk to you, you walking around here.
That knocks in the walls.
You are quiet because you want to listen too, in case you hear these the banks.
Not only that, they have had power under the bed when they sleep.
Like someone lying and scratching on the floor.
So all sounds are very important here now.
Do you like when knocking in the walls here?
Maybe we should look out of another theory ..
There may be something with the ground.
That it is not linked to the family but there is something below?
The strange thing is that they have lived here for 13 years, but this started about a year and a half ago, when his brother passed away.
Is there anything in the ground here?
Has something happened in this place?
Do you want to get the family to move from here?
Is that why you are punching holes in the walls?
Don't like those who live here?
Or is it a cry for help?
Want help from here?
If there had been a relative, his brother who wants to communicate and give him an answer ...
He should come through them and give us something now.
Or he wants to wait until he knows that Eva and Arne will come here.
That he wants to give it then, we do not know.
Or when the medium Wilma will be here late.
It may be that it might want to convey through.
I put this in bed.
Now I have added one to instruments in there, it is an iron stick that stands out from the bed.
Now we have put out quite a lot of tools, you do not want too much either, a tool usually becomes the center point for everything.
Otherwise, the energy can make us run around in circles all the time as it did in the beginning.
A little neighbor in the kitchen, a little neighbor here.
But now if we are here now we have been watching almost everywhere.
Except for the kitchen.
We have lots of surveillance cameras, audio recordings.
For the most important thing for us it is to document these physical phenomena.
These are the ones we want to access.
Stand here and experience them when they happen, it was absolutely incredible.
But it also feels like we have to address the right energy and I don't know ..
Then I do not know if it is linked to those who live here.
Because now, it feels like what's here not really comes through.
Not as strong as they have told you anyway.
No.
And the shivers has disappeared.
They were there in the beginning when you addressed it, it felt like something was stroked.
But it didn't really go on the instruments.
Should I try to lie down in bed?
I lie down on one side here.
I'm standing here.
Now Tony will lie down in bed there.
Can he do it?
Can you make this bed shake?
I get a lot with digs.
That's what I mean.
And Find Ashes.
What does it mean?
Is there anything under this apartment?
Finish what?
You may attack me when I'm here.
Pull in this bed and make it shake so I want to get up from here.
You don't have to be afraid of me, Niclas or Viktor who is in here now.
Without doing what you usually do when the others, Eva and Arne are here.
No vibrations here.
Statical field here!
Thanks!
Can you do it again?
Damn it fast.
Were you here with me exactly?
Shit, what shivers.
Wait...
What is it?
What the hell was that?
It was like someone knocked me in the back of my head.
I thought I went into the stand.
You who did that, can you do it again?
I was quite a hundred that I went into my mic, that it was hanging down.
It was quite intense, then I saw this field.
Can you do it again?
If you can walk on the edge of the bed there, it will shine just as it did.
How can it sound from the ceiling?
I don't get it together.
How can it sound up there?
I just have to test again ..
So I got up.
It is now shining.
Thanks!
You're in here.
What kind of sound was that?
What?
Viktor- "It was I who went against .."
No, not that sound ..
I heard that out here too.
Did you hear that?
We are here with you.
Need help from here?
If you can go to this now that is on the bed, light it up properly.
Can you do it again?
What you just did here.
That you lit it up, that you stood there.
Tommy, if you are here ...
Brother of Arne ...
Can you go to this on bed now?
Okay, we leave this room then.
It is difficult.
A little neighbor in there, it was interesting anyway.
We do it like this.
I have another instrument, we put it on the bed too.
This is a prototype we have, I put this I thought.
And it's the same thing here, green or red.
So if there is something that passes this beam, then we definitely know.
So you who usually move in the bedroom, can you go and take in the pyramid I put there?
If you are in bed there, can you touch that blue pulsating light?
Get it to shine red if you want us to go out here.
Make it shine green if you want to keep us in here.
I test a Ghost box.
Yes, test and see if we get something there, I would like to hear this individual's name.
And I would like to hear the voice.
If it now says something to us.
Ghostbox works like a spirit box.
It will roar a little.
I leave Ovilus there for so long.
Do you hear the noise I have here?
If you get close to me, you can talk to me.
Did I move at your arm?
No.
Surely?
Yes, I stood here.
What did you know?
It felt like, maybe we got it on film, it was like I was moving at you.
It was like you took ...
No, I stood like this.
You didn't touch me.
This is the second time, I didn't say anything last time, but then it was like someone was here under the sweater.
Good, move us if you want.
Take our energy, do stuff, we're here for your sake.
You will get help from here.
I try walking around with this one.
The energy that has pushed chairs ...
You affect him who lives here very much, he feels very tired.
Huh?
No clue.
It was like several ...
"Disappear!"
Did it say away?
We will not go here until you say who you are.
Say your name to us.
The family wants to know what you are called.
"Do you get it?"
It was a woman.
"Yes"
Here?
Is it a child who is here?
Have you died in this place?
Is your ashes under this house?
"Running"
Spring sounded like.
We will not run from here.
Can you push out a chair to us are you kind?
"Hå **** t!"
It may have each keep up, but I'm not sure.
"Go"
It was go.
We go if you pull out this chair.
If you move on the chair, we go here.
"The back"
I thought it said Arnes ...
Who makes these holes in the wall?
"Pass away"
Pass away.
Did you hear how dark it was?
We come in here instead.
We stand here.
We will not go.
You said go away, but we won't go away.
Who are you?
“The kitchen”
Every time I talk ...
Do you see this?
Can you put hand ...
“Yep”
Put your hand on this one.
"Why?"
Why?
Is it a child?
Yes, or is it a child?
It is a child who says it.
The child who is here, can you come in and play with us here?
Can you have it play?
The one at the office.
"If you pray"
If you pray.
Please, play on the one at the office there.
"Yes"
"Evil"
I ask you as kindly as I can, put your hand in front of it.
So it plays.
"Never"
"Does it work?"
I don't know, there will be a lot of strange words.
There are bangs everywhere, I don't take anything.
It feels like we are not coming anymore.
Not with this, right now it feels like it's a whole stop.
I don't know if we should take the family here, so they can be here with us and walk around.
Yes, we test it.
Or do you come up with something more that we haven't tried?
No, we try to communicate.
We'll see if it starts when they arrive.
If it is those who have things with them.
Then it's time again, now Eva and Arne are included.
We'll see if some more things happen now.
Exactly, it is you who experience these phenomena with the holes in the wall and knocks.
All the madness that happens here.
Then we continue, we start a motion detector.
This one sounds in case something goes in front of it.
I put it against the sofa here.
So if something goes by ..
And then we start this one.
Anyone who shows with red and green if it is something.
Now we have those who live here.
If anyone wants to come in here and talk to us, there are lots of different types of tools here.
On the bed or on the table, or out on the kitchen table.
Is anyone here with us now?
Who wants to communicate.
Come now.
Come show you to us now that we have all gathered.
There is a lot of energy to take here.
Can we hear a knock in the wall?
It does not want to.
I knocked a little in the wardrobe, then an instrument started.
It was like that so you can't do it, it's me to do it.
Can you do that?
When we were in a room, we heard something in another room.
And then we went to that room, then we heard from another room.
It was like it was moving.
But not very clear, we will see if it happens more now.
If we are going into the bedroom Niclas, because there you experience a lot.
Yes, turn off the pyramid.
Yes, it's mostly there.
I'm going to turn off here only.
Now we are here.
Exactly, now we're in here.
Can you knock in the wall?
So we hear it.
In this wall.
There was a bang out there.
Now it's there instead.
Do you recognize that sound?
Is that how it usually sounds?
Yes.
Small bang.
Yes, but sometimes it's higher.
Can you move this bed?
You have moved it and made it shake.
Can you do something like that?
Can you come in and put it hand in front of this so it sounds like this ..
Can you touch any of them the things we have in here?
Is there any child running in here?
Who likes to cuddle?
Can you go to the bed and touch this iron stick that stands out?
Or is there anything in the ground here?
Who wants to convey something.
Can you touch these things then?
We got this up with a camera, if it has anything to do with it?
That, now we film, does it not want to be documented?
We don't know.
If you are out there, can you go to the table there?
Where it blinks some stuff.
And then you touch it, you are kind.
Should we try to go out in the kitchen then?
We leave this.
I start it then when we go.
Then we go out into the kitchen then and see if we can get through ...
It was me.
He just goes past the instrument.
Tony!
Yes?
It starts here, it shines!
Come come!
I think we got it on surveillance.
Shone the pyramid?
Both static and REM function went.
Both?
Just as we went out and I turned around, they started glowing.
Good, follow us out here then.
So we go to the kitchen so we can talk to you there.
It is typical that it is after that it is in the room where we leave.
Yes.
You who have talked to us before, can you come in and talk to us again?
Who are you?
Say your name to us.
Something you want to say goodbye ....
"Remove"
Did it say go away?
Something you want to say goodbye?
Hello Hello!
Who are you?
Do you know us?
Why do you knock in the walls here?
“Banking”
Banks.
It sounds like a child.
I don't get it together.
What do you want?
Now we want you to come in here and then you say your name loudly and clearly.
It sounded very far.
It sounded a bit like Tommy, but I don't know ..
If it is Tommy who is here ...
Say yes in that case.
"Yes"
Is there anything else here?
That has to do with this ground.
Say yes if it is.
"Yes"
It's something else.
"Strong"
Are you buried under this house?
Is your ash under this house?
Lennie, have you looked up anything about the place?
Yes, I have found that there is an old pilgrim trail outside here.
Could it be true?
Yes, it's a joint.
It's a joint here?
Okay.
Is there anything more you've got about the place?
No more than there is a cemetery about one, one and a half kilometers away.
That's right.
It is out after the narrow road.
Thanks Lennie, great.
That's what we've been up to now, we get this with ash, legs, digs and now you asked if it is in the ground.
Then maybe we have a line to go on, that it is not linked to you in this case, but there is something near here.
But if there is something in the ground ..
who want to remind themselves that they are here ...
Can you touch something in here?
Have you followed any object in this building here?
So hard, we don't really get out what it is.
It keeps up with a bit and we have some theories but ...
We get no response that it is so.
Nothing.
We go so that we take in Wilma.
She has no idea what has happened here tonight.
So we'll see what she gets, if she gets something more.
And possibly can remove what is here.
Hello!
Wilma.
Arne.
Nice.
Eva.
Exciting.
Welcome here Wilma.
We have been walking around a bit here and we think it's your turn to feel.
And see what you get to you.
I only have one meter, so if we get something that happens then I will measure EMF.
But you can do the job here and see what you get to yourself.
How exiting.
Let's see.
I want to start by going straight here in the family room, it seems to be.
I actually get a first contact here.
And then I see as a figure of an older gentleman sitting in that armchair.
He sits just like the armchair is directed, so he sits and stare straight in like this, in the TV.
He is here to keep track and wants to be close to you.
So I connect that there is a relative.
He wants to keep track and he sits here and just wants it to be calm and well for you.
And he has a fairly clear energy and he shows that he has tried to contact you by affecting the electronics.
That he has hit the TV or raised the sound and the like.
And turns on the TV at night ..
I'll try to see how he ... I'll move a little here.
I'll know what kind of relatives this might be.
I get a name, it doesn't have to be this name, it can be similar.
And I hear Arne ... It may be that the letters A and R are in the name.
But it is Arne anyway.
And he feels a little older, about 80 years, as he shows up.
And I connect him a lot to you, that it is you that he simply belongs to that it is you he wants to be close.
But he is a good energy.
He says he knows you know about him, that you have felt his energy here.
And especially right here on the couch.
For example, if you have been here yourself on the couch, you have felt that you are not really alone.
And it is not intended to be intimidated, he says, but he just wants to show his presence.
By pure love.
But what you can do then, what I do with relatives and those who are friendly and are just here of love, it is that he tones them down a bit.
But I don't completely remove them if there are family bands.
I think I want to move on a little first, then we go back here in case he wants to show me something more.
Then I want to go in here.
Here I get a woman pretty quickly.
And this woman belongs to you.
She shows that she stands against the wardrobe and folds together and folds the sheet.
It should be nice and it is so important to her.
That it should be washed clean and be nice and so.
She has been with you and she stays like here, just because when she lived it was important for her to sew up curtains and as I said fold sheets.
It's my mother -in -law then.
I was just going to say something about mother, in that direction.
It's guaranteed your mother -in -law, I'll see if I get any name.
So we see if we can confirm it too.
I still get the word mother, that is, like it's Lillemor or ...
No, I'll probably stay at Lillemor, it feels like it.
Lillemor.
It's Lillemor.
No, it's not.
I get that name, but I still connect it to be the mother -in -law.
Because I feel she is here now and she wants to be close to you very much.
And she shows a connection to you.
And as I said she organizes a lot here and she also wants to be in control.
And this particular woman and that man out there, they don't know about each other.
Because they are at different frequencies.
So they do not know each other's energy.
Now I feel drawn to the kitchen.
So I think we go there.
When I enter the kitchen then it is like a small, compact energy runs between my feet.
Like a dog or cat.
Runs and strokes and goes in between.
Very curious and social.
And I know the typical animal energy that we medium can feel, that we feel the difference if it is animal or human, the energy.
Very happy.
Dog or cat, I actually can't see or feel what kind of animal it is.
But a very happy animal, likes to jump up on the chairs.
And this animal has a connection to you two together, if you may have had an animal that has passed away or that you have had to remove.
It's been many years since that.
Where do I want to go in?
Have we been in here?
We don't have that?
No.
It felt exciting in here.
In here, there are very clear energies, there are several that I get here.
First I get a man and he smells a little liquor, like he had some alcohol problems and was a little aggressive.
And his energy also turns out so that he falls in and is so that I should be seen and I should be heard.
He makes a lot of fuss here.
I think it's true to your brother.
He drinks a lot, he is almost an alcoholic.
He was noisy.
Very noisy when he drinks.
But this man who boots in so, I have a little trouble indicating what kind of connection he has to you.
But what I know is that he is not unknown but he has a connection to one of you.
And he is simply here because he needs help to be transferred to the light.
He thinks he did a lot wrong when he was alive and he is afraid that when he goes over he ends up in hell.
Therefore, he does not dare to go over.
So he wants to ask for forgiveness and wants help to be brought to light.
It is reminiscent of, this with the spirits, he was almost alcoholic.
Is that your father?
Brother.
Okay.
And he was pretty messy.
But I'm trying to tone him away.
Since it is a relative, I do not completely remove, but it will be very quiet when he disappears.
And I do it at once now.
So that we can continue in the rest of the house, otherwise he will disturb all the time.
I'll see if he has any last message to say.
The last message is to you then.
It is that you should think about the posture, not just for back problems but you should show that you are a man, you can do this.
You should be straight -backed.
He says that you should not be a look and go like this, but now you can show that you are the man here.
That you take over after me now he says.
So that's his message to you.
Are you okay with me tone him away a bit?
Yes.
That's good.
Then I'll bring in some light and angels here.
That's how.
I saw him go away and I showed the light and explained that there is no hell but he will get help there on the other side.
And get the love he needs.
He has also received his message through and has shown that it is he who has been here simply.
So hopefully it will be much calmer, just the passive and intense energy.
I actually felt the scrub there, I feel an energy that is hiding.
As soon as I come, it's like the energy is behind something.
Which is a bit shy.
It is a little boy that I get in, who is about this long.
Very mischievous.
And as soon as there is a medial person here, because he feels that I can communicate, then he starts and buses.
So that's why he hides and runs around here.
And this boy is a little lost, because he is looking for his parents.
He has not really switched to the light.
I need to get them to meet each other, so he is led into the light.
He has run here very much on weekdays, back and forth.
I hear in my head that you have heard these little running.
And he likes to re -furnish in the shelves and roll stuff and that's because he is busing.
When I ask about how he died, I feel fire smoke.
It may have been like he has burned inside or that he has been burned in some way.
Because I feel a lot of fire smoke around him and then he shows burns on the body.
I removed there, then we had the energy here too that I should try to tone down.
So now I will really just go around where we have been.
Our expectations of the house in Säffle were high.
After everything the family told, documented and experienced.
What if we would witness a powerful poltergeist phenomenon for the first time?
Which even had such power to be able to punch holes in walls.
It was interesting to see how the medium Wilma worked.
She got a lot that agreed to Arne's brother Tommy, who tragically died in a fire.
It will be interesting to see if it has been calm after Wilma helps the energies over to the other side.
But the question is whether it has become completely calm?
Or if the forces that remain in the house that cause the phenomenon appear to have switched to the other side.
Or lies dormant to get back with full force.