Then we finally arrive at The Conjuring House.
And it's hot, my glasses fog up again I notice.
So exciting to be here really, this is a dream to investigate.
Oh my God.
One of the world's most haunted houses.
If you've seen the movie The Conjuring, everything in the movie is about what happened here, but a little changed, it's a movie.
And they say that what was in the movie is only a fraction of that, but has downplayed that very much, what happened here in real life, with the Perron family.
They lived here for almost ten years.
But there are things that have happened here. We have the big seans room, now there is no table and so on there. They tell me the mother is sitting there and is thrown all the way back and hits the fireplace.
They get very angry so Ed and Lorraine are thrown out of here after this session.
We have the guise of a little boy upstairs.
We have something walking down in the basement.
People also talk about The Crooked Lady. There is a child who has drawn a woman with a crooked neck, much like one has been hanged. "There is no documented suicide in the house by someone hanging themselves"
It's really cool.
This is really going to be a great night, the team has already started bringing in all the bags. We're fixing all the cameras, so I think we'll start the investigation.
We go in.
Yes, then we are inside the house.
How does it feel?
I feel awful.
Yes, you see... we've talked a bit off camera too...
Even when we got here I started to get a bit of a headache. Then we walked around the house, filmed a little behind the scenes and I just feel worse and worse, now I feel completely finished.
Yes, it is a powerful house, we talked about it at the beginning, so much has happened here. Now we have to form our own opinion, there are many who have been here and investigated
and there are many stories. Now we are here to see if what people are saying is true. And I think we should have the background story of the Perron family with us.
Because we know that happened, it is documented. So we proceed from that.
Of course.
How does Johanna feel now that you came into the house here?
Dizziness and nausea. I'd be surprised if I didn't throw up today.
Is it that bad?
Yes, it's the same feeling. I'm not feeling well...
Wilma then?
I have never felt so affected. I already feel that I am very affected. I feel pressure above my head, I feel a little groggy. Like I'm a little drunk.
Also nausea and like the eyes just hang.
So this...
Exciting introduction. And we're going to start now.
What was that?
Did something bite me there or?
Bite you?
Damn that felt.
Huh?
Like a damn needle. I thought it was a wasp that bit me.
Was it that strong?
Wait, I have to hold onto this. I was completely giddy.
Huh?
Is there anything?
Does it feel like a wasp stung you?
It was like someone taking a needle and...
Nothing is visible.
Okay, but we'll keep an eye on it in case it comes up. It's like this, we've gone around, we've set up all the cameras here and you feel very affected. I feel like I'm pretty much on top, yet.
I may not have quite gotten that paranormal feel from the house, but I've done this so many times that I know it will come.
And you?
I've walked around here and in some places these shivers come. And it's hot here, but it feels like someone is standing behind you and it's freezing cold, your hair just stands on end.
Goosebumps indeed.
We can say it's not cold in here. It's probably 27.28 degrees in the house here. And you see how we are dressed.
It's not like we're freezing. But it is good that we walk with bare arms because then we might feel these caresses, because they can touch one or caress one's back.
So we'll see what comes up. And it happens in certain places here in the building.
But what do you say, shall we get started? And I think that now first you go Niclas, me and Wilma, we go around pretty much the whole house.
We´re just gona fell the house and bring few tools. And then you get… did you see something?
Lennie come here....
No, you're not either. No, Viktor, you have to stay there.
I have to see what it is. It looks like...
Johan, move. It is Johan who is seen in the mirror, it looked as if someone was standing and looking in through a window. But it was a mirror, okay.
You see, this house will give us things, we are on the alert. Every little thing we will definitely do here.
Then we have surveillance with six cameras. We will also place some different things and test here.
But let´s go, we start walking around. You Johanna and Lennie need to rest, drink some water and sit at the surveillance with Johan.
Then we get started.
Here again. I walk into something all the time. Check this out. I don't know if you see this.
It's like entering something, this came after the boat, I don't know, I've never felt this much before.
Sick, you walk into it.
The instruments I have brought are Melmeter, Polterscript and I have a Spiritbox in my pocket.
You have an Ovilus.
Now it's... you haven't been inside the house before, you came in just now, but this is where the big séance table was. Where the Perron family had their séance.
So if you know that story, it was here that she, the mother of the family, flew into this fireplace.
I see like an energy line, right here around the sofa in the same size, like a circle.
And this has happened way back, when black magic was practiced here, in this room. So they have cast spells and called up and down lots of evil forces.
I see a bunch of women who have been doing this and you haven't really known what you've been doing.
So that here it is like an open portal, anyone can enter here, from the spirit world. Or even the entities can get in here.
And I feel that there is a lot of activity here, but the spirits that belong to the house do not like to be here. But this is out of the question.
Spirits coming from outside and into this portal then. Because the energies in the house are in different rooms here instead, because they don't like this thing about bringing in anything or that energies come and go.
I start an Ovilus.
Here I am very affected, it rumbles in my ears and it becomes like a lid. And in here there is a lot of activity.
I take a step in..
It's like the energy in here.. I realize that there are two energies here. It wants to draw us in, but when we enter it disappears, it wants to play a game.
And I see these two energies working together and will build throughout the evening. The more times you pass here, the stronger it will become.
A man and a woman, they belong together somehow. They have made this their room and there is something about the books here, it is some special book.
I saw before me, a few weeks ago, a blue book that will fall.
I can't pinpoint which one it is now. But it is a book that is very special, like those who were here before and put spells, they also put a spell on that book.
There are quite a few blue books here, because this was a very active area. Here we have some blue books that stand out.
It could be something.
I'll try to scan a bit.
Yes, it could be interesting.
Because this has been a completely different room, you know that.
And, what had to do with this room..
is a bit special.
After all, they had...
a guise that appeared here. And it wasn't very nice.
No.
It looked quite menacing. And it was here.
Because this used to be a bedroom.
So the bookshelf and that came in a little later, but we know that books fly here.
Shall we just walk around with Melmeter and look around the library here?
Here we have a lot of doors too..
I was going to say about doors Niclas, they are said to open and close.
That's a lot of blue books you're dealing with there.
That's why I was drawn to this.
It was..
If we have something in here that could throw out one of these books..
that has that power.
Oh, powerfully right away!
It's blue...
What's it called?
Leave.
It feels like they don't like, this energy Johnny or whoever it may be..
Every time you say Johnny.
He's mad at me because I'm digging something up now, what I mention with the book, that's something..
now it stings my back when I talk about it too. It's something that he doesn't want me to dig up and speculate on.
It gets very aggressive.
Now the shivers are coming again, they come and go all the time. Like someone is behind you.
I was just going to say it, he's behind us. He's on my back all the time.
I'll just come in between you.
I don't know who Johnny is, it's not a name that we recognize.
I am getting in communication with him now. Then I get that he says you don't know what you're playing with now.
As if he wants to warn, that You doesn't know what you are about to do.
Shall we check out the living room too?
The first thing I notice here is that there is someone sitting in the armchair behind here. And that energy was already here when I came in, it has been here the whole time.
And it's like that energy sticks to this surface and kind of keeps track of who's passing in and out.
And this energy communicates with the other spirits here and tells them that now they are coming in here and they are going to do this.
It's a male energy and it's like he's tapping, he's finding out everything about us and sending it to the others. It's the only one I get on this surface.
Is there a basement or something here?
There's a basement there.
Okay, because I've heard it being shouted from there. A woman with a knot in her hair sits and waits down there.
What this mother was in contact with, do you get in who it could be? Because it is a case that has been talked about.
After all, it was a form of portal, that it wasn't the spirits that were around, but something else.
What is it that has such power, I think. Because it is almost five meters and being pulled or thrown requires enormous force.
Yes, I get that it is.. in the ritual world or whatever you want to call it, when you take from the good you take from up and when you take from the bad you dig down.
And I see images that you have sat in a circle, a group of women and that they have dug up. I also see that they have been doing voodoo dolls.
People have put needles in dolls to hurt others. And this that they've brought up, it's a form of energy I've never seen before. It feels like it could be something demonic or something very, very dark.
I think it was interesting when you said that about needles and woodoo dolls, I was thinking about the opening with your leg Niclas. Needles, the sting. We are close to this too.
Yes and when you mentioned it I get the number 7. I think we should remember the number 7 because it feels important, I can't connect why now.
There is something about 7, when you started talking about it.
Now that we've been standing here, it's been a long time since I felt this, I've had these shivers, but right now it's like someone is squeezing my shoulder blades together.
Like someone sitting or hanging on one. That's why I get these shivers I think because something is behind it.
I feel it like a weight on my shoulders.
You know when that happens then it will go down. Then it will settle in the lower back.
We'll see if it lets up. But shall we go down? Wilma was drawn there.
When you opened the door I got the name Deborah. Check out that name.
Interesting I got now.
Things have really happened here, a lot has happened here and it's a very, very powerful place.
There is a woman here, moving like this, running here. She has dark hair in a bun, she also wears something white.
She runs here and this is her place as well. And I see something like schizophrenia, like during the day she's a normal woman, but at night she changes completely.
Then she gets long nails, she gets dark hair in front of her face and becomes really uncomfortable. And she has pulled us down now, she is waiting for us.
She shows me three o'clock, as a sign that at night something happens here.
Yes we'll see. Again that with Niclas, that needle thing. Or the sting you felt.
Down here they talk about The Crooked Lady. She with her neck.
What happened there?
Spiritbox started in my pocket. Maybe that means we need to communicate.
Exactly, I thought so too.
Shall we get there?
No, stay put.
There is a woman in here too who says she wants to talk.
A woman.
Here it's good, I shiver here.
Shall we get over there then?
Wait, just let me be here a little bit, I want this feeling.
It was like she just wanted to say Get out, Leave.
And the last thing was like now I'm sick of it, leave.
I sense that this woman has no problem with me. She likes me very much and she likes women.
And I hear Oh, a witch like me! That she recognizes herself in me.
But that men provoke her, that they come down here and only provoke. She wants to talk about that.
I'm getting a heat here, I could lay on the floor here. I feel no threat that way.
So it's also kind of interesting, against what she's sending out.
It was here that the father of the Perron family got pats on the back when he went down here.
What was that?
*The sound of something moving in the building*
In the middle of your speech.
Can you do it again?
I think, Wilma senses something in that room.
We'll let this one remain, we'll go a little bit there then.
Wait..
Something was dropped on the floor above.
*The sound that Niclas hears*
It will be... above the floor, inside...
by the fireplace, right?
It will be, right?
Now we are in a very special place, we have a well behind here. You can't take another step behind because I don't want you to fall into it.
But if you get something out of this well, it's also very special, they said.
The first thing that comes to mind is the name Nea, or Linnea. It feels like I'm standing at a funeral, or not a funeral either but that someone has been thrown down here, someone who died here.
I see a little girl, like someone threw a child down or brought something down here. And I feel those energies and that energy is stuck here calling for me.
Or crying out for some kind of contact. And it feels like this room is very active. That you have sat here and really get in touch in here.
Because what's beneath me is so desperate, it really wants to communicate.
And here in the chair it's like there's an elderly woman sitting and she's not so distraught that there's something down here.
It's more like she's keeping watch, she's the one who wanted us to come in here.
But it feels very powerful, that it is connected to throwing someone down here.
We can say that children's cries have been heard from there. That it's like there's a child there. You can hear voices in here and all kinds of things, so you could sit down here and just be completely silent.
Here I think they have done some Challenge and tested here.
I read in the book about gallows, which move, being thrown when the Perron family was here. They were even beaten with hangers in some closets.
A voice is heard in the room.
What the hell was that? Did you hear?
Wait, I'll check.
Someone was talking.
A voice is heard in the room.
Woman.
Damn, I heard something through the headphones.
Did you?
It was a woman who answered.
Could you hear what she said?
No, it didn't work. Damn I'm shivering.
Did someone whisper?
Yes. It was something like that.
Good. This is what could happen and now it is happening. This is what we want because voices have been heard here and now you heard it Viktor. Too bad you couldn't interpret what she said.
Because I only said Hello, so maybe it was a Hello back.
This is the coolest thing I've ever experienced now.
Right now the hair is being messed with in different ways.
Are you touching me now?
Grab my arm firmly.
Imagine when you get a touch here, one there, one here, it jumps between.
I thought I'd see if the hair could move. But cool with an evp.
Wonder what it said. But we will be able to listen to that during the analysis.
And it's great that you got to hear it in real time. I'm super happy about that.
It's something with the mirror, I think.
I try to sit in front of it.
I do, because it's like they step out all the time.
I stand in here to the side.
Can you show yourself in the mirror to Niclas?
That's kind of what I felt.
Wait!
Is anyone walking?
Someone is walking.
There were clear steps over here.
That must have been heard!
We're moving towards it, I just have to bring this one up.
Did you hear the steps in the headphones?
Damn!
It was here Niclas.
Go towards it then.
Again!
But we're going up the stairs now, and we'll come back into the living room. Then we take the upper floor as well.
Did it restart?
Now its time.
I'll take this up then.
It's crazy that it starts up twice.
We're going to start something else, I'll turn this one on.
It's a hell of a run here, it's everywhere.
What are you feeling? What is that up here?
I feel stressed and have stress attacks up here. I see children again, but I also see adult energies.
I see that there has been a family here, or a mother and a father. And that something dark has stood here roaring and scaring.
And that you have stepped forward and then you have come from the side and taken a stranglehold on people who have slept in this bed.
Then there is a huge portal from here to here, this is where everything runs. Very much in there.
It's like the energies just pull me in there. That we should go further.
Shall we go further then? Shall we bring it too? Bring PRS.
This was the children's bedroom. Those who slept in these beds went into that room, that's where the older sister always was, Andrea Perron.
But it is also here, around the wall, this is where they woke up and heard this chant.
And their bodies have been found outside the house.
Right. The previous owners took the theory of these soldiers. That maybe it's not this wall but that wall that goes around. And then they found five.
But they haven't dug them up. They don't really know, but they think it's there.
Shall we try going into the last room here too? See if anything else happens.
And this should be Andrea Perron's bedroom. The oldest of the siblings.
I get to see two people the same age anyway, two girls. Now it's one of these girls who shows how she got pulled out of this bed.
That she was lying in bed and then was pulled by the leg and pulled out. She wants to show me that there is something here.
I also see a smaller girl, who gets out of bed and walks around the room, in circles.
Like she wakes up and then walks around and around like this. Like something has affected her and tried to take over her body.
Someone controls her?
Exactly.
The children have come in here because they have found it to be a safe place. But they have also seen a little boy who comes walking.
They have even played with the boy and had discussions with him from what I understand. But they have also been thrown around in that scrub there.
The door to that scrub has also been opened so I think you can check in there too before we go down.
I'm getting very dizzy in here. I see as an energy sitting down, thin and dark. It is not a person I see, but this is also some kind of entity.
Who just growled at me. Sitting in the corner now growling, with red eyes. Very unpleasant. Sitting there in...
It sits in the corner and bites the nails like this.
So yes, very uncomfortable.
We go down and then we make a new constellation.
Now we have changed a little in the groups here. I think we'll go down to the basement, you see I'm wearing headphones so it's going to be an Estes Method. Or if Johanna gets to test.
We're going down to this table that's down in the basement, we also see this well there.
We will place some instruments in the corridor at the same time. Now I'm starting to shiver, now it's coming..
Good.
I've had it like twice, you've had it a little more. It comes out of nowhere, it's nice.
Or?
But we'll go down, lay out stuff and get started and communicate a bit. We have no other communication tool, but now it is us and listen for voices.
And maybe we'll manage to catch some more evp, we caught one when we were down there.
We go down.
What is it?
There was a red light flashing over there.
Wait stay here.
Did you say a red light?
Yes.
I'll see if it blinks again.
No.
Here.
Here it was a red light that was flashing.
So hopefully the camera caught it, no hell I was probably in its way. I thought maybe it was a unit that was glowing, but it isn't.
I will okace the Paranormal Movement Alert. We'll maybe hear it if there's something moving out here.
I also have some motion sensors that say Hello Welcome, so I'll place them here. And we know that the woman has been seen walking here.
Now I have set it quite sensitively, just in case something goes by there. I'll try stomping next to it.
Over here I put a Hello Welcome.
And then we have these cat toys. We put everything in one line here.
We then have the surveillance camera over there and we go into the room there.
Here, Johanna, there is one that has been talked about, The Crooked Lady. It is this one that the children have drawn.
Yes, they have drawn her yes.
Yes.
I will place this.
Red and green. Wilma said there is a woman sitting in this chair.
So we can see if it gives an answer at the same time, because I will sit here, you can sit one there and one there maybe. So I start with the Estes Method.
I put another Flux behind us here.
For those of you who don't know what the Estes Method is, Niclas will start a spirit box with headphones. He also has a blindfold so he can't see.
So all the energies that are down here in the basement.
Can come in here.
Go to them here blue pulsating...
By the way, I have noise cancelling, so I won't hear what you say.
Yes. Good!
I'm getting started.
Now I got shivers.
It hasn't started anything before, has it?
No, now this begins.
Why do you want us to go?
Will you show up for us tonight?
Then show yourself to us.
Behind who?
Can you make a loud noise?
Yes, there!
My arms start to shiver.
Same here.
Both! There and there.
Someone touched my neck.
Okay.
Look!
Nor does he know that these have just started.
No, he doesn't know that.
What is it?
It sounded like someone was standing there.
Who are you who came and stood behind you?
Do you see him looking that way? Where you tell that you saw someone.
No, I heard..
It kind of creaked on the floor.
We want to know who you are.
There's someone touching my neck all the time, I'm going crazy.
Are you behind Niclas now?
Continue touching the neck.
I got a huge headache now.
Did you get a headache?
Here.
In the temple? I don't really see.
Yes, the temple.
Okay.
Who is affecting Viktor as well?
I have to break.
What is it?
There's someone pulling their fingers on my neck all the time, it's so fucking uncomfortable.
Like this?
No, very loose. Like this. From one side to the other. At first I think maybe it's a moth or something that landed on my neck.
But then you would have seen it and said so.
Viktor got a hell of a headache.
Is it going well?
But now I have tested. Now I want you to try this.
Do you want to hold it?
Immediately we get green.
Good. We immediately get green.
And then shivers.
What's your name? Can you say who you are?
Were you behind me before?
*No steps recorded*
I heard someone walking there.
Is a woman here with us?
*Loud bang in the building*
Did you hear that?
It came from that iron cabinet...
What was it?
Did you hear that?
Yes.
It is from outside.
That was it..
Although a duller bang.
*Loud bang in the building*
Now everything is starting to spin for me.
At the same time it sounds like a cricket, but we haven't had that in here.
No.
Things are starting to spin for Johanna.
She might feel something in the back of her neck there.
What is that sound?
I don't know if it's some cricket or...
Is it coming from outside or?
Now something happens.
It feels like someone is pushing, I kind of want to pull my head like this...
it's like someone is pushing like this.
What is it?
The battery on this one.
On which?
It went down to 20% now.
On the display?
Yes.
And then this strange sound.
Now it takes battery.
Should I break?
You can do that.
Wow strange. It was really like, I didn't feel like someone was pushing, but it felt like the head wanted to go that way. And then when I would pick it up, it was sluggish.
We said your name once, then you say your name.
Yes, green.
I really heard Johanna.
I have a headache.
Shall we cancel and go up?
Or are you going to run up and get a Sony camera and we'll continue a bit? We do Nighvision only here.
Okay.
We have switched to Nighvision because we don't have the normal camera we usually have. Because Viktor who has the camera has an extreme headache, we also have Lennie who has completely crashed, he is completely exhausted.
Wilma who also feels things, we haven't been up for a while so we don't know how the others are doing. But we had to send Viktor away so he can recover a bit.
We're continuing down here. I feel like it still works for me. Does it work for you?
Yes.
For you?
Same here.
We have tested the Estes Method and we got decent stuff on different instruments. Wait...
Now it's music.
Huh?
Is it music?
Didn't you hear music?
No.
With piano.
I hear it! I shiver!
Why do I hear this music? I hope the camera catches this.
*The music Niclas hears is not caught by the camera*
Is that the lady with the crooked neck walking down here?
Green on it.
Right there.
Thanks!
What shivers I have now, they come and go.
Do you Johanna want to go and stand there and look this way?
Okay, if there's someone behind Johanna, can you come here?
That's how Johanna gets to know you, if you're there.
I don't like this.
Does it feel like it could...?
I hear steps!
There is something behind it.
It's like someone is standing like this.
Will you show up for us tonight here?
*Knock*
Do you know what we do Johanna? We go up and check if Viktor is okay, then I think you and Wilma should walk around.
I want you to try sitting on the couch where the seans room was. And after that, I want you to go upstairs and test.
So we'll see if anything happens. We go and check how the others are doing.
Where do you want to go?
I am drawn to the room with the books. So if we go in there and see what I get through.
I have a PMB with me that I intend to place against this bookshelf.
What I will do now is that I open up and then I ask the energies...
to come here.
It is still this blue book that is being talked about. That's what I see connected to this man.
I'll see if I can get a name.
You standing there, could you touch any of the books?
Could you push something down from the bookshelf?
I would like to ask you to push something down from the bookshelf. Thank you so much for showing us so clearly.
*Steps in the other room*
*Whispers heard from the other room*
Surely there is someone whispering outside?
Oh God!
That's exactly what I heard.
As soon as I started with my hands.
What was that?
It was a great movement.
But God I saw some form here by the couch!
Step in here with us and affect the equipment again.
He's sneaking out there. He's sneaking around out there and it's like he wants to drag us out. Do you want to move to out there?
Does he want us to go out there?
Yes or so he....
I would like him to come in here first. If he comes in here, we'll gladly go out to see him later.
Oh my God!
This is absolutely insane.
Very strong.
Thanks!
We'd love to go out now.
Yes, now we have actually said it. We thank you very much and we will come out to you.
Now he is here! He plays here now.
He probably wanted to be in there himself then.
He wants us out.
Surely what he wanted.
I have such chills now.
Would you like to sit on the couch and I'll sit on the floor?
Can I place this?
Put it between us here.
And the energy that I was in contact with in there is standing in the doorway watching us. It's like they're charging up for something to happen here.
If we have someone with us now..
Thank you.
Is your name George?
Thanks!
Is that your book George you keep showing me? Does that book belong to you?
Thanks.
I see him charging up a lot, with energy before he can answer. He has quite weak energy in him, not that powerful so a lot is required of him.
Thanks!
Could you take out the book and show us?
If a book falls now I die...
I know you have affected and torn that book down, can you do it again?
*Loud bang in the building*
What was that?!
What was that?
Was it a book?
It could have been a book.
It was from there! Yes.
Yes, it was from there. 100%
From upstairs.
It sounded like a chair was knocked over or something.
It was right after we asked him too.
It was like someone threw something.
Shall we check out the library down there?
No book lying.
The stones are still there too.
I heard it like it was coming from the hall.
Yes, I heard it from your side as well.
There's no one here. Now it's all crickets we hear. Me and Tony are sitting with our headphones on and we hear this bang, we feel it on the floor.
And everyone says it came from where we're sitting. Johan, who is sitting without headphones, says that it comes from outside.
This is very difficult.
*Loud bang in the building*
This house has been on our bucket list for as long as we've had the paranormal interest.
The dream of one day getting to the USA and getting to investigate this house has become a dream and it now feels almost unreal to stand in this famous house.
We entered the house with the knowledge of what happened to the previous owners and the hopes of experiencing something like this are high.
We got to feel the feeling of being watched early on and the whole group was affected in different ways.
What stands out during this investigation is the sound of steps in the basement. And an evp that the cameraman perceived.
But what affected us the most is the distinct bang that everyone heard, but the cause of which we could not find.
We thoroughly went through the whole house and outside, but without finding the cause of the noise.
If we get the chance, we will go back one day and hopefully see and experience what made the Perron family leave for good.