There are many houses around the world, in which paranormal phenomena happen.
The house that really stands out is a house located at 24 Jelen Rynek, in Poland.
There are many stories surrounding the house and no one really knows the source of the evil that resides there.
Other families left the house very quickly. Within 10 years, more than 30 families have moved out.
That's right, no one has stayed that long.
Around 1940, a house is built for a family and their two children. As soon as they moved in, the parents started arguing.
It even goes so far that the father in the family abuses the wife and children.
Time passes and after a couple of years the children disappear under mysterious circumstances.
A rumor spreads in the village that it is the father who has murdered the children and that they are buried in the basement.
The parents flee the country and during a house search bloody tools are found in the basement.
But the remains of the children were never found.
In 1961, a new family moved into the house. Those who have now moved in start calling the police about strange phenomena starting to happen in the house.
They hear someone walking in the attic, things are thrown in rooms where no one is, and the daughter of the family screams in the middle of the night, which wakes the whole family up.
When the parents enter the daughter's room, she is hovering above her bed.
It went so far that the Catholic Church sent priests to the house to perform an exorcism.
Despite attempts to clean the house, no one has succeeded in making it completely calm.
We have now been around and tried to interview people, Simon has helped. Do the stories match? We have tried our best, unfortunately not many people want to join.
So I still think that we have received very good things from those who are here in the immediate area.
So exciting to see what happens here tonight.
Then we are here in the Poltergeist house here in Poland. We also have here and did a live, it can be seen on the website.
We recognize this house, we have been here before with Spökjakt, a lot happened then. Danjal was dragged in the leg, banging in the house and things being thrown.
So there is a lot that happens and is said to happen here. Over 30 families are said to have fled here.
And earlier today, very interestingly, we got Theodor through during our live broadcast from here.
And a witness outside, an elderly man, talks about how there were two Theodors here. A father named Theodor and he named his son Theodor Jr. So we got that confirmed very quickly.
He was also able to tell that an exorcism has been performed here in the house, so that is also confirmed and it is super interesting for the evening.
It's time to go inside, the surveillance cameras are ready. We will test different sessions, we have Simon from Poland who will translate some Polish words that come through.
Mixed sessions, we will go through the basement and up to the attic. But we will first go into the living area itself.
We go in.
As I said, we were here and played a live and it feels...
it feels different in the house, I don't know how to say.
I got chills immediately when we entered, just standing in the hall. And now it's also much quieter, we don't have the traffic outside.
We have installed k2 meters. 6 pcs, Rem Teddy is there too.
And if something comes close, they will react. We have some balls too, Niclas.
Shall we place them on the piano here? If something is thrown.
We allocate a little bit.
PRP there.
We put a parascope here.
We will mix Swedish and English, Simon will run a session in Polish later.
If there's anybody in here with us, can you come up with any of the things that are on the floor here?
I shivered when I said his name, it was strange. Theodor was something that came through on our live broadcast, several times.
And as I said was confirmed by someone we spoke to out here.
Immediately!
I got a pain here in the side, like something was stabbing me.
It's cool, when I try to film it keeps getting out of focus.
And it is classic from here, that it is not possible to focus, many say that it is not possible to focus the image.
What shivers, it's really freezing in here.
You called for him and this is what we get.
Direct answer.
I'll try an Ovilus at the same time and see if I can get any communication with him.
It's interesting though that it stops here..
now it continues.
It's wandering around now.
There it disappeared.
I have a hell of a lot of discomfort from the doorway. By a great deal of discomfort I mean it feels like I'm being watched and when I look over there quickly...
then it feels like someone is standing there. It's a little hard to focus because we have a surveillance camera there.
Yesterday we saw a little child walking, a black shadow walking there.
Now at Ovilus we got..
Now a lot comes through here.
Theodor, are you the one who murdered your children?
Now I get pain in my back, it jumped from here up to my left shoulder. It's like I've been carrying a camera for a very long time.
Now it starts to ache in the entire spine, as if it is taking energy from you.
I asked about this with the children.
Did you strangle your children?
I think we put PRP here.
Touch the antenna.
As soon as I said that, I start to shiver, my back gets cold.
Do it?
Shit I shiver...
Throw that cross down if you don't believe.
I think we're moving on, we're leaving this room.
Now we are in the room where the radio was before, now it has been removed. But it was here before, in the corner.
I put the PRP here on the couch.
More symbols of God and Jesus.
Yes.
What was that sound?
Is that the floor?
It sounded like something bounced...
The surveillance image is behaving strangely.
Show your power here now. You have caused so many families to flee from here.
The picture is slow and blurry.
Are you mad that we're here?
I have slight dizziness, it spun once.
Who are you? Why are you here and why are you attacking people?
You pushed a person down the stairs here.
Why did you push him?
The picture is still slow and blurry.
So you mean he slipped?
You weren't the one who did it?
If it wasn't you who did it, tap once somewhere.
2 knocks and some strange noise.
Can you knock like this?
2 knocks.
This painting here has been thrown down. Can you throw it down?
After Tony knocks on the room, the surveillance freezes.
If you don't like the Jesus symbol here, throw the painting down.
Then the image drops again, could the house have done this so we wouldn't get anything on film at the board?
Every time I say it, I get chills down my spine. A chill creeps behind me..
Forced boy.
It's a theory we're thinking about, the dark that's here, maybe it forced the father Theodor, or the son, we don't really know which of them it is, to do things.
Did you become obsessed with something?
Do you have the Flux on you?
Yes.
What came in here now? Now you can also communicate with this flashing light, soon it will be blue.
Did you become obsessed with something?
Were there six people possessed here? There are over thirty families who have left here.
I'm just going to check here quickly.
Throw some china.
There is a lot of crack here. It's because we walk on the floor, it creaks all the time.
Every time you say something, it creaks, but it's the floor.
Has there been anything here that is connected to Auschwitz
All this tragedy and evil that was there.
Did it accumulate and come here to this house somehow?
It's only 20 minutes from here.
We have the theory that German was also here doing his shit..
Come into this room.
Touch the blue light here.
If we have any children here..
We have an underground cellar down there. With rammed earth floor.
You don't know about the children's...
We go down there, we take the two of them and go down there.
Okay, we follow what Ovilus says.
We know where it is.
We're going down there right now.
Take the Flux with you.
Now we go down into the basement here and those of you who have seen the first time we were here with Spökjakt, it was down here that I saw this rock that fell.
After all, it said Soil, so we go straight to the soil trampled floor.
Lay the instrument out on the ground there.
Here we have soil.
It has a very low ceiling.
We're down here now.
Kill.
Were you buried here?
Are the children buried here?
Were you murdered in this room?
Nothing here.
We'll take the next room too.
If Theodor is here...
walk up to any of the equipment and we'll know you're still in this house.
It feels like it's just moving around us.
Come down here. If you are here with us..
come down and touch these lamps.
We got 6 up there too.
Are there six spirits left here?
Who are you then?
Do you know you are dead?
Strange noise in the basement.
Wait..!
A voice that Tony hears.
It sounded like...
..it sounded like a child..
I thought I saw something black right here.
It might have been my eyes playing tricks on me when I looked into the lamp. But it looked like something black was there.
Not big at all, very low...
Did I just see you?
Touch the lights if you're in here now.
We're shifting a bit, you can try standing here. Then we'll see if you get something through.
And if it's a little bit calmer here, we'll get up to the attic.
If there's a child here, can you come in here and ring that bell that's over there?
Can we hear your voice?
You can come in and grab this iron stick or walk up to the light flashing over here.
I'll start Ovilus too, see what it tells me.
The battery dropped quite quickly from 75 and now it stands at 66.
The figure 6 has been pretty consistent here.
It could have been an ir light, otherwise you got a light phenomenon at you. Or a reflection.
It may have been a reflection.
Are we just going to test a theory, we pull out the cable, we have a surveillance camera here...
Sometimes it happens that there is more activity when it is not documented in the same way. So we try pulling the cable out here. Then we'll see what happens.
Immediately!
You see, right away!
You don't want to be filmed from the front, do you?
I don't know if you feel it, but it was a completely different feeling in here.
There was a shiver behind my back that went as I stood there doing it.
Always.
It's goosebumps deluxe when I'm standing in here now.
It is an extreme discomfort from here. At that doorway.
Do you mean them here or?
It said Scratch and heard...
We might feel someone scratching.
Okay, we'll try putting the monitoring back in then.
Then we plug it in. I'll see if anything happens, I've been keeping track of this for a while.
We're doing this Tony, we're going up in the attic.
It was on this staircase that Danjal was pushed.
Here somewhere he was stuck with his leg.
Right.
You can also see here that we have a doll that we found here at the place.
We put a motion detector behind, in case something gets in. And you know how they sound, they say Hello welcome.
This doll..
this doll is very, very special.
Missing a leg too. I'm putting a PRP in front of her here and we'll see what happens.
Where you stand Niclas, that's where Danjal got pulled in the leg. It was also here that we heard the loud bang, loud noises, like the building shaking.
We have the boxes here.
The suitcases. They are completely empty.
Scraping noise and a high tone
What was that?
Huh?
A loud note..
Bang out there.
It's a special feeling up here.
It was so intense up here when we were here. You have to keep that in the back of your mind when you move around here.
Sound down there.
Shall we put the Flux down there?
Do it.
I keep the flashlight on so I don't hit my head on the beams.
We have traffic, we have a major highway a little further away, we have cars passing by...
it's very late here, so we don't understand why cars are going...
I'll also say it's Sunday.
And we don't wear microphones, it's because we want to hear all these sounds. Because there are so many things that have been thrown away...
Exactly.
Thrown stuff.
I'm going down with this one.
I'm coming with.
I can barely get here..
Very strong.
If you back off a little, I can get closer to you.
There it backed up, good! It listens.
Do you notice that it immediately follows your commands?
Is that Theodore?
Now it went behind you.
And then we got movement in that direction, I think.
It really follows what you say.
Now I saw something, something white behind you. A little further up on the right. I thought it was a human.
I can't focus at all now... here it comes.
You know like you see in a ghost movie, something transparent? It was up at the edge there.
It looked like a...
We'll test the theory and pull the surveillance out here.
Where do you mean exactly as you saw it?
Diagonally up there, we have a small point of light there in the ceiling. You see the slanted ceiling?
There yes.
And then maybe one and a half meters down.
Yes, there.
Now it's just us here.
It becomes completely out of focus when I stand here.
So, you get it on command. You control it somehow.
It also jumps around, I want to be able to communicate with it.
Somehow I get a calmness throughout my body, a sense of security.
So what's here isn't...
evil in any way. But it can also be false security.
That's exactly where it is.
Then it disappears, it's so fucking crazy.
If it's the children here, come near me.
My theory is that it's something pretending to be calm. But still a discomfort came back now.
There.
Wondering why it listens to me when I tell it to reverse..
Green there.
I'll turn this off now and then I'll test Ovilus. Testing if they want to say their name. It's strange, we got Beast and Gone there before, right?
Yes.
If it is the one who is here..
The one who moves in here. And you stand on a spot where we were before, so the whole house shook.
Right.
I'm pulled away from here, I'm pulled this way.
We'll go there then.
I plug this one back in.
We got well too. We've had that before.
The theory is also that the children were thrown into a well that was covered with stone.
Give us a sign that you are up here with us now.
A loud sound would be great.
Or knock us over.
Throw something.
Is this your doll?
Say what you wish.
We wish this doll would fly off the chair.
Can you do it?
Can you throw something in here?
I'm thinking like this now Tony, we know what it was like when we did the live stream, spiritbox. Then it started.
We bring in Simon as well.
I'm going to get the Flux down there, but should we leave this one?
We can leave it on. Take the Flux and we'll go back into the house.
Now we're outside, we brought Simon here too.
Who's in here with us?
Is Theodor here with us?
"Maybe"
What dark entity is in this house?
Are you from Germany?
"Yes"
What do you want?
Are you mad at us?
"Move"
It just said roughly stick or move yourselves.
Where are we going?
"Up"
When we are going up to the attic this happens with the camera.
If you are up here make a loud noise.
Have you lived here?
Do you want us into the dark room?
Did we see you?
Can you make the house shake?
"Yes"
Are you standing here?
"Standing here"
Why are you here?
"I don't know"
What's your name?
Is there a dark entity with us up here?
Are you standing here?
Shall we go there?
"Go"
We're going down now. We've been testing up here and trying to get in touch. We have something down the corner and we see now that Simon is communicating in his language that he is constantly getting answers.
We will also test Este's method on Simon.
"Go"
There we got a Go.
"You can"
We ask many questions but no answer.
I think we're breaking here.
We decide to switch communication tools to Ghostbox.
"I am"
I just asked if the children are still on this land.
Are they buried here?
"Yes"
I thought I heard something...
Behind here..
"Yes"
Okay, you are in that room then.
"Quiet"
He doesn't want you to talk to him.
"Yes"
"He's listening"
Battery drains very quickly, from 26 to 19%.
We must break soon.
We must break soon or we will lose this.
"I see"
Shall we break there then?
We do it.
So we don't lose the session, so we change the battery.
"Yeah, go"
Lennie, now we've changed a bit. Tony got in the car with Simon so you and I get in and you get to run a Paranormal Puck.
I have this in my pocket. Paranormal Puck 2. I also have the phone where we type the questions.
We test everything possible here because we are in contact with something dark in there. So we'll see.
I'll put it down there.
We put the Puck down by the instruments. Your phone will flash a bit, but it's just iphones, they flash. Now we see all the dots there, it has nothing to do with this feature.
Shall we start asking questions then Niclas?
Write and ask if Theodor is here.
Is Theodor here?
Memories of Theodor are here.
You can also say that, if it is a demon that has been here from the beginning. They did an exorcism here, so we're starting to understand that it's back here.
I know it goes down in the basement too. There is a dirt floor there, so you can interpret that as dirt, perhaps.
We've had that theory, but we also believe when we go down there, we don't get anything, but it's up here.
But if we say that everything has started down there, in the earth floor, it is not entirely impossible that the dark has been projected from there.
And got into the building here. Because it is precisely in this room that there is the greatest discomfort. The wind is decent, but it's here. You feel the most here, I think.
Didn't get an answer..
Very interesting actually because something always comes through.
When you asked that question, if something is buried in the dirt... nothing came of it.
Almost like our theory is starting to hold true.
Maybe through the camera then. Or the other surveillance camera.
I shiver. Damn I'm starting to shiver.
Damn awesome! I'm thinking if you should ask about something Christian..
It's also damn exciting, if it were to be. They want us to think it's a nun, something religious, but that it's something else trying to influence.
Then there is no one who likes the religious.
*What's being recorded now scares us*
*It's just Lennie and Niclas in the room, but a voice is being recorded laughing or growling at us.*
There was another voice!
What was that?
Someone else was also laughing with us.
What the hell was that Niclas?
There was another voice laughing at the exact same time as you.
Who called Jesus Christ a Witch.
Now we're starting to talk, now maybe he's here.
Kind of like Niclas.
It almost starts saying my name.
There was another voice that came in.
So damn clear it was.
A real  laugh. When we both laughed, it laughed with us.
No answer.
Now there is no nun anymore. When it called Jesus Christ a Witch.
Now I haven't even written anything and had to sneak.
And that means sneaking up on someone.
Exactly.
And you didn't even write anything?
No nothing.
Okay.
But that was so damn uncomfortable. Damn how unpleasant.
That's why I want to film with a microphone, because then we capture everything. If we had something else, we probably wouldn't have gotten it. It was perfectly clean!
There was one more voice. We got a dark, dark voice through ghostbox.
We go into where the painting and the cross are, bring Paranormal Puck there. We ask a few questions there.
Something is moving in the kitchen.
Did you hear?
What was that?
Something sounded out there.
It sounded like cutlery...
It sounded like it came from the kitchen.
There are teacups up there, wonder if it was one that sounded?
I ask a question.
Evp is recorded.
"Man's voice"
So it's a lot down to the basement there.
It's sick when we talk about children and digging.
Paranormal Puck stands there and you stand there. What if we put it exactly on the floor? Because right below there is the dirt.
What if it's some sort of portal?
I think it's really uncomfortable going into the kitchen now.
But it was the porcelain that sounded. We have previously asked if they can move something there.
It's like they're stuck there...
so they keep them there in the basement, but I'm wondering why.
What they should have done here is dig out the bottom of the house. See what they get out there, if there are bones...
if anything, certain energies remain tied to this house.
Shall we test the kinect in here?
We can do that.
We'll go around in here and see if we can get an up mapping. We got some good stuff on Paranormal Puck.
Really.
So we go get it.
Do we have anyone in this room with us? Show yourself now!
Come into this room now.
Back to bed.
I stand here and look at the piano.
It's like it's creeping around..
It doesn't want to show itself in any way.
Shall we try going in there?
I'm checking to see if anyone is standing here in the kitchen.
There was something that sounded at the mugs before.
Then we go into the room where we have a picture of Jesus.
And a cross. That picture has flown down.
Says the owner.
Is there anyone with us in this room?
Strange, because it really feels like there is something here.
We have felt a discomfort. If you back off a bit, we'll just hold it out here. So we try to call in what is there.
No up mapping here. We have also tested the basement and the attic.
Shall we try going up to the attic and check?
There! From the piano.
It's the bed.
It was like it lay there then crawled out.
It's the first up mapping we have here.
We make an attempt and go up.
At the doll!
Just like someone was sitting there. Now it's nothing.
Now someone is hanging above.
Two!
One is sitting on the chair, one is..
It's either hanging above or standing....
It almost looks like it's standing on the chair.
Sick!
Damn awesome.
What was that?
Is there something that sounds in front of you?
Here in the corner.
Now it is up on the roof.
It looks like he's climbing.
Now it climbs down.
It holds the ceiling. This is what happened to Danjal, he had something on his back when he walked here.
Right.
Wonder if it's the same energy hanging from the ceiling beams here.
I'll see if there's anything on the site here.
Nothing there. I feel a discomfort on the left side in here.
When you stand there?
Yes.
Shall we go further into the room?
It is so difficult with night vision when you have this screen.
Do we have anyone else in the room?
We had a good run down there in the corner?
There was something.
Someone is screwed up there.
Damn.
Looks like someone is hiding up here.
This is a little sneaky...
This is damn sneaky.
I'm just wondering what it is. That's how it was before, we had contact then it disappeared.
It's so sick, that it almost hides... You get hold of it and then it just disappears.
Here's another one.
Did you see?!
It was standing behind the chair here, almost standing on all fours.
Now we've run kinect and Paranormal Puck, we've got mappings up here.
But there is something that is not right here, there is something that calls itself what it is not..
It is so sneaky, first you look for it, then it disappears.
It's so sick.
The Poltergeist house in Poland really lives up to its expectations. As soon as we arrive at the house, we get shivers all over our bodies, something that everyone feels very strongly.
Talk about Jesus or other Christian words, then the discomfort comes right back.
Perhaps it is that the evil that was once tried to be cleansed by exorcism still remains.
During the investigation, we received many words that indicate that the children's remains may still be in the basement.
The question is what would you find if you start digging in the ground...
What was clearly felt most strongly, because we both heard and felt it physically, is the entity that calls itself Nun Sally.
Is she the one who stays behind and sucks in spirits and souls? Or is it the house itself that keeps them locked inside the walls of the house?
It seems that those who remain do not know why they are there.
Once again we see the theory of not having all the cameras running, works. And that the activity increases when we pull out one of the surveillance cameras.
We then got to experience phenomena that we haven't been able to experience for a long time.
What is in the house has such power that it can even freeze the image on our surveillance system. Just like it knows it is being documented.
We have never experienced this image freezing before in all our years as investigators.
In the attic, we got two mappings of energies through our sls camera. Could this be Theodor or the children who wanted to show themselves to us?
If we summarize the investigation from the Poltergeist house, we can say that it has been a long time since we experienced such strong phenomena during an investigation.
Bringing out the name Theodor, which is highly topical for the house, as a previous owner means that we got one step closer to who is still there.
But the darkness that rests over the place is something else entirely. It is a force that you should have great respect for when you are in the house.
You never know what it is capable of, but those who have the courage to visit the house, at Jelen Ryned 24..