There are few times in Laxton's history that we have difficulty putting words
on an investigation we will conduct.
But this time it really is.
It is with mixed feelings that we are now back in our childhood apartment in Kiruna.
Where everything started almost 35 years ago.
Memories from our childhood flushes over us, and the interior of the apartment
As our mother built and installed is still there.
We have the purpose of being back right here and it is ...
Becomes contact stronger at the place where our cousins Peter and Johanna
spent his last time in life?
And can we get in touch with our mother who loved this apartment?
Then we have entered here in our childhood apartment.
-We are up in Kiruna, so we have made our way to the apartment where we grew up.
Where it all started and where Laxton also grew up.
What I mean is that it grew up, the interest started in this apartment.
We had paranormal phenomena that happened here, which made us so fascinated
That we stand here today.
I can say like this that do you want to know what it was like for us to step into this apartment
For the first time, we have done a pod about this that you can listen to.
There is also a video odd so you can watch it if you want to do it.
What is so special to be here and talk about memories with our one sister.
Who started telling memories that didn't even remember.
It was totally sick.
I don't even remember the paranormal memories, I've suppressed them.
So there are certainly more memories inside the head of one, but they are gone.
-But it is special to be back and we have to thank those who have the apartment today.
That we may come here.
Because the apartment itself is not haunted right now.
We always go to places where it is said that a lot of things happen.
Now we got the chance when we were in Kiruna to actually visit this apartment.
And now we will find out if we can get in touch with Peter and Johanna.
Our cousins that tragically passed away in this fire in 1988.
Where they spent their last hours in this apartment.
Shit what dizzy I became when I talked about them.
It just spins ...
My eyes ... it feels like I would start to faint when I said that.
That was damn uncomfortable.
-It can also be when you listened to the pod, we talked about the wrong year.
You get completely gone.
But we should not forget that there are a lot of emotions here.
Our own feelings that the brain starts to work with when we came in here.
Because it is so many years we lived here and experienced things.
What is the unique when we come here as Tony said
So those who live here now do not notice anything at all.
But we should try in an experimental way.
I can't even talk.
- We will try with an experiment.
This is strange, we always be able to convey directly.
So I'm a swine.
Wondering what the hell was that happened there.
We will test different things and see if we get in touch with Peter and Johanna.
But also our mother who loved this apartment.
- There are details left from our upbringing that mom brought here.
They are repainted now, but we will be close to this.
But we will then seek contact with loved ones, which we have never done in this way before.
But now we are in this apartment and then we will see who wants to get through.
She who lives here now has no activity, but she said we want to test our theory around this
So you have this apartment to do it in.
Now I start to shudder about my legs.
So this is totally sick.
- I wonder if I should sit down.
Shall we back in or should I ...
- No, go and sit on the couch.
- I sit down for a while on the couch.
- But if we say they are here now and they come in, because they hear that we are talking about them.
I don't know what it is, there is something heavy here.
It is very difficult to say if there is something paranormal or if it is the brain that works.
- I don't know either, it was ...
... a dizziness that came only came from nowhere.
I thought "now I'm fainting here".
We have lots of stuff here now.
- Yes we have instruments that are here.
.
We have never done anything like this before, now we should actively seek contact with our cousins
Who passed away in this fire, and our mother.
- Exactly, but should we first try ...
Oh my brain.
I do not know what it is.
I shake and ...
I can also say that I felt bad and had a headache since we came here.
I don't know, but should we first seek contact with the mother?
We have a PRS here, which has static fields and now we place it right in front of us.
Then we have a new thing ahead of us too, should we post it too?
Or should we just take an instrument?
We know that there is nothing that disturbs the person who lives here now.
But do we drag anything with us?
That is the question.
I place this one, and we'll see.
And you who have seen it know for sure about close contact and static fields.
- Okay, we back here then.
We have lived in this apartment for many years.
This is where we celebrated Christmas Eve together.
So if Peter or Johanna is still here ...
Could you be able to go up to
This tool that is on the table and touching the stick that is there?
If you are here, go up to
This thing that is on the table.
Is our mother here?
Irene.
Are you with us?
Take energy from us, something affected us when we came in here.
I don't know what it is.
But take energy from us.
Stir the instrument here.
When we were little here, things were thrown.
If you have that kind of power
So you have to do it too.
And when we say Irene, it's the name of our mother.
We put this new one too.
We can only direct it straight out here.
I thought we should place it somewhere on the floor.
We were sitting on the Christmas table
Here somewhere.
Should I post it?
We take the chair here.
So if something then comes
So you see that it gets
White
It's this pyramid
So if
Irene, our mother.
If you can get through stronger.
Now that we are in this apartment where there was a lot of joy.
A lot of children, we were many children.
Is there more
Chances for us to talk to you here?
Can you come in to us here?
And touch this iron stick.
-A real shudder came and went here now.
- You sit in an active corner then when we lived here.
Right in that corner there were a lot of things that happened, we had a guitar.
We had a guitar that was here and then ...
What I was told that I forgot about was the paranormal event that
Someone played on those guitars when I was home alone, so I panicked.
And this I don't remember, I've probably suppressed it.
- Mom, if you're here with us
can you touch this white
The thing that is on the chair here?
Can you go past it once only?
Can you do it now?
After all, there are not so big rooms here.
So we don't have that much surface to move, there are lots of furniture too.
- but we take a room successively and
We start with this everyday living room really.
Is Peter here?
Busy Peter, are you here?
Can you touch that white pyramid on the chair?
- Johanna, if you're here ...
I remember when you were standing in the hall with your red dress and asked if you could sleep over here.
Some feel you at the museum in Borås as well.
But if you are here now
In this apartment where you spent
Your last hours with Peter and your entire family.
Can you touch that white pyramid that is on the chair.
Can you knock somewhere?
In this way.
- It sounded from there.
After you knocked, a knock came from there.
- From the toan?
Should we check?
Here is this hall Niclas.
Where the horse flew down.
It was something that flashed after you.
- Did it blink after me?
Can we put an instrument here?
Should we take the pyramid?
- Good, now it's something.
Who is here?
If it is you Peter, then get it to blink again.
No, it was Johanna you talked about.
- Did you hear knocks Johan?
- Yes, when you knocked in the table, it just knocked out here
At the end of the corridor, I have a free ear so I hear.
- What instruments should you have?
- I'll take this pyramid.
I put this in the corridor again.
Here it fell a horse, a small toy horse
from the roof
When I was with my best friend here.
When I was little.
Can the one who did it, I think it was Peter or Johanna who wanted to cuddle a little.
Can you arrive
And touch the one on the floor now?
It was something that snapped here.
- But if you stand here.
So I sit here.
- I take some communication now, I take the Polterscript.
So we try to communicate with
Either our cousins or mom who are here.
Anyone here with us?
Johanna.
Peter.
Or our mother.
Can you knock again here?
I'll be here in the corridor to you
If you are here.
It must be special that we are back here, if you are with us.
Take our energy and
Communicate with us if you like.
Nothing here on
The Polterscribet either.
Do you get anything inside Niclas?
It is this dizziness that I feel all the time.
- It feels like I have blood sugar drops, I just sit and shake.
I do not know what it is.
Mom, if you can get through here now
So go beside Tony there
And use that thing he has in his hand.
Should we try to move that to that corner?
- I'll take the triangle back, because I think it's good to bring.
So we see if they ...
- Now I start it.
Now we have sat here in the living room again and we just have the things here.
Because I want to...
I don't want to run around.
You understand what I mean.
We will go to those rooms and successively test to be there.
And try to be there.
And that's a theory we want to test now.
And we know that this comes in waves all the time.
We have put our PRS there
which takes static fields and the REM function in that corner.
Where we experienced things.
We had a statue that fell there, we had
Something that played on the guitar, who pulled on the strings though no one was in the room.
But I don't understand why you feel like this.
- The instruments right now indicate nothing.
Nothing on communication either, but the body reacts to anything.
And I don't know if it's just because you mentally and mentally think about being here.
With all the memories that it is so.
But we'll see.
That said, we
Have never done it this way before.
To actively seek contact with
Our relatives, our loved ones.
- Peter, Johanna
As you walked away
So things started to happen in this apartment.
Was it you who played on that guitar?
That scared me.
I didn't really understand what it was.
We really want you to get as close as you can, into this room.
You see this white pyramid here, if you go in front of it
So it will start to shine white, and then it means you are in front of it.
And it doesn't hurt you.
-Nothing like this anyway
Who wants to get in touch with us now.
So it is after all
interesting.
- If we take this theory
For she who lives here, she has her loved ones next door.
And they might be walking around here
And don't let in any others.
And they don't want to talk to us at all.
- Should we just test that theory and ask a question ...
The one who lives here today?
She has let us in here.
Is any of
Her family's relatives left here?
In this apartment?
Can you arrive at any of these
The things we have?
- There we have static down there.
- Now it shines.
- Good.
You who have come here now, you who are in the corner where we have
Tagged and known
Giants what it is strong in that direction.
Very strong.
And that's exactly in the corner it was.
And now it comes.
- And what do we have here?
- Can you get it to be piped at once if it is Peter who is here?
Can you get it to pipe twice if it's Peter?
- Two, did you hear?
It gets stronger and stronger.
It has lit all the lights, don't you see it?
- I see it, I don't understand what it does there.
There is such a jerk field around that now.
- Peter
Stir the antenna vigorously.
Now all lamps go on static field.
There extinguish ... no they are still there.
Can you do
make a
Cushion for "yes" and two for "no"?
Peter, are you with us?
At the museum?
Have you come here Peter, now that we got to this apartment?
"yes"
Here Peter I have one thing in my hand.
-If you want to say something to Tony, go near him there.
Can you make it beep longer by holding that iron stick longer?
- So that field came from nowhere.
Again you get a feeling, you put this one instead and so
- Theoretically why was it in the corner we experienced things?
Why exactly that corner?
And here we now see that the static field is very strong.
Do you have Johanna with you too?
- "No" ice cream, there were almost three beeps.
Do you have Irene there, our mom?
Are you Peter yourself?
- Are you alone?
- "Yes"
- Peter ...
We assume it is you, because it seems that you answer when we ask if it is Peter.
Is it
That corner
As all activity was strongest.
Why exactly that corner?
It sounded like it was small in the wall at that corner.
- Can you go to any other tool?
Can you release ...
“growing”
-We see that something is growing here now, is you trying
make you visible to us?
Can you show up for us?
So we can see you?
I wonder if we are directing the pyramid in that direction Tony, if you put it on the edge.
- “baby”
It was very strong now.
- Don't you want me to put the pyramid in that direction?
- "David"
- David is my friend.
- "Complete"
My God what it builds up energy.
"medicine"
“49 years”
- What is going on?
- It's really strong!
- We are putting the pyramid in this way now.
“Kitchen”
Here you get it, put it on the support there.
It said "grows".
It's just to check, it's like you want to pop popcorn or something.
- go by between me here
Or between the sofa and this office once, can you do it?
Pass here
in that way.
- What is going on?
- It sucks out the battery.
-I have never seen this.
I've never seen this before.
It's really strange.
- Really.
- I'll pick up another instrument.
- Peter
Are you left here in the corner?
“writes”
"remove"
- Wait, it's really strange.
It feels like trapped air.
And the smell was like ...
There was a very heavy air here ...
How the hell should I explain that, it was really strange.
- Should I try to remove it and put it back on the table?
- No, let it be.
- Should it remain there?
- What we start up now is one that will show green on one side and red on the other side.
And use it as "yes" and "no".
And when we start this now they get to choose
to respond to it as well by the fact that
make it shine.
Then we take red as “no”
and green as "yes".
Peter, do you see the lamp that flashes there now?
Can you go to it?
If you leave it there and go to the next?
Or is it Irene who has come here now?
So I was completely breathless only I went to the kitchen.
My eyes just run.
This is really strange.
- It would have been interesting that if it continues if we remove it from the field there ...
We try, then maybe I happen to touch this one just.
I understand how much that
What a power field that just ... we try again then.
- What is that in the corner?
- Who came from nowhere?
- But take it back here.
You see how it works, Tony happened to touch the machine over there now.
If you want to answer "no" to the questions then get it to shine red.
If you want to answer "yes", get it to shine green.
Okay, if you want to use this still, just come here.
-It jumped from there to here and it continues.
So what is it?
Check.
- We hear you Peter.
If you have Irene ...
Now it is the REM function.
It's max.
Away...
Who came here now?
Or that might be
He was able to do?
- Yes, like a discharge.
Peter, are you left?
- Irene, are you here now?
Has Johanna come here?
It works.
- I thought the batteries had been drained on it.
- No, but as long as the red lamp shines, it will work.
This was really strange.
- You didn't really get what he wanted.
- No, but when we got "come", thus grow
So it started to grow more and more, but I don't know ...
If that was contact with Peter.
He wanted to ...
I asked if he could show up so we can see him.
But we didn't see anything because then it was suddenly at zero.
- But we also get very sedentary.
- We are testing another room.
I shut down here, so the energy must accompany us to the next room I think.
I think we take here.
- Yes this is sick, this is, as I said, that room there
I saw the plaster figure sliding.
Over the floor here.
When I sit right here.
- Shall we do like this
We put a PMB here.
To see if there is anything that wants ...
- I wonder if we should put something on the floor, where I saw the plaster figure slip.
And the PMB you who don't have
Look and know how it works, you can only show Niclas quickly.
He places his hand over the unit.
Then it sounds there.
- I'm completely exhausted.
I don't know what it is, if it is an emotional storm that is going on in the skull now.
- I don't want to sit down.
I want to stand, but will see if I can fit because it is quite crowded in here.
This was my room when I lived here.
And I saw those plaster figures that slid over the floor.
We start communication here as well, but you can go to the blue vibrant light.
What was that?
- I trampled on something.
- But you can go to the blue pulsating light if you want.
Or pass just above.
Or talk to us through this.
Does anyone with us here?
Peter
Johanna
Or our mother?
- Irene, if you can come in here
And put your hand in front of that game box.
You have been with us quite a few times I think.
So I think you know how it works.
I sit down.
- I'd rather sit in those chairs.
Where I sat before in my desk chair.
- Like recreating what it was like.
- "Begin", "Cold"
- I have to say that it feels cooler around the floor.
- That was exactly how it started.
The wire says "Begin", "Cold", that is how I sit here and feel the cold.
And when I turn around, I seem to see someone and I think the door is closed.
About where Johan stands.
That's when I see the plaster figure there.
The one of you who moved the plaster figure, you can come
To the floor here where it flashes blue?
- Peter
You were recently
And talked to us, we think it was you who came through.
And we haven't talked to you for a long time.
You have come through a little neighbor now and then.
But can you come in here too?
Do you see this game box standing on the bench?
If you touch it
Then it will play a little neighbor.
Do you see what lies and flashes on the floor?
Make it shine green for "yes" for example.
And red for "no".
Or if it is Johanna or mom who is also here
So get it to shine green if you hear me.
Get it to play.
If you hear me.
After all, we have felt a discomfort when we lived here too.
We also have
done the "spirit in the glass"
And such things.
Do you like that we are still using Ouija Boards?
Or does the "spirit in the glass"?
- "Behind" (behind) I got up now.
What do you mean by that?
Are you behind Johan there?
If any of you are out there, can you enter this room?
Recreate what you did, to move that plaster figure that
Was here then.
As our sister Tina received in Christmas present
by you Johanna, you can pull past
On the floor here now where it flashes blue.
No, we don't get anything on the instruments in this room either.
- We are testing one more room.
- Should we try your room across?
Here's your room.
You had an experience in bed where you felt like someone locked you.
- Yes, it was not like Peter and Johanna.
It felt like something else.
It can come from all the different Ouija boards used.
Everything cracked you did as younger, that you brought something with you.
What happens when we are in your room over there you had and in my room here
is that all rooms seem to lean in different directions.
It is a very strange feeling that it is leaning.
It feels like this room is leaning there.
If I had released a bullet now, it would have felt like it would stick in that direction.
We just put this out.
So if you want to run communication you can do it too.
- Yes, I'll start it at the same time.
- So we'll see if there is something that wants to come in to us here.
We'll see if it can shine red or green if something passes next to it.
- so what was with Niclas there
When he was little.
Maybe it was the teens?
- I don't really remember.
Are you left here then?
- I think about our sister's experience when she sits there on the bed and sees a woman here.
Who is that woman ice cream?
- This is the only room where we have experienced something other than Peter and Johanna.
- You feel damn tired.
It feels if we have been going around here for six hours.
It feels like it's starting to get late.
It is a very strange feeling.
-This is our theory now that we are testing to go back to our childhood home.
We try to communicate with loved ones
And see if they are here.
- If it is stronger.
- Or does it require it to be other items?
So I mean this experiment
We will also test at the haunted museum.
And then we stand among these objects.
And see if Peter and Johanna can in any way be stronger there.
Because they say Johanna is running around there.
So it is very interesting.
- It is as you say that it might be more the objects that are coming.
It may not be enough with these four walls, the shell
In this case, in other cases it may be that you have built the house
It is a stronger relationship with it that way.
But there is nothing here.
We come here and go in here, but it feels pretty ...
Quiet except Peter if he was there now, if he was now.
So it was just a very fast discharge.
- It may have been like this that during the time we lived here
So there has always been a portal in that corner.
Which built up that this was where they came through and we got something that went or came.
But we should also keep that in mind that what I said about the best thing is to test it at the museum
Because we have all had contact with loved ones there in some way.
Even those who work there, Johan, Lennie and Thesso get something there.
So I ask no one, Peter can you come in to us here?
Do you remember that Tony would come along and sleep over?
Where you slept your last night.
- Do you remember that I would sleep over with you on Ringvägen?
That Christmas night, or Christmas Eve.
- Do you remember Johanna asked if you could sleep here?
That you got to sleep over here instead of going home.
And here I think it's so damn interesting with all this we do now.
She says she has nothing here, we hardly get anything.
But we get where we had our activity.
It's pretty interesting.
It feels like I want to go back there.
- Should we try again then?
- We can try to add any other instrument, not static or strap but a PMB.
- We try it then.
- We test it.
Then we set it up.
- Then you have to sit closest to there and we will see.
We only run the PMB.
- Yes, we start there.
And as you can see, the first investigation we just sit in different places is.
It is very difficult, we try
Recreate as much as we can, because in this living room we sat.
We sat a lot and watched TV here.
We sat talking and busing.
- The whole Christmas Eve we were really here, this is where we sat.
So you think it's somewhere it could be ...
A recognition factor
that we still sit here at the table
We are in the same place
In that corner now there is a small box.
Peter, if you were here before
Can you come back again?
- The PMB does not take static or REM function.
It just runs on movement if there is something that passes
of density in front of it.
- It is also interesting with the tone we have.
Do you notice it?
We talk pretty quietly, pretty
Almost like a library.
It is not a higher volume, we keep fairly even
Monoton's voice, I don't know what it is, if it's because we're just at home.
"home"
And talking to family.
- I think this is built into our system in ourselves.
You could have this tone here, otherwise it was heard down to the neighbor.
I think so, you couldn't talk higher because then the neighbor started knocking or stomping.
- Yes, it's a theory.
- Admittedly, we were five, six children here plus parents and television.
It may also have been very alive.
So in that corner
There were two guitars.
And someone pulled on the strings on one guitar.
Was it you Peter who did it when I was here myself?
Get the PMB to play if it was you Peter, who did that.
Or was it you Johanna, who did it?
Because you would pay attention to me, that you are here.
It is also so damn special.
We have never done it this way before.
We have never addressed our loved ones.
- That they should come through.
- We really only go to active, haunted houses.
Where the client tells what happened.
Then we have to search a little wider and ask much broader questions.
But we don't want to do this.
I don't want to do this at all.
For I think the most important thing is if loved ones can get through stronger on
An old memory site really, this apartment.
And it was really a nostalgic trip we were involved today.
It has been brutal.
- That's what is interesting if you think ...
- Do you know what I came up with?
I think I saw a tennis ball on a floor here.
I think if I put it on the table as we have a case here
with a tennis ball.
I go and pick it up.
There is one here too.
A slightly larger tennis ball.
There you can see that it also settled.
- there we have a ball
Who has thrown in this apartment several times when we lived here.
Can the person who did it, throw this ball?
Get it to move, roll down on the floor.
- We have people we have met on here outside
who live in apartments all around here
that knows things.
Is it in the ground?
Because we are not far from the mine.
- So it is, which is also a theory.
But also what we felt initially when we came in here, but you do not know
If it is because it is such a strongly charged place for us.
It may not have to do with the paranormal, but more about the memories we have from here.
You think about everything you have been through, so it gets stronger that way instead.
And that may be the difficulty of being in the apartment right now as well.
You do not know what it is you really feel, you become very
drained, tired and a dizziness that you also felt before.
Is it paranormal or for a natural cause just because we are here?
And that we do something that we are not so used to.
To actually seek contact with our own.
- And what may make you hold back a little.
It feels right to do this.
Without them to come to one when they want to do it themselves.
- but the interesting thing is that
which we start to see here now litigran to
We don't get much.
When we address Peter, Johanna or Mom.
Although we lived here and spent a lot of time.
In this apartment.
But they will not come through this place.
- No, not as strong as we thought.
- We have had stronger, such as Empes.
Abisko we thought partly as well.
At the train station there, something happened.
- But should we test a Ghost box as well and see if there is any voice or memories left.
We get through ... so it started after all
Fixed with spirit box.
And the Ghost box is like a spirit box.
And I think it's so interesting.
Will Peter come through here?
And say the same words again.
- Would you recognize the voice then?
- I think I would definitely recognize my voice, but that's the word I don't remember.
But I start it.
Peter, if you are here now
Do you remember when Tony did this
for the first time?
- "Well"?!
Okay Peter, then you hear us?
Where are you now?
- Johanna
Can you come in to us now?
Mother
Irene
We are in your old apartment, can you come here and say hello to us?
Did it say "no I don't want to"?
It is very difficult to hear.
But then you also wonder if it was Peter who was there?
I do not know...
Had they been close now and been able to come through and say those words strongly.
Just when we were trying to address them, it had been very interesting.
We don't want to talk to anything else right now.
I don't want anything else now.
- Not here, that's not why we're here today.
In all other places we can address everything.
But here we just want to get in touch with them.
- And see if it is stronger on the site.
But something that is very interesting is why it is just that corner.
The guitars, the plaster figure, Jojon are from this place.
- So there can be something else then.
- It may have been a portal that has been there for any length of time.
So that this is where the energies have come through as strongly.
So this is also the case that when we sit here ...
I feel this that
In a way I'm glad they're not here now
if you understand what I mean.
That they can visit us when they want to.
That is the feeling I get now and it is a lot of medium that says it too.
Right now there are no memorial energy of them here either, I think.
It's something
Here that I think has something to do with the ground.
But she does not disturb it who lives here.
And I'm not going to ask for anything else to come in either.
Nothing else.
Without it, our loved ones we want
talk to.
What is happening now
It also strengthens our theory a little.
It becomes...
It is quiet in a place where it is quiet.
And we can say that when we are in contact with so much people
that says they have activity at home
Then we have it to go on.
She said that we had to borrow the apartment but that she has a great time here.
- So it wasn't really the apartment itself, but more an attempt to get it together.
Does it get stronger?
Can I get the contact we had with those phenomena?
When we come in here, do we have something with us?
No, not that way.
Not here.
Here they choose not to come through.
- And this will be so interesting to test later.
At the haunted museum.
Where we know that
Johan got such strong contact with loved ones.
We have Johanna running there, but we have never addressed Peter or Morsan there.
Where these objects are so strong.
And there we can also address something else.
And there it is usually the variables;
Is it really you.
To ask those questions.
But we see here.
Nothing.
- and nice anyway for the one who lives here when we talked after this
That it is calm, it is nothing here.
Just as she confirms, and we can even with our theory say that
No, there was no more activity because we went back to childhood home
Where everything started.
We get to round this up and do the experiment at the haunted museum.
- If you sum up what we got to be with
So we think it was Peter we got in touch with who answered us via the PRS.
All activity came from the corner that was also an active place in the apartment when we lived there.
Maybe it's a portal to something else.
But it is important to remember that those who live here today do not know anything paranormal.
The strongest message was what came through the Polterscrip.
With the words "medicine", "sugar" and "49 years".
All these words are well in line with Niclas
who just been told to be close to type 2 diabetes.
What we can conclude after this investigation
is that it doesn't matter where you are to get in touch with your loved ones.
The contact does not get stronger in a specific location.
The contact can be established wherever you are.