Already after a couple of weeks, small green balls appeared -
where the rhubarb leaves stretched after the sun
Then came the drought.
The muddy soil that I touched around solidified to a hard crust
And burst into a grid pattern so my rhubarb jam looked like the pictures from a drying disaster in Africa.
The rhubarb cannot be able to get through.
But it made the weeds.
Admittedly, the quick root had to make an effort, but thistles and the horse hood seemed to be happy.
The lack of it
So they also have roots that go far down to the moisture in the underground.
I chopped and cleared so much I got
but seemed to constantly get on afterwards
There was so much else I needed to do at the same time.
My hatching was filled with eggs and when the chickens started to grow they have to have somewhere to live
To make the old chicken house in order became a priority project
First I cleared out the old broken interior
The doors for chickens and fertilization were skewed and murky so I built new ones.
I rounded perch for them to be comfortable for the chickens.
I built a foreclosure with compost grates under the pins to easily take advantage of the fertilizer
and in order for the chickens not to go in and warm on the floor in the darkest corner
The plan was excellent.
I had spent a lot of time pondering how I want a sensible hen house that would work just as well
For me as for the chickens.
It was the reality that was the problem.
I want dense walls in the hen house because pulls are worse than cold for chickens
But when I started to put up slices on the walls, the screws did not attach.
The old wood was rotten.
And when I started changing the old board wall, the rules behind were also rotten.
The sill was the route.
So I had to make a decision for how carefully I would be with the renovation.
Chicken house renovation is starting to grow uncontrolled.
To nail over the rotten wood would do all renovation to wasted work that must
Made about the day the barn began to sack together.
So I changed the sill and I changed rules.
And the project I set aside for a week for just rolled on.
Every rotting plank I removed revealed more and more work.
Meanwhile, the weeds were flourished in my rhubarb cultivation.
The chickens were hatched and began to grow.
After a week, the chickens are no longer allowed because they dust.
It is a fact that perhaps only chicken owners know.
Chicken birds - however nice they are - have the ability to create a dust layer that settles
Everywhere in the room they live in.
In addition, it starts to smell.
Even if you change litter every day.
The chicken house was far from clear but I gave myself some respite by letting them move out to the guest house.
After a week it was also tied by dust.
Pumah turned out to be violently fond of the chickens.
I had to hold her when we went in to them.
Otherwise, she jumped over the pallet collars that served as chicken houses.
Now she stood with the front legs on the edge instead and scouted for the little ones have the down balls that ran around down there.
The tail went like a propeller.
At first I told me that the piping aroused her mother's instinct
But after her first meeting with an escaped chicken, I had to accept that it was not the mother who
Woke up in her - without the predator.
The chicken move to the guest cottage was just a temporary solution.
So on the list of jobs that was in a hurry, I therefore had to add a new point: to create a temporary
Accommodation for the chickens.
The renovation of the chicken house was stopped and instead I started rebuilding the old pigsty
to temporary chicken accommodation.
Now I ignore the rotting planks but just slammed slices on the walls.
Put nets over the old rat holes, compost grates over all other openings and a plastic mat on the floor.
https://xn--dligaskmt-12ae.se/