This
-—-—-
It island
If there is no one who brows with the horn layer ...
Here comes the winter
Oohh I'm so thirsty
Where is there water, where is there water
And then it starts looking.
Uhrrrr
Well then we would collapse like empty bags.
Now it is
ðŸ ðž ð­ ð­
around all the cells.
Blälä-Lä-Lä-Lä
hack
Hack chop
Hack chop chop
chop chop chop chopping
Oh oh oh oh oh oh oh oh oh oh
The whole house is full of childhood diseases.
But one must not itch
No
And then I recommend
that you only eat
Mashed food.
(mm mums)
Starts all the antibodies to go
in a scarlet fever school.
Cold...
Hello
Cold.
Now check out all these yellow pups.
We say I poke myself in the eye.
Remember that this is a yellow plump.
But now
Now the body gets angry
Eghu!
EG-HU EGGH!
39 degrees
Now it's hot
So it's good with fever.
Well.
Then you get pain in the ear too.
Snort
Oh there yes
Aah
Minisnort
MM :)
Thanks Eva
Yes please.
You can get hnh
Snake many times.
The immune system
Hoh!
& gt ;: D
Banking Banka row.
Knock bank bank bank bank bank
And knock knocking knocks!
But hope
Namen what happened here now: o
Yes, hay hay, these they can't very much.
(a bit like me: '))
Hoh: o
He recognizes this one
I'm thinking of my mind
Mash Mosa Mosa
Mash Mosa Mash Mosa Mash Mosa
Mash mosa mosa mosa mosa mosa mosa mosa mosa mosa
Mash mosa mosa mash mosa mo
Bllölörp
and if you laugh too little
Blööschh
fart
Ahh hahah!
You want to swim on Saturdays,
You want to go on a party
Tuuut
yeah
So it is important
to take it easy
And just look at clouds.
Hmmm :)
And then another thing.
Eat with cutlery.
Now I will sneeze
Atcho
hm
Why do you have to sleep for (I am a borch literally this at 05:03 i'm Sorry Eva I have failed you)
Namen & gt ;: o
(chaos)
(more chaos)
Yes, then you can wake up (thank you, o you all -powerful Eva, for letting me wake up)
Lassel box should go to kindergarten.
-—-—-
So you have a flower ...
Yellow flower
With white pups.
Aa now I know.
Håhåhå
What do I like then
I like patches hehe.
Nam nam nam nam
Oh euugh!
Sweat sweat sweat
blossh blöh Börh bluöh
Swish Swish Swish
that there is no one sitting
ffffuling here and s
Keeps on and giggling and moaning.
(I am, I sit here and giggles and mojjar)
Varied
Brush Brush
ouuhohoho
ooooh
Hello and welcome to mine!
(fockin dies)
Hohoho
Oh oh oh
That went well!
: ')
Here it is
My dot and plump museum!
Here we now have some of the life's
eeelende.
A wart
HMHMM
Such but otherwise like this with warts.
That's life.
(: I)
Hello Mollusken.
For example, tomatoes ...
OPP OPP OPP OPP THANK YOU very much
(mummel mum)
(SALIVARY)
Bye
And I'm not going to slip.
& gt ;: I
It feels like you feel like a big pillow, actually.
Hööö pillow
Wire.
Pillow
Wet in bed
Did you think I was kissing on me
Well, it wasn't at all.
It gets grinning and so aa
Yeah come here now Skaru get
Well, come here you.
You are going
It is so good with massage yeah-
And the toes they can actually spin on like this.
Let your hands fall oouu
Häjsaan
Fruit and green poop nice!
AA:/
It will be showering.
Yes it continues here.
Bajs rally continues ï¸
The journey in the small intestine is over.
looks like this.
Hehehaah
Yes and here it lay down and stumbles a little neighbor and
Petting a little on one
Pliing
Now we have fixed a real constipation (yaaay good job!)
Ooouup
Aaah lovely!
Check
So down in the large intestine
Näää :(
What is this
Bye
Pliing
Oh hh
bye
40 degrees.
Huuualigen
Ooh and all the way up
oh oh oh oh oh oh oh
Check out which nice fevercurva: D
Häer up e yes so
Fy
really bad (: c)
The next day, then it is so -called: in
Then it was
Dustrious
Listen
Good luck with all the diseases
Bye