Hey!
My name is Björn Runow.
I am a trained civil engineer in industrial economics and-
-Just now I read an education called "Complementary Educational Education".
And it is an education for those who have read a lot-
-In any subject at the university and then want to start working before school.
Within, for example, high school or high school.
And in my case then it's math.
I am from Södertälje, I am 27 years old and I like to hold on-
-Mathematics and teaching.
And in this talk, the idea is that I first and foremost will-
-Satting on some activities that I have done during my time at college,
Who has made me realize that it is as a mathematics teacher just I want to work.
And then I'll tell you about some examples from min-
-The study time, in which I used math for loose,
In my opinion, pretty cool problems.
Then I will also tell you about a few different tracks at the college,
which one as a mathematics enthusiast can read.
Okay.
We start here with-
-Some activities I've done.
I started at college after taking a four -year break
And the first thing I was struck by it was that I really was-
-Is imposed on how good and talented math teachers there were here.
MAI, the Mathematical Department at Linköping University,
They are really awesome!
At the beginning of my education, I felt that I was stimulated in terms of mathematics.
However, I have always liked to keep up with math help and-
-After a while I found an association called Mattehjelpen.
And it is a student association where purpose is-
-To helping students to manage math better.
And it was done mainly by arranging math cabins once a week,
And by holding rehearsal lectures for Mattetentor.
And this was something I involved in,
And I thought it was great fun.
And something that I have always wrestled with-
-In time I have been doing math teaching-
-This is that I want to make things as effective as possible.
While between high school and college-
-W so I kept up with a part with private education.
And I always thought it was a bit ineffective.
Two hours of my invested time became two hours of help for someone else-
-So there was no scalability on the whole.
Through my commitment to math hero-
-I now got help to help lots more.
And I thought that was fucking fun.
Then, after reading about a year at the college-
So, however, I decided that I want to do that is even more effective.
I was inspired by Khan Academy, for example-
And decided that: I will create a Youtube channel.
So I locked myself in my corridor room one summer,
And then I produced material for grade 7 up to mathematics 4.
And then at the end of the summer I published it here-
-On a channel called Mattebjörn.
This was received well and I thought it was great fun to hold on-
-So since then I've just continued with it.
And today I now have the most mat that you go through-
-From grade 7 up to linear algebra at university level.
And there, including-
-So a playlist for the college test mat.
Like you who are looking at this may benefit from.
Right now this channel has about 7000 subscribers,
And soon one and a half million views.
And my plan is to continue expanding the content of this-
-So that in the future I cover most of what you can read in math.
But, why should you read mathematics then?
Something I have turned off during my time at the civil engineering program-
-where I have studied a variety of areas,
It is how incredible math is actually used.
For example, I have studied economy,
And we have learned how to financially analyze different business-
And its potential.
I studied mechanics to understand how forces affect our physical world.
I have studied statistics to understand how to predict future events,
And how to count on chance.
I have studied optimization to get a better understanding of how man-
-Can make things as effective as possible.
I have also looked at game theory to see how one can foresee-
-What different actors will make given different conditions.
And since then I have also learned a great deal about control technology-
-which in many and much is about trying to get things self-driving-
-or autonomous.
And that said, what I think is so awesome with math-
-This is that it is the language used to describe-
-All these different applications.
Something that I also think is awesome it is that no matter where one is in the world-
-So this language in principle looks the same.
And if you have learned the math for mechanics here in Sweden-
-So you can apply it when you are away in Brazil or in China-
-or wherever you are.
In addition, if you also connect that you also use a little programming-
-In combination with math-
-Then I can also do a lot of cool stuff.
And I was going to tell you now about a couple of different examples-
-To stuff that I have done during my study time-
-What at least I think are a bit small.
So.
The first thing.
It has to do with our bachelor's project,
As I did on the I-line, or the industrial economy line.
And I did it in system technology and the assignment was to-
-Take a radio controlled car and turn it into a self -driving highway robot.
And then we would equip it with sensors and make it be able to-
-Take exits.
Run on paces.
Able to go an optimized route.
It could keep the distance to a vehicle present.
Such things that one should typically be able to do on a highway.
And here you can see an example of how it went then.
So now the car will take an exit here.
And this is our self -carved course that we have built.
Now it will drive on the highway again.
And then it will take a lap.
And then when it comes to this black line it will now stop.
And this was the first time we succeeded in this,
And it was damn fun.
But, how did this work then?
Well, this robot was equipped with a camera that constantly looked-
-Rakt down the road in front of him.
And if we for the moment ignore these blue lines-
-The we see exactly what the robot constantly analyzed in the picture.
Based on the picture that the robot sees here we use the edge detection-
-What can be seen as a mix of mathematics and programming.
And then you get the picture in the upper left, this black and white.
Based on it so we can then use-
-The time a little more math and image processing,
To get the picture you see at the bottom left-
-As found interesting lines in the black and white image.
Then, based on that picture with red lines-
-So we can get a kind of average route on the lines-
-As the left in the original image and lines that go right in the original image.
And with all of them we can figure out these two angles-
-When of using some trigonometry.
And what is the key here is that if the car is directed straight
-So V1 and V2 will be the same size, or about the same size.
And would be such that the car is directed oblique-
-Then one of them will be much bigger.
So by then regulating our control rash outside-
-What the difference is between v1 and v2,
So we can ensure that the car is always heading straight ahead.
I thought this with math and image processing was very fun-
-So I decided to take a master within it.
And i was just going to tell you a little shortly over-
-This I did in my degree project as well.
As you can see the introduction here.
It had to do with point detection.
So finding interesting points in pictures.
And what you see here, it's a picture of an EU pallet.
And here you can imagine, for example, an autonomous forklift-
-You want to go away and pick it up.
And then it must know what points it should aim with its forks.
And it had then been-
-The two points.
And the key here, or what one wants to then-
-This is to create a model that automatically based on the contents of the image-
-Can find and dot out what points you want to find.
What I was going to talk in a little more detail about here now,
It is an application from the food industry.
When they are going to package festis cartons for example-
-The they have to put the straw out in the right place on the carton.
And if you don't, so the straw ends up outside,
Then there is a risk that the latter in the process will fall off.
And here it is also interesting to detect points-
-To that it is a cost-effective way to determine om-
-The tube is in the right place or not.
Because we can only find these start-, bend and final points,
And compare their position with the points that mark the corners of the carton.
Because they are relatively easy to develop.
And-
-How does this work then and how is it linked to mathematics?
Yes.
What I used here, it was a so -called deep neural network.
And I then processed a color image in mass, lots of different layers-
-To finally release what you see here.
One, what one might call,
attention map, which indicates where it is likely-
-That there is a point of interest.
And it is then like a white area.
And in this case, the picture is,
This color image we are looking at,
It is a picture from a mall with lots of people in itself.
These little white areas in the black image-
-There are indications of where these people's heads are.
That was what was of interest.
And a little short just about how this actually went then.
Here you see three relatively simple examples when the straw is placed either-
In the middle of the carton.
A little skewed outside.
Or where we have a slightly different variant of the straw-
-Or it may not be clear.
And then you see in the pictures under-
-time cross, as the model then has dotted out to-
-Here I believe that the start, bend and endpoints exist.
And in this case, we can see that the model is actually performing quite well.
But even though it has passed some simple examples-
-So it is always interesting to look at a little more difficult.
And-
-You can see this here.
Up to the left you see a straw that is skewed format,
and at the top right you see a straw that has the wrong orientation-
-Against what it really should have.
And we see here that the model is struggling to prick out-
-The right number of points to detect.
And also where these points should detect.
You see it in the form of the red crosses.
Finally then.
What different tracks are there-
-If you are interested in reading mathematics at college?
Well, you can of course read as a civil or college engineer.
And then it is more theoretical math if you read a civil engineer.
Then of course you can also read to mathematicians.
Then you read a lot of math.
And I can also recommend reading a mix of mathematics and programming.
Because then you will surely be very sought after in the labor market.
And then you can also read to mathematics teachers.
For example for high school,
or for high school.
Then I also just want to mention this track that I am currently on.
This KPU, or supplementary educational education.
If it is so that you have read civil or college engineer-
-or that you have read to mathematicians, so you can complement your education-
-So that you get the right to teach within the school.
And I am currently reading KPU at Liu.
And so far, my experience of education-
-That it is really good and valuable.
Clearly above expectation actually.
Okay, then you've been told a bit of-
-What you can do at university when you plug mathematics,
And what opportunities exist if you plug mathematics.
Good luck with your future study choice!