My name is Ebba and I read a civil engineer in software technology at LiU.
I'm in my fourth year.
As a civil engineer you read a lot of math.
But just on software technology you read a lot of programming, several different programming languages.
What I think is fun about programming is that it is very concrete. You get a response from your computer.
But it is also very creative. You can solve a problem in very many different ways,
So you get both the concrete and creative in one.
When we did our bachelor's work, we worked in a team of eight people throughout the semester.
They have taken 3D scans, inside the actual mines, up in Kiruna.
As they read to data file. And we developed an algorithm that can,
Our node graph generates itself. Then they can do simulations
that makes you can see where it becomes most worthwhile
to break ore, and that can do it for any mine.
It got very cool because it is actually used by LKAB's system today.
I think anyone can search!
It is a bit sad that there is a stereotype today, which you see a lot in movies and TV series.
That people who program are super -smart, self -taught and sit completely alone in any basement
and hack into institutions while
This is not the case in reality, but we are social and we have great fun.
So you should not hesitate to search.