My name is Evelina and I plug in software technology.
I would like to say that what you learn is to solve problems.
I'm on my master now. And then, for example, I have read some neural networks
- Teach a computer to see the difference between a cat and a dog.
Data security - then you have tried to imagine in
What it is like to be a hacker and have to try to make different attacks.
Liu has, of course, to say, a very good student life
And I really think so. There are so many associations at LiU.
It is usually said that there is an association for each person.
In Lithe Blås, we are a student orchestra of type 40 people.
And then we have a ballet of 10 people.
Everyone can join. You don't have to be able to play anything. And ballet, it sounds like you should dance ballet then
But it is definitely not. It's choreographies, but ...
It's not about being good. It's about having fun!
There is a kind of belief that in order to be able to plug something computer technically
So you already have to have a super big interest in computers or games.
That's what we learn here!
Yes, it's hard, but it's also fun.
That is what is so fun with programming,
For rewards you get all the time. And that is what we do a lot on software technology.
You just have to think it sounds a little fun, a little interesting.
Or if you think puzzles are fun type, because it is a bit that
everything's about.
See relationship and try to find a way to solve them.
And so you are looking, and it will go well.
It did it for me anyway.