You raised this with a home. It can be difficult in many student cities.
Do you have any special tips on how to easily get housing and what you can do to facilitate.
I was lucky enough to get housing by calling around to private landlords.
At first, none of those had, but a few days later there was a woman who sought someone to rent out in the second place.
So she had got my number and contacted me. So that's a tip.
Good, to lie on a little yourself and not be too scared.
Yes, to rent in the second place.
Has it worked well then? Have you had the same home all the time?
No I have not. I've moved too. But it was a good way in.
Right. Alexander what do you say? You mentioned the housing queue.
Yes, to queue early at time, at student housing
At my education, the medical program we have superfather.
They have many tips on private landlords, how to go about it.
There are also Facebook groups such as housing in Linköping.
And in the Fabook groups of the program there are often older courses
Which may take. A year abroad and post advertisements, etc., so it usually resolves for most people.
So that social media can be a tip. Maja do you have something special?
I stood in a residential queue as soon as I could. But my partner and I got our apartment via the block, so you can look there.
So we looked first, but found nothing and then posted our own ad that we got an answer to.
It was pretty smooth.
There were many good tips. You can call around yourself, or post your own ads on the block or social media.
You can also make your own contacts when you come here.