My name is Rosanna
And plugs my fourth year at a civil engineer in software technology.
The most fun is the problem solving itself and that you are constantly being challenged.
Whether it is a math or programming problem, that you sit there and really try
To figure out!
And then like it works, hopefully.
Sometimes it takes a little longer.
I recently read an AI course
Where we got to learn more about machine learning, by trying to get a rocket to center.
The rocket had to try to go in slightly different directions
And then we gave it a reward or punishment.
It may be that it gets a certain point, based on how well it performed.
The less negative the point is, the closer the goal is the rocket.
It is a rather practical education in the way of
You have to program quite a lot. And no prior knowledge is needed.
Anyone who has a technology interest,
who thinks this is awesome and
Want to learn more about the technology behind.
Just that you find it interesting.