Yes I have worked a few years now before and have been thinking
Been a little craving for a while now on starting to read at university
And there is nothing that I have regretted that I made this decision
It's a mix of people reading here
A little mixed ages
I am definitely not the youngest but not the oldest either
Are there very different activities to do after study time
But you choose for yourself what you want to be part of what activities
I have always felt welcome to hang on the a little younger but
Sometimes it becomes that you prioritize the family instead and go home after the end of school
It is probably a little depending on what kind of course you read
Or education how much you are out at university or how much you have distance studies from home
For me reading to teachers so I try to get up at 8 in the morning
Get my kids off to school
Then I'm ready to get started
Sometimes there are some studies from home but often you sit out at the university
You meet some plug friends you sit and plug and maybe take a coffee it is mixed with lectures and seminars
But I put my studies
Between 8 and 5 in order to be able to get evenings and weekends free to devote myself to something else then
Yes when you start plugging it makes little difference with the economy
It may not be as much luxury holiday and spontaneous shopping anymore
But I think this is for a limited time
A difference is now also that when you have children and plugs
Should they get sick or you want to take vacation like that
The job is in as well as still left
To do
But then it's up to me if I want to sit in the evenings and weekends and do it
There is still some flexibility when I do my studies that did not exist when I was working
Yes but I had probably been thinking about doing something else
I was craving something new
But once I took hold of it and started examining a bit like that
On the one hand, it turned out that one could be study service leave
And there was little to think about with the economy
But you can get some extra contributions if you have children from CSN
And no,
It's just grab it and search