Is it allowed to be a flour mask?
Chickens are quickly learning new things
When there is a flour mask to get.
Why are some individuals more impulsive than others?
In this test, we want to investigate how impulsive chickens are.
First we teach the chickens the concept stir.
We use a reward, which is a flour mask.
We put the flour mask in the middle of the tube.
Then the pipe is presented on this joint.
The chicken learns that it must retrieve the flour mask from the side of the pipe.
When they can, we do the test ourselves.
Then it is a transparent tube instead.
Again we put the flour mask in the middle
What happens then is that the chicken intuitively and spontaneously
will want to pick on the tube for it sees the flour mask
But it must stop its impulsivity
And remember that it should take the reward from the side.
(music)
Video: Anna Nilsen & Karin Söderlund Leifler
(Logo) Linköping University