If you were to choose a cultural work at random-
-A fiction book, a movie, a poem or a song-
-Is the chance that something in it can be tracked all the way back to antiquity.
We often see antiquity as the starting point for our modern history-
-Where democracy, science and Western culture arise.
But man has been around for over 200,000 years.
How was it that happened around the Mediterranean a few thousand years late-
-So important that we often see it as a beginning?
Ancient Greece is special because we know so much about it.
There is a lot of text and literature.
By there are preserved-
-Have it affected the Western cultural heritage like nothing else.
This series on the history of literary is about what is preserved.
Books, poems and plays.
Although human history is longer than antique-
-Is this we start our Western literary history.
What did you write and read when everything started?
Antiquity ranges approximately from 700 BC. to 500 AD
It is divided into a Greek and a Roman era-
-As a long time coexist in the middle.
The first 500 years counted as Greek antiquity golden age-
-And this is where most literary breakthroughs happen.
Geographically the ancient Greek culture is divided
-And consists of several hundred city states.
One would like to know how to experience it in place-
-for example. How it smelled.
We can only speculate, but it must have smelled very and bad.
In addition to the bad smell, the city states are bound together by two things.
The common language, Greek, and the common gods.
The Greek gods looked like and behaved like human beings.
They slept, ate, drank, danced, had sex, struggled and slandered each other-
-and could be pretty small. They were no moral role models.
There are twelve gods and they live on the mountain Olympos.
In addition to them, there are local gods and half -gods.
The gods could young with ordinary people.
With the common faith came a common view of life.
The ancient Greeks have clear ideas on how to behave.
It can be seen in the stories you tell.
A red thread through the Greek literature is to think about:
"How does it look?" "Will people remember me?"
The worst thing you can do in antiquity is getting hybris.
Not to be moderate but believe that you are as good as the gods.
Then you suffer from nemesis, punishment from above. Punishment is never fun.
As guidance you have the myths-
-Som with their stories explain the world.
One of the myth's functions is to answer these big questions.
Where does everything come from? What is the meaning of everything?
How is the universe interconnected, the world of gods and people?
A variety of issues of this kind are dealt with in the myths.
They can also be used to amuse. These are fantastic stories.
When you read them today you are still taken by them.
One of them is the starting point for our Western literature - the Iliad.
Where does literature start? It always starts with the Iliad.
The Iliad is an epic, a longer story written in verse.
Together with the Odyssey, it contains 28,000 verses.
An epic takes place in the past tid-
-and the Iliad attracts during the Trojan War in the 13th century BC-
-Sid before the time we count as antiquity.
It is usually said that it is written down by Homer in the 7th century BC.
Book Poiler Iliad:
The Iliad takes place during the tenth and last year of the Trojan war.
The Greeks have besieged the city of Troja. We meet people as well as gods.
The best fighter of the Greeks, Achilles, comes into trouble with agamemnon-
-and gets so angry that he refuses to fight-
-Ag until Hektor, the prince of Troja, kills one of Achille's best friends.
Then he takes to weapons again and chases Hektor around the city walls-
-What he kills him.
Achilles brings with him and violates the body of the dead prince.
After a little bang, the corpse is returned to Troja.
The story ends with hectoral funeral.
The iliad is important because it is so old-
-and has been with so long-time-
-And framed the entire ancient culture.
What do we know about Homer who stands as a writer?
He has been called literature's forefather - no bad nickname.
But we know almost nothing about him.
He might be blind, he might not be.
Here we see how he is led by a young good looking.
There are even An expression - the Homeric question ...
... who is wondering if there may have been a single man ...
... who have written two such influential books.
The story in the Iliad, how real is it?
The Iliad takes place in a real time but also in a mythological time.
It is a fantasy product "based on a true story".
The Iliad does not depict the beginning or the end of the Trojan war.
It also does not have the exciting story of the Trojan horse.
Instead, the Iliad has another theme - Achilles and his anger.
Here we see Brad Pitt as Achilles. He doesn't look so a little angry.
I interpret the Iliad as a problematization of a world-
-which is filled with war and rape-
-And as an illustration of how unsustainable it is as a social form.
Ancient Greece was a society where violence was constantly present.
The vast majority of adult men could count with-
-To sometime in one's life get meat down someone else-
-or stand next to someone who was meat down.
Furthermore, the Iliad is orally passed.
Only when it has been told for hundreds of years is it written down.
We see this clear imprints in the written text.
When we read, we often appreciate variation.
But when something is to be remembered, we put more value on repetition.
The Iliad was long live.
It was singers who could, what we could call a language-
-Arch consisting of word combinations that they could put in a solid rhythm.
We call that rhythm hexameter.
You could be asked to sing about Achilles.
So one began to put, in the hexameter's space-
-stories that one combines live in the actual conduct-
-ur The huge storage room you have of these rhythm combinations.
Having the same rhythm combination through a whole work is called a bound verse.
So it is with the hexameter of the Iliad. Here the first verse.
Notice that we already here hear about Achilles and his anger.
Sing, o goddess about the wrath that burned with Peliden Achilles.
Do you hear the rhythm? It goes like this.
Women Didi Women Didi Dam Didi Dame Didi Dam Didi Dam.
So it should sound, over and over again in over 28,000 verses.
The Iliad also contains so -called epithetic
-Where you tell about the characters' traits before their name.
"The fast -footed Achilles." "The Helmet Bronze Hector."
"The arrow -loving artemis."
The standing epithets helped the listener and singer to remember-
-What character traits the different people had.
This hexameter ...
It was new to me. I don't usually read that.
But I didn't think the language was difficult.
I had never read a piece written in hexameter.
It was special. A little difficult at first. A challenge.
But it was fun. You had to focus a little extra.
There are imagery, metaphors and parables.
There were many different types of writing in a text.
It was exciting.
The epic as the Iliad is often told by so -called Rapsodes.
They go around in ancient Greece and tell stories for payment.
Each time a poet tells a story-
-cent audience roughly what applies-
-But are prepared for the author to tell in a new way.
It is a big deal to spoil a story.
You must not say how it ends.
But in ancient Greece everyone always knew how it ended.
The important thing was how you told the story.
From the Greek word for action, "drama", comes two important concepts.
Through the philosopher Aristotle we get "dramaturgy"-
-The knowledge of how a story should be built up to catch the audience.
Stories need a beginning, a middle and a final-
-and a red thread that goes through what you tell.
It may feel given today as part of what we read and look at-
-But then, for the ancient Greeks, it was brand new.
From the word "drama" also comes "drama".
The drama that emerges in the ancient aten-
-As the origin of today's theater.
You distinguish between tragedies and comedies - seriously and fun.
But the tragedies have the highest status.
These are the ones you play at the city festivals.
The drama is known through the tragedy.
The tragedy is this spectacle that is set up-
-At the annual festival in Athens the so -called. Dionysos Festival.
People come from all over the Greek island world, sometimes up to 30,000.
The ancient Greek theater takes place outdoors-
-and is built on a slope with the stage at the bottom-
-and the spectators in a semicircle.
One of the most famous tragedies played-
-As "Antigone" by the playwright Sofokles.
Think about how our father went abrasive and despised in ruin-
-and for his crime as himself he brought in the day-
-With your own hand drove their eyes out.
We have epic where our epic is included as developing into fiction.
The drama is the basis for theater, television and film.
In both, action is crucial.
It also comes a third form of literary design-
-What does not focus on events, but on a feeling.
We are talking about the lyric, the basis for poetry.
It is almost always presented to music and it has been named ...
... from this instrument - a lyre.
One of ancient great poets is Sapfo. Here we see her think.
She was active in the 500-600s before our time-
-And is one of the oldest poets we know and have poems from.
Sapfo lives on than Lesbos, a rich Handelsö in the Greek kingdom.
She herself belongs to the island's upper class.
What we have from SAPFO is completely unique because it is so extensive.
It gives us an insight we otherwise would not have-
-And that shows women's lives in antiquity.
Of course, they are also very beautiful.
"Who is it now I have to persuade?"
"Who is it now whose silence torment you, sapfo?"
"She's fleeing you now will be following."
"She who refuses now will want to."
"She who doesn't love should love whether she wants to or not."
Her style is often direct and clear-
-and the texts often revolve around desires, longing and beauty-
-For everything women's beauty.
Lesbos, the island she comes from, is the basis for the word "lesbian".
Although SAPFO had a great impact on the history of literary
-Found very little of her work preserved.
We must remember that it is over 2,500 years since she lived.
Her poems have no names but are usually called fragment-
-To they have been preserved as parts and loose pieces.
In modern times, many have liked it. You have liked the fragment style.
There is a lot of room to interpret and enter yourself.
It has probably contributed to the attraction.
There is room to project their own thoughts and dreams.
The lyric is the third and last leg next to the epic and drama-
-On the ancient pallet where much of today's literature rests.
Three basic genres that live on thousands of years later.
Today it may appear that everyone in the Greece-
-As writers, philosophers, heroes and gods, but that's not it.
Most people live simple lives and there are obviously back sides in history.
Given that the Greeks find the democracy, philosophy-
-and much of the literature we have today, so you disregard-
-Th a thing that enabled the production of culture and thought-
-Where that someone else did the hard job. It's the slaves.
The free men, atenna-
-has the opportunity to devote to philosophy and literature-
-This to have to go to work.
A culture that has slave-
-Builds on a human view where everyone is not equal.
Some people are like items that you can change and sell and buy-
-Preatic as with a chair, bicycle or sweater today.
It is also noticed in the literature that one is aware of the injustices.
Becoming a slave is something you worry about.
A recurring motive in literature is the fear of pre-
-As losing one's affiliation and being sold as a slave.
The fear that one can be sold as slave-
-Is perhaps difficult to relate to in day-
-But much in ancient literature is still relevant.
The myths are still told-
-And is not only used by playing Greek tragedies.
It is made movies-
-And we have popular culture and series that use this estate.
These are good stories.
They still grab us and still have something to say us.
Texting: Henrik Johansson www.btistudios.com