Imagine if in the future one would decide that the time you live in now-
-is boring and stupid, that you were probably a bit sluggish-
-That the books were bad, the music uninteresting-
-And that everything you thought was just ignored.
And that you took your time and hundreds of years around it and baptized it-
-To something that would signal that here it was boring and cultural misery.
It was precisely the Middle Ages.
The Middle Ages is an epoch name that comes only afterwards.
The medieval people did not perceive that they lived during the Middle Ages.
By the Middle Ages is meant "intermediate time"-
-A period between antiquity and the Renaissance.
Those who came afterwards did not want to be associated with this interim.
The term is used to mark-
-That we are better than those who lived during that period.
We get this with the Middle Ages being dark centuries - "The Dark Ages".
There is a lot of darkness during the Middle Ages, with crusades and other-
-But there are also very exciting thoughts.
The Middle Ages are more than a parenthesis.
It was knight, adventure and culture. And new religions emerged.
What did they write and read then during the dirty Middle Ages?
The Middle Ages are usually counted from the fall of the Roman Empire in the 400s ...
... and all the way to the 16th century.
It is a period of time over a thousand years.
Although it is difficult to summarize such a long epoch-
-The there are two central things that start on r - knights and religion.
After the fall of the Roman Empire, it is messy in Europe.
Although the people here-
-Not seem to have any problems with being carved with sword-
-So it brings changes.
The kings find it harder to educate and pay all the warriors they need.
They give a piece of ground to the knights-
-In exchange for the knights setting up and defending the kingdom.
It is part of the feudal system-
-Where the king gives away some of his power in exchange for loyalty.
The second R made even more mark on its time.
Everything in the Middle Ages has a religious dimension.
All the ancient gods, such as Zeus, Apollon, Oden and Tor retired-
-And there will be new stars in the sky.
In Europe, Christianity goes from having been prohibited to dominating-
-And in the Middle East, Islam emerges.
The texts of both religions, the New Testament and the Qur'an-
-Is the most scattered literature ever.
The change of power in heaven has a huge impact on life on earth.
The church and popes cooperate with the governing power-
-And helps manage the state apparatus.
The farmers, the largest social group, have less power.
God and the Church are present throughout the Middle Ages and characterize all-
-from everyday acts such as cleaning-
-To go to church and seek out the divine.
Something that is also constantly present is death.
During the Middle Ages you get a lot of close contact with death.
It has partly with the great pest epidemics to do-
-And partly that we have a greater closeness to death during the Middle Ages.
One lives in large families together-
-With grandchildren and grandmother in the same house, which makes you see death.
You can die in the kitchen sofa and then the children see it.
But in the new Christian religion, death is something more than the end of life.
After death, you are assessed based on how you have done.
Life can be seen as a heating-
-If the existence on the other side of the grave.
One of the largest and most significant operations of the Middle Ages-
-Also have focus on death and life after that.
A work that reinforces the world-image-
-And scares people for what is to come later.
The divine comedy.
It is not a comedy, but it is called it because it ends happily.
It is written by this man - Dante Alighieri ...
... here wearing a boastful wreath wreath showing that he is a good poet.
Dante comes from a middle -class family in the Italian city of Florence.
It takes him 20 years to write down the story-
-Where he has himself in the lead role.
Book Poiler - The Divine Comedy.
The divine comedy is about Dante's journey on the other side of the grave.
Through him we get a guided trip to the three different parts of the Kingdom
-And we meet well -known characters from history and literature.
The journey begins in hell that is divided into different circles.
In the first circle we find the mildest sinners-
-And at the bottom, on the ground floor nine, the worst.
There we find, for example. traitor like Judas and brutus-
-Fast frozen in eternal ice.
After the tour through hell it carries off the mountain of the purgatory ...
... before Dante reaches his final destination - paradise.
My first contact with the divine comedy ...
... was when I was nine years old ...
... on a visit home with Grandma and grandfather in Gothenburg.
The pictures from hell caught me the most.
Horrible pictures of devils who torment poor sinners-
-Long down into the underground.
The book has a huge impact, but it is fuzzy how it is published.
You do not know exactly how Dante released the divine comedy.
It is thus the Middle Ages we are talking about.
When we find ourselves around 1300 it is still 170 years left-
-Still Johannes Gutenberg invents the art of printing.
This will be an incredibly scattered story.
You tell each other very orally.
The divine comedy is written on Dante's own verse measure Terzin.
There, all strokes have three rows of eleven syllables in each row.
So the divine comedy is written over and over, in a hundred songs.
Perhaps not the easiest way to write-
-But certainly help if you were to remember the whole story.
What is in these hundred songs takes people in bloodiest seriousness.
They believe in everything that is written about hell, purgatory and paradise.
The church also begins to use Dante's work.
That becomes the description of hell and the purgatory-
-So this is preached as the truth.
One uses it, not as a beautiful story-
-Outan like something actually.
It allows the church to gain more power over people.
Who wants to roll stones or burn in open graves?
"Do as the church says, otherwise it happens."
That it was written on verse made it a little difficult to read it-
-But it was interesting too.
It was written a little more poetically and it was very descriptive.
They flowed better into the text.
It was reminiscent of when I was smaller and read the hobby of Tolkien.
It creates a picture of what it looked like.
The whole description of what happens ...
... if you have sinned and what happens in hell ...
It draws up a horrific picture of how terrible it is-
-As an attempt to make it sound nasty, I would guess.
It's most bizarre. It's imaginative.
One reason why the book becomes so popular is-
-That it is written in a language that people are actually talking.
It was sensational.
The literary language that had been used then-
-During the last thousand years in the European literature-
-As Latin. Then Dante comes and does this in Italian.
It was important for him to reach out to not only the scholars.
Dante can be taken as an example of a breaking point-
-the the wide layer of the population, such as the elite in cities and on rural
-comes into reading and consumption of culture in a different way.
Dante is not the only one who starts writing in Florentine.
It becomes so popular that that dialect becomes national language-
-So what we today call Italian.
It is a remarkable example of the role literature can ha-
-In a greater linguistic context.
Text in the spoken language reached more easily to a wide mass.
But there was another literature that first had a narrower target group.
The knight novels.
The knight novel emerges during the 13th century.
The knight novels are aimed at a reading aristocracy - the knight.
They could usually read.
Knight novels are filled with adventure-
-and in the center always stands a knight-
-while, women protect and weak, behave honestly-
-and always stands by his word.
Being a knight was like being influencer or youtuber.
You are known and you also know celebrities, such as the king.
After all, it is the king who studs one more knight.
In addition to exciting stories, the knight novels are a label book-
-For noblemen who will learn the knight's ideal.
They would both entertain and raise.
So maybe literature has always been-
-But it is clear in the knight's novel.
The knight novels also contain so -called Hovish love.
The idea is that a knight should flirt passionate with ladies-
-But be a gentleman and not let it go beying further than crazy looks.
Hövish love is central to one of the most famous novels-
-Tristan and Isolde. Join us in the relationships now.
Tristan is one of King Artur's knights around the round table.
He is also a sister to King Mark.
King Mark is married to the beautiful Isolde.
One day so is Isolde and Tristan a love drink-
-while, they immediately fall in love with each other.
From that moment their passion is a fact.
This is a bloody and brutal story-
-If infidelity and tragic love.
Listen to this:
"Yesterday on the market I saw a couple holding each other's hands."
"I realized that we will never do it. Never anything like that."
"No picnics or unattended smiles."
"No rings. Only stolen moments that go way too fast."
Tristan and Isolde are a worrying story.
The love that is born between them is not natural.
It is the result of a magical love drink.
This is something that the medieval reader is worried about.
It was a theme that fascinated the medieval reader-
-And that fascinates us today as well.
In the knight poetry we always meet a dream picture of a knight.
He is strong, smart and honest.
But the knights of reality do not always live up to that ideal.
The knight novel reflects aspects of the knight's real life.
The knight's culture of honor, his virtues and living rules-
-Finds depicted in the novel.
But the knights are idealized pictures. The knights are raised.
In the crusades - in the stories and in reality ...
... the knights and religion meet.
The hellish warning examples from the divine comedy-
-Mixed with the upbringing and the feeling of duty from the knight novels.
The knight we meet in the novel is quite far from-
-The crusade knight you otherwise associate with the Middle Ages.
Europe's Christians are worried that Muslims will take over Jerusalem.
A French Pope launches the idea of a pilgrimage to save the city.
You equip special knights with a mantle with a large cross on.
Then they are obliged to go to these places-
-and complete his knight service in the crusade.
But the crusades are not an exciting adventure in a romantic shimmer.
What is sold as travel to save Christian sacred sites-
-In bloody conquest war that lasts for hundreds of years.
They move out-
-And pure massacres on especially Jews and Muslims.
There are terrible stories where one cleans cities on folk-
-And cut the throat of infants.
The knight's ideals that the novels have taught no longer apply.
An honorary culture has developed around the knights on the battlefield.
They fought against those who were not Christians.
Unfortunately, many conflicts are founded during the Middle Ages.
The crusade time is still invoked politically, in a clumsy way.
That the US president says we should pull in crusad-
-Acker bad associations in the Muslim world.
At the end of the Middle Ages, a book is written by two German monk-
-Som, even though it is banned almost immediately, has major consequences.
During the 1400-1600s, a book sells almost as well as the Bible ...
... and it's Malleus Maleficarum - "Witch Hammer".
The witch hammer is a book in three chapters on what a witch is-
-How witchcraft and sorcery go to and how to find and prosecute a witch.
It is an instruction manual in witch hunt-
-And becomes the basis for the witch processes. The majority that was convicted were women.
According to the book, women are more receptive to the devil's attraction.
Above all, the woman's sexuality is described as threatening.
A completely unscientific perception-
-As has influenced the view of women until today.
Nevertheless, the negative image of the Middle Ages has almost disappeared.
The knight novel had an exaggerated, romantic picture of the knight's life-
-And today we have an excessive romantic picture of the Middle Ages.
What is exciting about the knight novel is-
-The knight's novel is the source of our modern fantasy tradition.
The story of the ring, Narnia and maybe even Game of Thrones ...
The knight novel is there in the background-
-And is crucial to especially the growth of fantasy.
The crusades are also extensively portrayed. Every year Ivanhoe is shown on TV ...
... and we also got our own Swedish crusade hero - Arn.
Although the Middle Ages remain in popular culture-
-In computer games, music videos, role-playing and festivals-
-and some love to pretend to live then-
-So you should probably be glad it is just on pretend.
The Middle Ages are interesting to study but you do not want to live that way.
It can be fun to dress up and loop Middle Ages-
-But one would not want to be burned on the bonfire-
-To question whether communion is Jesus' body.
Texting: Henrik Johansson www.btistudios.com