Very funny that you are so many who come here and hope too -
That you are many who sit and listen to this online.
The title of our lecture, proximity to nature - has a way to better health?
with question marks.
It might also have the sub -heading, we are on the right track.
Not least with the image you can see here.
My name is Åsa Engström and I am, as I said, professor of nursing,
Also subject representatives there.
Also a nurse and worked primarily in intensive care
And courses linked to it.
And this with the importance of nature is something that is warm to me.
And maybe a little contrast to the high -tech.
Päivi and I work together on many issues linked to this.
You may introduce yourself.
Päivi Juuso is my name, assistant professor at the department of
Nursing and medical technology. And just as Åsa says,
Colleague and we have worked and work in many different projects together.
I am a district nurse, primarily worked in sparsely populated areas.
So this with nature is very close really, my everyday life -
And my everyday life. It will be great fun -
To give this lecture for you. And also welcomes all of you -
on site and all of you on the web.