Due to the Corona crisis, we interview researchers at Lund University.
Today we have with us political scientist Åsa Knaggård.
You have been interested in how politicians make decisions under great uncertainty.
Welcome!
During the Corna crisis, Sweden's strategy has been extensively discussed.
Among other things, you have compared to other countries.
But you mean that it is almost impossible to know whether we choose the right strategy or not.
What do you mean?
When you talk about what is the right strategy, you cannot give a clear answer to that.
It is always dependent on the framework you set or the perspective you have.
If we have an narrow spread perspective, you get an answer to what is right.
Then it is about reducing the spread of infection as much as possible.
If you have a broader perspective where you take in the slightly more long -term financial health issues
So maybe you get another answer.
Therefore, it becomes very difficult to say what is right.
To that should be added that I do not think that we will even be able to say what was right, in retrospect, we will be able to say, what was right,
If Sweden chose right, so to speak, because we can never know.
If we go back and say that
Sweden had chosen Norway's strategy instead, what would it have meant?
We don't know that.
But it feels a little frustrating that we may never ever know which strategy was right.
No, but that's how it is precisely when we have this great uncertainty, that it may not be possible to say.
You have to make decisions anyway.
I would say that is the content of this with decisions under uncertainty.
You can only cook by position.
What do you think stands out with Swedish politicians' actions during the Corona crisis?
Two things I would say.
It is not so much about which strategy we have chosen in Sweden
The first is that politicians listen to the experts to the extent they do.
It is quite unusual if we look at politics in general.
I think about school policy for example
Which is an ideological battlefield.
No one listens to the experts if we harden it.
It is a bit surprising, I would say that they listen to the extent they do.
But this applies in many countries, not just in Sweden.
The other thing that I think stands out in Sweden is that they have kept to continue listening to the experts.
That is, I really expected that when there were more people who began to die
When the figures began to leave, that we had seen more politically motivated decisions then
That you said that "this is not possible, we have to do something" but we have not seen that.
And I think that is interesting and exciting, that you have not done so.
Another thing I think about is that they also seem to be very unanimous.
Is it also something that stands out?
Yes I would also say that it is something that would be very interesting to study late afterwards
That the government appears incredibly agreed in standing behind the line to listen to the experts.
There is no criticism from within.
And you might wonder, is it really that way?
And it's hard to say.
We only see what they show outward at press conferences and in interviews.
So far, it has basically been total agreement.
Maybe not entirely surprising but it is interesting because it shows that they have talked together
before they have decided on a line they hold.
But how do you think before making a decision under great uncertainty?
Is there any template that the decision makers can hold when making decisions under such great uncertainties?
My research is not so much about templates.
What I research about is how the decision makers actually make decisions.
What I see, I have primarily studied environmental and climate issues.
What you can see there is that you can either concentrate on the uncertainty
Or can be concentrated on the knowledge that exists.
What it means having a strategy where one focuses on the uncertainty
This means that you want to reduce uncertainty.
It is said that we know too little about this to make good decisions.
We need to buy ourselves more time, get more knowledge
So that we can later make a better founded decision.
And in this case, with the Corona epidemic, it is about limiting the spread of infection
as much as possible and wait for new knowledge, for example if
Do these masks work?
What does it look like with the spread of infection when you do not have symptoms?
Lots of things that you can gain more knowledge about gradually.
Could a strategy be that we are running a lockdown now throughout the country waiting for us to have more knowledge?
Is that an example?
Yes it is.
And one begins to open up society again
Once you have gained knowledge that allows you to do it safely.
But then there is another strategy too?
And then you take in the existing knowledge.
Can you develop it?
Then it is about saying instead of saying that there is so much uncertainty here you say
We still know quite a lot.
We know how epidemics work.
And we know pretty much about viruses and spreading.
We know about how society works.
We have to base our actions on it.
And that is probably the strategy that Sweden has chosen to deal with the uncertainty with.
So, for example, you use model knowledge to see how the infection can be spread.
What is likely?
If we put in different restrictions, how would it affect?
This is how you can look at in these models.
But also such things as what we know about healthcare and healthcare capacity,
How elderly care works.
It can also be about the type of steering you are used to
And know works in a particular country.
The interesting thing about this type of strategy is that different countries can end up in completely different conclusions.
But that they are still based on the knowledge that exists.
Then it is partly that the experts may do different analyzes of the same knowledge
But also that you have completely different conditions in different countries.
It sounds like this is rational, now we will find some good strategy to fight the spread of infection.
But are there not completely different reasons why politicians make decisions?
Don't they just want to show action too?
You have to make a decision to show that you are doing something?
Well, it is clear, to a large extent it is.
Then I would not say that it is not rational.
It is not easy to draw that limit.
It again depends on the perspective you take.
If you take a broader perspective and say that a large part of this is to calm the population,
That people should feel that politicians take this seriously, that they do something,
That they do not care when people get sick, die and become unemployed.
It is a very important part of politics.
So that with action is rational
From such a perspective, to show that you do something.
And there that can close boundaries or say that you should have face masks to be great.
In that perspective, so to speak.
But if you look in a broader perspective, we see that some politicians use this after all
For example, to benefit their own political party.
You want to be able to win elections.
In the United States, it is very clear that Donald Trump uses this party strategically, or what to say.
Even in Poland, there have been discussions about it anyway.
And then also actually, and I think it's much, much worse, what we can see in Hungary, for example,
where you use infection -limiting policy to further dismantle democracy
It's really worrying.
You talk about different strategies that you can have but this crisis goes so fast.
There is constantly new information that is to be decided.
Is it possible to stick to a strategy?
Hard to say.
The important thing really, and the most important thing, when it comes to decision making under uncertainty
is that you go back and re -examine the decisions you make.
You can never think that we have made this decision already and then we do not have to think about it anymore.
You have to go back and rethink, partly because you get new knowledge but also because the situation can change.
So to go back and rethink and be very humble with this that one must be able to admit
That that was a stupid decision.
Now we do differently.
As a political scientist, during this Corona crisis, what has caught your curiosity?
Yes, all this is very exciting for someone who is doing decision -making under uncertainty
Because it is a single long decision -making, under uncertainty.
But that one would like to study afterwards it is this with
What are the balances that have really done?
Partly between the narrow spread perspective and the broad socio -economic,
But also how you have thought about uncertainty, what is the knowledge you have leaned on?
How have you weighed in uncertainty and thought about this with caution and so on?
So it would have been wonderful to sit and hear the conversations they have had.
Thanks so much.
It must be the last for today.
Thank you for being with Åsa.
Thank you very much.
And thank you for being listening.
More news about the Corona crisis can be found at www.lu.se.