It is good to eat seaweed because it has been found to have an interesting nutritional profile.
I.a. Has it carbohydrates of various kinds that can have unique self -saps that are good for humans.
From a sustainability perspective, it is also good how to grow pliers.
You do not need any fresh water, no fertilizers, no pesticides and no land surface.
Today we look at different types of pliers. We have brown seaweed, green pliers and red pliers.
We at biotechnology develop different products that will reach consumers in our market.
But it is also important that consumers like what we develop.
With this project, we want to learn more about what consumers really want.
We think it is taken by that input today.
When we have been done with the smell we go on the taste and then you can also assess the texture.
We want to develop products that can be ingredients in te.x. bread or pasta.
It could be supplements that you can bring with these nutrients.
Or it may be in its entire form, but we know too little about today.