Welcome to debate in Lund, both all of you who are here in the hall
At the Grand Hotel
and you who follow us via screen
Or TV someone elsewhere.
Debate in Lund is a forum for in -depth conversation, for intellectual debate.
It is a collaboration between
Lund University, especially the Faculty of Social Sciences, and Sydsvenskan
Which sends directly from here tonight.
My name is Lars Mogensen and I am a journalist.
Such a small grunk ...
Do you see sitting at the back and you who look on the screen?
Such a little thing with crank,
A crank radio.
Does anyone have such a home?
A gang.
This is a bubbler for this year's Christmas present 2022.
Another bubbler as this year's Christmas present 2022,
a woodwood.
Both of these things, after all, pretty crunchy gifts
If you see it back in perspective.
Think the other year when people wanted VR glasses and robotic vacuum cleaners.
Now it is firewood that bubbles.
Something has happened.
Putin's war against Ukraine,
The gas pipes that were blasted off our coast, at Bornholm.
Company forced to put down or postpone
their investments and plans
due to completely unreasonable electricity bills.
Private individuals who cry for concern that they are afraid that they will not cope with their electricity bills.
And besides, some understanding
that paints up horror scenario
About a Sweden that is partially extinguished in winter.
So the question is: How do we solve the Swedish energy supply on one
fossil -free, in a robust and stable way
And how should prices be set?
Now we have a new and much more nuclear -friendly government.
The question is whether it has power, energy enough to give Sweden new electricity.
This will try to find out here tonight along with two former ministers
And two engineers with control of energy systems and power work technology.
At the far right we have Mikael Odenberg, a known face, former
Minister of Defense in the Reinfeldt government
In the early 21st century,
CEO of Svenska Kraftnät between 2008 and 2017.
Welcome.
Isabella Lövin, former environmental and climate minister, environmentalist.
Minister of Löfven's government in 2019 to 2022 and a past as EU parliamentarian,
Author and more.
We have Magnus Genrup as a professor of environmental and energy systems at Lund University.
Beside him...
Well, now it was wrong.
It was wrong.
Magnus Genrup is a professor in power plant technology
And closest to me Lars J Nilsson, professor of environmental and energy systems.
So I got it right, excuse.
Warm welcome, they are worth an applause!
The last few days so the electricity prize has suddenly gone down a bit again
But we are in a very worried,
advice and awkward time.
We begin with
Lars J,
closest to me.
A brief situation, how serious is the situation?
The acute situation is well -seriously severe
But I think in a longer perspective so we have had
A safe, stable electricity supply.
We have no shortage of electricity.
We exported
25 terawatt hours electricity last year.
Now we have a problem in the short term this winter and next winter,
driven by the war against Ukraine
And consequences on gas prices that print our prices.
Magnus Genrup, your location description?
My position description is that in
principle we have gone from a very stable system, we have discontinued
Very much effect
And should it get really cold then we have a pretty huge deficit that we have difficulty dealing with,
that can mean, what we talked about before,
Manual disconnect but it is quite unlikely.
What I called darkening.
But that is quite unlikely, I want to say.
There is still on the map that it could be so?
It is always on the map.
It is always on the map and Svenska Kraftnät has flagged for it
But at the same time, the probability is greatest now.
Isabella Lövin,
How do you describe the situation?
Yes we have no shortage
on electricity in Sweden, on the contrary
Do we produce more electricity than we consume and export
and has been
the largest exporter even in the EU
during certain periods.
But we have an electricity crisis
can you say because it is so large
Demand for electricity in Europe right now.
It's tough
For many, for all of us would say in electricity area 3 and 4
Which has very high electricity prices right now.
But one should also remember that you have very high electricity prices in
Virtually all of Europe.
One should also remember how people suffer in Ukraine right now
And that the big reason we have this crisis,
It is Putin's invasion of Ukraine.
We have in common
decided that we should not buy gas by
Putin and otherwise we have no pipeline left after
This blast you mentioned.
Mikael Odenberg, your picture of the situation?
Yes, it is more that we have problems in the electricity market with very volatile and
Occasionally very high prices and large price differences
which sets it for
Industry's competitiveness and for households, especially in southern Sweden.
But the electricity system itself is robust.
It shines in the cabins and what Isabella said,
Swedish electricity is a successful export industry.
Then the electricity should also last a cold winter when it is not blowing.
It will do it
Although the margins in the system have decreased with the closures of Ringhals 1 and 2.
It is important to have clear to itself that when Pågens
Had trouble investing in a new bread factory in Skåne was not due to electric deficiency
Without it, it was due to restrictions in the distribution network.
And when Uniper runs the Oil Foundation power plant in Karlshamn
so it does not depend on electric deficiency without
It is because the price then is so high
So it pays for the owners to run the production.
So what is our basic problem now?
Is it in the war that Isabella answered and you others have been in?
Or which is the basic problem?
What does Lars J say?
Yes, I would say that this is the basic problem we have right now.
Then we have some problems out in the distribution network with capacity.
But the urgent now is of course the high prices.
Yes, the basic problem is the EU's dependence on Russian gas
And that we have sat down in this dependency relationship.
Now no one has been able to foresee
That we would see an invasion of a European country in our vicinity 2022 or 2021.
And you have not been able to plan for it.
Then you can see that there has been a
lack of planning for too
climate change that one has
seen the gas as a transitional energy type
On the way to completely renewable electricity.
They could not be able to help it in the rearview mirror.
That we have sat down in that addiction is the big problem.
We also have an electricity market model
But marginal pricing ensures that it is the most expensive power that comes in,
In this case, the gas, which sets the price on the entire market.
Many people think it is strange but at the same time one should be aware that
Marginal pricing is not a phenomenon for the electricity market,
It is not so that Norwegian oil for example
Is very cheap just because it is cheap to produce.
It is probably a reasonable principle.
But then the problem is also,
If you take SE4 that we belong to,
Our production capacity is
About half the size of our export capacity from SE4.
This, together with our internal cuts in the country, will drive the price picture in SE4.
Which leads us into this with electric areas, thought as well that we wash it right away
Because I think there are quite a few who are thinking about that.
So we can move on then into what the energy mix should look like and such.
But we received these four electricity areas in 2011 after the bumps from Denmark
And the European Commission.
Since a decision by Svenska Kraftnät whose then Director General was
Mikael Odenberg.
This was your invention.
It was I who made the decision and for a long time I had a loose beard when I went to Skåne.
How smart was this in the rear view mirror?
It was smart given the conditions.
Thus there is very much
ignorance of electricity areas.
It's nothing like bureaucratic invention,
Something you find for fun.
Without electricity area division is ultimately about operational safety.
It is because in an AC network network you cannot influence
How the electricity flows without it flows where the resistance is the least.
When we are going to transfer a lot of electricity from the production in the north to
Consumer Center in the south,
Then it runs a little too much electricity in some wires.
Then they risk being overloaded and can break down and then you can get big power outages.
Then you have to limit this flow in these bottlenecks.
And that is why these four areas were invented?
Until 2011 so
We limited the flow in a very elegant way, we screwed the cranes to Denmark.
Then the flows decreased in these bottlenecks
And then the Danes complained.
They already complained in 2006 to the Commission whose competition directorate started the whole
the investigative apparatus.
When we arrived at 2010, 2011
So were there many meters -high document collections that
The Competition Directorate came along and the message that:
"You can't do this, you can't discriminate against Danish customers".
Okay.
I mean, they were right.
Unfortunately
Then we have to relate to this and what do you do?
Yes, then the conventional wisdom says that then opposes man, that is
The system operator Svenska Kraftnät goes in and shops up
consumption reductions or production increases
so that you affect the actors on both sides of the bottle neck.
And on that road you reduce the flows.
We estimated in 2011 that it was not a viable path,
that we did not have enough opposite resources in
Southern Sweden to
Be able to handle the bottlenecks only with counter -trading.
This situation is even worse today.
It is often the case that it is described as these four electricity areas is about providing incentives to more
Production in the south but that was not what was ...
It was not at all on the map.
Besides, we had very
Small price differences between the electricity areas in the first few years.
According to economic theory, of course it is so
that there should be more investment if the price is higher
But that was never a reason, but it was exclusively operational safety reasons.
We must be able to handle our bottlenecks
in order not to risk large power outages.
When it is not possible to do only with counter -trading
Then only one electricity area division remains.
It also has a different point, namely that it is a fairly market economic
ways to handle the transmission constraints.
And really it is that the problem we have today,
We had the same in the 50s and 60s so we had our water production up the north
and problems to bring down the effect to southern Sweden and then we built
A number of power plants, Öresundsverket in Malmö, Karlshamn and Stenungssund
And basically drove drove daytime.
Then came nuclear power and then we removed them.
Now we remove the nuclear power and have back the same
Problems we had at first.
But Germany has no such electricity areas, Finland has no such electricity areas.
What does Isabella Lövin think about this introduction?
Was it so neat?
Thus, it is a lack of power generation
In the south today and there is a surplus in the north.
But that is today.
Now we see how industry ...
Those investments in green industry now explodes in the north so it does not
sure it is so smart to export this power to the south now without man
Need to expand the power to the south.
Although it was not an incentive from the beginning,
that this would be incentive to more power generation
In the south we have that situation today.
We have very much
Sea -based winds located on the government's table for example.
60 terawatt hours.
We have very much
Even land -based wind power that today municipalities have refused to here in the south,
that more than well cover up for the closed,
suspended reactors.
So that I think this mechanism
Also, it should work to the fact that we actually get more local production.
What does Lars say, how do you assess these electricity areas?
Do they work?
There are many who are very critical of them,
Who would like to see that they disappeared completely.
How do you judge it?
I think they are quite reasonable.
You have to divide in some way and have them,
where one bids in your production and
Buy and sell electricity so I ...
Then you can, after all,
one can certainly change that division, it depends on
If there is something specific you want to achieve with it.
But I think it is a reasonable approach at all,
provides incentives to increased production,
Provides incentives to flexibility as well.
You don't have to have the loose beard on you anymore it seems, in this gang anyway.
No, but you see that I have left it at home.
We need to expand production in SE4 but we actually do the opposite
So we have put down Sweden's most modern power plant that had the best
environmental performance, it is a rather sad story plus it was also
Our ability to implement hydrogen on a wide front.
Is it Öresundsverket in Malmö?
Yes.
And instead you can say that you should criticize it.
There are two levels and partly it is power reserve
But there are also preparedness dimensions around this so total defense stuff,
Where we happily invest a billion in Stockholm on a power plant that is 50 years old
While in Malmö we throw out one that is new and that is actually quite unreasonable.
Is it due to commercial grounds or political or administrative?
Commercial grounds can be said.
The problem was that they wanted to have paid because they were there as a reserve, so to speak.
Had they been lying on the other side of the strait they would have received quite a lot of money
in the Danish system.
Here they bidded to Svenska Kraftnät but you did not get it
And then you had to close down.
Svenska Kraftnät would have no opportunity to trade up either of the simple
The reason that there is no special legislation on this reserve.
There, the Riksdag's successively reduced the scope of it.
We can certainly return a little to the electricity areas during the question time that we drive forward eight hours.
I want to get into what the energy mix should look like in Sweden in the future.
Now we have
the moderately-led government and SD who presented their visions in the Tidö agreement
Which, after all, opens for new nuclear power.
400 billion in credit guarantees and new construction of nuclear power.
Is that a good idea Lars?
New nuclear power?
I think it will be too expensive.
It was a card ...
I think no one will want
Invest unless you give the right far -reaching subsidies.
The example is in England with Hinkley Point
that has an agreement on
in 30 or 35 years of age they shall deliver
For SEK 1 per cent per kWh, it is quite expensive.
In Finland, we have a power plant that has extracted a lot at the time.
It takes a long time to build new nuclear power.
17 years they have been there.
So it gets too expensive simply?
I think so,
There will be no investments for market -based grounds.
What does our second engineer believe?
I think like this: that we can be much better than that.
The other Swedish we built at 5-6 years each
And my attitude is that we will need just all the power we can get.
We need a healthy mix between
non-planning and planning and there I see that
Nuclear power has an important part to fill.
It is partly planned I would say.
If we are to say how planned, Svenska Kraftnät counts 9 % accessibility on wind power
And 90 on nuclear power so it is better.
But Lars J, when it is not planned, what makes it thrill then?
Is it when it gets too hot in the cooling water because of the summer heat?
It can be anything possible.
In France Har you had the problems
now with the hot summer and lack of water,
lack of cooling water and
technical problems that arise as
We now have that Ringhals could not restart
And the other day I hicked up when Oskarshamn 3 went down.
So fortunately they got it up again fairly quickly but otherwise it would have been tight.
Lars describes that it gets too expensive, it's just like that but
You see a completely different opportunity.
How do you get to it?
No, but I think like this
that the figures presented today because the production cost of new nuclear power is
Very optimistic.
So I don't think it will be as cheap as we think but at the same time
So we are short of other alternatives.
So we should not have to import,
in the future, fossil power
From other countries this is what applies.
And then maybe it should cost then?
Or must be subsidized in some way.
No, but it will be bid as usual so I don't think
that it needs subsidized that way.
Isabella then?
Yes, the name ...
This will not, firstly, solve the climate issue.
I think that has become quite painfully obvious to most
the last few weeks here now that
If we do not have the climate policy that
Reduces emissions by 2030 so we have to abandon our climate goals so that the whole discussion around
nuclear power as a solution to the climate issue
have been severely misleading and it knows that everyone who knows something about
How long it takes to build new nuclear power.
So we can leave that like that.
Then the next question is: Okay, but we must have this planned power supply.
Then I think it is important that when issuing 400 billion in so -called
Green credit guarantees that you do it technology neutral.
We have all the possibilities
To use the entire innovation power that exists today in Sweden and in the world
To store energy, to stabilize the electricity grid and
Cut the peaks when it gets very expensive.
We can energy efficiency, we can have smart electricity grids
And it just bursts out of power in business right now.
I was in Estonia a few weeks ago
and there you plan for a huge
Pump water power battery can be said about a mining hole.
So when we are thinking of storage of energy we have mostly talked about making hydrogen
of electricity when is very cheap, when one has an excess of
wind or sun or hydropower
So there can even be negative prices in the market,
You can do a lot during that period.
One can produce green hydrogen and that is what industries in the north
has already invested in.
But there is too
A variety of other ways to do this.
If you looked at Agenda's debate yesterday, then one of the experts tells us that
There are sodium ion batteries, when we think batteries we think lithium and
"Okay, this is a deficiency".
But you are in full swing with making batteries with sodium.
We will return to them.
I mean that this with planned power, that nuclear power is the only answer to that,
It's simply wrong.
We stay in nuclear power.
Mikael, as old moderate, heavy politician,
How do you assess the future of nuclear power?
I think there is
Two problems that one should not deny.
That one is to
It is not so easy for a normally found capitalist to invest SEK 100 billion in a processing
Who will start to yield a return of 10-12 years in a market that you do not know what it looks like.
The second problem that one should also affirm it is to
As soon as you lose a screwdriver in the wrong place in a reactor somewhere in the world so added
It to new cost -driven safety requirements.
With that said, I think that
There are very bright prospects for the concept of small model reactors
where one could keep down the capital tied up,
where one might conceivably get a system of
serial production of these facilities and there is no doubt about
that new such nuclear power in southern Sweden would
Make the Swedish electrical system very well.
Then I am allergic
against this religious belief that not only energy -interested people have
As for what is good electricity generation
But unfortunately, has crept into politics as well.
Parties believe in certain types of electricity generation and against other kinds.
What I have advanced ever since I was an energy political spokesman for the Moderates
94-95,
And which unfortunately is forgotten now,
So it is that it is not the task of politics.
The task of politics is to ensure
that electricity producers may meet the demand of electricity consumers
in a market that is as free as possible.
The Riksdag should not decide to turn off Barsebäck.
Parliament shall not decide to restart Ringhals 2
Without the Riksdag, the rules of the game,
the rules for the market
And that the market has to relate to.
Then we should not develop subsidies, but we should discontinue subsidies.
Magnus Genrup, this with SMR, small modular reactors, one can of course drop a
wrench in them as well.
There are the high security requirements, for every accident that occurs, they increase the requirements and
Of course.
Is that where you also see an opportunity?
No, I am personally not convinced that SMR is the right path
But it is something that has become popular and one believes that
will be cheaper but as I said,
You will need many SMRs and the question is whether it will be cheaper to build a large
And there I have not landed myself, I can say.
The logic of nuclear development has always been so -called shell economy,
So building bigger it will be cheaper.
Now you say that you should do the opposite.
I agree with Mikael in a lot of what you say, it can certainly go a little faster.
I am not very hopeful that one will be able to push down the costs
So awful much.
For it is still a reactor with
Pipes and generators and turbines and capacitors.
But significantly less than a conventional?
A little less yes.
And maybe 60 years of operating time so it's a good time to pay off.
It is very important to inform people that there is no country that has SMRs.
There is no series production of these small nuclear reactors.
That we will get this scale advantage then we must start
bring with us a very bunch of countries on wanting
Very many SMRs.
Then one will also come
Problem to into the picture
And that is the availability of uranium.
So today, the existing mines and assets that exist
They will last between 50 and 100 years it says on Vattenfall's website.
We say 80 years then.
If we see a doubling of investment in nuclear power around the world
yes, but then we will end up uranium about
40 years and then we have to start looking for new assets.
Then maybe we have to start thinking: "Well, but then we have to
secure a national access to uranium "and start breaking again in Sweden and then
Do we know that there is
Assets on Österlen for example.
Do we want it?
I mean, this is no quick fix.
This is nothing easy
to invest in nuclear power.
That SMR does not exist, every submarine has one
slightly larger variety, even a number of Russian nuclear submarines so technology is there,
It is not that it is brand new.
But there are security aspects of that too.
Now think if we had 10 SMR placed around Kiev,
No height.
Nah.
Is it an aspect that has become
More important or more acute Mikael?
Thus purely security policy aspects of
Nuclear power plants as targets in war?
Yes, it is clear now that we have a war and
battles around the nuclear power plants in Ukraine, it is clear that it puts an increased focus on
That aspect, of course it is.
But I don't think it disqualifies nuclear power.
But you still have to weigh.
Now we have applications that are rejected by
Municipality by municipality
on wind power that corresponds to approximately all of Sweden's production.
We have one side, on the other hand we have a technology that
We have no economist whatsoever of today, we have just approved
Final repository for
the fuel or for the waste,
But it is only enough for the existing nuclear power we have today.
If we start to scale this up then we will have new waste laws.
We must ensure uranium from somewhere.
We just said no to uranium from Russia which is a big
exporter out of uranium to
Lots of countries.
It is another such security policy
problem.
I mean we shouldn't ...
It has really been portrayed in this electoral movement as something completely safe and
reliable and cheap.
It is wrong on all points.
Magnus, I don't want to put on the total nuclear power
But you still have to try to respond to that.
No, but of course we have to solve the waste problem.
There is no doubt about it.
But the reactors of the future, the generation beyond those we are talking about today
will generate less waste.
Absolutely.
So it can resolve that way?
Partly.
Back to the task of politics, I mean
Svenska Kraftnät today has an investment program on
75 billion as they call north -south
Reinforce the transfer from north to south.
The problem is that if Hybrit and O2 Green style are really realized,
You know nothing about that then maybe that electricity is needed up there.
How do we solve the situation?
Yes, then it's all about getting large amounts of electricity
In southern Sweden and what should the government do?
Yes, it is reasonably to eliminate obstacles to investment, create a nutrition -friendly climate.
What one is very focused to do when it comes to nuclear power,
Remove the restrictions for where to build and how much you can build.
But we have similar problems in the investment climate
In terms of land -based wind power,
closest to the municipal veto.
One may very well have a municipal veto
But then you have to rig it on such a investment so that invests
not first get yes and then get no five in twelve
And then finally you need to create an investment climate
For sea -based wind power that is
The stroke of power where we could quickly get very large amounts of electricity.
There is no arranged process today at all
And the new government has also stoked to it further.
Let's take wind power because, as I said, there are a number, seven large projects
of sea -based wind power waiting for
Permissions and the process and the new government and the Tidö Agreement have then decided to
Place the connection cost to the companies themselves just like maybe on other types of energy before
The former government, you know everything about,
have said that the state would subsidize or account for that cost.
What does this change mean?
Is it sticks in the wheel for the wind power Lars?
I don't think it needs to be a huge change.
It is a connection cable that needs to be built.
It is longer than that?
No, but I thought ...
Sure, then either Svenska Kraftnät can stand for the cost or sheep
The projector is responsible for the cost.
Finally, it is the customer collective that pays somewhere.
So it's more how to post it.
So in Denmark
Do you have exactly that arrangement,
that is, it is the projector as self
pays for the connection
And they think they are great.
They take it out on the electricity price later.
Yes, because Ørsted thinks we can build
Cheaper than their network companies can.
But I was going to say to Mikael.
Well, it's a debate!
No, but I think that if you need the electricity in the north then you should expand wind power in the north
too and those in this
The Hybrid project, for example, they are set to the fact that it is cheap wind power that will drive their
processes so that they
Dimensions electrolyzers and hydrogen layers just before matching against wind power.
All my point is to
the entire tool image radically changes when you consume so much up there
And in a few years, like the conditions for Svenska Kraftnät's
Planning was actually eliminated.
It may not be invested so much in this transformation at all.
Then when it comes to
Wind power is that
When the government introduced this
The assignment to Svenska Kraftnät to establish connection points at sea so there were many
who had objections to it in the referral round not just the bourgeois parties
And the Swedish Democrats, but also some authorities as the Swedish Competition Authority.
That you treat differently?
Yes, one had in principle objection that it could partly be perceived as a subsidy
to that kind of electricity generation.
This is type example on when politicians are to be sensible
for there they would have left short lying
and said: “Good that they introduced that because we had never been able to do it with our
Principal attitude but now we leave shortly lying ".
You did not and it creates then
New ambiguities about investment conditions again, there is no organized process.
Investors in offshore wind power, those behind this seven applications,
they were assumed
Invest SEK 10 million in bottom surveys,
planning without having any rush about
they will ultimately get the necessary permits.
This is hydropower that corresponds to all current nuclear power
And it is sad if it gets delayed.
There are very large amounts of energy,
Still with the major disadvantage that it is weather dependent.
So that a combo of sea -based wind that could be in place,
If the permits, worked before 2030
and new nuclear power that could be in place before 2035
Would be an excellent mix.
Magnus.
There I agree too, that mix.
Then there is a dimension that is important, it is
Total defense dimension.
We cannot start the country with wind power if we were to get a big disorder.
We need a real production
With real turning mass in the system.
You like turbines?
Yes, what you say is that wind power can deliver turning mass,
Yes if it blows but it does not blow then there is no swinging mass.
Is the real foundation nuclear power or cogeneration?
Cogeneration in principle,
It doesn't have to be nuclear power,
There may be other generators but we need the right foundation in the system.
No, but I agree very much what Mikael says except that I don't think
It is just nuclear power ...
Not?!
No!
Surprising!
But this particular with permit processes
And how you have been messing with it now and it seems to be almost ideological reluctance
against us having renewable energy because you have locked up so incredibly
With this with nuclear power in the current government.
You even voted no, ie it applies
This municipal veto that Mikael mentioned
So it is so that the municipalities can say no to new wind power
But not only
At the beginning of the process, you can say no when there is a shift if,
let us say
A member of the City Council changes page
So all of a sudden one turns in opinion on this wind power investment
And suddenly you don't want it anymore.
At any time in the process, this can happen.
So it is not for any other establishment of anything else in Sweden, just for wind power.
It is clear that it gives extremely high doubts for those who are going to invest in it,
Uncertainty that it can turn around at any time.
And it is also very contradictory when the same parties,
When we had one
Completed proposal presented for the Riksdag this summer
So voted
These nowadays the Tidö parties no to this because you ...
Yes, there was no good explanation as to why you voted no, you just voted no to
To abolish this extended opportunity to change, to say no at the end of the process.
What do the engineers say about the municipal vetot
Who can mess with it for both wind power and other facilities?
Yes, we are not experts on really
Maybe but of course ....
You can appoint national interest and change such things.
I would call that one
Political question where I have no ...
But I have a question for Magnus.
You are welcome.
Won't be, you say nuclear power,
If we can get very cheap wind or solar,
cannot be cheaper to make electrolysis hydrogen
Methanol
and then back in
Nice gas turbines for electricity.
One loses half of the energy on the road
But they can still be cheaper than nuclear power.
In principle, one can say like this that
Do we talk 1000 operating hours a year
So we are at 2.50 kW per hour approximately
in that production.
It may be worth it.
On that kind of production do you mean?
Unfortunately it is so that you only get a quarter when you drive back
So it's a big pin on the road.
It all is based on the fact that
We have a surplus of wind production that we do not need here and now.
If we are also going to double our cargo in the country, the question is whether this electricity will not go.
I don't know that but still,
The efficiency back and forth is very, very bad.
You mentioned hydropower before, pump power.
It's so much more elegant really.
There you talk about getting 85 % efficiency and it is very good, and this one at 25, at best.
I think that question is very relevant
But it would be good if it was not answered by professors or politicians
Without the investors.
We have a consumption today at somewhere around 140 terawatt hours and according to calculation
In a few years, 2030, we will be up at 220 and 320 in 2045
So it is like a steep increase in our needs if we are to electrify this country of the future
And then a mix is required, I guess?
No, but they are the forecasts vary.
The Swedish Energy Agency
says much less than that and one should remember that 1970
So did you think that 2000 would have the least
twice as large energy needs
in Sweden
and we've actually been just lying still
All the time since then, despite increased population, despite a huge growth.
So energy efficiency is also a very important instrument
As we have not mentioned here at all.
But now think the last month when Swedish households have reduced their electricity.
by almost 20 %
Without even we even had a campaign that we should.
The industry is usually said to have about 25 % the possibility of energy efficiency.
Now it will go to huge amounts of electricity in the north to Hybris to H2
Style and all these.
We know that.
But I also see that
There is a huge innovation force in
How to also want to rig these systems.
Again storage is something we have not mentioned much.
Should we have nuclear power plants or small nuclear power plants
that should go all the time to cut the tops
When it is not blowing?
When we could, on the other hand
have huge energy storage in old mining holes, battery storage, hydrogen,
Methane, all this you are talking about now.
We are going to the future, we will not be back.
Lars, as an engineer if you met, now they are former politicians
But if you got to meet the responsible politicians, what would you advise them for something?
What should the mix look like?
What is the most important thing to think about?
I would probably go on Michael's line rather there,
that they should try to create stable conditions,
A game plan
so market players know they can trust
block -crossing agreements.
It may contain space and conditions for
Plan for nuclear power
And then you will see if the investors go on that ball or not.
Personally I am not so hopeful that you will be able to push the costs
But I don't exclude it.
Magnus and then Mikael.
It is also true that Swedish cogeneration that is the base in district heating
Is pretty bad at producing electricity on the heat substrate.
It is fully sensible because we have had low electricity prices but
We could build so much better and more efficient facilities
With tremendously more electricity generation than we do today.
And they are driven by?
Biomass.
So it's good production in that moon.
I was involved a little bit in the last Energy Commission's work and it came
From 2016.
At that time
Then, like still, Northvolt and Hydbrids were not on the map so that
The Swedish Energy Agency's estimates of electricity consumption 2030 to 2040
Be quite modest.
Now all of a sudden it is doubled.
It has then happened in 5-6 years.
It indicates that an important task and
And politics is quite different.
Namely to shorten the lead times
to build new power generation and to build new transmission.
It takes 10-12 years to build a 400 kW power line, from ax to limp.
It goes half as fast in Finland.
There is very much to do here.
Politics has begun to take hold of it
But there is much left to do.
We need radically
Short these times.
Should we check if anyone in the audience feels urged to comment
anything of this or setting a
Ask and you are welcome to signal, raise a paw.
If you run forward here we have a man in light blue shirt
Who wipes the second row, you are kind.
I can add that if I had met politicians then I would probably have given a little lecture
About nuclear power that I usually give at LTH.
There seems to be a lot of ignorance ...
In politics?
Yes.
Briefly introduce yourself and a short question.
Hi, Torben Claesson.
I live out in Veberöd in Lund municipality.
Out in Veberöd it is 70s villas that are bad
Isolated and electrically heated the entire gang.
After all, we are badly forced to turn off the electricity and go and freeze in there.
So when you say that electricity consumption decreases it does because we cannot afford to pay the bills.
And I wonder,
What do politicians intend to do about this?
Should we go and freeze the hedge of us and get
Mold problems with the house
And allergies and that?
I would have liked to see more action and less talk.
Build something, God knows what,
Just so we get power in the wires again.
Thank you.
Now we do not have active politicians here but Isabella feels anyway ...
Thanks.
First, the EU has agreed that
one should save 5% electricity during the hours it is highest
Load in each Member State and energy researcher counts on it and says that
With only the little savings
So the electricity bills will be halved.
So it's amazing.
But then we need more
Electricity production in southern Sweden.
I mean, again, we have a total production
In Sweden at 140 terawatt.
125 terawatt has been said no to in moderately led municipalities at
land and sea-based wind.
So then you just get a new power, so that you have to think about that situation.
Magnus Genrup, speaking of this with being afraid of
That it will be extinguished and such, you told me that at a given time, you
pretty recently,
Fixed a diesel aggregate at home.
Yes, in the middle of Lund I have a diesel unit so I can go off the grid with my house.
How did you think then?
That I have worked with power plants since 94 around the world.
I have seen such here in Pakistan, India, Africa and Indonesia.
But the idea in Lund was completely absurd from the beginning but then,
This with manual connection is a bad idea and then it became so.
But you judge it as a
Possible risk or possibility that you need to connect it one night or day?
Would we trade in something called mfk
So is it that there is a return load that communicates and handles the risk
with secondary interruptions, they are
I thought about the most.
Do you invite your colleagues home then?
Yes, and neighbors.
I have my own steering list that includes the coffee maker as well.
You can also put some solar cells on the roof and get a battery.
But then I can't secure tension.
I belong to those who do not
thinks it is very wise and foresight policy that
with parliamentary decisions try to compensate for the swings in the world market prices on
Oil and gas.
At the same time
If this is a little neighbor a unique situation.
And then I think it is right to use these capacity fees,
The bottleneck revenue they are commonly called.
55 billion.
Yes, they are generated by the price differences between the electricity areas
and accumulated at Svenska Kraftnät
To be used for investments that build the bottlenecks away
that has generated the price differences but it will take a long time
And then I think it is reasonable, it is probably 80-90 billion that has accumulated there,
then tag thinks it is reasonable that one
in one way or another re -resign
to consumers so that one can
Protect those who happen to be the most bad, both in the industry and
Those with electrically heated detached houses.
But it is important that the return is done with some accuracy.
Here it seems that things are going fast rather than right.
Many industries have after all
bound agreements and such and may be overcompensated when you are just putting
50 öre per kw.
What does Isabella Lövin say about the bottle neck money that is now being repaid to customers?
Are these the correct signals?
So I think it's just right
Take back the money that ...
After all, this prism mechanism has, as Mikael described,
that this is like a commodity market
There is the highest price is what sets the price of everything, even what is very produced,
Very cheap.
So 55 billion is great.
But it is clear that it cuts in the heart that it does not go to such as
In fact, can remove the crisis, but we go back to those like us.
You can buy your
diesel units for the money maybe but
It would be better if we could bet them on a safe climate change for example
or energy efficient action
So that we save energy.
Especially what is concerned it is, after all
that if you send signals to all people to, yes but,
It does not matter, you will be compensated for this on the electricity bill
Then no one saves energy.
In this
emergency situation and again, this is about
That the supply of Russian gas has been strangled, it is gone.
It has led to very, very high
Will in Germany, among other things, to buy electricity from Sweden that exports.
It is the highest price that sets the price of everything, that is the problem.
If we look at what the electricity costs to produce,
hydropower is about 10 öre kilowatt hour, nuclear power approximately
35-40 öre kilowatt hour.
So to some extent, the hit award is all.
The problem is also like this, pose that this persists so we have to
take the bottleneck revenue for a number of years and pay back to
Us so that we get reasonable electricity bills.
It is fundamentally wrong and then at the same time we have
VAT and tax revenue that this year will be approximately SEK 47 billion to the Treasury.
So that somewhere we have to do something else.
Either look at it
or the pricing model because we can't put back the bottle throat all the time,
Over time, how should we handle this?
So, I have a hard time seeing ...
I think you are wrong, Isabella, there.
I think you save electricity
Although you know that you will receive compensation.
This is exactly what we have seen with households in southern Sweden that have actually saved 20%.
Then it is a blunt tool and man
Prioritizes that it should go fast.
There are household customers who have tied electricity prices coming
Earn good at this too.
But then when there is a lack of firewood, you get crank radio, it is a completely different kind of consciousness
among customers or consumers now as we see that makes us start
Save and streamline?
Although we think we should be compensated?
Yes, I think so.
You can't count on
to be compensated with certainty.
Those who counted to get ten
Tighten cheaper diesel at pump ...
Or not.
But this situation then at last as we have with concern, high electricity prices, power shortages,
Sinks very badly with the high-flying plans with a fossil-free future-Sweden,
electrified from north to south
With Northvolt
And hydride and everything it is.
Can we get out of that lock?
We have a great starting point
and with new nuclear power
and large -scale sea -based wind power,
4-5 miles outside
the coast, beyond the municipal veto purely geographically,
so we get a emission -free electrical system
And then the climate issue becomes for us
Completely focused on the transport sector.
Isabella.
Yes, so we basically already have a, to some extent, a emission -free electrical system and it is important to
Build on it and it is important to build for the future so that it is also smart.
It includes energy efficiency, it includes smart
Control systems, it includes storage and storage capacity.
It will also be a service that you can pay for.
And demand flexibility, absolutely.
So I don't see any major problems at all.
What I see as the great threat to this,
It is that you are now so fixated on building new nuclear power
That you put a stop to everything else.
One sends very strong signals about
That we should not have sea -based wind power, now you get
Invest themselves in these connection fees.
You veto to get ground -based ...
And do not invest in storage and smart electrical systems, ie plan for it.
We have to plan for such a system.
Now you are planning for SMRs that do not even exist
and there
prices will be so high so it can make the industry hesitate in
to invest in these processes that will require huge amounts of electricity that need to be
Very cheap.
And that is what can put obstacles in the way.
Energiforsk presents the figure 56 öre kW, should we believe them?
Energiforsk has presented the figure 56 öre per kilowatt hour.
IPCC says 1.50.
On what energy then?
Energy body.
Small, small modular ...
For nuclear power plants?
Okay.
But what do they say about renewable energy with the full system cost?
I don't remember the figures but the report is available.
Sea -based wind is in the same piece.
Okay, not get stuck to those numbers but then Lars then, at the time,
Now you heard Isabellas
Problem description there, is it so bleak?
No, so I think ...
As Mikael started with Sweden having fantastic conditions with existing
Hydropower, bioenergy, good wind conditions.
We can build solar cells, we can even build solar cells in the Arctic.
It can be interesting
If we have the basic industry up there.
So all conditions exist
So I think like this:
Now it is war and a fairly acute energy crisis.
I also think you get
have some ice in the stomach and think that it worked pretty well just a year ago
and maybe not tear up everything
in affection.
With the words from Lars J Nilsson who is a professor of environmental and energy systems here in Lund
So we end debate in Lund here.
Thanks to you Lars, thanks to Magnus Genrup, Isabella Lövin
and Mikael Odenberg and to all of you as
come here tonight and all of you as
followed us via screen
And TV and so on.
Many thanks!