Hello! We broadcast from Lund University where we interview a researcher every day with
Research that in one way or another relates to the Corona crisis.
And today I have with me Henrik Andersson, a researcher in practical philosophy. Welcome!
Right now, care is facing very difficult decisions and doctors all over the world
Must choose whose life to be saved.
In what way did your research related to the Corona crisis?
As a moral philosopher, I think much of all research in philosophy
relating to the Corona crisis.
But come to me specifically so i have researched
Much about difficult comparisons.
And then it is about choices we make
When to choose between two different options and the options differ
In such a way that it seems impossible to say which is the better option.
It can be alternatives that are so different in its character
So that it seems difficult to know how they relate to each other.
And if we don't know how they relate to each other
Then it will also be difficult to make the right decision.
And it seems to be the way it looks today
In many ways.
Partly at some kind of state level
where Sweden as a state is trying to arrive at
What strategy we should have to fight the Corona outbreak.
Partly it is about the value of human life
But you also hear those who discuss
Values that may be more linked to economy
and that the standard of living will be reduced
If we try to fight the Corona infection too strongly.
So there are two very different values that are in contrast to each other.
And then the question is: How should we act?
A question asked right now is who would have the most right to intensive care
If two patients are set against each other, o ch i have a case here that I would like you
Thinking about from a philosophical perspective.
If two people,
who have the same need for a respirator to survive:
one is a 53-year-old sofa potato with poor health
And the other a 73-year-old Superatlet.
Their biological age is the same and they would have equal opportunities to survive.
How would you reason and what would you need to know?
I have come across many of this kind of questions
And they have seen on social media how people have reasoned about these types of questions.
I don't think the interesting is
To give a definitive answer
on this kind of question, without what is interesting
is that it rather raises questions
When you think about these things
So maybe someone is asking the question
What do we know about these people? Is one doctor for example?
Then maybe some feel that if it is a doctor then we should of course prioritize that person
While others may think it should not play any major role
So what is good about this kind of case
and to discuss them I think is that one
can learn anything from them.
One can try to reason up to what is relevant and important to know
in these situations.
And there maybe you come up with different answers.
Hopefully you arrive at the same answer
So that we can have some kind of consensus around them.
I think one should be careful about saying
That it should of course be this younger person to be chosen here.
In these cases we know far too little
About these people to make a good decision.
So it is good to lift these issues, because we can
come to what we need to know more and need to know
And we need to know more or if something is missing.
And if we all agree that if it is a doctor, it is clear that we should prioritize that person
Then we have learned something that we can bring it out in real life.
Or if we learn that it is not important what they have for professions
and that it is not important what types of life they will live
After they have become healthy, then we have also learned something.
Then we can bring this knowledge out in real life
Where we will encounter much more complex cases and situations.
I think it should look at these types of questions.
Another topical question is how much we should slow down the economy
to save human life. How would you reason about this?
What I think is interesting in such cases
is to ask the question is what we really want to know when we make such a comparison
About economic prosperity and human life.
And i think it is not about
that those who advocate financially and that we are not allowed to take on everything for drastic methods
Because it will have bad consequences for GDP and so on.
What they mean is probably not that we should
Protect people's money on the bank, without they mean it will have poor health effects
on individuals and society if we choose
To put too much financial resources here and now.
So what is really important
In this election situation, perhaps the health aspect is.
So it may not be about two fundamentally different
values where we are to compare economy and human life
but in many ways it is probably about
Health aspects here as well. And then it is important to know what would have the best health effects.
Is it not not to make a total lockdown
Or is to actually do it. Which has the best health effects?
And that is a question that others may be better suited to answer
But I think it's important to see that it doesn't have to be about
Two widely different values that are in conflict here really.
Do you think philosopher's knowledge is utilized in this Corona crisis?
To some extent it has been done because moral foil has been involved in
to develop different guidelines, far earlier but also to some extent now
How to make priorities.
It is clear that our knowledge could perhaps be used more than that.
Above all, perhaps for individuals in society.
I think it's a special time now
Then many people can live their everyday life without having to think
Too much on ethical issues.
You may have pondered some things in periods in your life, many times maybe in your teens:
is it right or wrong to eat meat
and one may have come up with an answer to that
and can justify for oneself and others to do so,
Or you put your head in the sand.
And so you can live a rather carefree life afterwards
Because one has made many ethical positions
But today it seems that we are facing ethical positions daily
And difficult questions even in our everyday lives.
Should we go to Åre or may I go and visit my older parents or whatever it may be.
There are many difficult ethical decisions that we encounter daily.
And there I think there is a lot of expertise in philosophy
To help people make these decisions.
Above all, I think philosophers can contribute
The tools needed to answer these types of questions.
To give people concepts to that
Discuss this and know how to reason.
It might facilitate their ethical pondering.
One last question: Do you think that the Corona crisis will in any way affect research in philosophy?
I certainly think it will.
There will be some ethical issues that one must address
After all this is overplayed.
It is perhaps difficult to say what those issues will be here and now
But I also think it will affect philosophers
in the way we discuss many times
quite extreme situations on a very theoretical plane
We are thinking about extreme situations
and trying to come up with answers how to act in those cases
And now we may be in such a situation.
And then maybe there is an opportunity for us philosophers
To ask the question again.
Now that it really is a reality, I can still stuck to my opinion
And can I still think my arguments are holding?
It is perhaps an opportunity to think about their positions once again. I think so.
Thanks so much Henrik Andersson
It was all for this time and more news
From Lund University can be read at www.lu.se