Hello and warm welcome you should be light Swedish with Oskar.
My name is Oskar and I do a podcast called easily Swedish with Oskar.
You may have heard it?
It's like a fun and easy way to learn Swedish.
You can listen while doing other things.
You can listen while you go for a walk, while you wash, while cleaning, while driving, while you go by bus.
...and so on.
And now I want to try to make easy Swedish with Oskar as video, as well as video,
Right here on Youtube.
I think it will be fun to try to do something completely new.
I can show things,
I can ... like ... I exist!
...differently.
I can show that you sleep, for example.
... or whatever it may be.
You can play guitar for example.
And in this first, first clip I want to introduce myself.
And I think like this, that you who have listened now ... There are 170 episodes of the podcast, to listen to.
You feel pretty good already,
But you may not have seen me ever.
And are you brand new here, and have YouTube: that you want to learn Swedish,
Yes, then it is also a perfect way to feel welcome and feel that we get to know each other a little.
Remember to like and subscribe and you will help me very much.
Here it will be filled with materials and content that is used to learn Swedish in a fun way.
My name is Oskar Nyström and I am 31 years old.
I live in a small town called Forshaga,
which is located two miles north of another city called Karlstad - a larger city.
20 kilometers north of Karlstad.
There is Forshaga and there I live.
... in this house.
I live with my fiancee, Amanda, and our two children.
We have twins.
Daughters.
Twin daughters.
They turn seven this year.
Amanda and I have been together for eight years.
... so then you may understand that it went pretty quickly from the fact that we suddenly had two children.
They came at the same time.
But it has been great and we are very happy together.
We have a lot of fun together.
We also have a puppy called Sixten.
Sixten is only four months old,
And we have had him for three weeks now with us,
So he's brand new.
He is brand new in life and brand new to us.
None of us have had a dog before,
So it's struggling and fun and we love him.
I enjoy playing music.
It began as a love for the piano,
And then became a love for guitar and such.
And now it has also become a job.
So I work with playing music.
I work on producing music in studio
And I play music live.
Most guitar and vocals,
But also with my band called the Norrskens Orchestra.
Last year, in the summer of 2022, I took a motorcycle driver's license.
It was a dream come true for me.
And I took my driver's license on a Triumph Trident 660.
It was an absolutely perfect motorcycle to start.
And absolutely perfect to commute with, for example.
And like that.
But, it was a little too small to take on long holiday trips,
And I also felt that it is probably a little too small overall.
I wanted a little more huge motorcycle.
You feel, when you are on the highway for example,
That it goes very, very fast.
Especially on a small motorcycle like Triumph Trident 660.
And...
Last summer we did so, me and Amanda - my fiancee - that we went on a holiday.
A motorcycle holiday to Öland.
It is an island on the southeastern part of Sweden.
Very nice.
And then we took an old, scruffy ...
Old and risky - but big - motorcycle called Honda Deauville.
We took it there, and then we noticed that we love this.
It was as much fun to go on a motorcycle holiday together.
So then I did so I sold both Hondan and my Triumph Trident 660
and bought a Triumph Tiger 900 GT Pro.
And it does ... everything as well.
I can't imagine a better motorcycle in any category really.
It is absolutely amazing,
And on it we will go on a motorcycle holiday this summer again.
And I use it to commute, to go out on the weekends, and such.
Riding a motorcycle has become a kind of meditation for me.
I can relax.
And just disconnect the thoughts.
And you are just here and now.
There is something about sitting outdoors, on a bike as well as ...
But that goes very, very fast ...
which is very addictive.
And the idea of this Youtube channel is, among other things, to take with you on fun trips, and to great places in Sweden.
So from the motorcycle.
I'll take you on the motorcycle.
You sit something like here.
And so...
are we going.
So I hope you will look forward to it.
I also like to read books.
Especially fantasy, horror and science fiction.
I like playing video games,
And I like to watch sports.
Football, Hockey, Formula 1, Motogp ...
For example.
Handball I think is totally okay too, if Sweden plays like that.
And yes!
In recent years here I have learned Japanese.
I have plugged Japanese from home, on the internet as well,
Quite so diligently.
So I know what it's like to learn a new language.
And I know pretty well what resources, what materials, what tools you need, such ...
And that, it's a journey that is still going on for me, to learn Japanese.
But I also know the joy of understanding more and more,
To find a good routine,
Finding something that is not super boring, but something you like.
Something fun to do.
And it's something I hope and believe this Youtube channel should be able to become,
And something that I think the podcast easily Swedish with Oskar is already.
Actually.
I think we got it good.
That was a little about me,
And I think it will be enough for presentation in this first video.
In the next we do some kind of deep dive into a subject,
What it can be.
How did it go for you?
Did you understand everything?
Did you understand a little?
It's totally okay.
If you just understood a little, you can get back to this video in a few weeks
And see if you can understand more.
Subscribe so we continue to learn Swedish together simply.
Okay, we'll hear again next time.
Bye.