38 adjectives - Learn Swedish with Marie
There are subtitles in many languages.
Hello everyone! Welcome!
Today I will go through 38 adjectives.
I will tell you how they are conjugated by EN-word, by ETT word and by plural-words.
The good thing is that you can also figure out adverbs.
Because in Swedish the adverb looks the same as in ETT-word.
It's good, is it not!
Then you already know all the adverbs.
Feel free to say after (me).
I exaggerate the pronunciation.
So that you will see my mouth movements.
Imitate me and tell.
Do you exaggerate too.
Let's go!
angry, one-word, angry, one-word, angry, plural
I have an angry dog ​​and angry cats!
satisfied - one-word, satisfied - one-word, satisfied - plural
I am satisfied with my test!
dissatisfied one-word, dissatisfied one-word, dissatisfied plural
I am dissatisfied with my test!
warm, warm, warm
I have a warm jacket and warm shoes.
calm, calm, calm
The children are calm.
expensive, expensive, expensive
There are expensive clothes in this store.
young, young, young
A young teacher has started school.
proud, proud, proud
Today I am a proud mother.
worried, worried, worried
It is a worried mother who is looking for her child.
boring, sad
I have received sad news.
It's been a boring day.
free, free, free
I am finally free from the flu.
Sunday is a free day.
Is the table vacant?
cold, cold, cold
It's a cold day.
What a cold house!
happy, happy, happy
My parents are happy.
unhappy, unhappy, unhappy
There are many unhappy children.
It was an unfortunate decision.
grateful, grateful, grateful
I am grateful that I am healthy.
ungrateful, ungrateful, ungrateful
an ungrateful man,
an ungrateful job
shy, shy, shy
It's a shy boy.
He's not talking.
rich, rich, rich
It's a rich country.
Millionaires are rich.
poor, poor, poor
It's a poor country.
Students are poor.
strong, strong, strong
A strong medicine.
She can lift 100 kg, a strong woman.
impatient, impatient, impatient
An impatient child can not wait.
difficult, difficult, difficult
It is a difficult decision.
Difficult questions.
easy, easy, easy
It's an easy decision.
Easy questions.
simple, simple, simple
It's a simple problem.
A single bed.
A single ticket
new, new, new
I have bought new clothes today!
kind
I have very kind students!
dear, dear, dear
A dear girl,
a dear visit.
We are in love with each other.
heavy, heavy, heavy
A heavy car.
A difficult decision.
surprised, surprised, surprised
A surprised min.
A surprised child.
Surprised people
strange, strange, strange
A strange animal.
I saw a strange movie yesterday.
brave, brave, brave
It's a brave girl.
We must make a brave decision!
hungry, hungry, hungry
A hungry lion.
The children are hungry!
starved, starved starved (I have misspelled the picture !!!)
A starving lion.
The children are starving!
happy, happy, happy
It's wonderful with happy people!
sad, sad, sad
Pelle is crying.
He's sad, a sad boy!
narrow, slim
I have a slim dog and walk on a narrow path.
thick, thick, thick
I have a thick cat and a thick jacket.
There were 38 adjectives.
Try to use more adjectives and adverbs when talking.
Then you get a rich language.
There will be more movies because I have 100 adjectives which are the 100 most common adjectives.
But if I had taken them all, this movie would be very long.
see you in the next movie
Try to learn some new words every day.
Feel free to write them too!
Then you will learn how to spell them.
see you in the next movie.
Have a good time until then!
Bye!
Thank you for watching my movies.