My name is Bao Shou Mei.
I was born in 1966.
In 1978, people could already start doing their own business.
You could start making money on your own, small scale.
But the farmland was not divided up between the families until 1980.
When the agricultural reform happened the division of the land took place at once.
We were all part of different production teams.
So they took the land of the production team and distributed it between the families.
It was distributed according to how many people was part of the household.
How much land you got depended on how big the family was.
At the time we were eight people in our household.
That's quite many.
Yes, we were eight people, so we got well over 10 mu land. (about one hectare)
Families that had sons
had it easier to work the fields
In my family we were only girls to do manual labour, which was quite tiring.
But all my sisters would give it their all.
At that time, my two older sisters were already married into other families,
But now we were free to do farm work as we saw fit,
and they could come to our home and help us if they wanted.
So they came with their husbands to help us out.
My father passed away 24 years ago, almost 25 years ago.
I miss my father very much.
While children in other families would often go hungry,
He never let me and my sisters go hungry.
Secretly, he would take eggs into the city -
At that time, you couldn't do any type of business.
If you got caught, you would get into trouble and get shamed publicly.
But my father secretly brought our family's eggs into to the city,
and exchanged them for corn flower.
We never had to go hungry.
He was so good to us, his daughters.
At times when other families could not eat meat,
he would give us meat to eat.
Even if it was very little, he would still make sure we got some.
So we all endured that way.
When I came into this family, when we got married,
We had a home with two rooms.
One of them was a new room, prepared for us, the newly weds.
We got married 1988, and the house was built in 1987.
It was built with wood, but very bad quality wood.
It was also a very simple house.
A house of the worst kind.
When I married into this family, life was still not very good.
But I changed their lives.
I began raising a pig.
I then sold the pig, and used the money to buy a small donkey.
After we bough the little donkey,
We could use the donkey to transport washing powder.
We would go to other villages,
like villages up in the mountains,
And exchange the washing powder for potatoes.
We would then sell the potatoes and make money from that.
And then slowly the donkey got older and wasn't as helpful anymore.
So we bought a big mule, and a horse cart.
That way we could transport even more.
We saved up money like that for two years, and then we could build a new house of pine wood.
Our children were also little older at that time,
so we could be away from home for longer then,
which made it easier to save up money for the house.
That must have been in 1997 or 1998.
It was the same year that Hong Kong was transferred back to China!
I remember that we had a small television in our house when it was built.
We brought the TV with us to my husbands brothers house,
and we all watched the news together on the TV.
At that time, when we build the house, everyone would compliment us.
The house was built all by wood.
But then everybody started building brick houses.
So we began thinking that we wanted to build one of those too.
But it would be a shame to tear down the wooden house.
It was only a few years old.
When we built it, we said we could grow old there.
That our kids could grow old there.
Everyone in the village was saying that.
It would have been a shame to tear it down.
So we decided to change some of our land for a place where we could build this new house.
So we started to prepare to move to this place and build a house here instead.
We built it in 2010.
If you compare my life as a 12 year old and my children's lives as 12 year olds,
there are both similarities and differences.
One difference is that they all went to school.
None of my sisters went to school.
My husband also didn't go to school.
But my both of my children went to school.
When I was young, there would be maybe seven or eight kids out of twenty that went to school.
All the rest didn't go to school, but did manual work in the work unit.
But when we had children,
China had new policies to whipe out illiteracy.
And every child were to attend school.
So, when my children grew up everyone went to school.
When I grew up, every family had just a small house.
If it was a family with many sons, but they were not married yet,
Everyone would sleep on the big kang together.
In winter time it was heated up with dried leaves and straw.
When it was heated up, everyone slept there together.
It was the same all over north-western China.
When we cooked we didn't use electricity.
We burned straw for cooking.
We had a stove made of soil
a big wok, and a bellows.
We would use the bellows to blow on the fire to keep it going.
One person would use the bellows while another would be cooking.
When we ate we didn't have these kitchen tables.
Just a small table that we put on the kang.
The older people would sit on the kang and eat.
The really small children would also sit on the kang.
The older kids would just take their bowls and sit wherever.
As long as they were fed that was fine.
When we were young,
The water we drank was spring water.
At that time there was no pollution, the water was very clean.
The quality was very good too.
We would just dig a well next to the river.
Then we would just drink the water from the well.
I never left this village, I've always lived here.
When I was 40 years old, or almost 40 years old...
When I was 38... I've forgotten.
That's about the time when the water got polluted and we couldn't drink it any more.
If we drank our spring water then, it was bad for our health.
The government build water pipes so we all had running water instead.
This water came from the mountains.
After that we all had running water to drink.
We didn't have to go fetch water anymore.
At home we just used running water, it was really convenient.
At that time we didn't have all these ideas about not having enough.
Not having enough money, or not having enough of this or that.
We didn't think like that.
If you had enough to eat in the morning, but not in the evening -
Then you would eat happily in the morning.
And when you had finished the food in the morning,
you would go out and try to make sure you could get something to eat for the evening.
That was a common situation for families here.
But people were still happy, very happy.
Every day people were laughing and smiling.
Both the adults and the children.
So what do you think it's like nowadays, then?
I think nowadays...
People who are forward thinking, they earn money fast.
But regardless if you make a lot of money or if you struggle, people are still the same.
The atmosphere is not as joyous any longer.
It's really uncommon.
Now everyday is just about money. Money, money, money.
People who have no money, are trying to earn money, always thinking about money.
People who have money are also...
...all about money
All about money, yes. That's what it's like.