Student life in Halmstad. Student Moa tells.
Moa is my name, reading political science- social analysis and communication-
-tredje year at Halmstad University.
Right now I am on the western beach.
The best thing about Halmstad is precisely the beaches, absolutely.
It's close to everything!
Jump up on the bike and you come to both city and nature, and the school.
I like the library very much.
There I like to sit and plug in peace and quiet.
Or ask for help when I need to look for something.
There is a very nice atmosphere in there.
It is a lovely atmosphere in school.
Very driven students and committed teachers.
I like it very well.
Halmstad University is a very good school that I can highly recommend.