I love that the people are green is ....
It was about it.
Yes, people don't really know.
Green is pretty underrated brown too I think.
Brown and green i think are two very underrated colors
When you keep on.
It will never ever become original again, I can say.
No, not after I was here either.
That said, my artist's ability extends so far
That I can with distress and hardly draw a bar guy.
Then it is extra fun that Kenneth comes here and drives on a little neighbor.
But the waffle, stop blowing, it blows in all directions now all of a sudden.
During work they have put down type especially the final finish
Have they put down non -existent.
That's what I like about this whole.
Good morning, sleep well?
Yeah i wake up in the middle of the night when my brain starts planning
Before day two here.
So yeah, i was awake for an hour to there in the middle of the night
At half past four an hour ago I fell asleep again.
And you kept falling asleep when we had dinner yesterday.
Yes, I was well tired so I leaned against the box.
Then I felt that now my eyes are starting to flutter
Now it's time to go up and rest a little.
You had a long time yesterday.
Yeah, I did the foundation and got pretty much
Of the lines too, but there is some left, absolutely.
It's the fun left now, so to speak.
The motives and some text and these things that I should do.
Will still take eight ten hours anyway.
Yes, it will probably take this all day before it's done.
Although this time we'll probably try to pause a little in the middle of Dan
And have lunch so you don't get completely spinning in your head.
It's not a stupid idea. Andreas works today.
Yes he is not there and I think that is great fun
And he will not come and look at the car until it is done.
No matter when he quits.
So it's very fun I think.
So then we get to see his reaction becomes like "pimp my ride" when he comes later.
Should you reveal what to do?
Yes he talks about that he wanted something
that type was a bit of a military
And more military than bombers shark teeth.
I don't think so.
Do not have to drive otherwise.
You drive something really cool.
I think it's pretty cool.
Unfortunately there are very many who make very weird shark teeth
on the side of the car by type so far or something like that
Where you buy decal at Wish.
It is not very nice simply.
I think a lot in that you simply have to draw it up.
Why do you paint with chalk?
Then I get a temporary painting to begin with.
I want to be happy with what I do first.
Sketch up as well.
Just look at a picture for inspiration.
After all, it will be very own now.
Walking and painting straight on this?
Yes it does. Then you just wipe off.
It can get a little messy sometimes, but do you have a lot of color
So then it is no problem to paint over chalk.
Spray or get that with pencil.
It will be mostly with a pen and possibly a little color.
I thought it should be some highlights with color with spray cans
And then it should be shaded around too.
But first I do these stuff now as well.
So it will probably be interesting.
Should start by pulling up with white or white lines I think
Then the teeth will be quite bright.
At least it is good with them as a starting position.
Try to follow the car's shapes instead.
I think I should. About the same on the other side as well.
It's interesting.
But I start with this one and then I know was how
I'll start from a second then.
Then it is only copy that applies.
So stand and spray a car goes pretty fast,
It's all else then when you have to sit and watch and think
And then it is good to have some time.
Because now I want it to be right.
When I made the starting position I don't want to have to hold on
And then paint over and redo and such things.
It's not so fun.
There will be decent teeth on half the car.
It is a 15 millimeter cape.
It is quite rounded when they are very sharp edges from the beginning,
But it is softened quite quickly by the color.
The best thing about these can turn on them so they become too soft,
Then you just turn them over.
Now I'm going to make my eye right now.
The eye that should always be a little angry.
But I just pull the first lines now then that lime falls away.
Sitting so loosely.
How is the color sitting?
Sits as well as any.
As good as this color black in so that I buy replenishment.
Instead of buying new pens, I buy refill
Because you can change the cape.
And then you do this only when you have to change
Or replenish color just when the other direction so.
Then you pick off and pour down just here.
It's so good so you fill them.
Is it just drive on.
I like that the car is really flat then.
Or not.
Is so easy to make straight lines when the car is like this.
Here it is simple, but when you go over the moldings and stuff
So it gets a little worrying sometimes.
I like your pose too, will be good for my back then.
This is much better to sit like this
than to do as I did before.
Then I'm actually good at moving me instead
to keep on turning your back.
It is the worst thing you can do when you are like this.
That is the best thing about Easter pen, that it covers
After all, all colors
SU sees the chalk disappear immediately.
It was a big line from the beginning.
Now they are starting to look for something.
Maybe look really messy though.
It is not really clear you can say.
I went without a clear lacquer but it can do quite well anyway
And it's like so damn cool as it is because they do so well anyway.
It's hard to cover right here.
It is such a gross repair that has been there so it is not possible to paint
Sick that it has dried in minutes.
Now I can wipe the chalk stuff.
Now we're going to put shading behind and I will also put over the teeth
So that they are toned down a little so it's not so damn white.
This is like you just put a shadow.
Now I use regular CAP because it is quite fluff.
It flows out but adds no sharp lines.
Or something like that.
But when you mix it like this you see that it looks
Like a shading around.
You have to wait until the wind has been moaning for two and a half seconds.
Then you can pull.
You see the difference
here. There is so little needed to really get it there.
You should have a mask huh?
Yes, now it was actually so that it was standing still here the air
Empty!
A shark always has teeth that are growing out.
And so that's why sitting in between.
That was not stupid.
It got cool.
And so gets the same on the other side?
It will be.
So transparent black.
Got to actually learn it this week, how good it can be.
I was one is perfect as well.
To do this, ie here so that otherwise I usually drive with regular black.
The smallest you press wrong, then you are completely black instead.
But I don't want that.
Want like shadows.
I eat so useful when I am working here.
I really think about food all the time.
Or not.
Finally, I know why is yes spicy and tough?
What is I fainting when I get up?
Just that, I have to eat.
Motor geek lunch there.
It is right.
That's it. Costs to be on top.
This is a special green that sits on the heap.
Thick green light. There it ran.
Are you trying to save what?
No. Part of in some way I think.
Don't you get stressed by the run?
No.
It's as it is.
Now I start with a little highlight stuff.
Acid green.
Yes, acid green.
There it was green and green and green.
Yes, gray and gray and black.
Yes.
Where is pink? And ketchup?
Ketchup is coming.
I have been waiting for ketchup.
Yes, I think like this if a shark has big fangs,
What is taken then?
You wear things in.
What then?
Blood. Just right.
But it's like the Final Touch when you have chewed up the buns.
If it is when you make it really fun, it is important not to stand in the headwind
When you throw red ...
Then you have ketchup all over your face.
Since we did the hill.
Yes, and in between the hymes and before we start recording this project
So it has received a lot of requests.
Yes, I have made a pickles, a Silverado 1500 from 2000 and a pretty big one too.
There was a lot to work on, but I did that completely differently.
It wasn't that I pulled such just lines
Without I made the whole body looked
as it was made in sheet metal.
We even sat real plates on all screen edges.
So they were really redone.
This one I came up with myself.
Many times I need when I drive toward edges
And stuff when I spray.
Then I just put it against spraying.
Especially when I did these who looked like plates on this chevan.
You use this all the time.
It was really sunny from the beginning as well as
The end result was really cool.
There I used all the imagination I had and some more.
But I thought I saw when you paint on some bus.
Yes, it is a new project.
It is a very good friend who has a bus he has done.
She did the order last winter.
I got some help from me and others and then I said that
But God I'll fix it, we'll paint it there.
Then the blue was underneath.
Yes about up here earlier.
So he wanted the black and but I want skulls and stuff etc
In the 80s skull. He calls himself the pirate
He has on his cars.
He drives a truck.
So I thought but god that's another friend
Which is absolutely cruel at making skulls.
So I start talking to him and he lit a lot on the idea.
So last Wednesday we were in fact and burned
On so he drove on a ten meter skull of the whole side.
A giant skull with spider leg.
So it is totally ouff!
It's so cool!
I have started running this kind of cartoon style
With Acid Green actually against mold and white.
What washing?
I drive over the mold so it looks great so it was actually really cool.
It looks really cool!
You can see the front here now, I drew after all
On the only thing I've done there as well.
But here I have done so that this dark green instead
And the other is light green on the outside.
It's a bit like that blink to Amazon actually,
Which has a barbecue six months.
I think it was pretty cool this.
It already looks a booklet on the hood so it doesn't matter.
It is not that it is not visible if we say so.
So now I drive with light gray.
It is a very nice color that goes well against this.
Yes, bright to the dark too so it as a shading.
The gray was black and now I run with this
So that it should contrast more.
You have to find with small branches to be able to draw straight lines.
You can take support for quite a lot of things.
So.
God how beautiful it becomes.
Now have you felt that today it went according to plan?
Yes God yes.
No conflict in your head either?
No, I'm one such so I can adapt all the time too.
I have everything, do not have to be black or white.
Or it should not be a nail.
Nothing is nailway.
Nothing is perfect.
I've never been afraid to think about it.
Many people think I am very, very scared
To think about when they are doing something.
Because then control disappears as they lose control.
I am never afraid to feel now we do differently.
We do this in a different way.
Because I believe a lot in this, that it is better to think like this
And adapt where in instead of running around and worrying.
Most people seem to do that nowadays as well.
And especially when it comes to creative work.
Just adapt.
There are no problems, there are only lots of opportunities
As you can do differently.
That's how I usually think.
That is an adaptation.
Oh, it ran a little.
Well what a nice thing I feel.
It doesn't make things uglier because they're not exact.
Straight Lines as well.
As you have driven with a fucking ruler as well.
If you want such stuff, you should not go to me, he says.
However, do you want stuff with a little more soul and improvisation
And as some say, a little more chaos, then it's fun to go to me.
How to get in touch with you?
I know you, though.
Yes, I have my Youtube channel RBCorten.
Then I am on Instagram too so it is easiest.
I am very active at Rat Basted Crew Sweden as well.
There I put up almost daily.
I have run the boxes on this too.
Let's see what he says about that.
It will be fun.
I think it's shit bell to drive on the boxes
Just because it really doesn't cover over something
that is dangerous or something.
So that's really.
One cannot say that it is unauthorized drawing
Because then you don't look, yea right?
You can put decals anyway, but you can't pull
Some lines on a box.
It sounds totally sick.
So we'll see what they think.
Here in Lidköping.
It is going to be fun
This is ketchup when I spray on the brush
A good color when you want some effects.
Written on the rear screen.
Yes it sat.
Damn a lot of red color it will be here behind.
Yes it does nothing.
It sprays blood and jaws on them here.
What are you going to do now?
Now it's time for Hologram Glitter. Glitter?
Yes, that's clear lacquer too.
Both clear lacquer and glitter and hologram.
This means that you have all the colors so it gets cool.
As much as ends up on the boxes when it blows so much.
But there is good pressure in this.
Oh what a difference right away.
Protects the shark teeth a bit too, it is clear varnish in this.
This so mixed with clear lacquer that it is a form of clear lacquer
Can you say that has lots of glitter in.
It is glitter the effect is very clear.
Yes God yes, it is damn clear. Check out the rear view mirror.
Then the gray darkens a little neighbor too.
Do you start feeling ready?
Yes, you can say that I have been more attractive. Ahh ....
Now it is legitimate to have real old man.
Yeah now it's really
Aaaaaaahhh.
And I've just called Andreas when he's on his way down.
Yes, cool.
What do you think he will think?
I hope for positive actually.
I think it looks very different and cool and fun.
Damn it was cool.
I'm totally.
I have a hard time finding words.
It is not possible to imagine the end result when you only see the colors.
No no. Just a cardboard box with jars.
Yes, so the chopping teeth were really bald.
Yes, and then blood was sprayed on the eyes.
Thus, the waistband of everything.
Ha said, it runs and flows.
It is quiet.
Douglas thought it was very busy.
It's quiet, I said.
It scratched in the body.
Yes, it did. It's art.
Absolutely okay with rinings that.
It also fits in.
Which makes it look like he is crying green gallow.
Yes, you see it has been a part of instead.
Yes yes yes.
Yes.
I love that the people green is uh ..... it was about it.
Yes people don't really know.
Green is quite underrated and brown I think.
Brown and green I think get very underrated colors
When you keep on.
The boxes got really cool and I like that.
It matched as well as the terrace in the back. It's just glue it
So that it sits as well.
What do you like most of Kenneth has done?
It is not possible to describe words that are just trying to bring in all this.
It's so damn awesome.
He has done good jobs.
I know he is good, but this is far beyond my expectation.
As I saw it yesterday.
I could never have imagined that.
The final result.
Now he is really customs that I wanted what I wanted it.
Now he lives up to my goal with it.
I am more than satisfied.
This is far above what I could have dreamed
about at all.
But now it is visible.
If it didn't do it before.
Hologram clear lacquer.
So the glitter it becomes glitter directly.
It's dry.
It's drier.
It's dry here.
It's not raining away.
I've put it on.
Then it blew like that.
But it blew less on this page than the other.
When the sun is shining on it, it glitters on well.
It is one of those where one can stand and stare in a long time
And discover new things all the time.
Will be interesting to see them when we have our hits next Thursday
Exhibit it and see people's reaction.
Set me a little and let people react to it.
You will pick around tonight.
It will probably be a turn. Yes.
I would sign.
So this is the first time.
Signs a car.
Now we are ready Kenneth. Yes.
Now it is probably more well 40 plus miles home only then it is quiet.
I'm so tired that I don't know ....
Then we are two.
But we are hard and tough.
We bite together and then we drive anyway.
We do it like this.
We are heard when Doc is ready.
Yes, and then we look at it.
If I feel right, it will show up several things.
The risk is imminent.
Or the chance is great you can say.
The chance is great.
And great fun to do here with you.
Absolutely! We must say on a look!
Have a good one! See you later!