I probably need to lubricate it a little maybe.
It's not my knees but the saddle.
I just have time to go from here so you have ...
Yes, I couldn't help but now I have put that cover there.
I have made new screws.
After all, it was small screws here before that were worn so damn.
So now I have turned on hex-screws in stainless steel as I have taken down a bit
So that they can lie along more.
They stood out too much.
Also removed this exhaust valve Pys Valley
Because it sat on the handlebars up here.
But it was so damn ugly with that handle so I have this.
I sat there a cover there instead.
It only worked a 350 so it works.
Then I also got there on the other side when it is finished here.
The switches in there even then the adjustment.
Here you see that it is moving here now.
It is what densification you should have so everything is done.
So really it's just to plug the generator now to the battery
and pull power up to the lantern to the power switch
And some cables to the taillight and a little.
I also got twelve volts ignition coil and this is a regular coil for car
So this is not a motorcycle really.
They are usually a little smaller.
But this one got a seat here so it had to be it.
And there we have a ignition cable that is from that
I had to my HD from 1920.
It looks a little old and thought it was good looking
So it gets a seat here.
I have also made a slightly better oil stick.
With a handle on a bud.
This is how you can see how much oil in.
Before was only a steel wire that they had made a loop on
And stopped into the hole there.
Now I have done so that it is a bit dense there too
And then it gets a little nicer.
There are no original stuff, but the cycle is not original
So that you must not be too stingy.
It is a bicycle to be used.
I got where I had to do the reflector inside with then in
and with me to have 12 volt lamp and then I thought
That then I want some H4.
Now there is no H4 glass here though.
I changed holders in the back, solder a new one and there will be good light picture in it
So it will work.
But an H4 is no problem to get hold of either.
Those 6 volt lamps that sat original on this one in.
It does not grow on trees.
There is no mack that has any such H4 there are in most places.
No, this is going to be more functional
Now with 12 volt system and that.
The taillight also came with more modern 12 volt lamps.
Then you can also have them.
Parking light.
It's LED.
Such a small lamp.
It never breaks.
It has not mounted it in the lamp but it should sit there later.
And actually shines very well.
And this ...
They work well.
He shines at least as well as a regular incandescent lamp
And this one does not draw any power either so if you stand
With the ignition on the lamp lights.
It doesn't matter.
But you do not have power so he empties the battery.
You can have some such modernities when you have 12 volt stream.
For six volts he had never worked.
And there is hardly anything.
LED is not something 6 volts what I know.
Sometimes you can be lucky that a lamp also works
at 6 volts, but that.
It's pretty hard to get hold of.
This is how it is moving forward.
Now we have looked at some sections of the old.
We have recorded and now it is done.
It is a small, small thing that bins a little neighbor,
But now I have actually managed to get hold of it.
When you switch so inside the gearbox there is a spring that is bent.
They think it goes up so and so and so it goes down
And it should, like putting the change so that it settles.
Back then in the center if you say.
But where it was.
Someone has found their own or made their own.
Certainly even sometime in a while.
So it didn't work so I had to make my own then.
Got to it pretty well, but sometimes I'm a little fat.
But now I have seen that it is possible to buy the new ones actually.
It is probably the only spare part for Sarolea.
But as I said, this gearbox was also sitting on English motorcycles
So that's probably why it exists then.
So it should be purchased.
So that's probably the only thing left to do on the bike.
Otherwise he goes now.
It is possible to switch and so, but sometimes so hooked up a bit.
Then you get a little on the gear lever and in the end it works.
And the package holder is finished.
Yeah, I had this part but no attachment
So these brackets here.
I have had to do them myself then.
And then I had to cut out and put this chrome strip in place
And even those stakes are also on the right and left side.
I have had to do and these brackets front and rear.
So now, now you are stable on it.
I still haven't done any pillow or the seat itself there
Without there we will see a little what it becomes of it.
I have foot sticks with if anyone wants to go with.
I haven't had to push yet so that's why it has
not become a pillow there.
But it is quickly done and then you just do
a piece of wood with foam rubber and then dress with leather
And then you make a little heel so it remains here.
It fulfills its function now anyway.
And then I replaced the entire electrical system.
Put up the charging lamp and there are high beam lamp.
Then I took such a red lamp.
Then there is a blue diode lamp in there which shows that the high beam is on.
I also found a list.
What you could have for the front screens here.
Now it is a little, a little narrower than the original,
But the screen is also not original so this is similar to the original
Can you say then.
And the handbrake had this bolt where they only took a m6 bolt,
cut a skull and then welded it.
But it was just that that welding flea was so small.
It did not hold for anything the first time
I slowed down here in the garage when I rolled it went off.
I have a damn lucky I didn't ride any motorcycle
For it rattling properly.
So this is now completely reduced so that it really should hold.
Now there is a recessed screw on the inside which is also hard solder.
It will never come off.
Now this is not a thunder good brakes but you have to think about, preferably 5 minutes
Before you start to slow down.
What was it Christer said?
Theoretical brakes! Yes, there are theoretical brakes.
No it was the back brake I got a little better actually.
It's almost the one you use the most.
Then it was these rubber pads then.
There was someone funny.
I don't know how they made that form, but it didn't fit anything
And then the screws were for long and large skulls.
So I have done that in order now and then the rubber lies
A little bit away.
Because it is against here it lies and scraps a little on the color.
So I made it a little from the thought.
Plus you don't know these screws.
These you want to be a little careful about.
This is something that cannot be obtained.
Don't think I.
Those gums I am glad that they are as the whole as it is.
It is safe to cast them into something other than plastic or something,
But should it be rubber then it should be rubber.
No, and then that was the support.
It was wrong.
This was quite absorbed here so then you have welded about it.
It was just that this record he stood so
He was resting on this edge only and then you can never put him on.
It is not even going on asphalt because then the entire motorcycle sinks
Down in the asphalt and he finally overturns.
So there I had to pick this up, cut off everything, extend it a little and so.
So now he lies completely flat so now he stands firmly.
The carburetor was a problem, it flowed over for me.
I couldn't understand.
I sanded the needle and this, but then it was.
Then everything was due to that one.
It's probably something they themselves have done.
The stick, you flow it with.
You push down the float.
It was just that it was a millimeter too long so float
could never get up far enough to clog.
So I sat on the gasoline that ran all the time.
So it was really just taking you off the lid,
Grind off a little neighbor on it.
Then it works.
Or so this has come from any other carburetor
with another type of float.
I don't know, but it was too long anyway.
What have I done more?
Yes, it was the lamp there.
I had to redo that so I could get an H4 there.
Because there will be 12 volt system now that I changed the generator.
So it became a 12 volt generator.
And it is absolutely no disadvantage to 12 volts.
But you have to change all the lamps and stuff. I also had to change the ignition coil.
This is not original stuff so I've got to do
Some special locks that keep it.
It is.
It ends up so then you screw at it
So it locks.
So here I have had to redo.
Yes, everything.
So I get room with one.
But that is where the disadvantage is that H4 they stand out
so it doesn't get room in here so then I have had to bend out them
and put such separate ones.
This bracket is taken from one.
Golf reflector.
This is the reflector that sat in from the beginning with you.
It works.
It will actually be very good light picture.
We see if we can get it together again.
Then it sits there.
No, now it works.
Has a main switch.
It is easy to turn off that.
And when you turn on the dice, well then the parking is also on.
And then you have it.
There you have whole and half a highlight dipped beam.
Then we'll see.
You get started on the first.
Then you have to flow a little on the carburetor so that you get some gasoline.
Then this is such an engine that would like to kick back.
About so yes.
Has barely begun.
He goes very well at idle.
It's so low idle so he doesn't even charge.
Gases the smallest.
He starts charging.
There you would really have the idle.
I think it's a little too loud.
And then I have brake lights on the Forpedalen but not on the handbrake.
It is most foot brake that you use.
Lovely sound.
Don't smell much either.
But it is this gasoline that makes it not those additives
Without them, they become very clean in the exhaust gases.
But then it is not appropriate to stand like this but ...
It's better anyway.
Surprisingly spiteful with to be a 350.
If you look at sales brochures and stuff like that
So there are as many horses in this 350 as it is in Matchless and BSA 500.
So no, he probably hangs with 500 a 1 stump
Fun to drive.
Although you sit a little.
I would have liked to have a lower saddle that went here.
You sit a little jerk.
It's almost like driving a moped it feels like.
I would have liked to have been sitting here so
Foot sticks sit far up and.
I probably need to lubricate it a little maybe.
It's not my knees but the saddle.
No. A fun bike.
That works.
May well try to go on this summer.
Yes, we have to.
Maybe we can take each hi and go to that animal's meeting.
Or go and have a snack somewhere.
Anything.
The most fun thing is to simmer on dirt roads and this one has
the suspension on me all around so it actually goes to
and with suspension in the saddle, which I don't really understand why
They have because they have suspension here.
Plunger I think it's called.
Swaying time when you go, but you don't sit still at some time
Without you floating forward.
Now I'm done with it now anyway.
Good work! Now i'm not going to do that much more
than that little spring there.
Maybe to the gearbox.
Then I was in the event that I would have repainted it.
Because one is the color, after all, is almost a little dull.
I don't know what I used for color.
It almost feels like it's powder coated.
If you compare this black and Willys, this one looks really matte.
But I have become accustomed to it now and I polished it a bit.
Well think it may be like you.
But again, this was not the project we would talk about either.
We've recorded or still record other stuff
So real stuff comes then.
Or, it sounds strange to say real stuff,
But what we have planned.
Yes, a little more advanced stuff.
Yes exactly.
That's how it is.
So it will come in the future.
It will probably not be this year, but we will kick sometime next year. Yes.
It will be quite long projects with so we may have to divide it a bit.
We'll see a little.
But what I have recorded so much because it happens
So much in this garage.
I just felt that I had to tie the bag together, sometime.
So we have tied the bag together with both Willys and Sarolea now.
So now we can move on.
And side wagon.
Yes exactly.
After all, it will be.
It just goes on after all. Yes yes.
The one can happen to it for sure.
And even Willys can happen to happen if you are going.
Then we can say on reunion.
Yes we're allowed to do that.
YES! Hello!