I'm going to build a camper and do it with a different approach.
Like to be a little inventor and generally crazy
So I've gone all in on crazy ideas.
Hello Hello! Hello Hello.
How's it going?
Very good! It is really good.
How's the construction going?
It goes according to plan.
It is a lot.
There are many loose threads to be tied together.
But it flows nicely.
Last time I was here you were waiting for some stuff.
Have you been able to reach things?
A very central part of the whole is energy manufacturing.
I have both solar panels, I have received inverter
And we've got the battery pack.
So now I'm ready to mount it and get unlimited energy in the car.
What a big they were.
Of course, there are special dimensions on them.
Don't surprise me at all, I should say.
50 millimeters to good on total length on the truck so tight
as the determining measure.
Then I have about 15 centimeters in width on each side.
Besides that, it is absolutely the whole roof will be covered.
There are six panels, each panel is 430 watts.
Just over two and a half kilowatt electricity production, which is about three times
As much as I will need is my guess.
I will have excess energy.
I can help charge electric cars on the journey.
It may be needed today with today's gasoline prices.
Yeah!
Solar panels have arrived, they are ready to be mounted
and i have also received my special batteries
As I have been waiting for a long time.
It is LifePo4 is called the chemistry, but it is
The safest battery variety and they are terribly efficient.
Since then you have a digital display showing charging status
on it and the digital values on it.
This one weighs 17 kg I think.
Not more?
17 kilos battery of 300 amps.
To with these four times twelve 48 vault
Then we will have 14 kilowatt hours of energy storage.
It's a half Nissan Leaf electric car in battery pack so I have a good excess
Although it is pouring rain and bad weather so I can run induction hobs
And AC so on.
But they can't be free on the batteries.
No, they weren't even almost free.
But it is such a central part.
Water production and energy production are the heart of the entire system.
It refuses compromise with without it are the two areas
Which stands out most and is most interesting to explore.
The purpose of a large test center.
What the life span then?
4000 charging bikes are the batteries guaranteed to hold.
It is from 0 to 100 % on 4000 occasions and would you run empty them every day
So it's 4000 days.
But 365 is 10, 12, 15 years maybe if you empty every day.
I will pick out 30 % of them so it is basically endless.
What the other small batteries? What is that?
It is a parallel project I am doing.
Thought about telling a lot about when I parallel to this building
In the process of building your own electric mop.
I have to have something with me when I go out and travel, so I have
The small batteries are even easier.
Five kilos, weighs nothing.
And is on 40 amps.
It is a hefty battery bank.
My goal is to have ten 12-15 miles range at Elmoppe,
Because it will be my general transport when I have parked the car.
Have you set up GoPro camera now?
Yes, it's the first test now on my panoramic window
that I will use.
I need a high -resolution image to make
a credible, create a credible window and it has discovered
That GoPro cameras work great.
But the modern ones are not suitable so I get back down in age
And I bought a used on the block.
GoPro 7 Black is exactly the model I need
Because it is the only thing I manage to find that has HDMI exit.
It is also used as webcams, high quality webcams
GoPro 7 will be my eye out into the world.
And so I have OLED TV, 4K OLED TV to create a picture.
That is just a test.
First, will be recessed on the back of the truck wall
so it will only appear a pinch head
Like a fly on the side of the wall side of the truck.
Then it becomes a permanent power cable into USB-C
So that the current and HDMI were constantly underway, so to speak.
But not film but just live it, so to speak directly to the TV.
Should we go in and check.
See how far I have reached the building,
Oh yeah.
I have come quite a long way.
Yes, I have received the structure with the interior
So all the rough building is clear and a little finely left.
Then it is the next step to draw in all the water and all the electricity
So I have a friend who is an electrician who will help me gross it
And then I take here a licensed electrician for connection so to speak
I do not want to drive the electricity myself, but I will leave it.
What is this cardboard boxes?
It's version two of my 3D cork.
It is a wall decoration that is a pressed cork surface.
If I turn it on, it is the usual traditional cork,
Although they have a 3D look on it.
I have tried to gray it.
Ok, is the standard that is?
The natural colored just so it is stained once
and stained twice.
So this will be my wall structure inside the truck.
Partly you get a better sound, less echo in it
And you get a warmer feeling.
Plus it is a bit cool with a 3D effect.
It is not as thick either.
No, the other was interesting pattern, but it was twelve millimeters thick
and that made cabinets gaps to open it collides with it
So it doesn't really work in reality.
This one is only four millimeters thick so it is much more manageable.
The whole purpose of the inside is to be minimalist.
Everything should be there, but nothing should be seen.
I have a fold -out induction hob, I will have built -in
Pantry etc etc. Everything will be there,
But it will be hidden behind a 15 cm false wall.
So what I'm building now is the need for my spaces.
Then I will cover it with a three millimeter MDF
and on it I put a 3D cork so you get a completely smooth, neutral
3D cork wall.
But there you have all the functionality built into the wall.
Here becomes a knife and spice shelf.
This will be the big one will be the electrical cabinet, because it belongs to the inverter
to the solar cell plant.
The whole of the floor to ceiling is a pantry
so there will be plenty of space at the back over the bed
So I will have a joint -lit European map.
And on the map i fold out so that when i sit
and make your own youtube movies so i have a good backdrop
So that it is also bedside tables with the alarm clock and other things.
So that all that wall will be smoking
With built -in features.
I have some Kalle Anka's Christmas Eve on a caravan holiday.
I have that as the role model.
Always have to have at least two different functions, preferably three.
But you have elevated the floor? Yes.
We can look at it.
I have an elevated floor partly.
Biggest reason is that I wanted a huge storage space
Below the double floor is 25 centimeters high and very spacious,
So I have two half a meter long and 25 centimeters high and one meter wide.
Stuff that I don't use as often or that is very bulky
is perfect to be able to store.
The perfect opportunity to collect things.
I will have more space than I need when I'm done.
A pleasant problem to have in a camper.
Winter clothes in summer and summer clothes in winter.
And a snowboard.
If I want to go out and go and there are always things to fill with.
A little bigger things they hide under the bed?
Yes, the bed is the garage.
There you have the biggest stuff, type of electric mop and big bulky things.
Then you have medium -sized things I will have 2 pieces
Under the stomach of the truck between the wheel axles.
There I have partly the battery system and partly I will have hose
And collapsible ladder you need.
So there we also have a lot of storage space.
And then I have the double floor.
It is three and a half meters of wall section with shelves as well
So I have a lot of spaces.
But what about the cabinets on the outside then?
The boxes are ordered, but they have been delayed.
It's still two months left before I go away
So I'm not too worried yet, but it would have been good to get them here now.
You have so much left to do so I don't know how to get it in 2 months.
I do not get it.
When I sleep in the box so I am close to work,
But it is seven days in a week so that it will go. I refuse to give up.
How can it come here?
An example is that when building custom stuff
So it takes a little longer.
This shelf system is ready for the separation toilet
And it needs it.
Then I have a fresh water tank and gray water tank
So that's why this is removed.
If it in turn, you have every centimeter,
is specially built to accommodate it and get the need you need
So when it is out of the picture.
I have a 20 liter fresh water, tank and a 100 liter gray water tank.
They are in place.
It was tight but according to the calculation.
The function is that condensation water from AC flows down
in the tank or fresh water tank.
And from there I pick the water.
And would the situation be the humidity that controls it
So I have no fixed figure on how much is produced varies from day to day
and land to country.
But should it over produce, I have a transfer protection,
So if produced, it runs directly from the water tank into the gray water tank.
What I need is a safe system that works in all situations.
I thought of another thing.
At first I thought it was hand spruce holder this,
But this is water.
That is an extra bonus if you want to cool
or room -temperature water.
So that's why you have a small two liter campsite
Containers so it goes into it first.
You can pick out fresh drinking water right away and that in turn
Delivers it to fresh water the tank.
And you do this because you don't want hot water to drink
No, just all that is picked from fresh water tank
will go through the heater so it won't have hot or cold water
The main part will go to disk, shower and so on.
Will be 37 degree water and that would like to drink
So that's why I take the little idea for it.
How many hours did this take?
Not so many hours, but many attempts.
It was very much cut and cut away, add and change.
It was funny.
First version in the box is a sharp test
of space.
What do we need and so on.
It is, I discovered that I can pull down it ten centimeters. 80 wide instead of 90.
Then I also get a decimeter longer kitchen counter.
I learn a lot to live in the box.
So there are very small adjustments have done that have been valuable
on version two point zero.
You come a long way I think.
You have opened the bed too.
Everything is relative, I have come a long way but I have a bit left.
Another thing that has been changed compared to version 1.0
is that I have made a more generous bed.
In there the idea was to have a 120 bed
Because I thought the corridor between becomes claustrophobic, getting too narrow.
But I discovered that it works just fine so the more generous
Will be a 140 bed instead.
So a big nice bed.
And besides, the garage becomes corresponding to larger
So these are the details you learn when you live in it.
That I can draw.
I can do a drawing in CAD and you get the right measure.
But when you deliver it so one gets the feeling of
That it does not feel crowded and that it works in everyday life.
Shop even more stuff now?
This is actually something that I have been thinking a great deal
on how I would solve it.
The platform that I fold down is my balcony
And it has been remote controlled.
Via a remote control only, but it must have a winch system
that winch it up and all the winches are watching
Are very nice and great and oversized for this wall.
The platform weighs 180 kilos and then we are in at 4, 5, 6, 7 tons
How can I get hold of a smaller winch?
And then I got a flash.
It is quad bikes to ATV winch so I checked it up
And have bought a mini winch which is absolutely perfect.
So this winch is classified for nine hundred kilos.
So a nine hundred kilos electric winch with remote
is the one who will lift the door.
So this will be a good solution.
What I did was I removed the cable that came with
and i have drilled up the bracket
Instead, I will have a 6 millimeter line.
So this system will slip in running blocks
And lift up and lower the door.
Have you tried Tajma also how long it will take?
Yes.
Nor unexpectedly.
Must, but I have to test that bit too.
In my head I have one one wish of between fifteen
and thirty seconds to fold up and fold down.
Still it will feel scary and slower
Then you will be crazy and wait.
So I will run this 12 volt win in 24 volts.
Since there is such a short load so no risk of burning the engine.
But with 24 volts it goes so fast
so that I have twenty seconds speed on it so
Then I just end up in the perfect range.
Besides, I drive by the truck being in 24 volts
So it becomes easy to drive directly from the truck's batteries.
Do you know, I will let you continue working because you have a lot to do.
Yes.
So I look past a little later and then we'll see how things are going for you.
It sounds good. You are very welcome.
See ya!
Hello!