MotorNerd
Episode 53
The car is named PLÅTLADY.
PLÅT = Sheet Metal.
LADY = Red.
[IN PREVIOUS EPISODE]
-Tell me, what car is it?
It is a Ferrari F40 replica of a 1988 model.
I build the whole car myself.
I've done everything you see.
-Hi!
Hello, welcome back.
-Are you ready for episode 2?
Yepp, let's start.
Here is the first Ferrari F40 that was made.
And some pictures of when Ferrari is testing
the F40 in wind tunnel and drives it.
The first F40 made had five gills.
All the other F40's only have four gills.
This car was stored at the Ferrari museum for a long time until a famous race driver was allowed to take it.
-Your car is not a Ferrari F40.
No, just to be clear it's a F40.
Just so there will be no misunderstandings.
My car is an F40 and I built as I want it.
Then there is always someone who has opinions.
I like this car and I've build it as I want it.
I wanted one and this is a tribute to an F40.
I build my own tube frame chassi
and how i did it I will keep for myself.
That will be my secret.
I can show a picture of it but nothing more.
-Just so people understand
what does a Ferrari F40 cost?
Prices have gone up like all other cars but you
probably have to pay 1 million USD or more.
-Don't we all have 1 million in the bank account?
Well, that something all car mechanics have...
-Wheels, tires & brakes?
There I have chosen 18" OZ racing rims.
Before I switched brakes I had 17"
rims that looked like the original wheels.
But those rims didn't fit when I changed brakes.
-Was the brake caliper too big?
Yes exactly.
Then I bought 3-piece 18" split rims.
I rebuild the rims so they looks
like having a center bolt.
Since the Ferrari F40 has a center bolt.
These are the rims that I want but as 18"
I will try to find a couple but need to save money first.
This is from a drag racing car that I bought.
Brake discs are Wilwood and JFZ brake calipers.
There are large 4-piston calipers.
The brake disc is 330x32 mm so there are thick discs.
I build my own wheel hub.
I have used A-arms as link arms
both as upper and lower link arms.
Then there are adjustable coilovers
at the front and fixed coilovers at rear.
This is a Porsche 928 caliper and then a
Skoda Octavia RS brake caliper for parking brake.
There is no parking brake on the car
and the Skoda caliper fits well.
Brake discs are from the VW Passat from 2010.
Discs are 317x21 mm and fit well on the car.
It's been tricky to get everything together.
It should fit and look good and work.
Much time is spent on what parts to use
and how it should fit together.
The rear drive shaft consists of
3 different parts from 3 different cars.
When you build with different parts
it becomes very difficult.
-You have done all the windows yourself.
It's not car window glass?
No, it is 4 mm lexan plastic with splitter film.
It's like a real glass but in plastic.
-Have you cut the plastic yourself?
Yes I have done it with angle grinding machine.
-Angle grinding machine, doesn't the plastic melt?
Yes it does, but you have to cut hole smaller and grind.
-Is the windshield also in lexan plastic?
Yes, same as the original Ferrari F40.
I think the Ferrari F40 got glass
windshield in 1992 but I'm not sure.
I first had a Porsche 928 engine but
it didn't fit well with the gearbox.
I threw it out and put in a
Audi A8 V8 at 4.2 liters instead.
I have been working as an Audi mechanic for 17 years
and I know it's a good engine so I decided to use one.
I know the enigne,
it's aluminum V8 and does not weigh much.
It became much easier to fit the gearbox.
And I built my own flywheel and clutch.
-Where did you find this engine?
I bought it from a crashed car in Stockholm.
I know it worked when I picked it up.
I have gone through the engine
and painted some covers.
The engine is silver in the middle but it dosen't
fit this build so I painted it red.
T04 turbocharger below.
Both turbos are linked to the weastegate
which are located here.
I have rebuilt the throttle and other stuff.
The air for intercoolers comes from the inner shields.
Audi race catalyst and with a short exhaust system.
It's just under one meter.
-Have people said anything since you
have chosen a German engine?
Well, there is always someone.
For me it has to be a V8 with double turbo.
-Did you build the chassis for a Porsche engine?
Yes I did.
I had built the chassis for the Porsche 928 engine.
Then I rebuilt the entire rear end and
I made the whole new chassis for this engine.
It's the engine that has been there since the MOT test.
I haven't done anything with the care since then.
-Where do you get all the parts?
Online, and I have order new parts over the years.
Race catalyst is from KL-racing.
Oil cooler I had been lying from another
car in the garage which I could use.
Turbos & intercoolers I have bought new.
Intercoolers I bought from KL racing.
The hoses are from do88.
These are santo hoses that I bought here locally.
These clamps are not optimal for turbocharged engine.
Especially with more boost pressure.
-How much boost is it?
Only 0,5 BAR (7.25 PSI) and that's nothing.
-What's the engine for performance?
I do not know.
I haven't had time to test the performance.
The idea is not to be the fastest car.
It is built for short weekend trips.
It will not be fastest and car around on a track.
If I push it to hard it will break.
Basically, I just want to drive without
having any problem.
The hardest thing has been to
build the gearbox shift control.
Wires that will guide the backdrop forward
and tune it with a 6 gears.
I think it has been the most
difficult thing on the whole car.
There are plenty of holes in the
body that air passes through.
Here comes air through the hose
which will cool down the turbo.
The hot air passes through the grid at the rear.
-Okey, the hot air comes out here.
This is the original Ferrari F40 tail lights
which I ordered from England.
I have built the frames around the lights
and the whole frame with grid.
-What does the tail lights cost?
They cost 500 USD / each.
-You're joking!!
Nope, But it was worth it, they are cheaper now.
Think you can buy them now for 300 USD / each.
Or used online but mine are new.
500 USD / each!!!
That's 2000 USD for all four.
Yes, all parts I have bought have
made the car quite expensive.
500 USD / each is absolutely crazy!
Yes, everything is so incredibly expensive.
A rear window costs 5600 USD which I can't
afford so I had to build one myself.
Original side mirrors costs 2600 USD.
Wait a minute, does a rear window costs 5600 USD!!??
Yepp, prices for Ferrari parts is crazy.
I made a template in masonite which I tense up
to see how big the holes will be.
I cut holes and glued with a special glue.
Since I couldn't afford to buy the real rear window.
It didn't take long time to do.
I guess, it took me a couple of hours.
Actually, I want to make another one
since I'm not really happy with the resualt.
I will leave as it is.
Otherwise the car will never be finished
These side mirrors comes from a Corvette C5.
The original is a bit more straight.
However, the car is 2 meters (78 in) wide and I can see
backwards with these which is the whole idea.
-The car it's also very low.
Yes, the total height is 112 cm (44 in) from the ground.
I have weighed the car on race wave because I want the
weight distribution in front and rear and per wheel.
And be able to weigh in for the spring system.
The whole car weighs without oil in the engine, no fuel
and no person in the car weighs 1082 kg (2385 lb).
Which I think is pretty good.
-For a car made in metal, it's great.
Everyone thinks that sheet metal is heavy but it's not.
It's just sheet metal and nothing
else it doesn't weigh much.
-How thick sheet metal have you used?
It's 0.8 and then it is 2 mm at the bottom of the car.
The metal is thicker on the bottom because
I don't want anything to happen.
-Why has the car a license plate with PLÅTLADY?
I had the car at Elmia auto show many years ago...
...and there were so many who
had their own license plate.
To see the difference between my car
and a real F40 online I choose Plåtlady.
Since the car is made of sheet metal (PLÅT)
and LADY is red.
I wanted to be unique with something and there is
just one F40 in the world that is build in sheet metal.
I have chosen to do it just because it can be done.
It doesn't have to be in plastic.
Another thing that a F40 must have is the
recessed F40 emblem in the rear wing.
I have cut out a piece and laid sheet metal behind it
and then used a Dremel and it took a couple of hours.
-I assume the car is Ferrari red?
Yes it is painted in Ferraris red.
-It would be weird otherwise.
Yes that's true.
Now the car is just painted.
When I had the car at Elmia auto show a few years ago.
I quickly assemble the car and had it painted
to see how it would look.
Then the paintwork would be for some
years so the car could be used a little.
Now I can grind it and repaint it and add clearcoat.
I don't have any clearcoat now.
Now it's just red paint.
In the coming year, it will be sanded
and painted so it looks perfect.
-When can we see this car on the road?
Yes, it is partially SRFO (home-built vehicles) inspected.
It's SRFO inspected but I have do drive and noice test.
The car is ready to be inspected now.
It should be done in 2 steps.
Step one is to check the chassis
and it should look like a car.
Step two is drive and noice test.
And it should work as a car on the road.
That's what left to do.
Then MOT inspection to get car registered for the road.
-There are many who want you to start the car.
-But then you have to wait, right?
Well then you have to wait until spring.
-Then I will be back.
-I guess, it's not the best weather outside.
No, it's snow and cold so I don't want to take it outside.
-I may do a revisit before the summer.
Great, looking forward to that.
-Me too, I also look forward to that.
-Fantastic, Thanks for having me.
Thank you for coming and thanks everyone who watch this video.
-See you later!
Motornörd = engine geek literally
but petrolhead is probably more correct.
More episodes will be translated to
English in the near future.
Thanks for watching!
Please subscribe for new episodes.