Hey! Tjena and welcome again.
Now it's been a while. Yes now it has been a few months.
In terms of design, it is finished and assembled.
Now it is the most small adjustments and brackets to be done.
In a few days it will be disassembled completely.
Then I start with the frame and arrange it and it should be foiled.
Then it should be picked up and foiled, painted and polished.
-The should have no color huh? No.
Everything that is in aluminum should be polished. It will probably go to some autosol.
If it becomes autosol, I have tried slightly different means but have not decided yet.
-What are there for other means? It has come a lot new to aluminum.
Autosol has come with 2 new ones and I have only tested one so far.
There is one that is only for aluminum and should test it with.
There are other means that you use that act as a wax.
There are 2-3 different brands on the market but I have not been able to try anything yet.
-There's happened to some time since last time. Yes rims and tires are in place and so did the whole car.
The tires I have offended myself down here. I bought iron so I could squeeze them.
Both front and rear tires have inner hose and I get punctured along the road ...
... then spare wheels are not enough, but you have to change the inner hose.
And then I have to know if it is possible to push the tire or not and I have practiced all 4 tires.
-And now the grill is ready. Yes, I have roughly polished to see all the bumps.
If you feel like this, it feels uneven.
I will smooth more but now I know what is visible and not visible.
I have made some covers to sit on the inside of the frame.
These are these. -And you have pressed this?
Yes and it should sit 2 screwed here.
It is to cover the ugly.
The plastic foil goes around the edge here.
Because I will foil the frame ...
... it is difficult to foil the inside and get it neat.
Then it is enough if I form up to the edge.
Then cover the cover.
-Is the engines ready? No it just sits ...
... the crankshaft in so they are empty internally.
I have finished all the covers.
-Yeah, they're done. Yes on both sides.
Look what a good thing! There will be some inspection hatches.
It will be polished and painted with cast paint.
It should look like you see the engine block.
-What are you holding up? It's an old whistle I've had lying to a motorcycle.
It must be cut and extended.
Or I take an old trombone.
After all, they are so long and are supposed to sit here.
-How should you be able to squeeze it?
There must be 2 plates that squeeze and be regulated with a pedal inside the car.
-Hahaha!
-Ope!
Then I get an electric whistle as a complement. A truck driver I think does not hear this.
-The inspection doors are they riveted or screwed?
They are screwed. There are small screws here.
Then you come in ... I'll have ..
I can't fit the oil filter because it sits here normally.
I have a help frame that holds the engines together.
Filter is placed here behind instead.
If you want to change filters, you can remove the cover.
Behind this hatch you see the joint between the engines.
Even when setting the ignition on the engines.
Distributers are behind here.
-How often will you use this?
I drive as much as the other cars, it is 600 miles a year
-Oops.