It could have been an Alfa Romeo
but this particular body is really nice.
-Just the idea that you should build one yourself is crazy.
Yes, it wasn't the plan from the beginning...
...that's the only way to get something so I started.
New week, new episode - let's go!
MotorNerd
Episode 50
I've built it myself.
-Hello!
Hi.
-How are you?
I'm fine.
I changed the headlight so I try get the lid to fit.
I removed the lid and try to fix it now.
-Tell me, what car is it?
It is a Ferrari F40 replica of a 1988 model.
I think F40 is the coolest Ferrari so
therefore I want one so I build one.
-What a car!!
I have done the whole car myself.
It is a tube frame and the body is made of sheet metal.
I've done everything you see on the car.
-When did you start?
Hmm, I started already in 2005.
I have done some bits and pieces when there is time.
Which I rarely have had.
Which all my friends will know.
The car is an icon for me so it may take the time it needs
I like to spend time in the garage.
-OMG, have you done everything yourself?
Yes, I ordered home beams and started making a frame.
Then I made a steel pipe chassis
which I covered with sheet metal.
- Is the whole car a tube frame?
Yes it is.
Then you get the body and chassis as you want it.
I could buy a car and re-build it but it would
weird because the engine is at the back.
Then you have to buy a Toyota MR2 or Pontiac Fiero
but then the car gets completely wrong in the measurements so it will be no good.
Since you can't buy and F40 chassis.
It's better to do the right thing from the start.
-Yes I understand.
-What a fantastic job you've done.
It's a lot of work.
-Just the idea that you should build one yourself is completely crazy.
Yes, it wasn't the plan from the beginning but
that's the only way to get something so I started.
I have done all sheet metal in this homemade bending machine.
That's the only tool I've used.
A homemade bending machine and a hammer.
-You're joking??
No it's all.
-Is it the only one you've used?
Yes, and a knee or tire to bend some sheet metal.
That's how it is made.
And I created this.
-Is everything made in sheet metal?
-So it's not a kit-car that you built together?
No, It's not a kit-car.
I have made my own frame and
built and added the body pieces.
It is a difficult body to build.
Everything is curved and bent back and forth.
It is sheet metal here and all the way up.
-You can't just look at pictures?
-You must have got the measurements from somewhere.
Yes a friend of mine built a Lamborghini Countach.
And he thought I should build one as well
but I said I wanted an F40 instead.
I had a small Ferrari F40 toy in
scale 1/18th as I measured.
I have the toy in the cupboard over here.
This is the little car I scaled up from 1:18 to 1:1.
And that's the model I've built after.
I haven't had any real car so I build from this model.
- So you've demolished a 1:18 toy car?
Yes exactly.
Then you see how the car looks like in detail.
I have also looked at pictures online.
A few years ago that I got hold of a real car so I could measure it and the dimensions are very good.
-This is totally crazy!
-How many Ferrari F40 are there in Sweden?
I don't know for sure.
I know that there are 4 but there may be more.
They are hard to find them because they are rarely used.
-How many cars made Ferrari?
Ferrari produced a little over 1100 cars but then people have crashed them.
So it's hard to know how many are left.
-I see you like F40 because you all have
type of toys in this cupboard.
Yes, it have been a couple over the years.
And I was stumbling on something on the floor.
Yes it's my granddaughters car that she travels in.
It was just a small battery in the beginning.
So she was sad when the battery ran out.
We put in a 100 amp battery from a car so
now she can drive all day if she wants.
-I am completely dumb and do not even know where to start.
-Where do you want us to start?
We can start on the inside.
-There is no car you just jump in and out of.
No not directly it is low and tight to get into.
It is very wide edge and high threshold.
In here is the frame and it's a crash zone
because there is nothing that receives a hit on the side.
So there is a tube pipe system inside here.
-You are a bit oblique with your legs.
Yes it is a bit like a Saab 900.
It's because the front wheel is right here
and it's similar on the real car with.
-Italian gorilla driving position.
Exactly!
I made my steering wheel position straight instead.
The original is angled so it feels like you are driving a bus.
This is an OMP steering wheel with flat bottom
so you can fit your legs underneath.
I think the flat bottom steering wheel is better looking.
I bought a Ferrari badge and put that it in the middle.
I have chosen sparco sprint racing seats
which I bought long ago.
I think the racing seats fit well since
the original car also has red chairs.
I have used sabel three point belt.
However, not all pieces are in place at the moment.
Also has regular belts which are
a requirement from the MOT test.
A 6-speed box from an Audi TDI.
-Many who build cars use a TDI gearbox.
Yes, exactly.
TDI gearboxes can withstand much more torque from the engine.
It's a 01E gearbox from an Audi A4.
Carved out metal so it looks an old -80's gear lever.
Yes, exactly.
Previously, I had a regular gear lever but this looks better.
Voltmeter, temp for the cylinders & water temp.
Then it's the usual petrol, oil, speedometer and tachometer.
-What are the buttons under the voltmeter?
It's the fan and the heat.
There is electric heat because it
There is no water element in the car.
Then you would have to pull a lot of hoses that there is
no room for so it became electric instead.
-Should we have a look at the front?
Yes.
-What are you doing here?
I was not satisfied with the headlights.
I'm rebuilding it and hopefully it will look better.
I had to remove the lid so I could change lights.
As you can see, the lid is metal.
When I removed the lid I manage
to scratch the paint so that must be fixed.
-Okey, so you have re-built it so the lids has to be adjusted?
Yes they should fit in and fix some of the plastic.
- Ah, awesome!
This is area is not finished yet.
Overhere, a plate is missing and needs to be fixed and installed.
Plastic fenders is from a truck.
-Okey, plastic fenders is from a truck.
Mounted so there will not be a lot of gravel in here.
-What's hiding behind the black cover plate?
Underneath there is battery, fan to the cabin,
brakes and oil to the clutch.
-Is it the same on a original F40?
It's the same.
-There's no place for a golf bag?
No, normally there is a spare wheel there.
But I chose to skip it.
I could put a spare wheel next to
the cooler but I don't want to.
In the front I have done the same as the Le mans model.
It has a large intake in the middle.
I'd rather have Le Mans but still the original front
but I do not want the headlights as original.
Then I chose to mix original and Le mans front.
-Is the cooler right behind the front grill?
Yes.
Then I have chosen to make the hole in the front much larger.
Original is the hole much smaller than this.
I chose to make that hole much larger
so that the air can go through easier.
This means that the car is pushed against the road when driving.
My dad made a fuel cap.
He thought it was unnecessary to buy one.
He made some fuel caps in the lathe that we could use.
-What's the sticker on the rear fender?
It's the same as original F40.
-What does it say? Pininfarina?
Yes it was he who designed
body with Enzo Ferrari.
-How did you get to all angles right?
I first thought it was angular.
But the body is round and bent in all directions.
It has been very difficult to do.
This part consists of a single piece
but this is a lot of small pieces.
Just small pieces so you could get the shape together.
-The door handle.
It's my own design.
This is actually a lock for a window section.
-What does it matter?
No it works.
-So it looks like the original door handle?
Yes this is how the door handle looks like from Ferrari.
-Put your finger here to open.
Yes exactly.
-Is this car finished?
No, it will never be finished.
I'm a little bit picky and always want to rebuild things.
Have always tried to build with cheap parts.
But then you find something better which is more expensive and I have to replace it.
The car runs and everything works.
TO BE CONTINUED.
Unfortunately, that's all for this time.
You will see the rest in the next episode.
But until then comment, subscribe and like!
See ya!
-What does the rear lights cost?
Oh, they cost 500 USD each when I bought them.
-You're joking!! That's 2000 USD for 4pcs.
Hmm, Yes...
Motornörd = engine geek literally
but petrolhead is probably more correct.
More episodes will be translated to
English in the near future.
Thanks for watching!
Please subscribe for new episodes.