Went off the road in Spain.
Got stuck there and was picked up
by a farmer with a tractor.
Then I had an engine failure
on the highway in Spain outside Valencia.
It was quite scary.
Hello Hello!
Thursday again and time
for a new episode of Motornörd.
And today we revisit Tomas
who sold his Tesla,
bought a Renault truck
and converted it into a camper van.
So let's take this opportunity
to check the situation.
What has it been like to be away
for a whole year?
Hi Douglas! Good to see you again.
It's the same Tomas, what's up?
It is very good.
It feels a bit strange
to be back in Sweden.
I have mixed feelings.
I've been on a long trip and now I'm home.
But I don't feel at home
because I don't live in Värnamo
but only exist in Värnamo.
It makes me feel like an alien
or outside of society.
I haven't had that feeling
when I was traveling
but you have been
in a different mentality.
Now I am back.
Absolutely fantastic year.
I am very happy and proud
that I have done it
and I have learned a lot from it.
It has been a challenge
and a great experience.
I'm super happy with it.
When I drove in
here, I have seen some changes.
First, you have the cover on top
where you can insert
your Star-link wind de-icer.
The Star link is recessed
and it has worked.
The star link is
a game changer is unprecedented.
No problems whatsoever anywhere.
It just works.
300 megabits anywhere all the time.
I highly recommend it.
Awesome! It costs 1050 bucks a month,
but it's worth it every time.
It works well.
No major problems.
I've had minor mishaps
but that's to be expected
when you're out and about.
So what's the big deal?
Went off the road in Spain.
Got stuck there and was picked up
by a farmer with a tractor.
Then I had an engine failure
on the highway in Spain outside Valencia.
It was quite scary.
Went into safe mode.
Can drive 50 on the highway.
20 kilometers to Valencia.
Google for a Renault workshop.
Coming in on Friday evening
at 17:55 principle.
Asked for help.
We can help you, but you have to come back
on Monday morning at 08:00.
Camping in Valencia works well.
In addition, on Sunday
there was the summer time changeover.
Then, on Monday morning, I wake up
and step outside.
If it's pitch black
outside, I get in the truck,
start it up and what I'm not told.
When I drove out on Friday,
it was still light outside.
Is that no lights work at all
in the front,
lights, tail lights, hazard lights,
position lights, instruments.
Not a single light in the entire truck.
I am in Valencia.
There is carbon black with a carbon
black truck,
driving on Monday morning
in rush hour traffic in Valencia.
That trip was not fun.
Bloody hell.
So it was a bit exciting.
Came into the workshop
and they fixed an electrical fault
so they fixed and it was great
and 4 hours later I was on the road again.
But what about the letters?
I gave up!
The letters were a wrestling match.
I tried to get rid of them.
After I got all the letters off,
I took boat polish, medium,
antioxidant and polisher to it
and it ended up
making the letters much shinier.
But so were the other parts of the fleet.
So even though I did all the work,
it was just as big a difference
as it was before
but everything was shinier
and the letters were still visible.
So I ended up buying paint
and rolling over them
just to get rid of the letters.
But all the boxes have worked?
On one of my films that I published,
one of the switches for the box
had become waterlogged.
After the rain, it ran down the side
and straight into the switch.
Then when I emptied it,
it had standing water
throughout the switch.
So there I found a new replacement
and replaced just that dilemma around it.
But it was only a ten-minute job,
so it was no big deal.
When I drove down last fall,
I drove south all the time
and then I had the sun low down
so I was dazzled all the time.
So I got tired of it and added duct tape
to protect myself from the sun.
I forgot about that so I kept it
for the whole period in Portugal.
So now I can't get the glue off,
it's so embedded in the bench.
It doesn't matter what I use for anything.
From razor blades to.
Acetone to bought this at Biltema.
Label off.
It works, doesn't it?
Nothing works as far as I have tried.
It's burned into the glass somehow.
I don't know how to get rid of it.
Tips are gratefully received.
How do I get rid of this shit?
I have no previous experience
of driving a truck,
but I must say that it has been
incredibly easy to drive.
It is like any other small car.
It is not heavy, it is not difficult.
It works very well.
Size-wise, I have also discovered
that I have.
Due to the fact that I have the isolation,
I have an exemption.
It is extra wide
so mine is 2.60 in total width.
Most large caravans are 2.35
so I'm quite wide,
but I have no problem with that part.
I think it is almost more of a challenge
and a bit of fun.
Trying to squeeze in
all the small villages with this wide one.
What I have a problem with is the height.
I'm not sure about the height.
The total height is 3.42 centimeters
and I've been under a couple of bridges
that are 3.50 centimeters.
It is not funny.
I crawl forward.
I also have all the solar panels
with a glass exterior
which is the highest peak.
Is it 3.50 on the bridge.
Don't know how drunk
the guy was who measured
or if it was before
or after on the new asphalt.
The heights do not like.
There is so much in it.
Even when I drive on highways
and you have five meters
up there, I sit
and duck to wait for the impact.
So I have a phobia about bridges.
Engine-wise, it's fantastic.
It's quite strong at 220 horses,
which is more than most in this size.
The Spanish mountain pass and all that.
Not the slightest hesitation.
No overheating whatsoever.
No overheating of the brakes.
In terms of trucks, it has been very good.
I am very happy with it
and the fuel consumption
has been well above expectations.
I have no experience whatsoever
with trucks before
so I thought it would be much worse.
3-4 liters per mile or something.
It is locked at 90,
but normally you are at 80
and if I am at 90
and maximize, I draw about 1-1.9
and the lowest I have been down to when
I drive 80
and drive calmly down there at 1.6
and 1.7 and 1.8 is normal consumption
on it and I think
it is good when it weighs 7.5 tons.
There have been no problems and diesel
has been cheap down in Portugal,
at €1.40 per liter.
14 kr a liter it costs down there.
Well, it was different
when we had 28 kr a liter here.
It is a good fuel price.
By the way, how many miles
have you traveled by truck?
I had an app that I have been using.
It keeps an eye on me.
It's only been 1,500 miles.
I've been standing still for so long.
I do a 30 mile drive
and stay there for a couple of days
and see 30 more miles
and stay for a couple of days.
It's actually less
than I thought it would be.
The rear ramp.
Did you do anything about it? No.
It is the same.
You get used to it.
It sounds quite a lot to fold it up/down,
but I did it for about two weeks.
After that, I don't give a shit.
There are so many barking dogs
and screaming children and so on.
That may sound like me too,
but it has taught me during the trip
that I went away
with the intention of being stealth
and being secretive.
But that's not how I've been living,
I've got 25% max that I'm freezing.
But 75% of the time I've been on pitches
and campsites
and living on farms and things like that.
So making the truck in stealth
to be secret, it was a waste.
It's not that I don't think I've used it,
but the opposite effect has been
that if you have
a large or small old or new motorhome
and you enter a campsite,
people will look at it
as if a new one is coming in.
But when I arrive, they look wide-eyed
because they think I've made a mistake.
A goods delivery to the restaurant
or something.
That I attract more attention on campsites
than regular motorhomes.
And I think that, without exaggeration,
maybe 200 people
have been inside the camper
and looked at it.
I've received a lot of feedback,
a lot of ideas
and a lot of suggestions
and thoughts that have made my head spin.
What are you doing now?
I check how much sun
there is. It provides 1680 watts.
Incoming such excess capacity
that I have probably fully charged
the battery before lunch.
So I have very good solar panels
and I've been very happy
with the batteries.
It works great.
Again, no gas at all
but everything is electrically powered
so it has worked beyond expectations.
Water production has worked
but has been undersized.
It works, but what happens
is that I delay filling the water.
Instead of filling the water tank
every five days,
you need to fill it
once every 15 days or so.
So I have a little bit
too little capacity on it,
but the principle works
so it's no problem.
Are you still drinking the water?
No, not anymore.
I did it in the beginning,
but out of sheer security or something.
When months have passed and you don't know
if there are bacteria and so on.
So I use it to make tea
and cook pasta and all this.
The only water I drink
is clean drinking water.
Everything else I use for this one.
And it's the same there.
I use the toilet all the time,
it works really well.
I have used the shower less
than I thought I would
and that is because my living pattern
has been different.
I haven't fricampa as much as I thought,
but I have toilets and showers
easily accessible on campsites,
so it's easy to run there.
The shower is overkill,
you could call it that.
In the last movie before I left, I said
it was 90-95% complete.
I'll do the latter along the way.
These will be the last strips to be added.
It never happened.
One of the things
was that I hadn't painted in the closet.
It is still unpainted.
The idea is good, but not always.
It is so easy to forget about it.
I have a thing that broke very quickly.
It was probably no more than 10,
15-20 miles
before I broke it the first time.
When I slid it out on the wardrobe module,
I had a locking device on it.
But it is such an insane amount of load.
When cornering, the bracket is high up
and has a lot of weight,
so when the truck swings,
the brackets come loose at once.
So it was a simple but effective solution.
It's when I'm going somewhere
that I push it in.
I lock it all the way in.
A temporary solution I made
after 10-15 miles.
It has been there ever since.
There is nothing as permanent
as a temporary solution.
In terms of trees, I'm super happy.
It's a bit boring but nothing remarkable.
It just rolls on
and works like any other apartment.
I have never felt claustrophobic.
I have varying views
through the back door,
but otherwise it's the same old apartment
that you move
around with.
I have actually eaten a lot inside,
due to the fold-down seat,
so we have been six people
plus a child at most in here.
6.5 people have eaten so it's been great.
Precisely because it has so much
more volume inside,
if the weather is bad,
people choose to sit inside.
It's better to sit in a tent.
So I've had a lot of people and people
I've gotten to know that I've eaten with.
This works well,
it takes 5 minutes to shit
and then it takes
5 minutes to clean up too.
It is surprisingly good.
It is made for cat and dog hair.
So it's motorized
and that makes it a good choice.
It is. I am very happy with it
and that is one of the reasons
why I find it very difficult
to see myself moving back.
Buy a 200 square meter house
or a 100 square meter apartment.
That is not going to happen.
It is a fundamental change that is valued
in a completely different way.
I have my 15 square meters
and it is absolutely perfect.
Just what you need.
The TV is the first thing
I turn on in the morning and then it's on.
All waking hours of the day.
This works great!
Super happy with it!
By the way, I have a 360 security camera,
I have not plugged it in,
it has not gotten my thumb out
and bothered me
and the reason is that I have never ever
during the trip
even felt the hint of threatened
or unsafe or insecure anything.
So the ability to close up and shut down
has meant that I am completely relaxed
all the time.
Wherever I have stood.
Before this trip I had the same old bike
for 15-20 years or so
and during this trip
I have grazed four bikes.
What!? Yes, I become a cyclist
in the process.
I bought an electric bike
and it was great.
I managed to use it three times
before it was stolen down in Halmstad.
I did not get far.
From Halmstad
I went further into the Netherlands
and if you are in the Netherlands
you can't do without a bike.
So I bought another electric bike
that I had for a while and it was okay.
Not as good as the first one I had
so I sold it at one campsite to another.
Then I ordered the exact same one
that I got rid of.
But then there's some rascal
who has your blue one in Halmstad.
Yes, it is.
It was locked outside the savings bank
and after 5-10 minutes there,
it was more picky.
You get angry about that,
but there's not much you can do about it.
It has a 4-5 mile range on it,
goes away and up hills
and anything can go shopping
in the backpack and just beep on.
When you live in a camper van,
the bike is your second car.
It's a key part of what you want
in a really good e-bike!
I got eleven countries in total.
By far the two best countries
that I am in love with
are Portugal and the Netherlands.
I have probably ten weeks
that I was in the Netherlands
and then it was six months
and over the winter
I was in the Algarve coast
in southern Portugal
and it is incomparable. I recommend it!
But what have you done with your days?
Have you made lots of trips
and met lots of people?
So many exciting personalities to meet.
I can feel it.
I'm going to be cruel,
but they lump everyone together and so on.
But to me, it feels like caravan owners
are hooking up
and then they go out for the weekend
with the family and barbecue
and so on
and then they go back on Monday or Sunday.
Whereas motorhome people
are very different.
Many pensioners
have sold their houses in Sweden.
They leave a small cottage or something
in a forest glade,
sell their house, buy a camper van
and spend 6, 8, 10 months down
in southern Europe
where warmth and comfort
are the most common.
Then we have another group
who are digital nomads.
A lot of people working on the road.
Has it been expensive?
No, especially not this year.
When you hear friends and acquaintances
complaining about electricity bills,
food prices
and so on, you feel very privileged.
I have lived in a long term stand
and I have a campsite
where I paid 7 euros
per day for the stand.
Then if you had electricity,
it was an extra 1.40 euros per day.
It has been expensive
and the food is not even half
the price of Sweden.
There have been very few YouTube videos
from you as well.
Yes, I have taken a break.
I don't know how to explain it.
Mentally, it has been hard to make them.
It was fun in the beginning
telling us about the truck
and telling us about plans and everything.
But then when I'm out on the road,
it feels too flashy.
I don't know how to describe it.
Me, me, me watching me and watching me
and it's rare to post a video
on a Tuesday afternoon
when it's pouring rain
and you're doing the laundry.
I'm in new places all the time
and I don't like the selfish focus.
I have taken a break,
but it is definitely not dead.
I have a...
I have an upcoming project
that will make
me resume Youtube again.
Then we'll have to say goodbye!
Take
care!