Motornörd =  Engine geek literally
but petrolhead is probably more correct.
A SPONTANEOUS PURCHASE
Hey, what's up?
I'm fine!
Do you have a rally car?
You have spike tires.
Yes, it can be good to have sometimes.
Today we will have look at my Fordson Dexta
with a 5 cylinder Volvo engine.
Fordson?
It's a tractor...
-A tractor!?
-Where is it?
It's outside.
What is this?
It is a 1964 Fordson Dexta.
-What do you use it for?
I have that to compete with.
I drive tractor-race, tractor-speedway
and tractor-cross we drive in Målilla.
-Traktor-cross?
Yes, we race at the motocross-track.
-Is that even possible?
It's possible but very bumpy.
-There's no suspension on a tractor?
No suspension at all, only the tires are swinging.
We are completely stuck in the seat without cushioning.
It works but it feels in the body
a couple of any races.
-There were several different branches?
For the most part we drive the tractor-race it's slalom
and then we drive between set bales.
It´s 5 to 6 differnt competitions a year
starting in June until October.
-Is there any competition ahead?
Yes, it's Hylletofta on September 14th.
That's what we're aming for right now.
Let's hope the stuff holds.
There has been some trouble this year for that
temptes pretty hard on the stuff.
It is a fully standard Volvo 850 engine with
original connecting rod, etc., The engine it's intact.
A bit for a neat tractor in really
but you learn to drive it.
How do you get the idea to put a Volvo car engine in a tractor?
Well ... I have too much spare time.
-Who has come up with the idea of ​​tune a tractor?
Well that's a good question ...
I think it started with ...
Rickard Nilsson from Gotland
which unfortunately is no longer with us.
He started by posting videos on youtube.
"The Terror-tractor".
I think many vehicle enthusiasts know who Rickard was.
That's where it really started.
When Rickard posted his clips on Youtube
I was building my own tractor.
It was a coincidence a friend had
been and looking for a tractor.
There is a T22a with a straight 6a diesel D24
lying next to which they have started to build.
Would you buy it?
Yes, I can do that ... so I brought it home.
It stood in the workshop for a few years
before I put it together.
It was not intended that I would compete with it,
but just a fun thing to build a tractor with a car engine.
Then it was a friend outside Sävsjö who asked if I would be in the tractor race?
What does that mean?
I said.
Well you drive slalom between bales etc.
Okay, I will try.
I went to the scrap yard and picked up a cabin arch that I mounted and competed with.
The first race I became 2nd.
Then I was hooked...
... it just kept going and then it was
more who were interested to race.
Then we started a Team.
Team Hylletofta.
We are 5-6 active drivers.
That was where it started for me and I have been racing since 2013
so there have been many competitions.
My old tractor got off in the middle of a race.
Back then the start and finish line was at the same place.
When I drove over finish line, It was massive pits and the tractor started jump...
.. when it had bounced twice so it knick
and then the tractor was like a folding knife.
It was a bit scary but that tractor is repaired today.
I have sold it to a friend.
-You have 2 tractors here what is the difference between these?
This is a Fordson Dexta and it
others are a Fordson Super Dexta.
Fordson is an English tractor.
It came in the beginning of the 60s,
maybe a bit earlier end of the 1950s around 1958-59.
I'm not sure of the history back then.
This particular model has I have learned a lot since mounted it apart several times.
This engine has a bit more hp than Dextra has.
Super Dextra was little better than
Dextra, you could say.
-What are you using this tractor for?
I have it as a truck.
I put together a couple of pallet forks so I can
lifting all my gearboxes and rear axles.
So it doesn't tempt my back too much.
It is a wear and tear tractor you could say.
The plan is that it should be refurbished.
Now I have bought so many tractors
since they break when I'm racing.
It is difficult to get hold of parts.
When I broke the rear axle last year, I called
five different tractor scraps yards and no parts was avaiable.
It took me 2 months to get hold of spare parts.
I got hold of this tractor in Hylletofta of all places.
I posted an ad on Facebook that I searched for parts.
Then I got a text message from a friend who had a tractor
and he asked me if you want to buy it.
Then I bought this and picked parts for the race tractor.
This is a standard tractor.
And I don't know what to call the other ...
We call it the little smurf.
I have spent many hours to build it.
After work, every weekend.
All the spare time you had was spent on the tractor.
Many friends pushed that Målilla tractor event is soon.
You must finish with the tractor.
A week before Målilla did
we first start up the tractor.
Then it was 03:44 i the middle of the night when it started in the garage.
Then my friend Jesper Fager was here and connected
his computer since it didn't start.
Then we had trouble with the trigger
and get all settings right.
But Jesper said I didn't go home until
it starts and we were all very tired.
People who were here and watching went home because it was in the middle of the night, it's really crazy.
I'm passionate about it and what it to work.
When we got the tractor started we were
pretty tired so we continued on Monday.
Then when I was out testing it I realized that it was leaking oil from crankshaft seal.
Then I became quite annoyed and said that I
ignore this and can't keep up anymore.
I'll be going to Målilla next year ...
.. but then the friends came and said
that we help you remove the engine.
Call and ask if you could have a day off from work.
At 22:45 we rolled the tractor into the workshop
and at 00:20 the engine lay on the floor.
I tore flywheels and crankshaft seals.
I called Volvo on Wednesday morning and
ordered a radial seal and had it within 2 hours.
Assembled the tractor and did a test drive in the evening.
Thursday we tuned the tractor on the street.
With the help of Natanael Ceder from Maxxtuning in Vrigstad.
Then it was off to Målilla.
I thought of one thing.
The front suspension are different when I compare to the original tractor.
This is how the original front suspension looks like.
This one is reinforced.
Since I have built a frame on the tractor.
I had to move the stabilization bar out.
They sit in the outer holes watching it
second tractor they are in the interior.
I've widened the shafts.
You can see that there are holes here.
I have moved the shafts out and grinded out of the holes.
Then I can angle the ball joints
so I get another camber.
Okey, The tires point outwards.
It will run more on the inside of the wheel.
Basically I want to angle the ball joints
forward so the wheels fold more.
Here the wheel is straight or almost so it points inwards.
You have welded these reinforcements on the inside.
Yes, I have extended the tractor 10 cm.
If we look at the trailing edge, I have made a sleeve.
As I have lathe and welded.
There are others who built their tractor in similar ways.
However, they have had problems since they have broke or bent.
Therefore, I have reinforced the inside.
Ah, you have welded a plate on the back.
Why do we have weights on it on the side?
Because the tractor is short.
It works differently from competition to competition.
This one is very smooth and I turn it around easily.
The disadvantage of short wheelbase is that it wants to
bounce and ride very much on the rear wheels.
Then you want to get the weight down.
I have made a metal belly in 15 mm steel, so it helps.
If that is not enough and want to get grip to the rear axle.
Then I put weights here that weigh 40 kg each.
So I have 120 kg on each side.
Then I feel that the tractor will be steady.
Is the side cover for Speedway?
Yes and for tractor cross.
This is when we drive several tractors at the same time.
When we drive slalom we drive on each track.
When there can be close contact, we have these pipes.
That pipe should be longitudinally
so nothing can come in between.
How did you get this puzzle together...
It was first and foremost you have to
consider how long you want the tractor.
The engine makes the tractor longer.
I wanted hydraulic clutch.
This holds the gearbox together
and I've made an adapter.
To assemble the car engine with the tractor.
Many times you build an adapter plate on the tractor or against the tractor's bellhousing.
In this case, I chose to cut a bit from the bellhousing.
I took the grinder and cut it.
Then I talked to a friend here in Sävsjö
who works at a company with a milling machine.
He milled off the cover so I had to measure by all dimensions.
I've used all the measures of
a Volvo 850 input shaft.
But has the tractor's input shaft.
I drive with a flywheel from rear axle parts
and a Sachs 765 pressure plate.
There is no longer the standard clutch pedal.
I have taken this one from a Volvo tractor.
It's like driving a car.
On the standard tractor, I brake with the heel.
When driving, you can disengage with
the whole foot or with the heel.
It will be difficult if you have a hard pressure plate.
Then we have the cabin, I have come to the
conclusion that we must be a cross on the cage.
In case of the tractor rolling over.
I have chosen to put pipes here as well.
Have also chosen to cross the pipes at the back
according to the rules.
I've done double crosses here.
I use the other for the seat belt.
The carbin is just bolted to the fender down to the trumpet.
Trumpet?
The rear axle is called the trumpet.
Because it looks like a trumpet?
Yes exactly.
I can see the battery, is it a catch tank below?
Yes.
-On a tractor?
Since the racing is very bumpy, I don't want to drop the fuel pressure.
Especially since the tractor runs on E85 Etanol
The petrol tank is a old pressure air tank from a truck.
I put the prtrol tank at the rear so
I have an escape route out if it catch fire.
On a standard tractor the petrol tank is under the steering wheel.
I don't want E85 there.
If I would roll over I will get all E85 on me.
That's why I want the petrol tank
behind me so I can escape.
It have wide and huge tires.
I have new tires this season.
Earlier I've driven with diagonal tires.
Tractor tires are expensive.
The tractor has been a jumpy and I haven't
got the right grip in the starts.
Radial tires are much softer.
I have chosen tires that have a tight fit
and the tire become almost straight.
When I rock the tractor like this
you see that it have soft tires.
The tractor isn't that bumpy anymore.
I had some problem when I was driving
Speedway and the tractor went like a duckling.
That's probably because it's short.
When it starts bouncing, it continues.
The only thing you can do about it is stop..
but you don't .
...first over the finish line wins.
Then you can't stop.
Why did you have spike tires earlier?
This is the case when you share ideas with others.
Rickard and some others also had spike tires...
Well, spike tires are probably good idea.
It was the first thing put on the tractor.
I've driven with spike tires speedway tracks.
Then others say it works
with standard 3 ribs tires.
I had trouble in the beginning that the
tractor is wheeling at the start.
The first race in Målilla I did a giant wheelie at the start.
When the tractor hit the ground the rim was
flat because the tires are too hard.
It destroyed both rims and after the race
I went home and was thinking about solutions.
I cut out a couple of rims of metal and
weld to the inside of the rim.
The other rims I have in there are reinforced.
Now I have tried to run original
tractor tires and they withstand more impact.
And the tractor get little higher at the front.
The grip is good and I don't change tires anymore.
Earlier I was changing front tires constantly
but that's a pain to do.
-What is this?
Why do you have one?
It is the steering column that sits there.
It's orbitrol.
-What is orbitrol?
Hydraulic steering.
-Hydraulic steering?
Do you need it?
It's much easier to drive.
Standard tractor have mechanical steering
and if that pinch you have no wrist left...
Hahaha!!
Many of these people get hurt...
Yepp, many have been hurt.
-They have to learn the hard way.
It had become very much
turning when driving slalom.
Then it had been a lot of
back and forth all the time.
That is why I have chosen to build power steering.
Then this is a very special sport...
-Yes!
You have to be stupid to keep doing this.
It shakes and jumps but the competition horns grow out.
It's terribly fun.
We benefit from charing ideas with each other.
No one has any secret at races.
When I ask others what they have
done, they are honest and helpful.
That what's great about this sport.
What kind of people are competing?
Are you all farmers?
Many have their own farms.
I grew up in Sävsjö but have also been
a lot in Hylletofta since my mother grew up there.
I was with my grandparents when I was younger.
That's where I got it from
since I work with tractors now.
Well, that's where I got the interest.
The engine is fully visible here.
I can remove the hood.
Here I have my little screwdriver
that I always carry with me.
This has to be easier work with then a car?
Yes, I can accesses everything smoothly.
I found the engine on Facebook.
It was a loose engine from a Volvo 850
with gearbox and suspension.
I picked up the engine in Husqvarna
and knew nothing about it.
It turned over and had compression
so I brought it home.
I've changed the timing belt and some other stuff.
It's only a small 16t turbo.
That means that it charge very early.
The engine is completely standard.
It is said that they can handle about 300hp
and it has lasted for 3 years.
I have had help to build the exhaust manifold.
-It looks like a snake pit.
Yepp, it's designed by Jesper Fager.
There are straight pipes on this one.
Yepp
And a screampipe out of the wastegate.
I have pipes here that go from the cabin to the front axle.
It is a reinforcement since I broke the
other tractor so you want it as strong as possible.
Future plans are to update the breaks for the next season.
It's drum brakes standard and that's what we use.
Drum brakes stop working pretty fast.
You tear apart and change the coating ...
... run 2-3 competitions and they hardly work it again.
Brakes are quite nice to have.
The idea is to build disc brakes.
I have some plans that should work.
More others have switched to disc brakes.
There are ideas how to build for next season.
This is probably the next step.
-Is it a 4-point belt?
Yepp.
Mine is quite wide.
Otherwise, it cuts your skin since it bounces so much.
The seat is bolted so the only one
the suspension that exists is the wheels.
When I have the steering wheel straight and
full steering left or right are 2 laps.
You see the wheels are straight.
Since it is orbitrol steering...
When has run a race the steering knob could
be over here but I never think about it.
-Is that the accelerator?
Yes it has a hand accelerator and there is foot accelerator.
You have 2 other pedals.
That's the brake.
For each wheel?
There you have left and right.
I push one of them when you want to turn.
And I brake with the heel.
When I turn left I press the pedal.
Likewise and I should turn the other way.
But when it bounces,
how do you know which pedal to use?
It's in your head.
2nd, 3rd gear and reverse.
You see I have welded an iron here.
That is beacuse the 1st is here.
I do not want 1st gear by misstake.
It has happened in the passed.
Then the gearbox would make a weird noice.
That's why I've made a stop so I can't get the 1st gear.
Here I have water temp,
oil pressure and oil temp, ect.
Here I have charging and oil pressure on ordinary diodes.
Would probably not need any gauges
since I can't look at them anyway...
-What does usually breaks?
Everything possible ....
I have had problems with gearbox and rear axles.
Here we got the problem.
Here is 2ans gear...
This is also 2nd gear from gearbox nr 1
which broke down in Målilla.
There should be 41 cogs here ...
Now there is no one left.
Here are 2 pieces.
There have been a lot of pieces at the bottom.
It's pretty solid stuff.
Now the rain has come but I think so
people want to see is when you start this ...
... and drive around a bit in the parking lot.
Unfortunately, I can't join you.
Haha!
We'll see if the gearbox hold this time.
-Haha!
Hahaha, the cap blew off..
HAHAHA!
A tractor.
It's crazy.
What a fantastic machine!
Yes it seems to work now.
Now I hope it works in Hylletofta.
Now I have practice on the start procedure.
So far it is no rattling from the gearbox.
I wish you the best of luck in the competition
I'll see if have time to drop by.
I definitely think you should
then you get to see some cool construction.
See you later!
Bye!
Support me on Patreon.
Patreon.com/motorkrantz
More episodes will be translated to
English in the near future.
Thanks for watching!
Please subscribe for new episodes.