When there is a lot to show on this building now.
Looking forward to showing all Kalle Duck Secrets.
I'm going to build a camper and do it with a different approach.
Like to be a little inventor and generally crazy
So I've gone all in on crazy ideas.
Hello Hello!
Hi Douglas!
How's it going?
Now it's good.
It was heavy a week ago.
Then I was pretty stressed.
The heat that has been here has not made it easier.
I am so happy that it is overcast now I can say.
It is almost thunder in the air so that it is now possible to breathe.
Now it is working and now I am almost done. It's nice.
Almost finished you say. Yes!
What does that mean?
Deadline and the budget I have withdrawn on this project,
But it usually belongs.
May 1 was set like my soft deadline and now it's last June.
So one week to approximately need me.
Then I'm done to go.
I would say i'm 90 % ready another week, say 95 % finished
And the last thing I do during the journey so that a week, ten days
Something is the plan. Then I stick.
But have you slept in it yet?
Well, it's now that everything happens.
I have built the last week, ten days that
I have done surface layers on it.
It's Thursday today and on Monday I was
And also inspected it.
It is now that everything happens.
Wonderful congratulations!
Thanks! It's nice to have that bit over.
I have set a deadline for myself that was not.
About any real reason.
Not just because I want to push myself.
It has been good and spurring.
But now, now that I pass on May 1st and that it was June 1st
so there are very many who have been on me
And it has become a stress feeling.
I knew you would miss this deadline
from the first day. I also.
It was far too much work.
But the hat off!
You have done a fantastic job!
Even though I haven't seen it see it on the inside yet. I'm so damn curious.
I have closed again and do not want to show anything.
I want to watch the reaction video to it.
But before we go in and look so, so some stuff has happened.
On the one hand, you have no pressure left.
No, the letters are gone.
On this page I have a few left on the other side.
It has been by far the most boring on the entire building.
There are two colors on a light blue, dark blue and the dark blue.
The sticker surface has crackled in the sun so you can pick square millimeters by hand.
With the nails do not go at all.
Doesn't it work with razor blades either? No.
The problem is not that they are stuck.
The problem is that it is so brittle.
It crackles.
It is five times five square millimeters pieces that one gets away regardless
What technology you use.
But I have tried with razor blades I tried with chemically dissolve rubber pulleys,
As you grind away and everything works and everything takes exactly the same time.
It doesn't matter what technology I use one
and half an hour per letter to get it away
And I have no patience.
Is there so much else you need to do so it's an eternal job
that never ends.
Besides now that I've removed it, the cabinet is so matte of oxide
And behind it so you have stickers that are bright
And it is not possible to remove.
I have tried polish clay, I have done everything possible.
It ends with me having bought color and I come and paint.
Look what geeky! Fy phase what bold!
Each battery has its own information display
to show the charge status on it.
So it's 14 kilowatt hours like a Nissan Leaf in battery capacity
Sisåd is 4-5 times as much as you usually have normal.
You have 2500 watts on the roof, which is also three times
More than people usually have.
There is an excess of energy.
That was the idea from the beginning.
And I thought it was so fun to drive it up there.
It was great fun!
130 kilos weigh the batteries and hydrome pistons
Draws 150 kilos each, they pallets.
The spoiler is left to plastic.
But that wasn't that the Star-Link would sit in it?
I have also slaughtered it.
The Star Link is motor controlled on a 3-foot.
But when I remove that mechanism, it's just Parabol itself
The surface I saved.
The one in turn is only five inches thick and as I will fold into the spoiler
So it gets fixed in horizontal position.
So it is simplified and.
Wondering how many people in the world are like butcher Star-Link?
I can say that surprisingly many on youtube
Have I learned a lot.
They start to go in and solder about components and so on
So that people can geek down in all subjects.
On this page I have.
I have an electric bike in the garage for longer tours
And then my plan is that when I get somewhere in Europe
Then I take the scooter and raise what to ask.
This is Durk aluminum that I have powdered.
It could not agree but mounted there an hour ago.
I have it down here too.
On the underside of the box.
It is like a design thing that you should have the dark
Because it is the same as it is on the back of the dock.
And you have fixed new hub caps as well.
They came there yesterday.
Big difference for a small money.
It does a lot for freshness and the whole.
There you have the key.
A and B are on the key.
Yes. Remote control.
It is not possible to sneak with that opener anyway.
No, it's a winch for a quad bike.
It is very strong and works great, but it is definitely not quiet.
The quality is not the best on it.
Then it is the disadvantage that it sits on the back of the bed,
So it's basically a drum that sits on a wall only.
It has been silent it has been quieter.
When you are at some campsite we'll go five in the morning
and wake half the neighborhood.
They have to take that.
The floor here on the door is art material called Eva.
Eva plastic or Eva rubber.
It is a substitute for teak
which is endangered and you have to devastate it longer.
Used on large luxury hunts and so on.
Has this type of material instead of the teak.
It's soft to go on.
It is soft and it is not slippery when it is wet.
It's easy to keep clean.
You can even take it if it has been given color on dirt.
On it you can take sandpaper and sandpaper away the dirt.
It is superbly good material.
It is certainly very expensive material?
No, it is mainly 3m double -sided tape that comes on a roll
Just buy a 70 wide I think it was three meters long roll
As you roll out it just self -adhesive.
It was very simple and smooth.
In the garage I want to try to squeeze in some features even when I sit outside.
I will be jawing.
Also fold down we have a kitchen table where you have a seat.
Again, it is 95 % clearly what is left to do
will do during the journey.
One of the examples is that the underside of the table,
What you see now is done.
But I will make the surface of the table in burnt wood.
Same as I have on the kitchen table inside the car as well,
So I will do it during the journey.
The first part is that you sit and take one berred together with someone
and then because I am about to tinker and stuff
And need to fix so you have to have a workbench too.
So then you can do so that you continue to pull it out.
Here I will have hanging off the tools and putting a screwdriver.
So here it is like a workbench and because there I have storage.