How do you know this will work over the main?
I do not know.
That's the fun.
The exciting thing is that so far away from my comfort zone
As possible I want to be.
I'm going to build a camper and do it with a different approach.
Like to be a little inventor and generally crazy
So I've gone all in on crazy ideas.
Hello Hello.
Hello.
How's it going?
It is just fine.
You look a little half the tire.
Yes, many hours.
We are starting to approach May 1st now.
Your deadline.
Yes, it does not appear to be able to hold.
Not so unexpected actually, because you have a lot to do.
But all construction pulls over budget and pulls over time
Is well the standard problem that everyone has.
But what is it wrong?
What is it that does not lock?
I have actually figured out why I have felt stressed.
I can't shower here.
That's the problem.
I have three days here so I go to Värnamo, showers,
Changes clothes and fetches more stuff and goes back.
My weeks rush until I realized that it is not three days at one week seven.
So I have three days here.
A day in Värnamo, three days here one in Värnamo which feels
Like one weeks, much faster goes.
So that's why I have felt so stressed
to get started with it.
Now I have calm down and it has made that May 1 Deadline
I iron or I move on without it that has
strolled is when you have no control over the situation
Yourself longer without being dependent on others.
So then it becomes that stuff takes longer and promises that is not held
And things disappear and so on.
It has been a bit messy now.
What are you waiting for then?
The boxes under the stomach of the truck are on order.
They have had another supplier but I have waited four months for
And leave them in the knit and I have been allowed to order them again.
I have ordered stuff that has disappeared to the freight forwarding company
slopes it away and it's handmade special stuff
It takes an eternity before I get new etc.
But how are things going for you?
How far have you come?
It's fine.
I have been in a phase when there is a lot that happens
But nothing that is visible.
When people are curious so I don't have that much to show off
Without it, it has a lot of finery and behind the scenes that need to be fixed.
Are you done with the garage?
Not finished but it just starts to become more useful.
You will get shelf systems and that bit in the form of LED strippers is in place,
But you will get a little workbench type
And shelf systems that we will build.
But should the bikes be hung up or?
Yeah, I will fix that so they don't crash
And gases and brakes. But it will fit.
You are the first thing I see in the ceiling here.
Have you received these panels or what they are called.
LED panels or skylights.
They have finally appeared now. I've been waiting for them.
I have three pieces here in the corridor
Do I have six pieces above the table
and now on Monday the electrician will come and we will plug them
Unscrew and make it more complete.
It will be a big case forward for the real ones.
Looks good and then has cupboards that you have put there.
Got those in place so they are ready.
And the next step is that I will have the surface layer
all below 90 centimeters will be micro concrete that gets a feeling of concrete doors
And even down here so it is a company from Värnamo
coming on Tuesday.
And put it on the wall upwards.
Exactly! There will be two main themes.
You have 3D cork, anything over 90 and concrete that is below 90
And then all horizontal surfaces become three millimeters of powder covers.
So here comes the plate and it will be good
And also the sink and everything else that is horizontal.
There are also other things you have done here. Electricity in the ceiling.
Is that the roof. Is on we pull.
And the camera?
Exactly. I have gained both GoPro and the camera.
And set up four surveillance cameras.
There you have the GoPro'n and the surveillance camera.
So much will be seen by them.
Unfortunately there was no white front to order,
But I have to accept the black part.
It is thus a digital device that connects the four images.
Here all 4 are drawn to the same picture.
The solar panels are in place, they are mounted and drawn in,
The electricity is withdrawn into the truck.
There I wait for the electrician to connect the zeal to the electrical system.
But mechanically they sit in place and everything is clear there.
It is moving forward, it is moving forward.
Electricity company that I work with.
They like odd projects but i think they've taken water
over the head for they have had long discussions here
and we have agreed that I may write on a piece of paper
with that they are not responsible for electrical safety
Because there is nothing like that.
Is correct or there are no real rules on how to do it.
Just such a simple thing as grounding.
If you have a vehicle you get it in the chassis.
It's no wonder.
But we will have CE outlets
Blue contacts I have at campsites.
Can't remember what they are called. CE outlets I think ...
What happens when you connect to the electricity at the campsite?
You have a local soil where you plug it in, then the campsite soil takes over.
What happens to the solar panels when they are connected to the earth?
One must have a switch that breaks the solar panels
and one can move over the earth from the local earth
To the campsite's soil.
There are many such strange questions that they have not been to before.
We have googled a lot and find some different solutions.
They push the boundaries.
Yes, and my project at the company where there is the most discussion
Around it is my shower.
They don't like the shower.
They have a nickname of what they call the death shower.
So I hope the "famous last words" I hope they don't get it right.
But they are not completely satisfied with what I want to do there.
It is a hybrid solution between recycling shows regular shower
And it stands out a little.
You can shower with rubber boots on. Lol! just.
You have dressed everything here now.
All gaps and boxes are largely done.
Yes, what will be when you get the 3D cork
is that it becomes more uniform.
But the door to the pantry is not clearly obviously.
But when you get everything in place you have.
You have everything you need so it is available,
But it's hidden.
Spice shelf and knife shelf.
Is there under the junk basket.
You have to learn your own limitations.
And I've done a lot of stuff before.
But this project has been difficult
For a different reason and that is why I am an engineer.
Come on and bring out all the solutions is the light part,
But I'm not a carpenter.
I have neither resources, knowledge nor equipment for it.
So in my head, the quality level is not what I want to be
Without doing as best I can.
It will be good enough.
But I am more engineer than a furniture carpenter I have discovered.
This is the kitchen table. It is perfectly fixed.
Nothing you move on but it should be stable and permanent.
To it I have a 43 inch screen so it folds out
screen and then you have it in front of you and behind
the computer on the wall.
Then you create a workspace where you sit and work.
But if you get guests
Well cables in the way ...
If you get guests you want to remove the screen.
Then instead you fold out there you get a bench
Most of the time I will be myself then I have dining table and work area.
Just such a thing. Materials cannot be taken in.
The next thing that has been so frustrating that nothing has built in here
Has been in real plywood but it is the construction plywood
that has to make concrete castings.
That is what is available.
They are oblique and wind and large holes in all this.
Regular carpentry plywood is not available
And the prices we should not talk about.
The absurd is that it has not been easy to get hold
in the right material for construction.
The seat bench will of course be dressed and then I will
Have the same wooden floor as I have.
On it I will have on that bit that you go up it to bed
so it will be floors similar there will be dressed
But the bench is uploadable.
The idea is that in here I will have my charging station
for cameras and drones and other things so it will be
Filled with charging options.
In the bathroom then?
It is connected and drawn.
But that said, I don't have the surface layers ready but it is
The next step after this.
What is the surface layer to use here?
You will not use cork.
No, without a regular wet room mat only.
I will make it easy for wet room mat.
But that is the big thing now that I have on order
is very much plate to order.
It is the slide system for the wardrobe.
I have forgotten them to order so they have made me delay again.
But I want to get the wardrobe fast as the eye.
In order to get the closet in I will also mount the front door
and these are the last two major buildings
which is left before you can start making the fin.
After all, the truck has three recessed LED lights
which I will reuse two of them.
This one will be covered by the slide part to the closet,
But the one over the bed and the one in the middle of the truck
Will I reuse, I watched Youtube.
The submarines have red light so as not to
Destroy the darkness.
Then you can get it that you need to go to the toilet at night
And so you don't want to sabotage the darkness.
So we will have the red recessed with red LED lighting on.
And the batteries have not mounted because the boxes are missing.
Exactly, they also wait for and are it card houses
So it is something that is delayed.
It affects so many other steps so it applies
to have many parallel projects running at the same time
So you don't get standing anywhere.
But the most frustrating is, as I said now, I am not controlling over time
You yourself are dependent on others and then it is not as easy to.
Plan as tough as I did.
Especially not with my three weeks three days.
Now calling people and wants help and so I discovered
That it was Sunday today.
I forget days.
Fiberglass spoiler over the cab.
I will build my latest toy that I got yesterday.
This is Star-Link that is SpaceX satellite
Based Internet systems.
It is quite unusual so far and they are.
Around the equator, the many satellites have postponed.
But the farther north you get, the more sparse it becomes.
Officially, I don't think you can order it in Sweden.
However, you have the cells going up to a certain level
And of a little bad luck with the timing.
The last cell ends between Ljungby and Värnamo
So I miss it with one and a half two miles about.
So what I did was I borrowed an address
For a kindergarten in Ljungby, so that is my service address.
Then I had another delivery address so I got it home
So it doesn't work here in the garage.
But it works in Ljungby and from Ljungby and the rest of Europe.
But right here it doesn't work so long.
Elon Musk owns both companies and it has nothing with Tesla
Without it, SpaceX is.
The second space company that today has 2300 satellites
that has postponed.
It covers the whole earth so you can have high -speed internet on.
In the middle of the Pacific Ocean or in the Sahara Desert.
This is what they are now using during the war in Ukraine as well.
Exactly. That's what is the really big thing.
Because it has been because the United States has had it now for just over a year
or one and a half years where there was a good while
And then they release it to more and more countries
And they basically have switches.
So they decide that from now on, it applies to Sweden
And now it applies to Ukraine.
What was the big thing about Ukraine is that they have started roaming
And Roaming does what all of us motorhome owners have longed for.
It makes that instead of becoming a stationary on a cell
So you have the opportunity to go around with it.
This one comes with three -foot and it has motorized
that optimizes the angle and everything to the satellites.
But on Youtube I have seen a lot that do tests, stealing it
And just mount the firm pointing straight up.
And does it go as I hope they do, then it is perfect
Because then I will fold it directly into the spoiler.
But I also want to see how much difference it will be at the download speed.
Is it negligible then I will stel operate it
and has a great impact.
So when I drive loosely with my foot.
You know this should work in the main.
But I don't know.
That's the fun.
The exciting thing is to go out on areas that are not so far away
From my comfort zone as possible and that is the goal.
To test all the crazy ideas I had in my head
And it pulls to its tip.
Some work and some do not work, then you learn.
Have you set any new deadline now, right? How do you think now?
No hard deadline but just continue at the pace that I do
And then it must take the time it takes.
And I think that sounds really good.
I also have another philosophy.
I will not make the final finish, type paint inside cabinets and such things.
I will leave that completely.
Because in the same way as in a house that never gets finished
As one is doing and stuffing with, everything comes
What I can move on or shoot on.
It will do during the journey instead. So I have like mini projects
Which I can grab when I feel it. Rainy days.
When it is rainy and windy then you stand in there and paint?
Exactly, some things that I will take with me on the trip.
It won't be so fun to sleep in it then.
You have to be a morning girl and then you have to be out for the rest of the day.
So when it doesn't rain, then you have to do it. So it must be.
It is great to see that it is moving forward here.
It is making progress.
Next time we see I have much more surface layer in place
So it will look like it has happened much more outside it.
Good luck and fight for now!
Thanks, now it's the final sprint.
See you! Hello!