Motornörd = Engine geek literally
but petrolhead is probably more correct.
Sven Billred odd project.
PART 2.
Vetlanda Sweden, September 2018.
-I'm back!
We will follow this project until it is done.
It's all the way up to Elmia 2019.
Yes.
-The car should be ready before Easter, right?
Fortunately easter is late next year.
It's late April so there are many months left.
It have been progress since last time.
Yes.
I have to get the body done.
I've started here.
These plates and trunk cover are finished.
The shape is done but it needs some small adjustments.
It is a little wavy after the English wheel.
It should be straightened up and smoothed out
with body file before starting to grind.
I also made the trims which
should sit over the joints.
This is a front trim, here.
I have had to shape it a bit since
so the convertible fit.
So I've had to lower it a bit.
This trim is dimensionally customized.
It sits so tight that it can hardly be removed.
There is a screw mount in the front.
So you attach it there and also at the back.
The trim is fixed like this and then
it is angled in place at the front edge.
From the beginning, this is a Volvo 123 (Amazon) trim.
Which I have to fix because
it has been bent in all directions.
I heated up the trim and stretched it
out so it gets perfectly straight.
Then I have to weld this one
so it got something to attach to.
It can be tricky since
it is thin material in stainless steel.
It works if you are careful.
It's the same kind of trim but I have
narrowed to make it pointed.
And get another shape at the bottom.
I have done this since the joint is much more pointed.
Otherwise there would be a gap in between.
Now I've made the trim a little narrower.
The width up here is the same.
The trim then becomes narrower all the way down.
It fits very well.
-Yes, very good fit!
-How have you manage to do all this?
Long nights hahah..or late nights.
-It must be more than 4 hours a day, right?
On weekends there will be more, there may be...
...up to 24 hours on a weekend.
It all depends on how many others
activities I have to go to.
-You've dressed the whole rear end!
Actually it went better than expected.
-This was just paper last time I was here?
Yes it was cardboard.
Since then I have completed the inner frame.
I finished it first then I painted the frame.
Then you template the frame and cut the metal.
It will be a long piece of sheet metal.
This sheet has been curved in one piece.
And here is the joint.
It's not so easy when you're alone and going
curve such a long sheet in the English wheel.
Don't have any friends?
Yes, but they don't like to work.
They are mostly here to watch.
-It's like me then ... Yepp.
You reinforce by adding one
angular profile along the entire frame.
I attach the plate with welding rods so I get
stiffness so I can roll the metal sheet back and forth.
When I start rolling the sheet it becomes stiffer.
Then everything should fit.
Everything is handmade around all the rim.
It can't be done with a machine
so then it have to be done with a hammer.
-Wow, what a job!
-The difficult thing is to make two equal sides.
Making one is easier but the other must be the same.
I do not build this body like other car builders do.
They build fish skeletons in wood with wooden boards
and then the sheet molds after that.
Then you can place the metal against
the mold and check if it fits.
I don't like working with wood...
I rather do this and measure until it gets right.
It may take longer but it does not matter.
Then I do not have to make a skeleton in wood.
Then have to have pretty good eye measurements.
It was a carpenter who once said...
...a little oblique is not easy as long as you do not see it.
Would it be that it differs a few millimeters
here and there it doesn't matter if nobody sees it.
It has nothing to do with the
construction if it gets little wrong.
I think that's a bit charming for then
you see that it is handmade.
If I would crash with this car,
you can't buy spare parts they have to be manufactured.
The lock for the trunk is here on the inside.
It sits here.
Now there is a spring here but it will not
be needed when there is a rubber strip here.
Then the trunk will then open automatically.
Possibly there will be gas pistons
or a lock in a fixed position.
It works pretty well.
- Absolutely crazy what a job you have done!
It's a lot of millimeter fit.
You have done this too.
Yes it is the platform against the frame
Since the frame swings like this
it would have been difficult to get to the line.
Then this line had continued down then up.
Then I thought it was nicer to
put in a piece and get a straight line.
Which is in line with this line.
Then five more of these are added.
All the way down.
We have previously seen a template in cardboard.
These are made of stainless steel and
I have welded the end together.
I will glue the screws to the back.
Which is cut into the holes and screwed into place.
Here on the edge a friend has made small brass hats that will...
...be glued so it looks like a brass cut.
Like this one but they
others are too small for my lathe.
They are made in an automatic lathe instead.
At the next phase it is...
...the doors and the torpedo.
The torpedo is just a basic construction so far.
Here, reinforcement beams should be put down like this.
In a potential collision with a
deer, elk or a passenger car.
It should be a support up here.
So it can be folded down.
And don't come along then I should be safe.
I have made a door template.
I'll bend the sheet metal around.
So I get a light bend that goes
along with the torpedo around here.
The sheet from the torpedo will be curved
and then the sheet parts meet around here.
The door will follow the line and then down.
The second sheet part will be aligned with the door.
The shape continues up to the dashboard
all the way to the other door.
The whole curve on the torpedo
will be handmade.
I have made a special tool.
I pin it on the metal piece.
and start shaping.
I've knotted it so it attaches
on the metal sheet and not slip away.
The length I have to adjust as you can
make a turn without it getting angular.
We do this instead.
Attach it.
Like this.
Then you have to tap the last.
Also bend with a pair of pliers.
Then you get the right rounding and then
you can move the pliers afterwards.
Then it will be the same rounding all the way.
It will bend slightly so it goes all the way.
Then it becomes a soft line all the way.
-How thick is the aluminum?
2 millimeters.
It is semi-hard aluminum.
I don't want too soft for then...
...then there will be no hardness in it
and then it expands too much.
-Now we have a sound that has made a comeback.
Now it sounds again.
The fluorescent lamp sound also
wants to be included in the film.
Yes the fluorescent lamp lives its own life in the garage.
-Yes it's quiet then it starts to creak.
When it comes to interior I have
made a chair to begin with.
To see if it will fit.
It is a prototype that should be cut down
so it is easier to step in and out.
Then make another chair.
This is the padding that will be used.
It won't look like this
it will be covered in black leather.
Also leather around the edges.
A bit of the aluminum will be visible
because I want some of the raw material left.
A wall must be manufactured behind the seats.
And the wall will bend as much as the body.
Here there will be a couple of speakers.
I don't know I can hear anything but we will see.
I hope the car will be quiet anyway.
In the middle there will be a podium for the gear lever.
- Should the gear lever be high or low?
It will be very low.
It is a control from a boat.
It is probably from the 1920s.
I don't really know what it has been
to but some kind of controls for a boat.
This control should be gear shift.
-It'll be an automatic gearbox, right?
The second slider will
open and close the exhaust control.
And it should sit here.
This piece I will not do anything with.
It should look old.
However, I'll make a cover here.
I will try to get hold of a carpet.
And it should be rough in the material.
A bit like a doormat.
A copy of the headlights.
Yes we've seen them,
Where should you place them?
They should sit here.
It gets in between the trims.
Then I will also add a reflex.
Have not decided if it should be lowered.
Make a recess and get this in.
Or if I hang the reflex under.
We have to wait and see.
-Where should you put the petrol tank?
Under this plate.
Then it will be built so that
it will follow this line.
The idea is to follow this line along the frame.
You should not see that it is a tank without it
it should look like the body continues underneath.
-Is the idea going from side to side?
Yes it goes inside of the frame.
And the idea will extend over here.
-Where should the fuel lid sit?
It will sit here.
It will be an old model with a quick opening.
-How big is the fuel tank?
About 67 liters.
About 67 liters?
Yes according to my calculations.
The goal is at least 65 liters
and then I can drive about 400 km.
The car will consume more than 1 liter
the every 10 km I can guarantee.
Well an inline 12 I'll guess consume more than a liter.
Yes.
Then it depends on the gearing you have on the rear axle
and how big the wheels it is and how easily it rolls.
This car will not have as much resistance.
It is a fairly small and narrow body.
The air resistance will be quite
small so I don't think it will be that much.
Next time you come I hope so
the torpedo and the doors are done.
-It feels like you want to continue to work?
Yes there are things to do.
-Then they have to wait for the next episode.
You're welcome!
See ya!
Bye.
Watch the entire project.
More episodes are available.
Thanks for watching!
Please subscribe for new episodes.