Motornörd = Engine geek literally
but petrolhead is probably more correct.
Sven Billred odd project.
PART 3.
Vetlanda Sweden, Oktober 2018.
-Hello!
Hi!
-I'm back.
Yepp.
-Let's see if they have been any progress?
Well there has been no huge progress.
I got my waterjet grill in aluminum.
And all the moldings.
The moldings I have been shaped and they are not
finished yet but should be rounded and sanded.
All screws should be recessed.
And had to rolled to this one.
When it's polished on the outside
it looks like it is cast in aluminum.
It is because it is a bit dull but then it becomes
when they waterjet it then it looks more real.
So you're going to polish it?
Yes only on that surface.
Then it may be gray like this.
It took many hours to do but it looks great.
There are many holes.
I have created a door.
And fitted the trunk and it's almost done.
It needs to be polished.
It's rough sanded.
Here I did a rough... and I tested to polish.
Then I tried something eles and
the other side got much better.
I have to redo the other side.
Now it is wet-sanded.
-Okey.
It's only the polishing left.
It is very straight and looks fine
compared to the other side.
That part took about 14 hours to grind.
-You're joking!??
No, it took 14 hours.
-14 hours to sand the little triangle?
Yes.
It about anothe 5-6 hours of polishing before I'm done.
-You're crazy.
I'm lucky I don't have to pay someone
for it would be very expensive.
-It's totally crazy.
If you spend 6 hours to grind just that side.
-Then you have 20 hours of work on the other side.
Yes.
-And you should be ready before Easter...
-Yes hehehe... that's the idea.
I have made a door that is
suspended in my own hinges.
I cut to it so the transition is not quite straight yet.
I want a little sweep on it.
I got to weld and put in
pieces to get a good fit.
-Have you built the door yourself?
Yes.
-You're good.
Well...
...stubborn.
On the inside I have tried jeweling.
Same way as the dashboard
but it was difficult.
I can't do that in the pillar drill
because it gets too deep.
I tried by hand though but now
it will be covered with leather instead.
With a compartment here in leather.
Did you wanted it to look like this?
Yes, jeweling is difficult to do.
It's a different thing if you have a machine
Which could push just as hard to get same type of jeweling.
Then you get smooth and even results.
-How long did it take to build do the door?
Well, how long did it take ....
hmmm...
About one and a half week.
From scratch.
I had to make special tools.
When I've cut the sheet metal I put it here.
So it stands out around this much.
Attaches it so it stays firm.
-Yes.
I knock with a plastic hammer around the pipe.
Then you get this bend.
-What bend do you want?
Partly upwards.
And it turns in.
-Ah, right.
When I do the other door,
I have to cut off the welding and turn it around so that it becomes mirrored.
These parts are welded into this bend
The door itself consists of outer skins
and the two edge moldings that you can bend.
A bottom and a front piece where hinges
sitting which I had to reinforce.
And finally, the inner leather on the door.
-Impressive!
And now the hinges are in place.
Here, there should be a sealing strip
that is in line with the hinge.
A sealing strip or D-list as it is called.
It should sit here since I want the car waterproof.
I should be able to wash the car
without getting the whole inside wet.
-Yes you should be able to drive in the rain as well.
Yes that is the most important thing.
That's about as far as I've come.
I have created some other small details.
I didn't have these mouldings before.
Was the rearview mirror in place when you were last here?
-No.
It is mounted with a standard M6 stud bolt.
Then it is removable.
I put it here first...
It should be below this.
Then you attach the rearview mirror like this.
The only thing which is missing is the passenger door.
And fit the rest of the parts.
I smooth out the body with a pansar blade.
-Pansar blade?
A car body file which many experts says.
It is used so that you get a smooth surface.
To get rid of any small elevations that exist.
And after that I start sanding with sandpaper.
If I would use sandpaper it
would just follows the bumps.
A car body file removes the bumps
so I can then grind later on.
-How much is it planing off?
Not a lot.
I have to careful so I don't get i wrong.
IF I cut a jack in the sheet metal.
Then you get to plan the entire area so that the jacket disappears.
You can't just plane at the same spot.
Then there will be a pit there when you polish.
If you have a pit or a jack, I have to plane
down everything until I get to the same level.
This area takes about 5 hours to plan.
Here it is smoother and then it takes
2-3 hours with a car body file.
There are various grinding machines you can use.
I tried a machine that
car painters call pancakes.
It is slightly larger and has oscillating grinding.
It does this movement.
And it also forcibly rotates.
A regular oscillator grinder
does not spin it just vibrates.
This machine spins and
makes an oscillating motion.
Then it is easy to get the surface smooth.
I have tried this machine on this site
and therefore it became much smoother.
That is why I will redo the other side.
This type of sandpaper is used.
This sandpaper is larger than usual.
So it takes a bigger surface and it is easier to get flat.
-What sandpaper do you start with?
This is 180.
I use from 180 up to 2000.
With 1000 and 2000 I wet polishing.
Then it becomes this surface.
I use window cleaners products.
I think that's smoother.
It gets leaner and much and easier to wipe off.
-This is pure craftsmanship.
Well... Could we can take the other side instead?
This one is stuck.
It is instead of chrome or paint.
It has a tendency to get burned pretty quickly.
So it is better to make a cover that covers.
-Mm, I will do such a cover in 20 minutes...
Well, half an hour..hahaha!
-Crazy!
It takes a bit longer to do.
Here you get some cooling.
Right.
It takes in cooling air here
and lets it out underneath.
Then it gets a stream of air that cools the covers.
-Is this one polished and done?
No it is just roughly polished.
-And the other side is just sanded?
Yes.
I have started to polish.
Do you use machine then?
Yes I use a bench polishing machine.
As I use with 3 different polish pads.
-The headlighte are mounted.
Yes, but I don't remember if this was done then.
This one will be unpolished though
the stripes will be polished up.
Possibly the edge around it.
I thought it looked a bit naked so I've lathed a metal sleeve.
It brings more life to it.
The screws will be replaced. It will be
countersunk screws with a lid in brass.
Here it will be brass tiles.
-You have an eye for details.
That's the fun bit.
That's the icing on the cake.
-That's what makes the difference.
I think it can be good...
I hope.
-Here you started sketching on the rims.
Yes.
I want it to look a bit different than the original rims.
That is an original rim.
I don't want the spinners so I have too
shortened this cover and made it tougher.
I am thinking about using
brass in this pattern.
The cover I have been thinking about
engraves Chevrolet in brass.
The brass will be creased.
Same as I have done with the steering wheel.
It becomes like spokes that I should have on the rims as well.
I'll test on a rim and I'll see what it looks like.
I haven't decided yet.
I'm unsure if it fits but we'll see.
-You do not know until you have tested.
Right.
The rim whould get a personal touch.
We have to wait and see.
-Interesting, It'll be great to see when it's done.
-I suppose you want to continue to work?
Yes.
Okey, see ya!
Bye.
Watch the entire project.
More episodes are available.
Thanks for watching!
Please subscribe for new episodes.