I drink way too much coffee. Thanks that is good.
Must celebrate the start -up with coffee and good cake.
After that maybe there will be funeral beer instead.
Hello! Hi, is it party?
It was like damn!
Well, it's Easter soon.
Well I know ... hahahaha!
-Now the motor is mounted. Yes.
All ignition cables are drawn and vacuum for the ignition and electricity ..
... and even the oil pressure. It may be good to know when starting the engine.
Most of it is connected and clear.
The cooling is also connected so you can see that it works.
So it does not go hot or any leakage.
It always leaks in some hose clamp.
It just should be to turn the key now and we'll see if it works.
You never know but it will be exciting. -Yes, very!
I am preparing the main power switch.
I am Anders and brother of Sven.
I try to help as best it goes into the last.
He has a little stressful ... hehehe.
He still has a lot and still do.
-What is your task today? It will be to help him with small things.
Then he gets to polish and polish what he is good at.
It's a switch.
There are 2 ink here and here the cables are switched on.
And screws ate with them hear the screws. Then you stop in this ...
So it sits there ... when you turn it out.
And when you put this together.
When you turn on it, it goes down so it becomes contact.
One of these grounded in the body instead of going to the other Poland and now it is fixed.
-Do you think the car will start? Yes it will go well.
He is good at this Sven. It will go well.
It is certainly something that needs to be fixed, but it will go well.
Tjena, welcome! Good today's!
Here are the guys who have balanced the entire engine package.
Crankshafts, drove yes the rub ...
Now we see if it works.
-Had you managed to do this yourself? I probably hadn't been able to.
It probably takes some letters to cope with it.
-Do you have any vehicles yourself? Well I have some mustangs standing.
-So you are Ford guy then? This cheva. Well that's why I have my hands in my pocket.
-Hahahaha!
It scratches a little ...
-Are you nervous? Well I'm so used to ... hahaha.
Don't know how many cars I have built ... It is probably 12-14.
Sometimes it goes and sometimes not. I think it will go well.
I'm not like American ...
... when they stand and scratch their heads as it shoots and throws fire out of the carburetors.
They cannot understand what is wrong. And then they discover that the distributor is wrong.
That kind of thing is you checked before?
And this I have checked several times so it should work.
-It will be very exciting. Yes.
-And lots of friends are here. Yes the rumor spreads quickly.
And then it's something new. No one has heard such an engine before.
It's a little exciting and will be fun.
We'll see how it goes.
Yes exactly...
The small computers to the cooling system. -A fan or?
No, it's the water pumps. They go for a while and feel.
What do you think, will it start?
It will probably start but with some problems maybe but ...
... goes it does.
Should I start?
It does not get fuel.
I have screwed up the idle on both.
To get some flow. Then fuel goes so it gets sucked all the time.
Otherwise, it can be difficult for the other carburetors to get gasoline when they are so long.
-As it gasoline? Well, I have to have a choke on it.
It gets gasoline but not enough.
Does it work now? YEA !!!
Sven can you open the door? So we get some air.
We may need it.
Finally!
-Are you happy? Now I'm happy.
It was good ride in the engine when it got hot.
Ah but it needs to be run in before piston rings and everything has settled.
It is noticeable that it leaks a little.
Now it will work. Now it is just driving on so you get ready for Elmia.
There is only a little polishing left.
"A LITTLE!" Hahaha!!
All the mocks ...
I think the carburetors are tight. Usually leak a little otherwise.
I have to start it again.
At least one more time.
Now you don't need a choke? We'll see if it's easy.
Where.
A ray straight out here. Well there.
Oh phase. I try to tighten this.
Well it is from there.
Yes that was why ... but it must leak more.
-How has it been? Well it has gone well I think.
-What was it that was first strolling? I have to have choke.
The car needs so much fuel when it is cold.
And then...
... I'll probably put in a cupboard.
The ax pump is a little too small.
So I have to put it there.
What it is leaking ...
There Sven.
Up somewhere. That's that welding.
Well there. There it leaks.
When I pressed my finger, water came.
When I pressed my finger, the welding split.
It's fun to be able to help a little ... hehehe.
Then there will be a back job there.
-What do you give for the first start? The experts have to comment on this.
To be Chevrolet it was pretty good.
Hahahaha!
What grades do you give an 8a? Yes somewhere there.
Always exciting. Absolutely superb.
Yes it was something new. Yes with such simple means.
You have witnessed as no one else has seen.
I haven't seen any straight 12A.
Definitely no one with offset ignition.
-Can he approve then? Oh.
With praise!
Then we come to the look but there it is the taste like the back.
It was probably a sense that I would have a crane here.
If something would happen along the way. Yes then you become standing.
This system holds quite a lot. How many cans were I filled up?
Three large glycols as much water plus two 5 liter cans.
If you want to pick up water in a stream, you can run many times.
-What do you give Sven for points? An 8a or 9a almost.
A little water leakage but clearly approved. I get to agree with a 9a.
It's a cranky creation this, huh? Clearly different but absolutely wonderful.
-What job he has done. Great!
And the innovation.
Just getting the idea to build the car in this way.
He is good Sven.
-No had fixed with the engine, huh? Jajemän we have balanced both.
Adjusted and mixed a little so it should go soft and nice. And it obviously did.
We have balanced with the cardan.
It is quite important.
-What do you give for points to yourself?
If 10 points are perfect then it's almost a 9a.
You can expect a little leakage.
That I must have choke ... yes you could have thought of it.
Other I think the engine went well. And then the engine is not yet run.
I am satisfied, really satisfied. It will be fun to test drive then.
-So this was the thing to fix? Yep, this is the water leakage.
Are you doing it or can you blame someone?
That's myself. It is a very own construction.
Unfortunately, I can't blame anyone else.
There in this welding. I get to weld all the way and add support.
There will probably be some break on this but then it will work.
I get to print it before I put it again.
-But it was the only thing. Well, you have to be happy about that.
-And a little stroll with the carburetor. I get to put a choke and a cable.
It's a pretty small thing really.
And your friends give you high ratings. Yes it is always nice.
I hope to finish with the grinding tonight. Then only the polishing is left.
A little fire to taillights. The idea and interior should be mounted.
I have one and a half weeks on me.
And the grill is going there ..
-Does it start to get stressful now? Well it has been for six months.
Now it feels to go in the right direction.
I have to start polishing now.
If you polish, we will be visible in the future.
Have it for so long! See you!