Jeeeesus, what a moped!!
Motornörd =  Engine geek literally
but petrolhead is probably more correct.
STANDARD IS FOR OLD BASTARDS
-Hello!
Hi.
-How are you?
I'm fine.
My name is Mats Ohlsson.
Hi Mats my name is Douglas
-I understand that you like mopeds?
Yes, that is my passion.
-What is this?
I have a son.
He is often in the garage here with me.
Has tearing apart and build things.
-I love old mopeds
and here were many.
Yes it is ... half of them I own anyway.
-Which one would you want to show first?
This one I like the most.
It's a Zundapp.
Zundapp and drag racing are my passion.
-Drag racing with mopeds?
There are competitions around the country
and a National Championchip is included.
-Why did begin with drag racing?
I've been a drag racing mechanic
when I was younger, in the ProMod class.
I have also with been involved
around snowmobile drag racing.
I've always liked drag racing.
-Let's see what you got.
What are you competing with?
We can start with the veteran class.
Then you can have a moped like this.
Sure you can have a nicer one but I
have chosen it to look a worn...
-Like a rat rod?
Yes.
Mechanically, it is in top condition.
Brakes and bearings are new.
It is in a very good condition
even if it doesn't look like it.
-70's
No all mopeds I got are from 1966.
Sport Combinette 1966.
So 1966 is the year...?
Yes for now...
Well, I got some newer mopeds as well.
The mopeds that stand here are from 1966.
This is a 1966 Zundapp Sport Combinette
moped for veteran class 70cc.
There are veteran class 50, 70 and 90.
-Is the number for CC?
Then you can modify to 52cc, 72cc or
92cc and that is the maximum limit.
This one has a 66cc with a
superterm athena cylinder.
Standard engine and has not
maximum cylinder volume.
It could be stroked up to 72cc.
-What does it cost?
Is it expensive?
Both yes and no.
It's a cheap sport to be a motorsport.
Motorsport costs money
but this is cheap.
I crashed an engine a week ago.
The engine block cracked and the gearbox...
It cost 2500 SEK (250 USD) to fix.
-Oh!
A few gears and shafts and then it works.
A car engine that breaks can cost
around 75.000kr (7500 USD) to fix.
Absolutely!
Or more.
This one I bought far in
the forest a few miles away.
The only thing I couldn't fix was the petrol tank.
It was so rusty, I now use a petrol tank inside the tank.
-A tank in the tank?
Aha!
-It couldn't fix it.
There is a smaller petrol tank inside.
Aha!
Only to keep "the look".
-What is this?
It's flocked.
It was very popular in the 70's.
I've seen it's popular today as well.
Yes it may have come back.
Flocked car dashboards,
stereo stuff etc.
-The seat didn't look comfortable.
No, but it should look like this.
It can't look too "good".
-But what is it?
I first drove with the original seat.
When I was carrying the moped on a trailer
to Lycksele for a competition...
...then it started to rain.
I had to pull on a plastic bag over the seat.
So I wouldn't get wet when competing.
The moped is mapped.
15.7 hp on the rear wheel.
-15 hp!?
Yepp, 15.7 and earlier it had 15.4 hp.
I think it has more power now
since it runs better.
It runs well and revvs...
The last race I drove I had to change the sprocket.
It revved 14,500 when I drove over the finish line.
Then I had to add a bigger sprocket.
-How fast is it?
I have driven 102-103 km/h at best. (60 mph)
-You're joking!?
-On a moped??
10.3 seconds.
-Do you drive 200 meters?
Yes, 200 meters with stationary start.
-How many gears do you have?
This one has four.
3-4 years ago I had a 3 speed gearbox.
It was such a big step between 2nd and 3rd gear.
It was not suitable for drag racing.
Especially if you want to perform.
What I remembered from when I was young.
I didn't have a Zundapp myself but...
..the shift lever had a very long stroke.
Yepp, you hit your knee in the elbow.
That is why we as competitors have gear stops.
-Gear stops?
I never miss a gear with this.
It rarely happens and works well.
It takes time to adjust since it hard
to change gear when driving slowly.
When you drive fast it's much easier.
-Then we take the next moped.
Which one do you want to show me now?
We can take this one.
This one is newly build.
It is also a veteran 70cc
the same class as the other one.
In veteran class 70cc you can also
race with a liquid cooled engine.
This one has a stage 6 cylinder from Minarelli.
It is also stroked.
If I stroke it with Zundapp
parts I get more than 72cc.
Stroked to 39.7 and reeds feding
directly in to the crancase.
I broke this engine ealier this
year but now it's up and running again.
-This one also have a gear stop.
Yes I have it on all mopeds.
This one have not been proper adjusted yet.
Hopefully I can do it next season.
-When you compete, do you use several mopeds?
Last race I had 3 mopeds with
me but that was too much.
It becomes more quantity than quality.
I don't have time to give all mopeds
love they need between the runs.
One or two is recommended.
How much adjustments it is vs driving?
Hmm ... change sprocket and nozzles...
..the rusty I've been driving for years
and I hardly do anything with it.
Last race I change the sprocket
and that was probably the only thing.
This requires ignition adjustment, nozzle...
...there are so many adjustments left to do.
It can take 10 hours of driving
before I get 90% of its capacity.
The rusty is probably at 100% of its capacity.
It can hardly run any faster with it.
It is difficult.
But there is a lot left to do.
This one should go faster than that
rusty but it doesn't.
It is still a long way to go.
-Is it still in a run-in period?
Yes, very much left to adjust.
-The petrol tank looks a different?
Yes it is older.
I think this one is better looking.
-How much older is it?
From 1964 or 1965.
The "pear" tank is much nicer than the rusty one.
-Well both looks fine.
I can see another thing.
If you straighten the handlebar.
-The handlebar Isn't that wide.
It's just a bike handlebar.
There were many buttons to be a moped.
Yes...
Here is the water pump.
Temp gauge.
And the electric fan.
-No speedometer?
Nope.
Only temperature gauges.
And a kill switch.
It's needed for drag racing.
I run with HPI ignition system so I
can choose between 2 ignition curves quickly.
What a job!
The tires look the same as my motorcykle.
Continental similar to motorcykle tires.
Does it need some upgraded brakes?
No, but it must work.
Often you have a long distance to slow down.
Some tracks it may be short distances.
Often it is enough to release the throttle.
But it is important that they work
if anything should happen.
We also have a third moped
but it looks a little different.
This is the next class, ProMod.
-ProMod!?
Yes it sounds violent.
ProMod is available in 50, 70 and 100cc.
ProMod 100 is a impressive class
and they drive really fast.
In ProMod you can have modern engines.
For example, AM6 and Derby engines.
And in this class there are Scooters included
with variator operation and they very quick.
When a Scooter is fully adjusted it is full
throttle since they have automatic gearbox.
I have chosen to run a Zundapp
engine on this one as well.
-What does a modern engine mean?
Yes you can have 6 gears.
Most engine are reed-fed as standard.
These are great engines and esy to work with.
This is a little more complicated.
-But you stick to Zundapp?
It would be ridiculous to put
an AM6 engine on this one.
Then I would rather be further down the results list.
This is a ProMod 50, ie 50cc.
The rusty is 66cc in the veteran 70 class.
This one is pretty much 70cc in the same class.
And this ProMod 50 and it is about 50cc.
It is also stroked down to 39.7
to keep the cubic boundary.
-This one has wheelie bars.
Yes but I haven't used it yet...
...since it's not fully adjusted yet
so i have no need yet.
But when everything works, I will need it.
The other mopeds i have could flip over
since the wheelbase it is too short.
I have to be very careful at the start.
60 feet I drive at 2.2 seconds at best.
When this is optimized it is under 2 seconds
and then the wheelie bar is needed otherwise it will not work.
I understand!
This moped is much longer.
It is a custom built frame
which is extended around 12-13 cm.
And the parts are extended about 5 cm.
So it is about 20 cm longer than a standard moped.
I've seen 3 different things.
The rusty has the handlebar bent forward.
Yes it is to get the center of gravity forward
and it should be easier to get a great start.
-And you've turned the handlebar forward.
Yepp.
Here the handlebars are in the right place but are straight.
It is straight and a little more weight
on the rear tire but it works.
And this moped has the handlebars far down.
Yes has moved down the handlebars on the front fork.
To be able to hang as far forward as possible.
The entire moped is build in fiberglass.
We have made plugs from a moped.
-The Petrol tank as well?
The tank is made of fiberglass.
Behind is my trump card.
Several people have it in ProMod.
It's fed with nitrous oxide.
-Nooo.
-Hahaha!
This is how it looks like.
-What a moped!
When did you started to building this moped?
I've probably 1.5 years ago.
Me and a friend named Magnus Lindelöv
has helped me a lot.
We have built this moped.
He lives nearby so we have garage nights
with a beer and fixes with the mopeds.
It sounds great.
-How many races are there?
There are 4 national competitions.
Geographically it has been Lycksele...
Hudiksvall....
Orsa and Ludvika and it has been different every year.
And this year it was a competition in Laxå.
That was arraged.
-How many are competing?
-We were quite many last and then we were 33st in total.
It's not a huge hobby, but we are
hope more people will join.
-I can imagine it's fun to watch.
Yes it is.
-Our mopeds have been ivated to some car races...
...they were impressed.
They thought the mopeds were cool.
We hope more people start competing.
-Which is the most fun to drive?
Right now it's the rusty one because it delivers.
It is tested to max.
The other two I have a lot of work left to do.
-Both?
Yes both.
Last year I tested the chassis with this engine.
Just to test the chassis and then
I used this engine with a Polini that I ported myself.
I drove 10.3 and 105-106 km / h with that engine.
I discovered that the chassis needed to be reinforced.
Trying to build as light as possible but...
...but that engine turned the whole chassis.
The chassis was too tight so I had to reinforce.
Last year I got the chassis to work.
This year I have used the real engine but...
...I've had problems with it.
It sounds strange and I have scraped some membrane
and blown radial seal when I run nitrous oxide.
Here's how...
-How many people use nitrous oxide on mopeds?
There are some ...
..there are also those who ride with nitro in ProMod.
And those who run methanol.
The rules are pretty much unlimited in ProMod.
-How's the spirit at the competitions?
It is very good.
- No fierce rivalry?
No, it's a nice level.
There is no prestige.
Everyone knows everyone and we have fun in the evenings.
-You don't reveal your secrets, do you?
Well, maybe it is, port times etc ..
-Do you do everything yourself?
I try to do everything myself.
I've built some exhaust pipe but
haven't got it really good.
Lately I have bought factory pipes
which I have modified.
Shortened and extended and made some other adjustments.
There are many pipes hanging in the roof.
Yes some different pipes that I have tried over the years.
-How long does a piston & cylinder last?
That one..
You're talking about the rusty, right?
I've been driving it for 2 years and
I only changed piston ring that's all.
Although it revvs so much so it works well.
-What is this?
It looks like...
Here I usually sit and port cylinders.
Isn't this what a jeweler usually uses?
No, it's from an old workshop.
It's a little small sometimes and
I haven't been able to port coil.
Now I have found this one and I think it is from the 60's.
It is old dental equipment.
Now I get down into the cylinders
so I can change the coil.
-Where do you find such old stuff?
Think it was at Tradera. (Ebay)
You had another scooter over here
is it also a Zundapp?
Yes it is a riding moped completely standard.
Just a daily driver.
-From what year?
1969 with the famous ...
...ball crushing petrol tank.
-HAHAHA!!!
You see why.
Don't want to run into anything with this.
The "famous" ball crushing petrol tank, love it!!
I was on a moped rally last year but
I wouldn't be welcome back if I don't upgrade the cylinder.
So that engine will be used instead.
-It can't be a standard moped?
No no...
...standard it's for old bastards.
-Any success when you compete?
Well, it have been some good results.
I have been placed 1st, 2nd & 3rd.
Sometimes you go out in the first round
like I did last weekend against a fast moped.
Then you are out.
It was against a teammate Jens Hägglund.
That bastard!
-Hahaha
I have no problem with that.
He was faster than me.
It is worse if you miss the start
or a gear and lose when you have a faster moped.
Then it does not feel good but you lose courage
a faster moped it is easier to take.
-Is there any moped we can start?
I can start any of them.
We could try the rusty one.
Do not think people understand how qiuck it is
especially when it looks the way it does.
Great, lets have a go.
-Is it comfortable to sit that one?
No!
I usually practice a lot of starts
and I get abrasions on the inside of the thighs.
It's not nice but everything for "the look".
14400 rpm.
It could revv more.
Now the moped it's cold so I don't to push it.
Damn!
What a moped.
15840 rpm, Jeeesus!
Is there any moped team in town?
Yes there is a club called RFR.
RFR?
Straight Forward Racing, a simple name.
There are some poeple in Ö-vik, Lycksele and Bjästa.
Good name!
Easy to remeber.
Hahaha!
It sounds like a motocross.
16320 rpm, that's totally crazy.
-This is like a motocross.
Looks are deceiving.
Hahaha, really!
It's totally crazy.
I didn't have time to turn the camera when you drove past.
I missed gears, since I'm not in race mode
and I have "racing Crocs" on my feet.
Normally changing gears works fine.
Not many people think it should go fast when you see it.
That's true.
It has a wonderful sound.
Yes it's the clutch housing.
That makes the sound buzzing.
What a machine!
-What should people do if you want to start competing?
There are two good pages on the internet and facebook.
Facebook: Swedish Moped Dragracing och
Lyckseletwostroke.se
There you can read and ask questions.
Read about past events.
Then I think you should start competing.
There are so many fast mopeds...
... that can be competed with.
It's really fun.
Many thanks for taking the time and to show us all your stuff.
It is really appreciated and it has given
me a new view on tuned mopeds.
See you later!
I hope to see this on other events.
Well, I have to go to southern parts of Sweden and attend to other races.
Many thanks!
See ya!
Support me on Patreon.
Patreon.com/motorkrantz
More episodes will be translated to
English in the near future.