-Good afternoon! Good afternoon.
-Where did the car go?
It has happened a bit since last time.
-The time I was here put it together but it doesn't do it anymore.
-The car is completely dismantled. Yes.
It is easy to mow with. I didn't need any help I could lift everything myself.
It went pretty fast.
I have built the car myself so I know what order it should be picked down.
What is left to pick down is front and rear wagon.
Then I start with the frame and weld the holes again, put and paint.
After that, the frame should be foiled.
-Who should do the foil? I do that myself.
I have ordered material.
-Have you done it before? Yes we often do it on the buses at work.
-Oh okay.
The only thing that is a problem is the corner here. The rest is quite simple.
The foil is easy to handle so it should probably work.
The engines are completely disassembled and the crankshafts are sent on balancing.
The cardan is also sent to the same guy.
I've got all the parts so I can pick up the engine when I get the crankshafts.
And the engine should be cleaned and painted.
-What is it for color? It becomes plain silver.
The color will not appear so it becomes something simple.
-Type Matt Silver? Yes.
-like the covers here? Yes exactly it will be the same.
I have also prepared the stainless steel exhaust system and suction.
What is located here should be sent on electrolyte polishing.
I don't really know how it goes. I think they dip it in some kind of acid.
So it corrodes all deposits from welding, etc.
Then some other liquid and last with current and then it becomes a glossy surface.
It will be exciting to see how it will be when it comes back.
-What do you have lying here? It should be elected gold.
It is controlling the p-end that is original from the 30s that I have sanded and made smooth.
Also these and some other small details.
And it gets gold.
The car has a fun shape when you look at this behind it looks like a boat.
It is the front of a 30-40s boat. Yes, haha.
That is why called Boat-tail.
Although it is big stuff, it is the heaviest frame.
I managed to carry it myself last time so I'll probably succeed this time.
Here we have the rear or luggage.
It is a skeleton made in 20x20 tubes that are clad in aluminum.
It does not weigh that much and is easy to lift.
But still stable.
The same goes for the torpedo. I can lift it myself.
Here we have the kick plates.
Passengers and driver's side.
It will not be polished. Everything on the inside will be brushed.
About this piece. Now I've only done a little bit.
You see a difference.
If you take a photo from above, it looks like a ...
... car building kit that you bought when you were little. When everything sat together in a map.
There will be a few square meters to be polished.
Here is...
... the floor itself.
To the luggage. And here's the turn over the wheels.
I have to back a little because the car is so terribly big.
Here is the fuel cap.
This one should also be polished. I don't polish it on the inside.
Just what is visible.
-What does aluminum have deficiencies compared to sheet metal?
Aluminum is done correctly so it does not rust.
If you make a mistake, it rusts more than regular sheet metal.
All electrical drawing & lamps should not be grounded.
This is drawn a special earth cable.
You drive power through the body.
With these iron beams you get the correction directly.
-Where does the frame come from? The frame comes from a Chevrolet truck from 1929.
Which has been a fire truck from the beginning with a water tank.
It was perfect.
I had just gone through what I needed to build my own frame.
With axis spacing and how long the frame rails would be.
I was about to order materials.
Then there was an advertisement on the Block on this chassis.
It was just to hit and pick up. -Wike flow!
-What have you done with the frame? Made some rust.
That section here ...
... was at the water tank and here it sat double plate.
It was upset so this part is changed.
I have done this reinforcement cross.
So that the frame becomes more rotated.
Now it is a mute frame when all rivets are welded.
There are no rivets left.
The attachments for the leaf suspension are original.
They sit on the outside which is good.
Often on passenger cars, the attachment sat in the middle or on the inside.
Its further out they sit so more stable, the car becomes good.
The rear axle is from a Camaro from 1977 or -78.
As I have redone the brackets on.
-Why just such a rear axle?
A regular GM rear axle that it is easy to get parts and right with width.
The front car is largely original with leaf suspension longitudinal.
I've got hold of the murders brakes from 1953. -hahaha!
It's Bolt On.
From 1929 until 1953, they have not changed anything.
What if it could be the same on today's cars?
I have changed so that the front car is above the leaf suspension instead of below.
It lowers the car almost 10 cm.
Right. It provides a smooth height front and rear.
This is an original beam that I have redone a bit.
I have raised the beam because the front carriage comes higher up so it does not hit when it springs.
And that it is welded instead of rivets.
Here I have some left to weld. I haven't accessed before.
Yes you have things to do? Yes, there are a few weeks left for Easter.
Surely it is two months left for Easter? Yes something like that.
I would have had anxiety if I knew it was only 2 months left and so much to do.
That's what pepper one. It is almost as fast to pick it up as apart.
When it is to be picked up, each part must be polished before.
I have gone through it 2-3 times before so there should be no problems.
-What are you grinding this one with? It is its own invention.
I have driven this in the English wheel and was not so huge ...
... it is quite roughly processed. There is a lot of structure in it.
I have leveled mostly with a hammer.
Here you need as you can see here ..
... it is a little uneven. Here it is finished.
Then I have taken the big machine that spins while being oscillates.
I have made an aluminum board that is stuck in Velcro.
The sandpaper is stuck in adhesive paper.
This is a sandpaper.
So I can drive with it.
It does not follow any contours and grinds completely flat.
The problem is that it gets very hopeful.
Then I spray on cold breeding and grind on.
It works well as a lubricant.
-How long takes this? I usually say a quarter 14 days ...
... it depends on how nice you are. Hahaha!
Haha, a quarter 14 days ...
This has taken ... This page is finely cut up here.
Here I have the polishing left.
Here it should be honed and then polishing on everything.
For this, it has been 10 hours. Oh.
And I have about 20 hours left.
So around 30 hours
It takes to grind and polish such a piece.
And that's pretty little. For the torpedo I started on Friday ...
... at 14:00 and was finished Sunday at 21:00.
Then I lasted for 13 hours on Saturday and 10 hours on Sunday.
It was a little more difficult because it is not smooth but more shaped.
I've built .... I think it's ...
... 10E Rodden that I build from scratch.
And also other cars so I know what it takes.
Previously, I worked as a injury repairman on buses.
There you could have jobs that took 700-800 hours.
Then you had to put everything in the right order.
Then you had to go through everything so it was completed within a reasonable time.
You have great benefit from this when you build yourself.
Being able to set up planning properly.
Anticipation.
I see many people starting to hold on ...
... with brakes or engine.
And then something is missing or that they do not know what they should do.
Then they go home and shit in it.
I don't know how to do it.
I always have 4-5 different items.
Which I can work with.
I'm not going to come here and think about what should I do tonight.
I'll have finished tasks.
So I want to take it easy and sit on a chair so there is such a type of job.
It should still be done later but then I can do it now instead.
You have great benefit from that. There are many friends to me who have been stuck.
Because they don't know what they should do. I'll take it another day ...
I will take it next week that will be month ago it will be standing.
You might have made a Swedish angels who go around and fix the last in the garage.
Hehehe ...
It is often so that you need a kick in the ass so you can move on.
Many times it can be the financial but there is much you can do that does not cost anything.
Which you can continue on if there is no money.
It is important to plan correctly so it goes.
When you are done with the car, should it be inspected before Elmia?
I'll try to inspect it before.
It is always fun to come to Elmia with a registered car.
I only have the old F sign.
Well, it was probably an a sign.
X!
X2686.
It would be nice with it is not certain that time is enough, but you never know.
There are no more things to be ordered or manufactured?
Well I have some orders from the USA, among other things, new distributors.
And some other small things. Other I should have everything.
It should not be anything. Wouldn't the benefits come ...
... I have used lying down but then I have to renovate them.
It would have been smooth with two new ones so I don't have to do that much.
I realized that you had no floor in the cab last.
No, I have made a template. Ah a woodwall, huh?
Yes this template fits both on the right and left side.
Easy to grind and cut out a new one. So I have the whole floor.
Will it be in sheet metal then or? No, it actually becomes such a 10 mm wooden board.
There will be good sound insulation. Plate is happy to be shameful.
Otherwise it is not so much more. A little putty and painting on the frame.
All that job I will do down here. It's not the weather to take a frame outdoors now.
It is better to stay here and do it yourself.
It should not be painted it will be brush painted.
The frame should be ground down so it becomes smooth and then foil.
Most of it will happen down here in the garage.
It will be cool to see. I'll have a return visit soon.
So we'll see how long you've come. See you!
We hear, Hello!