What you done?
After all, it was just tearing everything up.
I see it, but you would just fix a little neighbor.
Yes, it was probably the desire if you say.
But no.
Hello Hello!
Do you hear we were at Öland this summer.
Yes, very nice.
Check out Pers Sarolea where you had built.
You had some small fixes on yours.
Yes, it wasn't really like this I had imagined.
The fun here is that we would use this motorcycle as a reference
Before we went to Öland, so one would understand
What it was.
It was not intended that this should be a project.
No, but it was.
Yes, you see that it is still a motorcycle.
But it is a little bit picked.
After all, you had removed the lamp last.
Yes, I don't know.
Probably they have built this mound for them to have it as a pedistal
And just have something to look at because everything was resolved.
Every screw, nut.
I mean the connection and everything raged and.
Yes then i did not get the charge up and then i have been doing
And tried to get hold of a generator.
But this is this, a Miller generator.
Fairly common generator in England at BSA and Royal Enfield,
But they always had their switches in the engine block.
But Sarolea has her switch for the ignition then in the generator.
So that generator is pretty rare because it's just sarolea
that uses it.
So the only generator I could find.