Jeeesus!
Now you got something on camera.
Did you see where i put it?
Hahaha!
MotorNerd
Episode 59
One million KM (620.000 miles)
-Hey!
Hi.
-Douglas.
Viktor.
-How are you?
I'm fine.
-You have something odd to show me, right?
Well, it's just a regular Subaru.
-A regular Subaru?
-What is this?
It's a Subaru Outback from 1999.
-Okey..
With a 2.5 liter petrol engine.
-It's look a bit rough.
Well, it's an old car.
-What's special about it?
It has run more then 1 million km. (620.000 miles)
-WHAT!?
That's right.
-ONE million km!?
Yepp.
It's like new again.
The odometer starts over.
-For real, is the milage 1 million km?
Yes, and it has also been hit by a moose. (Elk)
-And crashed with a moose!
- I would just about to ask what is special
with this car and now i got the answer.
- I can see, the moose impact has to be here.
Exactly, the front and head slipped over
the bonnet and then on the roof.
The moose bent the roof here.
I'll tried to bended back again to
make the best of the situation.
I also changed the windshield.
-A new windshield and fixing the roof,
was that the only problem?
Well, then the moose spun around and slid off the roof.
And hit the side of the car.
Both windows were broken.
And destroyed the C-pillar.
-How did you manage the accident?
Not a scratch.
Not even shattered glass hit me.
-Why do you buy a car with a mileage higher than 1 million km?
It's fun.
The mileage was not 1 million km when I bought it.
It had only run 940.000 km
(580.000 miles) when I bought it.
Yes, ONLY 940.000 km...
Well, only...
It would been fun to drive it to 1 million km.
-How is it to own a really high mileage car?
What have gone wrong?
Well, I'll had to change the gearbox.
It run 980.000 km (600.000 miles)
until the gearbox died.
Besides that, it hasn't been much.
I have not changed the brakes on it yet.
I have only changed brake pads and
regular oil service every 10.000 km.
-What was the mileage after the first owner?
He drove 940.000 km.
-How many years did he own it?
He owned it for 6 years..
-He must have lived in the car.
Yes, hahaha!
He imported caravans and commuted between Sweden and Germany.
-What's the yearly mileage?
150,000 km a year, I think. (90.000 miles)
No, he manage to drive 150,666 km every year...
Hahaha!
As you said he has proberly lived in the car.
-What's the status on the paint?
The clear coat is struggling.
-Rust?
It's a bit everywhere.
-It looks okay since it a very high mileage car.
The paint on the bonnet is a bit faded,
it have been repainted a couple of times.
We can have a look a another odd thing.
The fuel cap, it has been refueled quite a few times.
Every time you pull out the handle
then it drops petrol here.
The petrol eats up the paint so it gets like this.
Now you can store things down here.
-It's not a sheet metal left.
Overall, if you count on inflation, we have calculated...
...that the fuel cost for this car is
about 1.5 million Swedish kroner. (135.000 EURO)
-Hahaha, for real?
Yepp.
With this car there has been a lot of
petrol flowed through the fuel hose.
-Here it says, 1 million km. (620.000 miles)
The previous owner reverse until he could feel
the coupling head to know where the caravan was.
-Did he reverse until he hit the coupling head?
Yepp, and the he pulled on the caravan.
-This is also a bit innovative.
Especially, when it's mounted straight on.
It's simple.
-Yes, beautiful design...
-How does it look on the inside?
It's in good condition.
Rear seat is like new.
Have nobody used it?
No, almost none.
The previous owner has used the car himself.
And I haven't used the rear seat at all.
The interior are spotless.
The steering wheel have seen better days.
It is falling apart.
The driver was probably left-handed.
-The previous owner does not seem to have had
any passenger either since the seat looks new.
Exactly, it is probably me who used the seat the most.
Here it says 999,999.
Yes, the odometer didn't turn back to 0.
I have driven another 10.000 km but
now I had to count it manually on the trip meter.
Each time it has exceeded 10.000 km
then I have written a note on a piece of paper.
-Is there any documentation?
The glove box barely close since it's so full.
Here is a lot of paper work.
It's almost all MOT records.
All receipts and all maintenance that is done with the car.
The past few years the MOT inspection
have gone well and it only have been minor problems.
However, the latest MOT inspection did not go so well.
Rusty thresholds which is too
close to load-bearing construction.
Headlights are in bad conditions.
A lamp that was loose, fog lights that were broken.
Parking brake didn't work properly.
Both springs in the front suspension is broken.
-What future plans do you have?
I'll donate the car to a friend
who have crashed his car.
He drives more or less around the world.
He has done so the latest 1.5 year.
Now this car becomes a good candidate to travel with instead.
Anyway, the car will be difficult to sell, hahaha!
It would be difficult to explain the mileage in an ad.
-Is it time to hand it over?
Yes it is.
The car will move to Holland.
-What must be done before you donate the car.
Replaced the timing belt and change a brake pipe.
After that he gets it.
I thought I saw him here somewhere..
-What a lovely project!
Yes.
We stand and are freezing to death.
It's January and he walks around with a hoodie.
-Let's see if it starts?
-It is Saturday so it may be a little tired.
No problem!
Next stop is Japan.
-How does it feel?
Sad but still very good at the same time.
It will be a crazy journey.
Something I never had time to do.
-A great story gets even better.
Yes that's true.
Now we will wait and see how it goes...
Motornörd = Engine geek literally
but petrolhead is probably more correct.
A playlist with all episodes with
English subtitles are created.
More episodes will be translated to
English in the near future.
Thanks for watching!
Please subscribe for new episodes.