playing classical piano is truly one of
the most rewarding activities one can
engage in
my name is Francisco and I'm a piano
teacher at Malmo Academy of Music
I teach my students how to interpret a
score and how to improve technically
and how to manage their performance on
stage
another important aspect of teaching is
to help the students find their own
artistic voice something I think is
important
to be able to interpret the great
Masters both living and dead of the vast
repertoire of classical piano
Music School
yet for
eign
thank you
foreign
[Music]
Master Class
my name is Julia Saxon and I study
classical piano at the Malmo Academy of
Music
and after my studies in London at the
Royal Academy of Music I decided to
apply to the diploma program here in
Malmo as I wanted to study with
Francisco
and
our class here in mama is quite small
but still very much International
and the school offers lots of practice
possibilities
as well as
great instruments
and
I feel like you're really given the help
and support you need in order to find
your own artistic identity as well as
explore exploring and learning new
repertoire and preparing for
competitions
um as well as meeting great guest
professors
and
as a diploma student here you get a
unique opportunity to perform as a
soloist with a professional Symphony
Orchestra which is just an amazing
opportunity for young musicians
[Music]
foreign
[Applause]
[Music]
Academy of Music