It was so fun to hear you play! Thanks!
Now we have an EDI session on the music college's website. Yes.
The question is, many ask the question, what is Edi?
So I think we want to long it directly to the camera here.
Edi is then electronic digital instruments
And Berkley in Boston was the first to use it.
Before we talked here at the Music College about the computer as the main instrument
and we were many who thought it is a bit unfortunate
Because the picture is that someone sits at a keyboard only.
But edi summarizes, one would not be able to say
that these are these three components, computer and software
Then there is the computer and everything we connect to it. YES!
What kind of software do you have?
I have used Ableton live as software
and then as midi controllers to control
What I have in Ableton so I have an Ableton Push 2,
A Novation Launchpad and a Midi cavity.
But then you also play on your Procussion Pad here?
Yes exactly. And I do not control that no midi information with
but then i use the sounds found in the rampade
Just as I use the sounds of a base.
And all the micks have you connected to your computer?
Yes exactly. I have a sound card that I have connected all the instruments into the computer.
When I look at Youtube and check people who are doing live looping
Then it is not so common for it to say this is edi
And the concept is quite new.
But if I understand it correctly you have in your degree project
Written about EDI.
Rumor has it that there are high schools
who have students who have edi as the main instrument
And have you discovered that too?
Yes exactly. In our study we have asked informants in the immediate area
About the Music School at the upper secondary level.
This is certainly a difficult question to answer.
But you have been doing this entire semester.
Do you have any conclusions, something that you have come up with at work?
Yes, but an interesting conclusion I think was
that all our informants thought edi made it easier
to authentic play some genres.
But it was not tied to those genre, but you could play many different ones.
So a very genre -wide instrument.
Yes, but that's my view.
After all, we have had quite a few years Edi at the School of Music
And it was a student here who had EDI as the main instrument on the cultural school educational education
As I had in subject methodology and then I was an administrator in practice.
That's my experience too.
There were a lot of genres that can be played and very much creative.
That I am very fond of here when I see you music
is that you have so much acoustic along with digital.
It's something I want the future educators
who attend training here and have edi as the main instrument
Must be the acoustic along with the digital.
And maybe as much dynamic as possible.
I'm not so fond of Step Programming
where you just press; It should be that battle and so the second sixteenth on the third in the pace so
Without it, it should preferably be played as you do.
There is groovy and there is dynamic.
I am very, very happy we got to hear your session
And proud that it is on the website.
Thanks! And now you graduate.
Good luck with everything happens!
Thanks!
Thanks so much! Thanks for us!