Welcome!
Here is the first of six programs from the Green Lund theater in Stockholm.
We hope you at home follow the series because it will be a lot of fun.
- Yes, most things will probably be pretty fun.
-60-70 percent is guaranteed fun.
Half - then we have not promised too much.
If it becomes a weakness in the program, do not change channel - it will be fun later.
When I listen to boring people I usually pretend they get loose beard
With these measurements there is always a risk that validity errors will occur
To ensure internal and external validity -
- So it is important to look back to get a safe hypothesis.
For those of you who want to read more about ...
- What is our ambition of the program?
- We show it with the flanellographer here.
First and foremost, we want to make a fun program.
And an honest program.
We do not belong to the ironic generation.
They are now 35 years old and have had children and so ...
But they are still ironic: I "love" my kids.
You can speculate on what happens to Henrik Schyffert at the old age home.
"Have you pooped again, Henrik?"
- "No."
I never liked the ironic of 90s.
I never took the irony.
People started giving me compliments and someone said: you ... good looking loafers!
You can divide the Swedish humor into two schools - Eastcoast and Westcoast.
The ironic generation belongs to the Eastcoast School: Andres Lokko -
- Christian Luuk, Henrik Schyffert, Fredrik Lindström and Claes Elfsberg.
The comic is based on a deep fear of being wrong or saying the wrong things.
You have to be "on".
If we leave the cold east coast we see here the warm Westcoast School:
Madness, Kurt Olsson, Stefan Ljungqvist -
- Laila Westersund and Ronny Jönsson.
Their comic is characterized by lack of self -criticism and poor judgment.
The review is weakened and culminates in Halland, the mecca of the Lyteskomiken.
Here, easily figures such as Stefan and Krister, shy Örjan and Augustina arise
There is a clear risk of ridiculous hats and glasses.
- Over to you!
Thanks.
- The program should be festive, a little tricky and, above all, fun.
But what is fun?
We asked 100 Swedes.
-Did we?
-I did it.
- When did you do it?
- Now this weekend.
- I went around and asked people.
- What did they answer, then?
20 percent answered with a counter -question - of the type:
Who are you?
What are you doing here?
How did you get into my house?
30 % became violent and let the fists speak.
- So the subject arouses strong emotions.
- You asked nothing else, Johan?
No, not about humor.
But: May I borrow the toilet?
Is your daughter sex mature?
We want to make a youthful and fast program -
- At the same time we use the satire as a weapon.
Most importantly: the humor bottoms out in seriousness!
This gives us the name of the program: Rä ... shrimp frozen.
I talked to Mary.
I'm not wise to her.
She is so self -sufficient!
I can't handle her.
She gets worse and worse.
The hard thing is that she thinks she is so good looking.
I do not think so.
Some probably think she looks good.
Can you see it?
Like today:
"Sure I'm fine in my hair?"
It looks too damn good!
She has put rubber cords on the sides, hip like happ
And then a tassel in the middle of the head!
You can't say she looks like an idiot ...
I said, "Oh, how nice you are! Oh, how nice!"
Actually, one should tell the truth.
She has no taste.
She mixes colors.
- Now she comes.
- Can I borrow the binoculars?
- You can ask Dad.
- It goes great.
- But be careful!
- Did you see what she was wearing?
My girlfriend is celebrating years tomorrow.
It is difficult to find anything to buy.
- A jewelry is never wrong.
- Isn't it sad?
It is important that it feels personal to her.
Clothes?
It's also boring.
It should be the right size, the right color and shape.
If you buy a gift card, she can choose for herself.
Is it nice to unlock her at a particular deal?
Cash is better.
Cash is great.
They have a concrete value.
It does not have flowers.
Then you say you are worth this.
The question is just how much you give ...
- You may probably give SEK 200.
-Do you think so?
Yes absolutely.
200, 150 ... How much does she fill?
- She turns 30. - You may probably give 200.
- It can be wrong.
She got it last.
- It will be the same gift two years in a row.
It's not that.
I had only a five hundred, so she had to withdraw money
It was raining outside.
The ATM was broken.
When she came up, I said:
Honey, it's your day.
Take the whole 500 -tag and you will owe me 300
- So we wrote a small promissory note.
-It's nice.
I give money to my girlfriend to show that I appreciate her.
If we had a hot night, I put a twenty on the pillow in the morning.
You can girls, Johan.
Hello.
I would eat for free here today.
-What do you mean?
- I would not have to pay.
-Who said that?
- He who owns the restaurant.
It is me, and I have nothing heard.
- I talked to Stefan ... Staffan ... - Bengt?
He can't decide that.
- No, his name was Bosse, Bertil ... - Albin?
- I talked to Albin today and ... - he is on vacation.
Ah, I just got a chance.
If so, it goes.
Very nice restaurant.
We were going to joke a little about rock music.
Hard rock music
David and I have a favorite band - hard rock quartet Kiss.
Here is a foreground figure - Gene Simmons.
Ace Frehley, electric guitar, Paul Stanley and Peter Criss, the drummer.
They are touring even though they are 60 years old.
- How to cope?
- They have loans and bills ...
And when Genes Fruga whines about the children's ski trip:
"Get the makeup! We'll take another turn."
The makeup, yes!
It is interesting.
Gene Simmons is the demon.
This guy is the space man, awesome makeup.
He here is the star.
But this guy is a cat!
Where was he at the make -up delivery?
This is how my little acid looks on masks.
How have they reasoned in the rehearsal room?
"I want to be the cat."
"Or squirrel, maybe, or mård ..."
Peter Criss jumped off the band and was replaced by Eric Carr who became a fox.
The constellation has changed over the years.
A. Frehley was replaced by Vinnie Vincent who had an Egyptian mark in the forehead
It went well for Peter Criss.
He released three solo discs:
"Out of Control", "Let Me Rock You" and "Cat Number One" -
- With height songs like the classic Blue Moon over Broadway.
It is the original set we love.
As late as 1999 ... - David!
Sorry.
Well, there are no real rock stars left.
Not in Sweden!
Only one maintains the rock myth with long hair and fireworks: E -type.
We actually have E -type here.
Everyone does not know that Dad to E -type -
- Is none other than the pogram leader in the world of science, Bo G Erikson.
How does it sound on their family dinners?
"Birka was excavated another 3 cm."
E - Type replies: "Coming Up, Coming Up ..."
It is as if Siwert Öholm would be the father of Leila K.
Sweden has had many export - successes: ABBA, Ace of Base, Cardigans
It is sensitive to launch bands.
In India I saw when Roxette was launched
But Roxette is the brand of India's most popular laxative.
So the record "Crash Boom Bang" did not sell so well.
Many bands do not come that far.
They are split.
Gigi hamilton-
–Tommy Ekman -
- And Christer Sandelin.
Once they were super trio style.
Now only bitterness and pain remains
- Of what was once a winning concept.
With songs like "Dover - Calais", "Want You" and "Fantasy" -
- If they have sung straight into the people of Sweden Sweden's heart.
Why was Style split?
In the beginning everything was perfect and just fine.
- Yes, great.
- It was good with everything then.
- We trusted each other to 100 %.
- Yes, to 100 %.
When you learn that someone carries a big, dark secret then ... then ...
- You are scared, that is.
- Yes, very scared.
The background to the brawl is a statement-
- As Gigi Hamilton did at the enriched Music Awards in Gothenburg.
I would like to tell you one thing to Christer and Tommy.
I'm negro.
Gigi was negro-
- Something she kept secret for Tommy and Christer for many years.
Yes, it came as a shock.
After all, we suspected that everything was not right ... Gigi ate a lot of fruit.
But that she would be negroes we could never imagine.
It was not possible to continue then.
It feels hard to talk about it.
You have not really realized that it is true.
If Gigi is Negro, you don't know who you can trust anymore.
Then Tommy can be Eskimo or Indian ...
In today's fast community, one must have a person to seek support from.
In the United States, it is popular to hire a so -called.
Life coach as support.
We have our own lifestyle consultant.
Hello, Henrik Elmér.
Thanks.
Welcome to the course "Meet life with Henrik".
We will learn to think positively and to meet life effectively.
Many courses claim that there are no right answers.
It's nonsense!
On a course in personal development, one should be able to present finished formulas.
Otherwise you are not serious.
A little later you will be able to order this course booklet.
Unfortunately, it has not yet come from the print shop.
You probably keep up anyway.
Look at the headline, so you see that I have mixed lower and upper case letters.
But it's not random.
The uppercase letters form the word "with", which is the key word in the course.
One should float with your surroundings - do not strive for.
Float with: Acquire!
Strive against: adversity!
It cannot hurt to sometimes float with
Bring beautiful hand against each spoon
I'll take an everyday example.
I'm single.
It may feel lonely, but then you should think positively.
I think I'm not single and that someone is waiting for me at home.
When I go home, I call my answering machine: I'm home soon.
I am very happy when someone has called.
I hear: I'm home soon.
I think: Then I can clean before I get home.
I also thought positively when I was lying and listening to the neighbors who loved
It is actually quite nice to be single, if you compare ...
Before, I was with Gunilla.
It was hard.
It was embarrassing to hear the neighbors when she lay next to me listening.
It was even more embarrassing when Gunilla's parents slept over in the living room -
- And the neighbors started.
"Now the parents think we are doing here."
So I screamed, "It's not us!"
Then heard from the living room: "Shut up! That's us."
Next time you can order the booklet.
- Dad, yesterday I saw a horse.
- Giant fun.
Did you pat it?
-Yes.
You know what?
It eats sugar.
- Well, that was the worst.
- I want to talk to mom.
-Wait!
- Maria is on the phone.
-Hello Maria!
What fun you call.
-Yes.
Yesterday I saw a horse.
- It eats sugar.
-How exiting.
Stefan, you can start.
We can look at this year's outcome in relation to last spring.
- January was fantastic!
- You would not have thought.
"Now they can't have money left?"
But they had, obviously.
- Do we have any overhead images?
- I have some fresh slides here.
It gets a little more clear when you see the glory in the picture.
I turn on the "respirator" right away.
- This shit doesn't work.
- Is the contact in?
It is in. There is something wrong with it.
Shit too!
- Stefan ... - but that's something ... oh!
-Hello.
- Yes, "the suspects" is a good movie.
I like this movie.
SEK 45.
Don't miss the surprise at the end!
The handicapped guy has found everything.
He lies throughout the movie.
Keyser Söze ... is not even there.
Welcome back!
On February 28, 1986, Sweden changed forever.
Then the greatest leader and the dream of a safe folk home were killed.
Shrimp frozen reviews the murder of Prime Minister Olof Palme.
It is said that all Swedes remember where they were when they were reached by the message.
- Daid, where were you?
- I was 14 years old then and lived in Lund.
- Do you what you did?
- I lay in bed in the boy's room and ...
Yes!
They say that everyone remembers exactly what they did.
Do you?
No.
Yes, I remember.
Can we move on?
-What then?
Did you lay and read?
- Can you release this now?
I had Affisher with Samantha Fox on the wall.
You lie there in bed ...
14 years!
Can we release it?
This event, and the unresolved murder, is like an open wound in the soul of the people.
- Daid!
- I am an ordinary guy, Johan.
Okay?
It was in puberty.
Can we release it?
Hans Holmér immediately started new in the unfortunate PKK track.
David!
That's enough!
You've had your hands on the blanket all your life ...
You had a loaded rifle in the trolleys and got a women's bike!
The year is thus 1986. The spouses Palme has seen the Mozart brothers at Grand.
They want to walk home and have no bodyguards with them.
At the intersection Sveavägen - Tunnelgatan, the murder takes place.
The killer disappears.
The next day Sweden wakes up with a jerk.
You fear a coup.
In a room in Lund, David Batra stains himself!
I thought we would reconstruct the process.
This is David's room.
The bed and nightstand table.
Here is Josefsson's underwear catalog -
- From spring and summer –85.
Here is Samantha Fox on the wall.
Here is David under his quilt.
Look, how happy he is!
David's mother is not as happy.
- "Why have you locked the door?"
- "Go, mom! Let me be!"
- "Stop, you ruin the spinal cord!"
He was so amazing!
He had been sitting in a minimal inflatable boat -
- Prompt Sigyn.
Isn't that cool?
Everyone has to get involved. We do not inherit the earth, we borrow it from our children ...
You have to say.
-Thank you and goodbye!
- It went well?
-Yes.
We learned something from the program.
-What have you learned?
- The palm murder arouses strong emotions.
The most beautiful man can give a woman is still cash.
If you get a slack wine over after dinner, you can freeze it like ice.
When you cook wine sauce, you take out the ice cream and do not have to open a bottle.
- But we didn't say that in the program.
- CHRISTER said it before the program.
- What do you bring with you from here?
- This sink.
- It is you who have taken it ... —Mitt has cracked.
Thanks and good bye!
SVT Program Sewing: Lisbet Olofsdotter