A first love meeting.
They will get married -
- But the future is not as light as they dream of.
We are heading into the time of the superpower.
Soon, small Sweden will become a powerful country in Europe.
Far from big politics, people are struggling in their ordinary lives.
They are the ones who will pay for the kings' successes on the battlefields.
And the price will be high.
This is the story of our country.
About the people and forces that shaped it-
- Endure from the ice age until our days.
This is the story of Sweden.
Gustav Vasa is dead.
His eldest son Erik will inherit the crown.
It is a kingdom in order Erik takes over.
Gustav Vasa's rule was stable.
Skåne then belongs to Denmark, while large parts of Finland are Swedish.
The cities are quite small.
We would probably perceive them as rural.
But Erik wants to compete and his kingdom with the royal houses in Europe.
There the kings have regent numbers, and Erik wants so too.
He turns to the history writing of his time.
Erik has XIV as his regent number.
He has been inspired by this high number -
- Of Johannes Magnus's historical work about the kings in Svea and Göta Land.
With a high number Erik wants to show that his kingdom -
- Has a longer and more honorable story than it has.
Admittedly, several Swedish kings have been named Erik before Erik XIV -
- But not so many.
For the coronation, Erik XIV does not want his father's old royal crown.
He lets make a new, exclusive crown.
The crown was a so -called closed crown that went together in the middle.
An imperial crown, and something completely new in both Sweden and the Nordic countries.
For his coronation, Erik also allows a spiral.
An Apple.
And a national key.
The National Regalia has remained our national regalies right up to our time.
This was really a little ahead of the real superpower time.
It still shows Sweden as a new type of kingdom -
- As can compare themselves with other countries in Europe.
No one probably guesses that Sweden will be a great power in Europe.
But Erik XIV takes the first step in that direction.
During his first year as king, Erik sends troops to Reval-
- What today is Tallinn.
Reval then becomes Swedish.
It is an bloodless deal.
Reval asks Sweden for help against Russia.
Erik accepts to become their protector.
It is the prelude to the expansion of the Great Power -
- Even if it was delayed before it started seriously.
Erik's time in power becomes difficult.
He has inherited the crown, but his brothers are not satisfied.
A power struggle between the Vasa sons Erik, Johan and Karl begin.
When Erik has been king for seven years–
- His brothers Johan and Karl make a coup.
He is thrown into jail.
Eventually he dies in his captivity.
Johan takes over the throne after Erik, and calls himself Johan III.
He is married to Katarina Jagellonica, a Polish princess, now queen.
During Johan's time as King, he conquers Ingermanland.
It will make Sweden even bigger.
Another of Gustav Vasa's sons ensures that Sweden is growing inland.
Duke Karl has been given more or less free hands within his duke.
Karl exploits this, and builds up and makes the Duchy strong.
He builds a state in the state.
The duke reaches from Södermanland, to Närke, into Värmland.
Karl thinks that tax revenue is fundamental.
He wants to get more people into the Duchy.
He gets people from Finland, where there have been quite difficult times.
They get good agricultural land and opportunities in the duke.
They are called forest fins.
They break land and populate forests in Sweden.
They are from Savolax in eastern Finland and are experts in burning.
The ash becomes nutritious and perfect to grow in.
The burning requires a lot of forest, so they populate large wilderness areas.
It can be said that Sweden is now growing within the country's borders.
From the 1570s, a period of movements and colonization-begins
- In the then Swedish Empire.
It is forest fins that move over to the Swedish side of the kingdom -
- To what came to be called Finnmarker and Finnish forests.
After cutting down the trees and burning up the rice -
- In the sister of the sweat, you are sparse in the hot ashes.
Several years have time to go before the harvest comes with the sweat mill.
But when it comes, it's a message.
Each grain you sow, can give a hundred new grains back.
The sweat also has a higher nutritional content than regular rye.
The porridge they eat is a forest Finnish porridge called motti.
It is a food tradition that has still lived today.
The forest finds come in waves, until the mid-17th century.
They populate large parts of the Swedish forests -
- And gives names to many places that still remain.
Karl is successful and a very powerful man in the late 16th century.
He is also a convinced Protestant and wants to remove all Catholic customs.
Someone who helps him with it is the new archbishop:
The very strict Ångermanlänningen Abraham Angermannus.
They both believe that the hard times of harvests that hit the wrong -
- Dreks on the sins of the people, and that the Swedes are not good Protestants.
So Angermannus is commissioned to investigate how the people take care of themselves.
Duke Karl gives Angermannus authority to visit people out in the parishes -
- So they become better Christian subjects of Protestant doctrine.
You want to get rid of the old Catholic customs, which still live in the villages.
The Archbishop is harsh, and issues severe punishment for sinners he meets.
Often it is about immorality.
The problem is how the people live.
It is a terrible immorality that they go to bed as unmarried.
It belongs to ancient Catholic tradition:
That you could go to bed as engaged.
The Protestants wanted to get rid of it.
It was wrong, sinful, and teased God.
One of those convicted is the boy Lasse in Örtomta, Östergötland.
He has made three women pregnant and promised all three marriage.
Angermannus punishment becomes harsh.
Lasse is convicted of hor.
The penalty will be 39 strokes with the rice.
Lasse in Herb Castle is just one example.
Many are judged in this way.
Angermannus thus wanted to punish hard before God -
- The people who had then committed a crime against the law.
Lasse's punishment was probably awfully difficult to suffer.
There were no death penalties.
It would be sarious, torment, send a signal.
They would not die.
After the punishment, Angermannus forces the sinner to get married.
The boy Lasse is sentenced to marry the first woman he made pregnant.
They are inserted into marriage.
That's what Angermannus wants - to safeguard marriage.
If they have committed these sins, it should be corrected.
But Angermannus must not last for so long.
His inspections arouse the anger of the people.
Duke Karl will have to stop him.
Over time, Karl becomes so powerful that he takes power over Sweden.
He takes the royal crown with force from his Catholic nephew Sigismund -
- He secures power with terror, and becomes King Karl IX.
He is king for seven years, before he dies and leaves behind the crown and three war -
- To his son Gustav II Adolf.
But Gustav Adolf is a teenager and needs help to control Sweden.
And he gets help - by Axel Oxenstierna.
Axel Oxenstierna is probably the official -
- As has the most power for the longest time in Sweden's history.
He sat as Chancellor for 42 years.
Until he resigns with death.
Many have called Axel Oxenstierna Sweden's foremost statesman.
He is formed, with a strong sense of organization.
He leads Sweden towards becoming a modern state.
No easy task.
When Gustav II Adolf and Oxenstierna come to power, the money is over.
Government finances are abysmal and Sweden is at war.
A real Christian for the Swedes.
But the crises for something that changes the conditions for Sweden.
In order to pay debts to Denmark, new tax lengths are established.
It will be like nationwide census.
Everyone should be involved in paying.
When Gustav II Adolf and Oxenstierna now know how many people live in the country -
- It is easier to get an even and well -balanced tax flow.
And the money is of course used for the armies.
The young king and Axel Oxenstierna become a dynamic duo -
- As will make Sweden a military superpower.
The armies are sent at war against Russia, weakened by internal political struggles.
And it's going well.
The Swedes win the war.
In the peace agreement from 1617, the border Sweden - Russia is drawn further east.
Russia is excluded from the Baltic Sea.
It is Russia's temporary weakness that largely explains -
- Why Sweden could grow and become a great power around the Baltic Sea.
Although there are difficult times with war that cost a lot, everyday life goes on.
People dream about the future and they seek love.
The young people had their ways of meeting.
One custom that seems to have been practiced in the 17th century was the nightfall.
Night Freedom is a kind of dating, mainly in northern Sweden -
- There are young women and men to try to sleep next to each other.
There are guys of married age - 17, 18, 19 years.
They walk around the shock in the countryside and wake up girls of the same age.
The teenage daughters had their sleeping places in the outbuildings, in the ceiling, in the barns.
There they received the young guys.
The guys, they knocked on, and then maybe they sang a song -
- And noticed the woman that they wanted to split her bed during the night.
There are fixed frames around the nightfall.
The couple should be fully dressed and they must not touch each other.
We know that women got pregnant.
One has fallen in love -
- And could not resist each other, and things have happened.
For the most part, the rules were kept.
One reason why it survived.
After the nightfall, the young people can ask the parents if they are allowed to get married.
The parents were involved in this.
The young people in these areas can thus to some extent choose their own partner.
Sweden is deeply Christian at this time.
Wedding is a big event.
Before the marriage, they belonged to the youth team as a maid or boy.
When you were admitted to marriage, you became a wife or master -
- And you got a completely different social position in the local community.
Marriage has previously often based on agreements between families.
Sex before marriage is pretty okay, only there is a promise that is fulfilled.
The church wants it away.
Marriage should be a church matter, and sex must wait.
In order to emphasize the rules of not going to bed before marriage -
- Only fell the woman who was innocent at the wedding ceremony wearing the parish's bridal crown.
As a symbol of her honorability.
The bridal crowns could look different - beads, stones, gilded silver.
It was large and nice and expensive, and it was owned by the congregation.
However, if a woman is not a virgin, she may not carry the bridal crown.
The message is clear: the people in Sweden should be guided by church and state -
- and not by lusts.
In Stockholm, Axel Oxenstierna builds a new order for Sweden.
During the first 10-15 years -
-Is Gustav Adolf for a long time out in war outside the country -
- While the Oxenstierna is mostly at home -
–And is working on building up the management and the tax system -
- As is required for Sweden to be able to participate in the war -
–And send out 100,000 jacks -
–As a population of a little over a million people -
- During the 40 years that Oxenstierna is the Chancellor.
One of the things Axel Oxenstierna wants to get organized is the judiciary.
There was the problem that quite a lot was lawless country.
You did not really know which judgments and laws were applicable.
The national team was from the mid-1300s.
Several kings had tried to modernize it -
- But went into the wall with his attempts.
Then Oxenstierna does the beautiful -
- That instead he does the judicial system.
Instead of changing the laws, so he before Svea High Court -
- As can change judgments, and force the courts to redo trials.
In this way, you tighten up the judicial order.
Oxenstierna's reforms lay the foundation for today's courts -
- As now there is around the country.
Axel Oxenstierna is one of Sweden's most important statesmen of all time.
Before he dies, he lets this palace, near the castle in Stockholm.
He makes Stockholm a capital by changing the state administration.
In the past, everyone who worked for the king has followed him everywhere.
Oxenstierna decides that the administration stays in Stockholm -
- Wove where the king is.
Gustav II Adolf and Axel Oxenstierna wanted a Swedish capital -
- As could compete with other European countries.
Stockholm was made into a central city and was transformed into a modern metropolis.
But almost all Swedes live in the countryside in the early 17th century.
Sweden's population is now growing and is now approaching a million.
But even if many children are born, it is not risk -free.
/Tormented sound/
Births were one of the most risky elements in a woman's life.
For many women, childbirth also became the last thing they did.
/Child screams/
In general, no men were present in connection with births.
The women who assisted in the births, such as help women or earthmates -
- Had acquired their knowledge through practical experience.
Either that they had given birth to children -
- or that they had assisted in other births.
Fearing children not only meant a concern for the mother's life.
Every fifth child at this time does not survive their first year.
Everywhere in Sweden, in the smallest parish there is a church.
The church plays a very important role in the lives of Swedes.
The church is central at this time and the priesthood has great power.
It is a duty to go to church on Sundays -
“But it is also true that most people want to go to church.
In the churches you not only meet God.
There you also get to know everything important.
In the church you can call for everything -
- From lost cows to deserted soldiers.
The priest does not just preach.
He will also keep a book on the parish's population.
And he has to help when choosing the men who can become soldiers.
To get soldiers to the wars, you start printing jacks.
The Riksdag makes the decisions - perhaps that every tenth man should become a soldier.
The priest ensures to establish lengths over who is available.
So you simply take every tenth man, and it is not voluntary.
Some may see the army as an alternative to a poor life -
- Or even as an honorable duty.
But most people probably see it as a death sentence.
At the beginning of the war, you choose the way you can save.
The poor, those who are not inherited or who are generally troublesome.
They would rather choose the one who had a small homemaker, than a big one.
They wanted to keep tax revenue as high as possible.
It was tried to make sure that the person who had only one son or boy was spared.
You would rather take families with many sons or boys.
But the longer the wars went on, and the more soldiers who died -
- Desto was more difficult to keep on these principles.
Soon, they also printed house farmers, those who only had one boy or son.
More and more men disappeared to the war.
The view for those who were printed was very bad.
Many are brought out in the war, and very few return.
About 85 % of those who were discharged in the war never returned home.
And people knew about that.
There are those who try to escape the printouts.
You could escape, but you could, too, if you had the opportunity -
- Get out a large amount of money to buy a replacement.
Others hurt themselves ...
... to avoid the printing.
But most people do not escape.
They are sent to the army or fleet.
Many end up on one of the nun's ships.
Although Sweden at this time is a corner in the north -
- Oxenstierna and Gustav II Adolf have completely different ambitions for the country.
Gustav II Adolf builds up a strong fleet.
One of the ships is a real boast - Vaasa.
The vase ship is a floating exhibition item -
- For how Sweden wants to appear - powerful, warlike and dangerous.
At the top of Vasa's aft mirror, Gustav Adolf himself is depicted.
He holds out his arms, both holding them over and relying on -
- Elevated small figures that symbolize the Swedish people.
The message is clear:
Gustav Adolf is Sweden's rightful ruler, and has the people on his side.
Now it is empty on upper battery deck.
August 10, 1628 is full activity on board.
The crew has been brought to the day in honor with wives and children.
It is easy to imagine the excitement, enthusiasm, pride.
Around the ship, people are out in small boats to follow the maiden voyage.
But what they get to see is how throwing winds make the ship swing, more and more.
When water begins to rush in, the disaster is not held.
Vaasa drops after a journey of 1,300 m and about 30 people die.
The ship Vaasa then rests on the bottom for almost 333 years -
- Before it is rediscovered as an untouched treasure chest.
Vaasa is the world's best preserved 17th century ship.
It is a very lavish ship.
But it should be remembered that Vasa is not just built to fight.
The ship is an advertising player -
- This should show that Gustav Adolf is powerful, and that Sweden is rich.
But Vasa's sinking does not slow down the war plans.
New ships are being built, more soldiers are printed.
Just two years later, the king rises in Germany and interferes in the war.
Now Sweden will take a seat in the European arena.
Gustav II Adolf favored military solutions to political problems.
He meant that Sweden should be active, not let the enemy come in.
One should wage war in the field of enemy.
By this time, Sweden has become even greater.
Livland has been conquered from Poland-Liteuan.
For a few years, a coastal strip in Prussia will also be Swedish soil.
But now it is the 30-year war that applies, the great conflict of the 17th century.
Many European powers fought.
The conflict was about religion and politics, and was played on German soil.
Before Gustav II Adolf leaves Sweden -
- He farewell to his only child - Princess Kristina.
Like so many other children at this time, Kristina must never see her father.
Over 10,000 soldiers accompany Gustav II Adolf to Germany.
It is during the 17th century that Sweden becomes the land of the soldiers.
Before Sweden even entered the 30-year war, 50,000 soldiers have died-
- of a population of just under a million.
But most people do not die in battle.
Many of the newly printed end up in guard forces and garrisons.
There they encounter diseases, viruses, bacteria, which they have never met.
It is poor hygienic conditions and poor food.
It is more common to die in the war of diseases than to die in battle.
But not just soldiers die.
So do kings.
/Shooting and removing cries/
The Battle of Lützen in 1632 is perhaps Swedish history's most famous battle.
/Sounds of battles/
Gustav II Adolf was called "The Lion from the Nordic countries".
German parents scared their children with stories about him.
But the Swedish king's path came to end here.
/A horse froze/
The battle has been going on for an hour when the Swedish attack stops.
What is happening on the battlefield is that the Swedish side is pushed back.
In the pressed situation, the king decides to do something drastic.
He goes to counter -attacks ...
... but becomes isolated with a minor strength.
So left, in the middle of the gunpowder and the fog, the king - is located
- In the tip of Småland's rider, without a backup.
And the enemy is everywhere.
/A SHOT/
After two years of success in Germany, the victory train ends here.
On the battlefield at Lützen.
The lion from the Nordic countries is dead-
-And returns to Sweden from the 30-year war in a coffin.
Now Gustav II becomes Adolf's only child Kristina Queen in Sweden.
But she is only six years old, so Axel Oxenstierna takes the helm.
Sweden is governed by a guardianship with Axel Oxenstierna at the forefront.
He teaches both Kristina and cousin Karl Gustaf how to rule the country.
Something they will both benefit greatly in the future.
The wars do not end because the king is dead, on the contrary.
Sweden is at war almost the entire 17th century.
It costs huge sums.
The Treasury is incredibly strained almost all the time.
You look for opportunities to find resources.
Oxenstierna is starting to control trade in northern Sweden.
Several new cities are founded to be able to withdraw more tariffs.
You do everything to utilize resources in the country.
In Falun there is an important source of income.
The copper mine in Falun was a very large source of income for the Treasury.
The income from copper production was the basis for -
–That the Swedish Treasury could pay for the military apparatus -
- which was required for the conquests during the great power period.
The copper mine is Sweden's largest workplace in the 17th century.
During certain periods, 60 % of the world's copper production comes from Falun.
Swedish iron production is also important.
Walloon immigrants from southern Belgium to work with Swedish iron.
They were not very many.
About 400 families are expected.
The most famous Walloon is Louis De Geer.
He becomes the most successful industrial man of the Swedish great power.
He will play a role in Sweden's colonial history.
Now they want to increase Sweden's treasury by establishing colonies.
First, they try, without success, to create a colony in North America.
Louis de Geer instead draws attention to Africa -
–And the trade in gold, sugar and slaves.
First you test with a pilot study, examines the potential in West Africa.
It goes on to the Caribbean where you sell slaves with good advanced.
This leads to royal interest.
Queen Kristina approves that you form a Swedish Africa Company.
The Swedish Africa Company becomes an important economic player.
Here, on the Gold Coast in Ghana, you open a Swedish trade colony.
From the beginning the fort was built -
- For trade in gold, textiles and ivory.
But over time it began to be used to imprison slaves -
- Once they were shipped across the Atlantic.
In Sweden, slavery and slave trade have been banned for a long time.
But that does not apply here.
By extension, West Africa and all of Africa will be affected deeply -
-of the trading networks that Europeans form during the 17th century.
It breaks down local economics, and almost the entire social system of Africa.
How many slaves Swedish Africa Company deals with is uncertain.
It is usually said that these are about a thousand slaves.
Outline those you have on their fort in West Africa.
Internationally, Sweden is a small player, but after all a player.
One of the greatest meanings that the Swedish Africa Company has -
-Is to be involved in laying the foundation for the transatlantic slave trade -
-Which takes off properly during the 18th century.
The Swedes will not be long -lasting here.
After only 13 years, Sweden loses the colony in a war against Denmark.
This fort continues to be used for 150 years after the Swedes have left.
It is being rebuilt on several rounds, but parts of it still remain today.
When the transatlantic slave trade takes off and expands -
- This is deepened with the resources in the slave trade.
One exits lots of abuse, starvation, diseases -
- To be transported across the Atlantic.
A large proportion has passed away, many are labeled for life -
–And has entered a state of social death.
You are a property in someone else's ownership.
Up to 200 men were held in here at a time.
It is difficult to convey in the picture how crowded it is with 200 people here.
But that means 100 people in this part of the room.
It means 50 people here.
It means 25 people here.
This means that ten people need to fit on this surface.
Many who were imprisoned here already died before they had aboard the ships.
It was terrible scenes that took place.
And Sweden was involved in the foundation for it all.
That Sweden extends into the world to become economically stronger -
- There is no ordinary Swedes noticed.
On the contrary, life is hard.
Several years of misgrowth cause many to die.
At the same time as famine prevails in the country, Kristina will be crowned.
The throne she sits on when it happens is this - the silver throne.
The coronation took place in Stockholm, and not in Uppsala as traditionally.
Kristina wanted to be able to invite many foreign dignitaries -
- So they spread the word about this young queen who came to power.
When Kristina has become regent, the war ends -
-Between Sweden and Denmark-Norway through the peace at Brömsebro.
Shortly thereafter, the 30-year war ends.
This means that Sweden is getting bigger.
Jämtland, Härjedalen, Gotland and Ösel are conquered from Denmark-Norway-
- And Halland becomes Swedish for some time.
After the 30-year war, Sweden wins several land areas in Germany.
But Sweden not only grows territorially during Kristina's time.
She will mean a lot for the culture to grow and get more space.
The cultural expansion that started during Gustav II Adolf's time -
- Intensified during Kristina's time.
With this she puts Sweden on the cultural map in Europe.
Kristina is a trained dancer.
She is happy to practice the court ballet of the time in pieces where she is the star.
The court ballets were virtually public documents.
At one point Kristina dances in the role of Diana-
- The goddess of fun in Roman mythology.
This is to represent their decision not to marry.
Today, it is common to have a press conference.
But at that time Kristina chooses to dance her decision.
The National Council had complained to Queen Kristina that she should marry.
But she didn't want to.
Instead, she manages to maneuver so that her cousin Karl Gustav -
–Seses to the throne followers.
One of those dancing with Kristina is Karl Gustav.
He becomes the king of Sweden when Kristina suddenly announces -
- That she abdicates and resigns the crown, just four years after the coronation.
Kristina abdicates is a great scandal.
At this time you see royalty as raised, chosen by God.
So she goes against the fate that God has set out for her.
Even worse is that she, the daughter of the Protestants' great ruler - -
- Evices to convert to Catholicism - the death enemy.
Kristina shocks the Swedes.
Many people experience it as a betrayal.
Axel Oxenstierna helps Kristina, but does not come to the ceremony.
A short time later, he dies, 71 years old.
Now it is cousin Karl Gustav's turn to sit on the Swedish throne.
With him begins a new period of war.
War that draws on Sweden's map in a way that partly applies today.
Directly when Karl X Gustav comes to power, he begins to plan war.
Oxenstierna had tried to pursue a moderate foreign policy -
- Where Sweden would be just great, without provoking the major powers.
When he dies, Karl X Gustav strikes a bolder foreign policy -
- There he is not content with the Polish coast against the Baltic Sea -
- The way goes in and tries to conquer the whole of Poland.
But in the midst of ongoing war, Denmark explains war against Sweden.
Karl X Gustav decides for a drastic maneuver -
- That goes to history and changes the future of Denmark and Sweden.
He attacks Denmark from the south.
During the winter of 1658 he marches with his army into the country.
But in order to succeed, the army must cross the frozen Danish sound.
The trains over big and little belt were extremely risky companies.
If the ice were to hold, it would be a huge success.
But if it were to burst, then the Swedes would be bad.
Not even during the cold 17th century could you certainly march over.
It may have happened every tenth or fifteen years.
In the morning, Saturday, January 30, 1658–
- Rider Karl X Gustav out with his army over the ice.
The risky tactics succeed.
The Swedish army marches into Zealand.
As it approaches Copenhagen, the Danish king gives up -
- And closes peace in Roskilde.
Sweden has won.
Sweden gets Skåne, Blekinge, Halland, Bohuslän, Trondheim and Bornholm.
And you have defeated Denmark.
Denmark now does not have the upper hand in the Baltic Sea.
Denmark has lost one third of its territory -
- And very fertile agricultural land.
So it is a disaster for Denmark, and success for Swedish.
After the peace in Roskilde, Sweden has territories around the entire Baltic Sea.
The little kingdom that Erik XIV took over in 1560-
- Has become a European great power.
The expansion has taken place both within the country's borders and through conquests.
It went because they managed to create an effective state apparatus -
- As can utilize the country's resources for the needs of the armed forces.
But the political situation in Europe also comes into play.
That Sweden became a great power -
—Berded that the other major countries were so weakened -
- So there was a vacuum that Sweden could go into and fill in.
But it will change.
The neighbors will be strong again and more wars are coming.
War that needs new soldiers.
Before Sweden's time as a great power is the end -
—The the country goes through some of the worst times the Swedes have been with –-
- With witch hunts, starvation and plague.
And even more wars, which never seem to end.
It will get worse before it gets better.
Texting: Karina Berg Johansson Swedish Media text for SVT