How many?
Five?
Mardell we have to keep an eye on.
Last time he bluffed my money.
What then "better card"?!
Lena is at "conference".
Baths a whirlpool and laughs at the small savers ...
Okay, then we'll see you.
- Well, kids ... do you manage alone for a few hours?
- We have done this since we were born ... - I have loaded the pantry with food.
Two bananas and one package of Mariekex!
Alone in the house - what an adventure!
It is almost blackened!
- What should we do?
- Hopping in beds or going handrail ... - Now I'm on my way.
Gustav, are you sure you should not come along?
Someone must make sure it works here at home.
And play poker ... those people you have met every week for ten years!
- Because I like them!
- You never dare to try anything new.
I do!
This morning I tried that new toothpaste you bought.
It wasn't good!
It was foot ointment.
Don't worry about the kids.
I have arranged a babysitter.
- Mom, we're actually big now!
-Yes!
Surely it is an unnecessary expense?
- This babysitter works for free ... - tadaaa!
What do you say now?
- Close the door.
It pulls.
- Yeah, what I have longed for you!
- Is it you who is our babysitter?
- Lena told me you were alone.
Pontus would also go away, so it was a perfect opportunity to meet you!
You didn't check if we had other plans?
Be a little kind.
It's been four months since last.
- Three and a half, but okay.
- Sara, we get to talk more later.
- Did you think the phone number?
-No!
How nice!
Kiss!
Think, a whole weekend with you!
Tell!
It must have happened a lot!
- Yes, Dad has bought a new toaster.
- Yeah!
A brown.
There came visits from Stockholm that I have to spend time with.
Yes, it's a fucking city, but now it is!
Where are the kids?
I do not know.
Do they know where I am so they stay away ...
The food is ready!
Where do you usually sit?
-I'm sitting here.
-Here.
Obvious!
Father and daughter, mother and son ...
- You know that you are not our mom, huh?
-Obvious!
So ... be so good ...
-What's that?
- Sushi.
Pontus and I eat it evenly.
You can eat with your fingers.
Start, Gustav.
-No thanks.
- Gustav ...
You can play with the boys some other time.
How are things in Stockholm?
What do you usually do?
On weekends we go out and eat, go in some fun place ...
- It has opened a new nightclub!
-Thanks!
There are children in the room!
Yes, yes ... Stockholm is wonderful!
I'm glad I moved there.
What about Pontus, do you enjoy together?
I have something important to tell ...
-Oh no!
He has left you!
- You have left him and want to live here?
- He is sick and is to be operated?
- Pontus and I will have children.
- I want a family.
-Why?
- Getting a family is the meaning of life!
-Thanks!
That's why I wanted to be with you and feel the advantages and disadvantages.
The disadvantage is there.
-I understand.
We are guinea pigs.
- Don't see it so.
It's like buying a car.
You want to test drive first.
Welcome!
You are about to test drive the families' Rolls Royce!
Rather flat mop ...
You have to get your gifts!
Exciting things that are not here ...
Yes, some in school grow themselves.
- This is actually nice.
You are welcome.
-Thanks.
- Did you think about sushi?
- Think that raw fish can taste so good!
-What is this?
- The city house in winter garb.
Turn it.
Look!
It's snowing!
What invention, huh?
Now you understand how far before they are in Stockholm.
- This is to you, Lina.
- A t - shirt with the Globe on, maybe?
It actually is a little more fun.
- The nest tower ... - did you prefer to have the Globe?
No.
I become the most popular girl of the school ...
- To you ... - I don't get away.
Yes, yes ... underwear.
Björn Borg - Calunders.
"To my friend Gustav from ... Björn Borg."
What do you say now?
It's the finest gift I received!
- He stood and signed at NK ... - you may only have them when you turn years.
Children, listen carefully.
These should never be worn by any human being.
- They are over.
They are "Karim".
-What did you say?
It is Hebrew: elevated, forever inadvertent.
Only the Virgin Mary and these are.
- Do you mark any difference in here?
-Yes.
Your wedding photo is gone.
- Do you do she get angry?
- No, there are underwear there.
-It is one o'clock.
What should we do?
- I am going to Camilla.
I am here for such a short time.
Can't we do anything together, like a real family?
Tell!
What do you do in a real family?
You make excursions, you play games, big shops ...
- We go to the new shopping center!
- Yes, there we have never been!
Stop!
I've said that before:
We do not fall for simple cream tricks!
We have a well -sorted consumption here!
- Sorted?
They lack middle milk!
- Tyd, max.
No one is perfect.
-What then?
Do they not have middle milk?
- They said they had heard of it.
They have four floors.
Over 50 stores!
- And may they all burn in hell.
--Inomhus fountain and water slide!
They can have dancing penguins too!
They have that!
At one o'clock outside McDonald's.
I don't dance after the pipe of commercialism!
But look ... it is three o'clock it is the Banarne show.
- He will introduce some new coffee.
- The tracks?
The real one, from TV?
Yes.
They had everything!
I was actually a little set when you showed up this morning.
But I have to say that this struck most.
–Fast I pulled you away from the show?
- I had seen it three times.
Funny middle talk, good songs ... you were shrugged!
The banaries looked surprised when you hugged him.
I was moved.
He was probably too.
Look, how nice he wrote to me.
Then was it good that you came along?
"Copenhagen" wasn't so stupid, huh?
The "free city" should be hot!
See!
You had to take as many people you wanted.
Buttons?
Nonstop!
That stupid clown had a whole wheelbarrow full!
- They were for the children.
- kids now just have and ha!
- It's been a long time since I had so much fun.
- I knew you could change.
Now we help fix the dinner!
I start by peeling potatoes.
Start!
One, two, three ... I passed go!
Phone signal
Take it you, max.
Max Svensson.
I do not know.
- Pettersson wonders when you come.
- They should start playing the second round.
- I don't have time with his poker!
You heard, huh?
I know.
He is cheating in monopoly as well.
Bye.
Well ... what do you say?
Could there be any mom of me?
Absolutely!
- Your family becomes a happy family!
-Do you mean it?
You are safe, have fantasy ...
... and standing on Hamngatan!
Where did your talk about solidarity go?
I have almost a million.
Then you do not need solidarity.
The family plays games and little pans and has a cozy ...
Yes, we should play monopoly more often.
Here the intelligence determines.
Exactly.
Stupidest wins.
I have to ask one thing ...
You have been together as a family for almost fifteen years.
How do you cope?
What makes it work?
- We eat at different times.
- Sara is on something essential.
What do you think is the reason why we enjoy it so well?
I can say what I think.
It is enough that you let each other be different.
The Svensson family's three words of honor are:
Respect, community and enormous warmth.
You have mixed us up with others ...
I think the most important thing is -
- That we care about each other, listen ...
Silent, Lina ...
In the family you can try your thoughts and ideas without being convicted.
Like when you rebuilt the lawnmower into a kitchen fan?
Then you lined up!
Didn't say a word when mom wondered over grass in the ceiling.
- Because you safeguarded the family!
- And because you gave us half the salary.
What is most important?
Whatever I do, I know that mom and dad love me!
- What has tuned it?
-No.
But that's what she wants to hear.
But God ... it is almost eight o'clock.
Replace.
The disco will start soon.
- Disk?
Which disco?
- At the People's House.
It's live -band.
Wait now ... What's wrong with the Knatte disco?
- Just that the guys are enough here ... - I want to see the horror movie tonight.
- Yeah ... are you satisfied now?
–Wa?
All the community we just talked about you have just ruined!
Come on now!
Lina is fifteen years old.
She must be able to go to the People's House!
What did you do at that age when you would have fun?
- On the plot, you mean?
-It was nothing...
-I'm getting ready.
- Gustav ... Take it easy.
She can borrow my mobile phone.
Sure, yes ... money for taxi.
- Okay, then I'll see the movie!
- Just don't talk about anything for mom.
-What is it called?
- Devil's offspring, part 5.
- Was the movie scary?
- Sick, not very much.
- What are you doing in this bed?
- You probably don't want to lie here alone?
- Of such movies you just get scared!
- I am not afraid but panic.
Max, everything is on pretend.
The blood is ketchup and the monsters men with masks.
-Okay?
-Okay.
What is it now?
The devil has 6's tattooed in the hood.
Lie down and be quiet!
Or go into your room and read Kalle Duck.
Is it Lina?
Huh?
Ask them to lower the music!
What are you doing?
Dancing?
It's time for you to dance home!
It's getting late!
Take a taxi now.
Niklas Urban - now!
Bye.
What to do for the line?
After all, she is fifteen years ...
Yes, it is a difficult age, with the adult woman's need for confirmation -
- And the child's longing for security.
-Go to sleep.
-Okay.
Wake me up to Disney Day.
Good night.
Check in your wardrobe.
I thought I heard something hissing ...
- Gustav ... are you sleeping?
- No, I read.
- I've been lying.
- No danger, I always do.
- Pontus does not want to form a family at all.
–Wa?
I asked if he wanted children with me.
He said, "We'll see."
It certainly sounds like the devil himself ...
- You know that "we'll see" means no.
- You should hear a secret.
The worst men know is sudden demands - our instinct is to infect.
We want reflection time.
It is about not having to choose in the long run.
-How do you mean?
- If you reveal one, you miss something else.
If I stand and veil at a glass kiosk and choose a big stroke -
- Then I will be missing out on a good Nogger.
I would probably have taken an igloo.
Sara ... Give him time to vela -
- So it works out.
Do you know how we had children?
- You turned off the light, undressed you ... - when we talked about having children!
- I want a family like yours!
- You will get that.
Give him time.
- Can't you hurry at the Velland?
- No, then it only takes longer.
For two years Lena has asked me to dry under the bed - and look here!
- Day to go to bed.
- It was nice to talk to you.
Good night!
–Sara ... —MM?
- Wish out my bed.
-Oh...
Sorry.
Good night.
One two three four five.
This is how all our Sundays will look!
- Why did Sara go so early?
- She's going to talk to Pontus.
- I only have 2,000. - It's the fun thing about games.
Soon you are up again.
Hit with 6,000, your little rat!
Dad, don't say so!
Max, I'm sorry.
When I say rat, then I mean ... Bisam rat -
- Which looks like a cute little kangaroo.
- Do you try to say sorry?
- And improve your general education.
Hello!
God, what a weekend!
You really lost something.
We have discussed the depreciation of the bank's property portfolio ...
- How have you had it?
-Oh oh oh...
We have eaten sushi, visited the shopping city, I have hugged Banarne ...
- What is you say now?
- The tracks!
Trazan Apansson's friend!
- We have had great fun.
- Yes, Sara got up to you.
- Day for the next event!
- Purchase city?
Wrong speed!
Now you should experience excitement, joy, drama ...
We will play poker.
- Gustav ... you play every weekend.
- I, yes, but not you!
Nothing goes up to sitting in Pettersson's garage!
- We don't play poker.
- But they have a nice garage.
- Where is our wedding photo?
- I then explain.
SVT Program Settling Karin Esvik