Unbelievable.
Incredible.
Incredible!
- What is incredible?
- Did you know how many meters of gut we have?
Eight.
Unlike some others, I try to get education ...
In the past we did not have the same opportunities.
I was needed at home in the yard.
- In the yard?
- Yes ... in the apartment then.
At that time, the parents went before school.
- And you had failed in eight subjects!
- Who told it?
- Farmor tells it every Christmas.
- Then she gets to sit alone on the Christmas!
- Hi, Lina.
Are you coming?
- Here we knock before we go in!
Obvious.
Bye daddy.
So close to each other you don't have to go!
The sidewalk is wide!
Then he was here again, the little nasty.
Lina's boyfriend.
- Ge Marcus a chance.
- That guy has got his chances!
- Because he had to scrape our boat?
- He had done a good job, so ...
Do you get angry when Lina does not come along?
- It's the last chance to be together.
- Should you go to sea?
The children are getting big.
Then we have to sit there alone, we two.
Do not say so!
It takes a long time before they grow up.
No!
Max is fifteen years old.
Soon it is a car and your own apartment.
He is twelve.
We have to spend time with our children.
That's what we do!
We are going to Pettersson's cottage.
I am skeptical that Marcus is alone with rope.
Annika and Göran can keep an eye on them.
-Is it necessary?
- Well than you are worried.
Kiss.
Only one does not appear as a police officer ...
At
9.00 you go on the first pass.
Our car disappears.
What are you doing then?
Waiting a bit, and then checks that Lina is alone.
This is repeated every half hour.
22.30 we bed her down, lock and go home.
Don't listen to him now.
Just check that Lina is coming home well in advance.
- Can you have dinner with them on Saturday?
-Love to!
We were actually going to ask if we could look after them.
We think it's fun.
- Gustav said he can be violent.
- What did you say now, Gustav?
- The truth.
He fights on the weekends.
- He trains judo.
- It's a sport.
In sports you use ball.
Judo is about being kicked.
-No!
I was doing judo before.
-Congratulations!
Then you can fight out here.
- When you come home?
- Eight, if everything goes well.
- Why wouldn't it?
- Everything doesn't go as it should for you.
-Hello.
Does the wilderness nerve irritate you?
- Yes, I can hardly stand still.
- Is food there?
- Dad took the last one.
Eat properly now!
This weekend you should be tamped with nature!
- Do you always go to the mountains?
-Just me.
The bank has courses in Åre.
Wonderfully!
Slalom in the afternoon and very nice in the evenings.
In the mountains you should devote yourself to nature, not to hostile luxury courses!
Come on now, Gustav.
You are jealous!
At the post we have exciting courses, we too!
- Why didn't you tell it?
- News lectured the Director General.
He scolded you.
It was an interesting topic.
"Sharpen you, otherwise we will put down the office."
- I stand out again.
-Have fun!
Then I'll show you how to handle a throwing rod.
Think ... father and son in God's free nature.
-Hello!
-Who is it?
Sofia.
My girl.
We got together the day before yesterday.
Bye!
What is Max's doing?
We were going to the mountains.
I didn't know he met girls!
Do not say so.
It's just a friend who happens to be a girl.
You could expect Lina Fjantar around, but Max ...!
If he is going to go on Sofia's ballet, we cannot force him with us.
Nonsense!
It is the duty of the parents.
Yes, you might be right.
The kids grow faster than we think.
- We have to hit the fist in the table!
- Hit them to stop growing, right?
No.
But should you not ask what they feel, and such a hard time ...?
We have not had a real conversation with Max in several years.
Well, I scolded him out last yesterday.
- You don't want to penetrate.
- You can know something, so ...
You are right.
He must explain one and the other.
-It's half past twelve!
- Want to know how your son feels?
Yes.
About some years!
Max, I want you to come up.
So yes.
Try to stand on the legs.
Lina had broken the tennis trainer.
- That's what I thought.
Get her!
-Silent!
- We are curious.
How do you feel Sofie?
- She goes in the class next door.
There you see.
How did you meet?
Was it at some disco?
- No, she put the hook for me.
-How cozy!
- Can I go to bed?
- No, we're going to talk.
-Okay, talk on.
- There is a lot going on with you now.
You are faced with many new situations.
Dad and I are here whatever you want to ask about.
- Sure it is?
But Gustav!
- Do you want to ask me and dad about something?
-Yes.
May I lie down now?
- It's nice to lighten one's heart.
Okay.
Sofia is with children, and I'm going to start drugs.
Can I go?
Certainly.
We rent the cottage some weekend when the kids can come along.
No!
My God, we have our lives!
We have as much fun without them.
We can have great fun in the mountains, just the two of us.
–And Styrbjörn.
- The board of directors?
Pettersson's dog.
- What should we have it with?
- It's not that dangerous?
You don't know that ... what kind of race?
The veterinarians said they had never seen anything like it.
Good night!
- Are they sour because you don't go with?
-No.
Your father seems determined.
You are not used to someone sneaking on one all the time.
He is like that.
He just wants to check that you are okay.
- Yeah, Marcus.
Here you sit again ... - I know.
- But I haven't been sitting for so long ... - Little Sports Mirror ... Good bet.
Perfect balance between cartoon and regular sports elements.
Right?
- Yes, really.
- Marcus has religious tests tomorrow.
—Religion - so interesting.
- Mest a lot of invented stories.
They form the basis for how we live today.
Take Jesus' hike in the desert.
Jesus, Paul and ...
... Bellman and a German?
They had walked for 40 days, and had not eaten in a week.
Paul asked: Shouldn't we give up?
Then Jesus answered:
- No, the letters must come up.
- The letters?
We have that setting at the post today.
- Do you bare that Jesus was a postman?
-Yes.
One of the first.
Okay.
- Come on, we go up to my room.
Ola Hedenius, 13, is investing in becoming a hockey professional.
That's right, Ola!
- Look, what we can borrow!
- Freeze -dried food and down sleeping bag.
Thanks, but it is not necessary.
Lena and I intend to live on the conditions of nature.
If you get hungry, you kill an animal.
And if it gets cold ...?
I borrow sleeping bags!
- How does it feel to travel away alone?
- Giant.
It's been a long time since we traveled ourselves.
If something is missing, I can fix it.
Hello.
Come and sit down, honey.
The cottage seems to be very nice.
- Here is Hovsjöleden.
There is the cottage.
–Usch ... it looks like a snuff spot.
He had no pen.
Do you see how close the river we live!
How nice!
Imagine, where we grill our freshly caught fish!
Cozy!
Why haven't we done that like that before?
Yes ... In our age you have to affirm the adventure!
Hello, kids.
Dad and I sit and plan our weekend.
-Where are you going?
- Hovsjön.
My friend has a farm there.
- or a torpedo.
Here goes the river.
- Do you sing that you are not following?
No.
That is not a river.
It is a power line.
- It goes right at the house.
-No danger.
It goes high.
- Gustav, do you know where my anorak is?
- How so?
- You extinguished the fire with?
- It was just a grass fire.
Dad lit up on Olssons when he was going to show how to make a fire.
- Why didn't you tell it?
- There is that your anorak managed!
It is in the garage ... in the floor well.
Well, it was you.
Dad talked about it for several weeks!
What is he working on then?
- He is fire chief.
- Do you want to have buns?
One hundred?
- What is in the garage?
- A Volvo 242.
What is chained.
It's Styrbjörn.
He came this morning.
Surely he is cute?
I do not know.
He has a bag over his head!
- Yes, he can't stand certain things.
-What?
People, daylight ...
- Gustav!
-Yes.
Nämen ... I thought you had thrown the hippie jacket.
It's not a hippie jacket, it's a wilderness garment!
- What do you have there?
- Harpun.
- I have food with.
- Imagine if there is a wolf!
Then we run!
Was Petterson disappointed when we didn't take Styrbjörn?
-Yes.
He had intended to invite people home.
- Now it's just us.
- It's like a second honeymoon.
-Third.
I don't count your aunt's hospital.
We got a weekend in Nässjö.
And the hospital food is not so stupid.
- Hi, old man!
Are you going to ballet?
- There will be no ballet.
Sofia is over.
I'm going anyway.
I go up and pack.
If we stick directly, he does not notice anything.
Max, stay.
-Is it safe?
Why is it over?
- She didn't sit with me in the dining room.
- then.
What kind of food was that?
- Max, tell us what happened.
Do not know.
She said I was not allowed to go to the ballet and then we became enemies.
She might just be nervous about what you think.
Come here ... Mom is right.
Women can be so sometimes.
Sometimes you can almost believe that they are stupid in the head ...
Sofia is good much smarter than you!
Sorry, I didn't mean that.
Listen up.
Sofia likes you.
And then you get afraid to do away with it.
Then you can do contrary to what you feel.
- You will be insecure and ... cursed.
-Why?
What you ask!
You do well ...
- Lena!
- I would rather go with you to the cottage.
- There are fun things to do here.
-Like what?
- Puzzle you got from Grandma ... - Don't you want me to come along?
Do you want the computer game ...?
Sofie will be very happy if you come.
-What did you do?
- I called her.
It was as I suspected.
She was nervous.
- I invited her here for dinner ... - then so ... should we go?
- Be kind to Göran and Annika.
- Hold an eye on Lina and Marcus.
- Then we can talk about the computer game ... - kiss.
- Ni is the world's best parents.
-What did you say?
You only say that one.
Bye!
Oh ... now it is napping again.
How exiting!
Oo!
Nämen ... a tablet box!
What it will be good!
- Something who wants to see if it paces?
- Can you be silent, we watch TV.
- Pour the candy in a bowl.
- What you are boring!
- Start.
Immediately?
Certainly.
-What should we do now?
- Is it going night train to mom and dad?
How fun it was to see the ballet.
It was really ... different.
- Wasn't it boring then?
- Lite eventless.
What was its name?
"Sleeping stones" ...
- Tight to stand still for four hours!
–Okay ... Time for tonight's highlight.
- Should you go home?
-No.
- Do you know what this is?
- A magic box, I'm afraid.
-Right!
Do you know what this is?
- A magic wand.
You are welcome.
- I wanted to become the world's best magician.
- You became the worst in the world.
- What should I conjure away?
-Yourself.
-Come on!
It's great fun.
I think we are too old for this.
We intend to make it nice for you, whether you want to or not!
- Can we not watch video?
- You had a movie.
Yes, a romantic comedy ...
- "The avenger from hell."
- You can't see!
I know, we have a disco!
- Get our plates, and I'll clear away here.
-What then?
Should I stop trolling?
- This is needed!
Chips and juice!
Dad!
Tell Göran and Annika to go home.
- What are you doing at home already?
-What do you mean?
- You would come tomorrow night.
- A day here or there ... it was enough.
I have to correct you.
The line next to the cottage meant rail!
- The train passed by every five minutes!
- Why didn't Pettersson have said anything?
We will find out that.
We will fix an anesthetic gun for Styrbjörn ...
SWEDISH SUPPORT: Karin Esevik (C) Swedish Television AB 2005