Art - or weirdness.
Sweden's art history is part of the huge story of our country.
We will with some impacts show art-
- As depicts changes and creation power.
Surely he looks satisfied, knight Bengt Jönsson Oxenstierna?
The artist has got to the hairstyle.
The bells hanging down the back clearly show that he is wealthy -
–And is in fashion.
And at the same time, all generosity and godliness signal.
Because it is he who has paid for everything.
He has ordered all the murals throughout the church.
Tensta church is special, mainly because it is very well preserved.
It is cohesive.
From the choir to the farthest in the west-
- There is a coherent image program created at the same time.
It is unique in this way.
It is important in our art history.
We are in the choir in Tensta church just north of Uppsala.
What did the Middle Ages look like and how did she want to see herself depicted?
Notice the weapon with the ox boiler, his armor -
–And the coke bells.
You try to summarize everything that is earthly and heavenly life.
And that's not a small task.
From the deepest to the superficial and most easily accessible.
Within these walls, they try to create a reality.
Reality in the Middle Ages is about everything that is between the Bible's binders.
You do not pull out to put in human life here.
Even the worst species.
Also the devil.
Johannes Rosenrod is the artist who filled this church -
- With the help of him who created everything, which the artist himself wrote on the wall.
It is 1400s.
The battle for power in Sweden waves back and forth.
The church paintings will tell you about what is important to the people.
In the neighboring church Täby you will find the most well -known and scattered church painter:
Albertus Pictor.
German, just like our artist Johannes Rosenröd– -
- That seems to have disappeared after painting the church in Tensta.
In this type of churches you tell from the top down.
The most important thing at the top.
Then the motifs become more human and more human.
And aesthetically, it is important in Swedish art history.
I also think it's nice.
It is a light color scale.
It is quite neat plant ornaments, superficial throughout the church.
The figures are fine -tuned.
And then it has a little peculiarity -
- And it is that the motifs sail freely in this plant ornament.
It has not been felt the need to tie it together with lines.
In the rear of the church there is a comic book -like "strip" -
- In Holy Birgitta from the cradle to the grave.
A pretty unique suite.
First an upside -down boat - a shipwreck that is historically coated -
- When Birgitta's parents Ingeborg and Birger are going to a coronation in Kalmar.
They are miraculously saved, and then Ingeborg is pregnant with Birgitta.
Birgitta is betrothed with Ulf Gudmarsson.
Then she is 14 years old.
Birgitta in cot.
She gives birth to children and gets help from two women.
Here is Birgitta at a desk.
Above her, she has Jesus and Mary.
She has a pen, Stylus and a delete - so she works quickly.
Here we see the devil trying to seduce Birgitta.
The last picture shows how her relics are brought from Rome home to Sweden -
- And finally to Vadstena.
So got the citizens of the 14th century, instead of googling-
- Holy Birgitta's life in some squares.
And when you have looked through the entire church, you knew what was worth knowing.
They wanted the whole world to be in the church.
It was a matter of course, and rather a philosophical attitude -
- That everything is covered.
Both the evil and the good exist.
Texting: Karin Esevik Swedish Television AB 2023