In tonight's section of Ifs, immigrants for Swedes:
The world's Swedish Arab: Elaf Ali.
Rinkeby's own Harry Potter: Daniel Sanchez.
Cremiest woman on Instagram: Afrobellas.
Sweden's second best celebrity dancer: Filip Dikmen.
Greek from Alby: Thanos Fotas.
Gothenburg's best Somalis: Assia Dahir.
From the Middle Eastern Boy Band Last meal: Mustafa Panshiri.
The podcast pirate from Cap Verde: Victor de Almeida.
Sweden's most fun Chinese: Evelyn Mok.
The cheeky Melodifestival bird: Farah Abadi.
And last, but not least, our incredible program manager: Ahmed Berhan!
Welcome to IFS.
The program that will definitely have public service closed.
My name is Ahmed Berhan.
You see the quiz about all culture in Sweden.
A large applause to today's competitors: Linda, Martin and Elsa.
A competitor chooses one in the panel that I ask another question.
Then the contestant can decide whether the panelist is lying or not.
The two with the most points make it to the final.
We drew who would start.
The happy was no less than you, Martin.
Who do you want to talk to?
I want to talk to Mustafa.
Does it feel good?
I have a nice question.
We have heard of Bar Mitzva.
Judaism is a tolerant religion.
When you get into it it is celebrated.
But even if you leave, it's a ceremony, and it's Bat Mitzva.
- What do you say, Martin?
-No.
Bullshit.
- Did you know what a Bat Mitzva is?
-No.
- You just don't trust black skulls.
- You will say no to everyone.
You know what?
Sure it's bullshit.
Bat Mitzva is really not the Jewish login -
- Without a bar Mitzva, but for girls.
You could, Linda?
Heavy you are.
- Next competitors.
Elsa, ready?
-Yes.
- Who do you choose to talk to?
–Evelyn.
Jan Guillou is coming!
Fill the buffet.
Jan loves China Buffet.
No, but Gwailou ... I don't want to reveal it, but should.
It is a racist expression that we Chinese use.
We use it on The Whites.
We call white people Gwailou.
It means ghost head, if you translate it verbatim.
True or false?
Do you believe in Evelyn?
I felt confidence in you, but I say it is false.
- Is it false?
-Yes.
Typically gwailou.
You should have trusted her, because that's just right.
- Ssorry, Elsa!
- It's just like Evelyn said.
It means ghost head, which is probably the cutest racist word.
You need to work on your racist terms.
You should know what we call Black People.
Codejo.
Everyone is Kodjo Akolor.
- Linda, are you with?
How does it feel?
- Giantbra.
- You knew the questions.
You nodded.
- I teach me something.
- If I couldn't, I can now.
-Good attitude.
- What do you want to talk to?
–Afrobellas.
Afrobellas?
My question to you is:
Many Swedes live there.
They have Swedish schools, Swedish grocery stores ...
But the Spaniards began to get tired of Swedish youth -
- Because they committed crime and did not learn the language.
That's why they started calling them fucking white skulls.
I can confirm that.
-Wind?
- I think it's false.
I haven't heard of it.
It is pensioners who live there.
- No young people.
So, false.
- But you know of town?
- Did you know what the worst is?
You are wrong.
-Aah!
- The city has had that problem.
-In the 40s, or?
A documentary was released ten years ago about the problem.
- They have Swedish homeless people there too.
- Unfortunately, Linda.
No point.
On to the next.
Only Martin has managed to collect one point.
Do you think you get one more?
- What of the chews are you going to chew with?
- Farah.
Skåne in between.
Skåne represents.
- Farah?
What is the largest immigrant group in Malmö?
Paperless.
No.
The Öresund Bridge opened 20 years ago.
Since then, Danes are the largest immigrant group.
It is cheap to live in Sweden and work in Denmark.
- Martin, like Fellow Scania?
-No.
You're lying.
- I think you are lying.
- Serve a better answer, then.
Can not.
Then it becomes too racist.
- See it, Martin.
- Martin has counted.
He stands with a clock.
I've seen him on the streets.
Martin, you are doing absolutely right.
It's definitely a lie.
Danes are the third largest immigrant group in Malmö.
First are Iraqis.
Yeah!
- fun that the only Iraqi applauded.
- For everyone else is in Skåne.
No. 1: Iraqis, No. 2: Syrians and No. 3: Danes.
Thanks so much.
Elsa, your turn to drive.
Come on.
You have it.
Not Filip.
I run my Fellow Gothenburg citizen Assia.
- My fucking sweetheart.
--Assia?
Two young girls in Gothenburg started an anonymous instakonto -
- Where they hung out hundreds of guys and girls and called them -
- "Horor, Orrar, they suck cock behind McDonald's for cheeseburger."
The last one I was.
But...
That's what they did.
They end-shameed a lot of people.
I don't have to say anything.
I trust her.
- You do that right. That's right.
--Assia, it went for you.
031, 031!
OOOH-OH!
This happened in 2012. The account was obviously Gbgsorroz.
And the person behind, it was Paolo Roberto.
Congratulations, you got your first point.
Linda, time to jump into the match.
Are you ready?
Who do you take?
Lets see.
I take Filip.
Thanks!
Finally.
Don't disappoint me now.
His name is Ali.
His Swedish parents thought it was a nice name.
- Can you say the name again?
- He was named Ali.
/Panel pronounces it in different ways/
The pronunciation depends on who pronounces it.
His ethnic Swedish parents thought it was an excellent name.
What is difficult?
Do you mean the name is ugly?
I don't know his name, but it feels like a gear.
Or he was called Ali because it's a nice name.
-I do not believe that.
-Not?
-Wind!
–Sorry.
Filip didn't actually lie.
The actor is named Ali Alarik.
- I never forget his face.
- I tried to be honest anyway.
Better luck next time.
Let's move on.
- Martin?
–2 out of 2. Should we see if it will be 3?
- I hope so.
- What do you choose?
- Victor, my man.
Victor?
As you know yourself, placed words.
For technical reasons I can't answer it, but drive.
You fly with Ryan Air.
Joking aside, at the time when working with youth crime -
- You chose to fix fat boats -
–And take the youngsters to ... yes, South America -
- So they had to remove their criminal aura.
He said with his most criminal voice.
True.
They sent worst to other countries.
Especially South America.
No reason to pull it out.
3 of 3. Congratulations!
For those of you who are not familiar with the phenomenon:
The social let criminal youth work on sailboat trips.
- It went both well and badly.
- It went very badly.
- I am here.
- They worked and learned to sail.
- They jumped off and fled.
- They are not criminals now, I think.
-Do you think so?
- I read something ...
Elsa, should we drive?
I drive Thanos.
He looks tricky, but I think it can be good.
–Thanos ... –yes.
The Syrians, from the beginning when they emptied the day cash register before the cash register had taxed.
Say it quickly five times.
There are Syrians called Batch, which means stealing.
- It's where it comes from.
-Bullshit.
- Why do you sound so doubtful?
- I am bomb -proof.
I don't believe you.
You are doing absolutely right.
Obviously it's false.
- Whether you were BAXA coming from?
- Unfortunately not, but please tell me.
Baxa is an old honest Swedish word for moving things.
- It was included in this year's college exam.
- Concern have such random facts.
Awesome work, Elsa.
Congratulations.
- Linda ...
-Yes.
- Unfortunately, you are poorly located now.
But maybe catch a point?
Honor in retaining, your children love you etc.
–And grandchildren.
-Grandchild?!
- You want to drive?
Who do you choose?
- Daniel.
- Will I last selected?
- Just: "just like in the gym."
- Daniel?
You who are still from Rinkeby.
- mm.
Pork chop.
No, the correct answer is lamb.
Then I don't talk about Elaf's boyfriends.
- I talk about real meat of lamb.
-How?
Does Daniel feel credible?
Ramadan ...
You knew the history of the Jews.
It's the ninth month that Ramadan is.
Do you know how many Muslims are just "Word" right now?
- I wait for Saudi to say.
- It's like lamb.
It is certainly so.
They party in lamb.
No.
Unfortunately, Linda.
I wanted to give you one more.
It's false.
The correct answer is dates.
Had you come up with it?
It's dates.
This is usually what Muslims break their fasting with.
However, lamb is in the top five, with rice, rapeseed oil and chicken.
Name!
- Martin?
- I don't have much to choose from.
Sorry, I'm sorry.
I am also a scan.
If it makes it more fun.
I understand what you are saying anyway.
It is a really fun animal.
Namely rabbit.
They have no word for it in Persian, so they call it a ridge.
Final.
- Makes No Sense.
- Have you met Iranians?
No but...
Just for that, I say she is right.
That's right.
Martin, it's incredible.
Full fucking pot, then!
A huge applause to Linda.
An even bigger applause to Martin and Elsa who made it to the final!
Now it's time for the final round.
It is only to five points.
Martin, you won the first round.
You may start the final.
- Who do you choose to talk to?
- Mustafa.
It went well last.
- Mustafa?
–Yes.
Develop nuclear weapons.
It is a form of courtesy.
You offer something.
So the person refuses no, but is offered again.
Like food.
"Eat, eat!"
- "No, no, I'm measured."
This is how you keep on.
- I think it's true.
-Just right.
You can't miss.
Taxi drivers usually refuse.
You have to say: "Get paid."
- Elsa!
- I drive with Elaf, My Girl.
- Yeah!
I'm happy.
- I trust you now.
- Just truths here.
Stolen goods.
No, but actually a dirty fish.
And that's their main thing at Christmas.
It is so big so it can only fit in the bathtub.
When someone is going to shower, put it in a bucket and then back in the bathtub.
- I have to say that it is false.
- You think it's false?
You are wrong, Elsa.
It sounded like a invention, but that's true.
It is a Polish lutefish.
It's called carp.
A must on Polish Christmas.
Because you answered wrong, Martin got one more point.
Thanks so much.
Elsa should have plugged in all the world's cultures, as Martin has done.
Martin is from Skåne and has met everyone.
- Eilsa comes from a small village.
-Gothenburg!
Martin?
Who do you choose?
- Farah, we drive again.
Help me out.
- Farah?
Learned African dance at ABF.
Throw the spear!
It's popular.
No.
Sweden is not as innocent as one would like to believe.
500 years ago, Swedes went to Africa -
- took slaves, shipped over them to the Caribbean ...
It was even
A city called Gustavia, after the king.
That's what they did.
I know we had a colony called Sankt Bartolomeus or something.
You are absolutely right.
But did we transport slaves there?
Were we so nasty?
- Did we make it?!
- It's false.
Tell him, Ahmed!
Incredible that you are like this: "We had a colony."
A resort, then?
- They wanted to work for free.
- Hotel, beach ...
You thought, "It was like Marbella, huh?"
Martin, unfortunately.
You lost.
That was absolutely true, what Farah said.
Not applause for slavery!
Not only did you lose your first point.
Elsa got a point.
The Swedish I heard: "We had a colony. No slaves."
Elsa?
Who do you want to talk to?
- I drive with Evelyn again.
–Evelyn.
Okay.
There were two names.
It was Glenn and Abdi.
But: Glenn, hyphen, Abdi.
For in Gothenburg there are many Somali families.
Abdi is a common Somali name.
They want to integrate their children.
They have chosen Gothenburg's most common name, Glenn.
Glenn, hyphen, Abdi.
Although Glenn everyday is Silent.
/LAUGH/
Mustafa, it seems that Somalis in Gothenburg have read your book.
Do you think what Evelyn said is true or false?
Is the most common boy name in Gothenburg 2019 Glenn-ABDI?
I have to respond falsely to it.
Obviously it's false.
You've received a point.
Congratulations!
The most common boy name in Gothenburg 2019 was Elias -
- But in second place came Muhammad, so we're soon there.
- Martin?
- I choose Victor.
-Good choice.
- Victor?
South Korea.
South Korea manufactures very well and advanced things.
Smart children, such as
K-pop artists.
So it's South Korea.
I have a feeling that it is true.
-You are a big BTS fan?
-Yes.
--What is?
- He just: "What is it?"
- You think what Victor says is true.
-Yes.
You shouldn't.
It's fake!
The point goes to Elsa.
The country Swedes adopt most from is Sweden.
Domestic adoption is more common than foreign since 2013.
It's like weed, it's Home Grown.
Elsa?
Who do you choose?
- I drive afrobellas.
- Bring it on.
In Sweden, most of the crispbread have at home, if you are Swedish.
If you are from Somalia, it is strange if you do not have the track at home.
They usually cut it up or mash it.
/Smashes/
I'm saying fake.
I heard a Somalis in the audience: "huh?"
Unfortunately, Elsa.
That is absolutely true.
Martin then got a point.
- We do not mash.
It's just there.
-But why?
-Why?
- It's a culinary experience.
- The track with rice?
- It's sweet, salty, strong ...
SOOMALIYEEY TOOSOO
- Martin?
–Yes.
I choose Thanos.
It's actually from Kulu.
I put on the Turk.
Kulu in Turkey, it had become a city.
9 out of 10 Turks in Sweden come from Kulu.
They have such a place in Kulu.
/Someone laughs out loud/
- Is you going to another person now?
-Take it easy.
I market myself.
- Don't you Greek?
- A few, it's the same.
What do you think, Martin?
I think that's true.
In the Turkish city of Kulu there is a parade street named after Olof Palme.
Martin, that's fucking right.
Congratulations!
You know, when I become Turk, I speak the truth.
First it was called Kulufornia.
Then Hollywood, they have taken California, contract 100 years, just hot kulu.
Elsa, that's your turn.
But it is worth reminding you om-
- That if you answer wrong now, and Martin gets the point -
- Martin has won the whole thing.
-No stress!
- nice.
I have to pick points now.
- Then of course I choose Assia.
-Okay.
- Come again Gbg.
--Assia?
He wanted to introduce his Sunday Service Choir-
- With the English School and the Word of Life.
- False.
- False?
Congratulations, Elsa.
You got a point.
Do you know which organizations West tried to collaborate with?
–Ikea.
Then I can't the other.
-Think of...
-Beard.
Or?
-What fuck is that, the man?
-I get it!
AC ... –Acne!
- The man, what is it?
- It's panic.
Right now to our producer: "Next program: Charades with black shells."
- Type like this.
- For the first thing, it's bulges.
- I pop a pimple.
- How big are your pimples?
-What is it?!
- Because it's a lot.
I'll let you continue the debate later.
We are in an exciting situation.
- It's your turn, Martin.
If you guess right, you have won.
If you guess wrong, Elsa has won.
OOOH!
It's always on the white man.
- Team Elsa.
- What do you choose?
- Filip.
- Shit!
Dachri is a combination word of respect and humility.
It is important to show at Stora Dachri.
It is often communicated in interaction between younger and older generations.
You show Great Dachri by putting your hand on the heart and saying: "Dachri."
–Yes.
- Martin?
- I think it's bullshit.
- You have no big Dachri.
I know when you say in Arab Ala Rasi and so you do this.
What the hell does Dachri have to do?
There are two different languages!
Let him talk about Arabic.
Tell us about Arabic.
He made a type: "Are you Syrian? I know an Arab!"
Completely crazy.
"Do you know my friend, Mahmud?"
- What had your Arab friend taught you?
-Ala Rasi.
It's respect.
--Ala Rasi is my head.
- No, on my head.
- I know very Arabic.
- He thought it was respect.
- You have never heard of Dachri?
-No never.
I will tell you.
Dachri is a tube for cock.
But forget about it.
You got a point and have won the entire competition.
Big congratulations to tonight's winner.
Come on, Martin.
Come come!
-Thanks so much.
–Ifs diploma to Martin.
Cruelly.
Thanks to the audience, the competitors, to you at home and our fantastic panel.
Texting: Cristel Nyqvist Swedish Media Text for SVT