- Sites it well in the back?
- Giant, old man.
- Why are you going to have a ball?
- It's tradition!
- I remember my first bale.
Lovely!
- Where did you meet Dad?
Get it together!
I was actually there with dad, on the school ball.
I was wearing a blue dress.
- Dad had a sailor costume.
- Sjöman costume?
He did the lump in the fleet and could not afford a coat.
- You would arrange dinner.
C. Head talk - I have done more important things.
C. Head Tapers I have made my banner a C. Head talkative first train.
What do you say?
- You do not complicate it ... C. Head talkative - now the director's pack will be fit!
Do you have to walk in the train?
C. Head talk is Sweden's worker's C. Head talkative festival.
C. Head talk we are united and strong C. Head talk and you go out of houses for our ideals.
- And there is free coffee in the square ... C. Head talk - it's about solidarity!
C. Head talkative self is probably the only one in the family C. Head talk, if selflessly puts up on others!
- Do I get half?
C. Head talk - no.
May 1st is for you and your friends to feel important.
The C. Head talk is in the broad layers C. Head talk as the knowledge exists.
C. Head talk away all managers for a month, C. Head talk - no one would notice anything.
- So it's not noticeable if I'm gone?
C. Head talk - you do some kind of benefit sometimes.
C. Head talkatives take Melander - my boss.
Now C. HuvyPratarehan is going on a luxury course again.
Shameful!
- So it didn't sound when you were on course.
C. Head talk - we got something done!
- You won the tip walk!
C. Head talk and finished second in the karaoke competition.
C. Head talkative post can do without Melander.
You are jealous.
Melander is good.
- Jump down, and we'll see ...
C. Head talk - what nice you are!
Is there anything going on?
- It's a bale, I've said.
C. Head talk - you were invited by little Roger, huh?
- Patrik.
His name is Patrik.
C. Head talkmeroger is ten years C. Head talk and collects on frogs.
- What fun that Patrik offered you!
- Strange.
He looks normal.
Add, max.
Follow!
I have to have someone to train drums with.
- Mom, say something!
- Help your sister.
- She can help you with something she can.
-What then?
Chewing chewing gum, read the Weekly Review ...
C. Head Tapers - Are you membrane of our first bale?
- It was nice.
C. Head Tapers were nervous.
I asked your father C. Head talk to escort you to the ball.
- What was he saying?
C. Head talk - "May I see you again ..."
- But you ignored that. C. Head talk - yes!
Because I loved you!
C. Head talkators I cook dinner, C. Head talkatives and wash -
C. Head talk - or get away and play poker?
C. Head talkative self just wanted to check.
Where is Dad somewhere?
He would drive us to school.
He cycles with the post.
Something has emerged.
- A tractor ... - have you read the test?
-Yes!
-Is it true?
- The truth is relative.
- It is concrete:
If you have not read the test, you will be adopted.
-Finally!
We'll be too late!
C. Head Tapers - Wait, Wait, Wait, Wait ...
C. Head talk - Melander is gone this week.
- The children have to go ...
C. Head talkative guess ... Guess who he has appointed C. Head talk to his deputy manager.
- It's not true ... C. Head Tapers - Yes!
- Children, your dad is the manager!
C. Head talk - do you understand what this means?
-Yes.
Vivalla will be without mail.
Go out, I have to talk to dad.
- Have you thought through this?
C. Head talkum is moving about a week.
C. Head talkatives have prepared everything.
C. Head talk - it takes care of itself.
- Why are you going to be a manager?
C. Head talk - Therefore, it's fun!
- You get any longer there without compensation!
C. Head talkative self receives some managerial privileges.
C. Head talkative key to the candy machine.
- Gustav!
C. Head talk, yes ... C. Head talk I have to try everything I wanted.
- Sita in Melander's room and sleep?
C. Head Tapers - get to know what it's like to be a manager!
- You said managers were superfluous.
C. Head talk - I was slightly categorical ...
C. Head talkative self has never tried.
I was not elected by C. Head talk as student council chair.
It was a difference.
They wanted someone who was a little more ...
C. Head talk - What then?
-Normal.
C. Head talkative self had a clear political will!
You roared, "Vote for me and you should be liberated!"
The C. Head talk was such times!
C. Head Tapersche Guevara, Student Revolution ...
- Do you recover 20 years of disappointment?
C. Head talk - no.
C. Head talk I think I can achieve something.
Congratulations then, the postmaster!
But now the kids are waiting in the car ...
C. Head talkative song The Wait.
I will call home c. Head talk and tell me that I have become a manager.
C. Head talkative mom ...
-Hello boss?
Did they obey you?
C. Head talk - it was a bit sneaky.
C. Head talkatives thanks to my experience c. Head talkative I quickly solve the problem.
C. Head talk - A strap loosened from a bag.
- I don't think you are a manager!
C. Head talkative things have happened.
Yes, there will be some talking pig somewhere in the United States.
C. Head Taper Are You Not Proud of Me?
I C. Head talkative ficked a trust assignment as well.
- To fill in toilet paper?
C. Head talkative - to look through this one.
C. Head talk - and it was important.
-What is it?
The C. Head talkum I have not listed yet.
C. Head talkative self may ask mom.
C. Head talk - How does it go with the bale?
- I and Patrik - that's too good ...
C. Head talkative thinking positively!
C. Head talkator on me, only.
Now I'm the manager!
Soon you will be a postman again.
I haven't dared to say a word to Patrik - and then he invites me!
- As long as you don't talk, you're okay!
C. Head Tapers - Max, Be kind to your sister!
Sorry ... do you want?
Watch, the boss sits and reconscents.
How has it gone for you?
C. Head talk - good, just good.
–Okey, Max.
Now you have to lead.
- You dance in the wrong direction all the time!
- It's your duty to bring me right!
Funny that no gems came away, that no paper got stuck in the copier ...
C. Head talkatives tease!
Melander gave C. Head talkative an important assignment.
C. Head talkative self has not taken what.
This is a regular work schedule.
It is needed for salary payment.
C. Head talkative seminar salary is in the account every month.
C. Head talk is all you have to know.
- I go through this for you.
C. Head Tapers - thank you.
-Where are you going?
C. Head talk - at the Grand Meeting.
C. Head talkatives sometimes have such things.
He goes C. Head talk as what can be improved ...
C. Head talk - I have some thoughts and ideas ... - don't make it away now, Gustav.
C. Head Tapraredu will be the manager all his life.
C. Head talkative self just wants to take the opportunity to enjoy.
-Okay, I understand.
Take care, you!
- It's a black limousine outside!
- Do you feel for something about it?
C. Head talk - no, I ordered a white.
C. Head talk - but it rolls well anyway.
Bye!
- Mom, you have to ...
I know what to say!
Now it's Monday.
On Friday it is as usual.
-See you then!
-Good luck!
- How is the election training going?
- They are in the fine.
Kossa you can be yourself!
- Gustav seems to thrive in the managerial role.
- He goes around in limousine and waves.
Yes, it's ridiculous.
But it's fun to go in it.
It has everything.
Yesterday we watched TV and ate salty sticks.
- Isn't it expensive with driver?
- Yes, but it is Gustav who pays.
Tomorrow is the postal cycle again ...
He is doing right.
Far too few dare to live out their dreams.
- I wrote a poem about it once ... - I think Lena understands the message.
Nämen ... you will be the queen of the ball!
- Mitt necklace fits perfectly!
- Patrik is coming soon.
- Have you seen my gold earrings?
- I will see what I have.
-How does it feel?
- Maybe you should stay home ...
- Yes, a new dick begins.
- Lina probably doesn't mean seriously.
C. Head talk - health family!
- thank you, director.
C. Head talk - Are our nice neighbors here?
- Wogs up nice clothes!
C. Head Tapers - thank you.
Pure wool.
- I thought you loved your uniform.
C. Head Tapers Writing the Week!
If you want to get the c. Head talk, you have to dare to develop.
These I think fit ... - But Gustav!
-You look nice!
C. Head talk - have you never seen a suit before?
Yes, but never on you.
Now we have to go.
- Gustav, we got no post this morning.
Rune has not received post in several days.
C. Head talk - I shall punish the culprit.
- Easch, we will surely get it tomorrow.
C. Head Tapraredu is very cute!
Do you want something?
C. Head Tapers, Candy, Life Wisdom?
C. soundtut!
Patrik is here!
What should I do?
- A tip is to go out and say hello.
- Good idea.
-Bye Bye.
If you want to be picked up, call!
C. Head talkative self sends Karlsson!
You are good looking in a suit.
You should have that more often.
C. Head talk - for 4,000 you get some quality.
–4,000?
Can you afford it?
C. Head talk - There is a lot of money on the mail!
- ART ... what are you saying?
C. Head talkative is there a lot of money on the post.
The C. Head of Care Unit cannot go around C. Head Tapersi a uniform.
- Gustav, have you taken money?!
C. Head talk - Melander was very clear, he said:
C. Head talk - Used resources to their own head.
- And tomorrow he chops off it!
C. Head talk, so dangerous is not.
It is probably C. Head talkative deductible, such as managers have ...
You can get fired!
C. Head talk it calmly.
Melander encourages C. Head talkatives.
He becomes happy.
Look at me.
Do you really think that Melander will be happy?
C. Head talkative may not be the right word.
C. Head talkative a little surprised!
- It always goes overboard.
C. Head Tapers - Forgive.
I rushed away.
You would just make sure everything floated.
C. Head Tapers I know, but I was so inspired.
C. Head talk I entered the office C. Head talk, I felt that everything was possible.
It costs you your savings capital.
You talk about the honest employee - and then you behave like this!
C. Head talkative self has tried to keep the C. Head talkative active personnel policy.
C. Head talk you knew what I have invested C. Head Tapers on the staff!
C. Head talkative self has ordered a mini golf course C. Head talk and I bought a courtyard.
-What did you say?
C. Head talk - a mini golf course and a courtyard.
Gustav, tomorrow you cancel the track, and sell the farm.
- Then we can only pray to God!
C. Head talk - I wonder if one's God can help.
C. Head talk staff has been a bit clear.
C. Headpratarede has resigned.
Have they resigned?
How many?
C. Head talkator42 with the caretaker.
Do you mean that all employees in the post have resigned?
C. Headpratarede became annoyed when I changed C. Head talk and wanted them to rotate.
-"Rotate"?
C. Head talkative - exchange task.
C. Head Tapers Pettersson got to try something new.
The C. Head talk guys were allowed to sit in the cash register.
C. Head talkative time stays received the morning tours.
- Is that no one got any post?
C. Head talkative - people may write fewer letters!
- How much mail has not been distributed?
C. Head talk - I made an estimate this morning ...
C. Head Tapers - Thing ... and ... - what?
C. Head talk - 4,000 letters, 250 packages.
-Where are you going?
C. Head talk - I have eleven hours - I have time.
-No...
Nobody can!
C. Head talkative self may be the world's worst manager -
C. Head talk - but is a seven -half postman!
8,000 people have gathered at Norra Bantorget.
The LO manager gives speeches at 15. We will return then.
-Where is Dad?
- Hos Melander.
- Melander is pretty angry, huh?
- If he does not, we must look in the lake.
Do not be sad.
Rals is difficult.
It's Max's wrong!
Had I had some good to practice, it would never have happened!
- Small accidents happen constantly.
- But not everyone tear the buffet table ...
I didn't think he would let me go.
- Not those who took roast beef either ... - didn't you get any more dance with Patrik?
He offered ... but I didn't want to ruin the coat with potato salad.
Gustav ... how has it been?
C. Head talkativelander was impressed that I C. Head talkatively out 4,000 letters in 11 hours.
- What did he say about the other?
C. Head talk - which?
- That 42 people resigned ... C. Head talkative - he touched it a little neighbor.
-What did he say then?
C. Head talk - Fo see ... It was a lot ...
The C. Head Taple Order was fools, C. Head Tapers Lock ...
C. Head Certainer ... repeated again C. Head talk and move from Vivalla.
C. Head talkative my work schedule was the best C. Head talk and most thoughtful he has seen.
–Wh's work schedule?
C. Head Tapers - Mitt ... our ... okay - yours.
- Health and thank you.
C. Head talk - Now I have to go.
- You have cycled ten miles.
C. Head talk - it doesn't matter.
C. Head talkative workmates are waiting for the square C. Head talk and then I set up!
- What should we do with him?
- They lower shark cages in the ocean ...
If there is a batter he is bad out ...
Lina Svensson.
Yes, okay.
- It was Patrik.
- Yeah ... are you going to pay the dry cleaning?
-No.
He wonders if we should be together.
- What did you say then?
-I do not know.
Heard anyone what I said?
-No sorry...
I have to call ...
How fun!
Have you met Patrik?
Gustav hit him in the head with a stone when he palled apples.
- Hi, have you forgotten something?
C. Head talk - I stand over this year's first train.
- You were waiting for the square.
C. Head talk - they waited outside.
Shouldn't you join them?
C. Head Taprarede has a banner C. Head talk I can't put up.
"Death to the overflower Gustav Svensson!"
C. Head talkator hides us in the basement!
SVT program text: