I have a time machine.
No, it's a regular box.
I'm just kidding.
I was in Skåne this weekend and ran on your dad.
He asked me to bring a thing to you.
- This clock.
- It's his old one.
Your grandfather gave it to your dad and now your father gives it to you.
Be very scared about it.
I had to go through a lot when I brought it here
I've had it in my tail all the trip up here.
- In the butt?
-Exactly.
In the butt.
Why?
I had lots to wear and my pockets were full.
Our Lord gave us a natural pocket.
Here is the clock - from father to you.
Hello, yes.
It was Gun.
Gun from Gran Canaria, yes.
You have come home now.
Yes...
I stand here on the balcony with two newly mixed groggers.
So I came to think of you and unless you would come over ...
Huh?
You're going to try again?
Yes...
No!
No danger!
It was just on holiday, yes.
No, no problems.
Hello...
Hello, it was Gun again.
The bottle of Malibu that we would share, should you pick up your half?
Oh really?
Then I thank you for that.
Hello...
What are you looking at?
Have you never seen a puma on a balcony?!
- I do not believe in.
-I do!
Vacuum cleaner...
You didn't think this.
- I am not a speaker ... - what fun!
A speech!
I was going to say some well -chosen words to the host couple.
-How fun!
- I have written a small cheat.
K ... k ... ä ... r ... a ... a ...
... VVV ... friend ... down ...
... viii ... h ... is ... kkkän ...
...each other...
...for several years!
We have known each other for several years.
-This is how it looks.
- But God what a nice thing!
Great!
This fits milkshake perfectly.
It was in high school.
Great fun that you called, but what do we do here?
We should go out.
I have acquired a babysitter.
I'll tell you why I called.
I have felt that Milkshake was never divided.
- We were the school's best dance group.
-Yes!
And we were good!
What memories!
Okay, girls ...
Come on, girls!
Oh, the night is my world
City Lights Painted Girl
In the day nothing matters
It's the Night Time That Flatters
You remember the choreography!
It really sits!
We have to start again.
I'll be coming soon.
I'll just lock after the dancers.
No no.
These are old lovers.
- Do you often storage stuff in the back?
–Oft and often ...
In the summer when you only have shorts and t -shirts -
- Is it a practical place to have small money, tulo, something to read ...
- Do you have anything there now?
-No.
Well, the front of the car stereo.
They are so theft -proof.
- Jesper, what are you doing in there?
-Nothing.
Leave me alone.
- What you do is unnatural.
-Leave me alone!
I am who I am.
Hello.
It's Gun again.
You shouldn't take and come anyway?
I only have little leopard on me so I can be your kiss cat.
I can be a lion.
Can I do!
I have bedded with the Hawaii sheet, and there is grogg and wood.
I stand here on the balcony and it is full of men who look at me.
Yes, it is.
One is looking at me now ...!
Hello?
"He came as a storm in April with a Höganäskrus on his neck ..."
We all recognize the introduction to August Strindberg's "Hemsöborna".
Strindberg starts in the middle of the events, so -called.
In media resume ...
... as I did now.
Hello!
My name is Gunnar.
Welcome to this printer course.
Before the course you have all been given the task of bringing a text with you.
We throw ourselves straight in and see where we end up.
Read for us!
- I have used well -known characters.
-Good!
Identification...
"Ally McBeal entered the lawyer - the office. She was stressed and tired."
"It was full of people in the office and Richard wasn't happy."
We're holding there.
Another example of in the media res.
-What's your name?
- Gunilla.
I haven't written anything, but I have a character that I work with.
It is a young woman, or a girl, who lives alone in a large villa.
- She's a strong girl.
-Good.
Strong women are interesting.
She is very strong.
She can lift a car with her bare hands.
She has a different lifestyle.
Her pet is a horse and a monkey.
Her only real friends are neighboring children, Tommy and Annika.
We recognize that a bit.
It is largely Pippi Longstocking.
A little, but it's such a popular figure that you can write more about her.
But as Astrid Lindgren has already written about her ...
It can be difficult to follow in Lindgren's footsteps.
- She should have received the Nobel Prize.
-Absolutely.
Many people think ...
It is not easy to come up with a look.
Should we check some topics?
Just shout out, and I write on the board.
I write "love".
It is a popular subject in literature.
- What more do we have?
-Love!
Falls a little under love.
- boxes!
- Absolutely ... what's in the box?
Very exciting ... more!
Fish!
- Pike!
-Paris.
-Ferris wheel.
-Cod.
Thanks.
Now we have three words on the board - love, boxes and fish.
There are three words.
- I have fixed a show.
-Already!
Where?
- Strorget's day.
-God how fun!
Here we go!
This doesn't work.
We are good, but we have to be the best and then you have to train, work out!
Right here we have to start paying with ... we have to pay with ...
- What do we have to pay for?
- Cramp, cramp!
Fy fuck ... now you have to get out of here.
Now the brides will drive.
- Then the canned goods are inside, then.
- Set up here and we'll have a snack.
Before we have a snack, I would say some well -chosen words.
Jeanette, you have now moved from your childhood home in the polkagris city Gränna.
Mom and I think it's empty, so empty.
But we have known that this day when you flee the nest would come.
Now I want to give a gift on the journey.
As proud father and owner of the Polkagrisfabriken Grisfabriken -
- Want to give you a go'er rod to suck on when the homesickness gets too difficult.
It's a new taste for the season.
Already today, you should, dottra mi, suck you measured on this good rod ...
... and think about mom and dad every time you suck.
Mom should have a go's rod to suck on too.
Is there anything good than hearing dottra and mom suck?
Out to the paintball track, super him full, puts on him rabbit heat ...
... and chases that bastard like a hare through the forest.
Pepper the ass with color balls, film it, and send to his girlfriend!
- Didn't we do it with Håkan?
- Yes ... we have to come up with something new.
We take the Finnish ferry, full as eggs ...
Then he is allowed to sit in the whirlpool with a bunch of strippers -
- And we have put laxatives in his drink!
And then we film it and send to his mother -in -law.
It's great fun with these burlesque, popular procession.
I have my own proposal.
They have a fantastic exhibition at Liljevalchs with a pour painting.
Why not let him decorate his own bridal chest?
Instead of ordinary glue colors, we give him a water -based color -
- So his painting becomes much paler.
Hello, it was Gun again.
Now you stop fitting and coming to me!
Stop getting you and come!
What then, old girl?
You are not so young yourself.
Shit in it then if it doesn't fit!
I can go down to the pub and get whatever man I want.
Can I do!
No!
You don't have to wish me good luck.
Hello!
Hello, it was Gun.
Gun that you met in Båstad, yes ...
I stand here on the balcony with two newly mixed groggers ...
Okay, how many have read something by Nobel Laureate Imre Kertész?
No?
No.
He has a great way to paint pictures with words.
Read for us.
VVV ... in ...
... hh ... a ... they ...
... VVV ... than ... tat ...
-... Locate ... ne ... - long.
Do you remember Salle?
Who was a teacher at TBV, who was in Fame, which all girls were crazy in!
- There is an old man behind the palm!
- How did you see me?
I played leaves.
- Get I present Salle!
- Is that Salle ...?!
Girls, we're running!
- What good we are!
- Fan, how tired I am.
Keep the fine feeling.
It's time for the next step.
- A cig?
-Easy.
Keep the feeling now, we drive!
- Thanks, Salle!
It wasn't me who shot Palme, you.
Jjj ... a ... g ...
... sss ... will ... g ... e ...
... t ... three ...
... e ... xe ... exe ... example ...
I'll give three examples!
... one ... example one!
Excuse me, this feels a little flimsy.
Can't we learn how to actually write?
You probably have to develop that a little ...
How to form words?
All letters, how do you use them?
Okay ... how many in here feel safe on the alphabet?
It is important to find positive energy even when life is bath.
Positive Thinking Will Always Help You Navigate Your Inner Landscape.
Have you Experienced Negative Energy?
Yes.
One of the Toughest Moments was when my brother got very sick.
--That must be negative.
–VERY worried, very very worried.
It was a painful time for the whole family.
A Couple of Weeks Later ...
... he died from his disease.
Sorry ... that must be negative.
Two Weeks Later ...
... My Mother Died Too.
That is also negative.
It was a hard time.
–We cried a lot.
-You cried a lot!
Like ...!
I WANT TO BE LOVED BY YOU
Just you, and Nobody else but you
... Alone!
Boop - Oop - a -doop
Well, shit in it then!
Fucking eyeglasses ...
But you, you miss the pussy's Rolls Royce.
Hello!
We have gone away.
Do you know where the station is?
Keep shaving the road here, and to the right at the houses over there.
Thanks.
We are newly moved and do not find so good.
Moving to a new city can be likened to anal sex.
It is slow at first, but with a little effort you will fit in soon.
A tulo?
No thanks.
SVT program text: Karina Berg
- Is it okay if I read a little?
- Mm ... sure.
Kkk ... ka ... p ...
... ka ... pi ... tel ... chapter 1!