Nice place!
This was a great idea.
You only celebrate years once a year.
Thanks!
Just what I needed!
- A great gift.
-Do you think?
- So, what a nice room!
-Yes.
Big bed.
Close the door, Magnus.
Finally alone!
Happy Birthday!
-I have a surprise for you!
-Oh really?
-Congratulations!
- Now you are old, your bastard!
We have no time to lose.
I have made a schedule for the activities.
The tip walk starts in exactly seven minutes.
You didn't think this, huh?!
No, I didn't think so.
There is the question.
"On May 6, 2002, Magnus happened to break an ornament."
What then?
1: a plate, X: A candlestick, 2: a vase.
It's 2: a vase.
She has probably never forgiven me for it.
How much was the vase worth?
SEK 1: 500, X: SEK 4,000 -
- Or 2: Not so much, but it meant a lot to Frida.
- Was it worth SEK 4,000?
- It's probably the last option.
- Does what the girls are doing now?
- They have some other activity.
Tjing, tjing!
Mm!
God, what good wine!
!
- I hardly know where we are.
- Here is the next.
"What did Frida's grandmother say to Frida on her deathbed?"
1: Take good care of you, X: Love is the most important thing in life -
- Or 2: Be afraid of this vase.
- It's 2.
Get to hear, then!
When Sebastian takes me, it is as if everything around is still.
- We may be two in the world.
-Wonderfully!
When Magnus takes on me, it becomes electric.
It's such an incredible erotic charge!
When Ulf takes in me it's like ...
... to solve crosswords!
It makes time go.
Surely it's over soon?
"Why did Magnus Vasen destroy?"
1: He's sloppy, X: Missing fine motor skills -
- Or 2: He lacks respect for Frida and her possessions.
Cross?
Look here what I've found, Carita!
- Where did you find it?
-On the ground.
Nice pictures!
It's a guest house.
Do you know what I've been thinking about?
-What have you thought out, Per-Arne?
- Look here what it says!
"Experience a cozy atmosphere far away from the stressful everyday life."
"A relaxing and romantic weekend with someone you like."
We're going there.
We need to get away from the stressful everyday life.
Great!
When are we leaving?
Now!
I'm sure it's a weekend.
-Oh!
Should I bring this one?
-Yes.
Mm ...
The guys have been away for a long time.
It is getting dark.
They are doing well.
Magnus has a video camera so they can show what they have done.
I am so afraid.
I'm so terribly scared.
We will die out here.
--Ulf has been crazy.
- A, cross, two ...
Oh, Per-Arne, what you can find!
This I call a romantic weekend!
Cheers, Carita!
Cheers, Per-Arne!
- Yes ... no ... now we can this, huh?
- Yes, now we go home.
- I go out and start the car.
- Yes, I lie down here.
No, now they may come!
I'll have dinner soon.
-Hello.
Now we are here.
-Hello...
- How have you had it?
- Good, I think.
We ... Ulf went down, but we found a dry bag, so ...
-Good.
Then we go and eat.
- I would like to turn a blind eye to five minutes.
I don't know ... A romantic weekend seems to just fortify the gender roles.
No!
It will be absolutely wonderful.
Just you and me.
No TV, no phones ...
- No, I don't know ... - no men.
There you have a point.
- I love you, Robyn.
- I love you, Leon.
Oh, fuck!
Gosh...
-Hello.
-Where have you been?
You would have opened the door for me.
I had a bag with me.
- We don't do this.
Can I take your name please?
- Gun.
- How was your name?
- Yes.
Now you have been so stupid, so now you have to make it good.
- You can start by giving me a kiss.
-No...
- Give me a little kiss!
- Room 27.
- I can't find, Johan.
- Anna!
- She helps you.
- Night ... Hello!
What are you doing?
I am not handicapped.
You are crazy!
Shouldn't you have the key?
Crazy!
Magnus has been promoted.
Now he gets to work as head of department.
Sebastian has got a new leasing car, a Toyota.
Great!
- He is very poppy with the manager.
- Magnus is the manager himself.
Sebastian refused to manager jobs for my sake - but yes to payroll.
--Ulf has gone down part -time.
- Yeah.
Sebastian got an Atlas in leather from his company.
Magnus got an Orrefors bowl.
You will see it later.
- Tell what I got!
- I don't remember it.
I got an almanac.
Magnus took me to a conference to Hasseludden.
Great place!
Sebastian goes free at S.A.T.S Sports Club.
He wanted to get in shape for my sake.
Magnus is already so well trained.
- I don't understand how you succeed!
--Ulf has started with Nordic walking.
-How fun!
The only thing he could do after the purse ...
You are left.
Lucky!
They have such strange stuff at this place.
Saddle - Who wants to eat it?
Especially not when it has been on a deer.
Tonight's appetizer: Tuscan salad with arucolabed and honey roasted ...
No no.
We will have ribs with cooked potatoes and two large strong.
Take in a half bend and light up the ceiling.
Take out the rabbit food!
Now we cuddle before the jaw comes.
Check this out!
Oh!
But God, Peter!
Don't be so grumpy because you don't have a girlfriend.
You are the nicest of the world!
What can such a small hand painted porcelain doll hot?
My friend came home from Scotland yesterday.
He brought a whiskey with him.
I am not a whiskey must, but it was something in the horse.
An incredible smoke flavor!
I think it was called Glen Hockney.
It is stupid that everyone has become such experts on malt whiskey.
I was in Scotland last year.
A friend cheated me into a whiskey tasting.
We got to taste a 30 year old Loch of Frahenass.
Totally amazing!
There were only 100 bottles in the world.
I'm not a whiskey guy either ...
... but I was once at a giant - small distillery in southern Scotland.
Glenn Hochenflochochass was called it.
Four giant monks produced a whiskey that was so sickly smoky ...
We had to speak Gaelic with them.
At home I have a 300 year old Glenn Obanochnochlochloch Ulangloch.
I bought it from two Celtic druids that have a tiny distillery.
Only two more have been there.
You have a blindfold when you go there.
I was in Scotland another time too.
Then I was abducted -
- To a small, mysterious ... ancient little cave.
It was below the seabed.
They went down to it in an old submarine.
In order for the gates to open, one had to say an old magic formula.
Sure it's sick!
In the cave lived an old wizard.
Her name was ... lochoch ...
... Hochlogsch ...
... Glenndalhua.
Legend says that if you pronounce her name backwards -
- So you get caught in the cave, forever.
- Did they make whiskey there?
-I do not know.
- Something who wants another beer?
-I!
I'll take another round.
How wonderful to have you as friends!
We can talk about everything.
- We have been given such a close relationship.
- It's cool with this vicinity!
I can put your arm around you, Frida.
- And you don't take it badly, Magnus.
- What a lot of fun we have done together!
- We haven't done everything you can do.
No...
There are many exciting things to try ...
-...to do.
- Fun with this weekend!
- Correct with relaxation!
- Revision is content.
One should not be afraid to change.
Gosh...
For example, say that I eat brown beans every day ...
It's delicious with brown beans, but say I have to eat them every day.
Then it is clear that I am curious about how other food tastes.
And Magnus eats lobster every day.
He may be tired of it.
If I get to try your lobster you get to taste my brown beans.
- For the sake of change ... - what do you want to say?
We can be natural and free with each other.
If I massage Frida, then you don't think it's hard.
You can do the same on Kristina.
- Kristina has gone now.
- Yeah.
- She would call a taxi.
- We will go to bed now.
It has been a long day.
Thank you and good evening.
Good night.
It's just you and me, Jenny.
- Should you order anything?
-Yes.
-What then?
-A few beers.
It's a carladae, it!
- You are happy today.
-Yes...
Do you know how to say "happy" in Danish?
-No.
-Horny.
It is spelled with "D", so in Danish you are "resistant" today.
Hello!
Do you know what the Danish says when something has gone wrong?
It's cock in the machinery.
When you are horny you do not want the cock there, but in a nicer place.
-Hello!
If you get no help here ... - Follow with me in the room!
-No thanks.
- Did you know what that means in Danish?
"I want you, Gun!"
Then I say: "The store is open!"
Come here!
Hello!
That you can never be at peace!
If I sit with you, don't you take up badly?
I sit here with you.
If I put your arm if you don't take up badly?
- I have tear gas spray in my bag.
- Yeah.
- It was time for cleaning.
- half one at night?
Here we clean at night.
- I don't want any cleaning.
- Then you get fined.
It is high fines if you do not receive the cleaning - SEK 675.
- Fan ... How long does it take?
- It only takes ten minutes.
Yes, yes ... Join, then.
Ringtone
- It's Gert here.
- Is that reception?
I'd like a wake up call.
Aren't you awake?
Are you talking in your sleep, now?
- Can I order wake up from you?
- Sleeping!
Can't you take my order?
- Bu!
-Hello?
There I woke you up, you!
Don't you bother the other guests?
No, I'll just look at the bed a little.
You do not usually clean in the middle of the night.
- I just have to clean up here ... - what are you doing?
- So you can come ... - you are not a real maid!
Go out, for fucking!
You don't say no to a neighboring woman!
Come now!
Come ... Hello!
Hello!
-Help!
-Come back!
So!
Release!
Come now!
What is it about?
He took the dust lash and tried to get me into the room.
-I'm shocked.
- Help her into the room.
There you are...
Then maybe you can get the puzzle now?
Program text: Britta L Bergman (C) Swedish Television AB 2004
This is life, Peter!
Be out in the countryside and breathe healthy country air!
Great!