Art - or weirdness.
Sweden's art history is part of the huge story of our country.
We will with some impacts show art-
- As depicts changes and creation power.
When Drottningholm Castle began to be built in the 1660s-
- Sweden was a European superpower.
Extra care was placed on the part that connects the lower and upstairs:
The stairwell.
Here, architect Nicodemus Tessin created the older something brand new.
A large symmetrical representative stairwell -
–A parade room which is also actually a bit of a program statement -
- And sometimes used for dinners and parties.
If we look here we discover -
- The statues turn their backs on us standing on the stairs.
Everyone turns towards the center.
It is so-
- That there is no one where you see the entire stairwell.
You are supposed to move - as one of the explanatory models for the Baroque:
You are constantly moving, constantly participating in the artwork.
Sweden also wanted to claim -
- With the great nations in artistic terms.
The stairwell is one of the monuments where you get inspiration from Italy -
- And to some extent from France.
A monastery in Venice is the biggest source of inspiration for the architect.
Up here is a large painting on canvas by David Klöcker Ehrenstrahl -
-which was the dominant painter at the court from the 1660s onwards.
It represents two antique gods, Apollo and Minerva.
They raise Hedvig Eleonora's name cipher in a warehouse wreath up against eternity.
David Klöcker Ehrenstrahl is the celebrity of the time.
A superstar who has been on a educational trip to the continent.
He is an early PR maker, with the mission to serve power.
As he himself has expressed in any of his writings is his task -
- Painting the fame of the high authority.
His biggest task is to portray the Swedish royal power -
- And to do it in a symbolic allegorical way.
The picture of Karl XI in the Battle of Lund 1676–
-Is at first glance realistic.
Tabs, gunpowder and blood splashes.
But the king is still set alongside the hit.
The king becomes without supernatural attributes the inaccessible hero god.
The unrelenting winner.
What Ehrenstrahl paints expresses the political situation in Sweden -
- And the needs that the royal family has at the time.
Time is the empire.
A Sweden that extends beyond the Baltic Sea -
- And has colonial claims in the north as well.
Land is taken into possession.
Cultural heritage is plundered.
I.a.
Gift drums are brought to museums south - where many remained.
But the royal ideal at the time was taken from the continent -
–And was characterized by the hungry - the baroque.
Drottningholm is at the forefront.
This is the purely Baroque's major breakthrough in Sweden.
Here, architecture, painting, and sculpture.
And maybe there were members from the court chapel -
- Which stood for the music.
People are also part of the composition.
You participate as a spectator in the event going on in the stairwell.
Here we see Diana Ross.
Texting: Karin Esevik © Swedish Television AB 2023