Jenny ... you've been so weird lately.
I have to ask a straight question for you.
Have you met any one else?
No, it's clear that I don't have.
What you are paranoid!
- I just had to ask ... —Sov now a bit instead.
Mobile signal
It's Ulf.
Hey!
I'm just going to order food.
- I also have lunch.
Do you have a cold?
- Yes, these are such times now.
- Frida and I want to invite you home.
-How nice!
Sorry, now I didn't hear what you said.
There must be a mess on the line.
Talk to you later.
Hello.
- There is poor coverage in here.
We have nothing in common anymore!
Yes, the sofa!
We bought it together.
- I want you to sleep away tonight.
- I should go ...
But I can sit a bit on the couch first ...
I go shower for so long.
Oh...!
I actually looked!
Have you called someone you can sleep with?
- How can you be so cold?!
- Sink, you just make it worse.
- What should we do with the food in the fridge?!
- Take exactly what you want in the fridge!
I have no cooler bag ...
Can't I stay and eat my part here?
Stay and eat, but tomorrow morning you should be gone!
We bought these sausages together ...!
-Hello?
- Tjena, it's Magnus.
- It can be broken at any time.
- I should take me briefly.
I have received nicotine patches from Jarmo.
It should certainly work shit.
The suction has already decreased!
Who can manage this package every time you feel smoke suction?!
Are you still there?!
- I should go.
I just thought that ... - What?
I have to go to the bathroom.
- I am gone when you get home!
- It is safest.
Have you already thrown our soap?!
We bought it together!
Are you a robot?!
Magnus!
Hey!
- New Svid?
Shit!
-Thanks!
I am extremely satisfied.
It's a real Hugo Boss.
Outside Stuttgart they have factory sales.
Everything costs half the price!
They say it is manufacturing defects, but it is not visible.
- What is wrong with this?
- The seam on the inner pocket is not straight.
- It is not visible.
What did it cost?
-Half price.
SEK 4,700.
It is shit cheap for a boss costume!
- You also have something new, huh?
-Yes.
Kenzo.
Reduced by 25 %.
-Why?
- It has a hole on the back somewhere.
It is great quality.
Feel!
Really.
It's not H & amp; M!
- I don't usually ... - no, maybe we shouldn't ...
We work together and ...
- Fan, I have no ... - it's quiet!
I have.
Jenny ... how can you?
-Are you still there?!
- The condoms we bought together!
Yesterday there was an aunt here with sandals on your feet!
They may take off the shoes or take on plastic covers.
Hygiene is the most important thing on a bathhouse.
-But hi!
- Hi, the sock!
- Have you been bathing?
- Yes, the sock is with dad at work.
Do you want to swim a little more?
Take your leg!
Hope in!
You there, with red bathing pants!
Do not touch the sock legs!
Vivaldi: "The Four Seasons" is played
What is this song?!
Now I know, Israel's Schlager grant!
I love mysterious ethno-techno.
Mouth to mouth method?
Never, I said.
Who knows where that trout has been?
Here comes the sock again!
What does she have with her?
Is it an animal?
I think it's a tupé.
Sorry!
- Have you picked up the Uncle's tupe?
-Hello!
How's it going?
- Giantbra!
- I lay with a guy yesterday.
- It doesn't sound stupid!
With whom then?
-With him.
- David Beckham?
We didn't do it in the old usual way.
We had cyber-sex.
We met on a single chat.
Haven't you tried it?
You tell each other what you do ...
It's like fantasies, though with another person.
He was so damn nice!
Wasn't anyone pretended to be him?
No.
Why would David Beckham do it?
We will meet tonight in that parking garage.
I'll have a red hat so he recognizes me.
- What should he have?
- I well recognize David Beckham!
You are funny.
Hello!
But hi!
Oh, congratulations!
What fun, you who have been trying for so long.
When does it come?
Well ...
Now I see!
How narrow you have become, Magnus!
It becomes such a ... optical vision villa when you are so skinny.
You are not too narrow.
It is neat when you contrast each other.
Kristina, do you have a little cig?
That's right.
Helan and Halvan were very successful.
Peter, do you remember what dietary supplement Jarmo should have?
Why can't he have dips sauce for the macaroni like everyone else?
- What good it was!
- It was a wonderful paella, Frida.
It feels just like sitting down in Italy.
Do you know what I ate in Spain this summer?
Pig ears.
It was tapas for the beer.
I didn't understand what it was.
- The bar said it was pig ears.
-How did it taste?
- crispy ... - SUPPOSE ...!
Do you remember when we ate coming in France?
We ordered something that we thought was steak and got a gray mourning.
No one has eaten poop?
It's not as disgusting as you think.
- And that's cheap.
- What disgusting!
You're joking, Frida?!
Now I don't want to eat anymore ...
What do you mean?
You can eat it with potatoes and lingonberries.
We have eaten it several times.
I said it was puddling, but it was poop.
- See that you are joking now, Frida.
-No, I do not.
It is clear that you can have poop in the food!
Was it poop in the pair?
Was it poop in the pael ...?
Yes some.
Come, Ulf!
It was poop in the pair!
I was just joking!
Came back!
It wasn't poop in the pair!
Honey, I was just kidding!
Don't they tolerate a little joke?
We can eat this ourselves, then.
It will be chocolate pudding then.
With poop ...
Just kidding!
Magnus, I was just kidding!
Yes it is...
What do you want with your theater lessons?
- I'll teach me to give lectures?
- What are you, Per?
I am a safety representative at the company and will soon give a major lecture.
So I got this offer ...
- We will start with an exercise, Per.
- Shoot.
-How beautiful you are.
-Thanks.
You have a lot of black in you.
An actor must always be prepared!
- It's not an actor I should ... - Bank!
We take the remote control and a mug.
We take three feelings that you should ...
We say you are horny ... and then we can take euphoria ... and then you are a hairdresser.
You are welcome.
I'll just give a lecture ...
Breathe...
Look at the audience.
Bring in everyone.
Take in the seventh row!
Take the text as well.
The Work Environmental Protection Agency has called for this meeting to ...
Good!
Here we go.
Continue!
Give all you have got!
The Work Environmental Protection Agency has ...
Now I feel like taking an iron!
Hit the door again when you go.
Yes ... but is it really the nose that is the problem?
Rather, I think it's your ears.
They make the rest of the face look a little disproportionate.
What would you say about removing them altogether?
-Does it hurt?
- It pains a few days afterwards.
- But you enjoy it all your life.
- Yes, it's an investment.
I think we put up a while and remove them.
I apologize for having the annual general meeting.
Some of you had to cancel the holiday.
But I considered it to be urgent.
I have considered this and decided to leave my husband Lasse.
Everyone recognizes him from the marketing department.
We have never had it very good.
You can summarize our lives together in two points.
Here is a measurement that I have done since 1996.
It's Lasse's stack and my stack.
Then we come to the sex life.
It is almost non -existent.
It is non -existent.
Nothing.
I have a sketch of the apartment to show what a Friday night looks like.
I put on music and pour up champagne -
- And trying to bring Lasse with me from the living room to the bedroom.
When after an hour of nagging I get him into the bedroom -
-Starts the TV series "The architects behind the world's foremost bridges"-
- And Lasse is like blown away!
As you can see, there is a conflict of interest.
I've decided to say: Thanks for this time, Lasse!
Posyston can give an applause!
Get up!
You get flowers too.
Thanks.
- It will be SEK 16,900.
-What did you say?
I don't want to buy the whole gym.
Membership 2,000, annual card 7,900, freezable card 2,000. There will be 16,900.
No, it will be ... SEK 11,900.
Okay, maybe I took in a little neighbor.
Go to Friskis & amp;
Svettis.
It's a great gym for people who are a bit ...
—... uglier?
- It wasn't me who said it.
But this is the only gym nearby.
Welcome then.
Welcome to Mansforum!
My name is Torbjörn.
André is my name.
Today we will talk tools.
We guys love tools.
Girls like curtains and soaps, but we love tools.
Here we have gathered some cheeky tools.
For example, this one is very useful.
Then we have all the power tools.
Here is the classic drill.
It is great if you are going to drill ...
...hole.
We will test the drill.
If you hold the plank ...
Wait, I'll hold it so ...
No, it doesn't feel really good.
We don't have to drill holes.
Just press the button and show how it sounds.
- It was ... a good drill.
- A real don.
- What do you have there?
- A window.
Five, six, seven, eight ...!
Down!
Spin around!
Go back!
Drive!
- Break!
- You are new, huh?
Welcome.
-Thanks.
In the beginning it goes a little fast.
I can show you at a slower pace.
- Is it okay with you others?
Check out here now.
It's just driving.
Five, Six, Seven, Eight!
I had to ... I couldn't help but.
Shit.
Okay!
Music!
Here we go!
Are you with?!
What do you wear when working with your hands?
It is uncomfortable clothes that apply.
Preferably durable hinge pants with buttoning forward.
You can hang the accessories on the body in hanks.
A bandana keeps the hair away.
It is important with proper shoes.
Preferably a simple low shoe, no socks.
- A loafer or a sandal hall.
- The picture has a good work suit.
This man here ...
Or this ... No, this one.
You have to see the cards on my sponsor children!
- I would just show my cards.
- This is Raoul from Nicaragua.
Very nice ... look, here is Dragan from Bosnia.
She is only four years old.
I think Raoul is much sweeter!
You are the sweetest in the world!
- Here is Janis from Lithuania.
- Some really fit in the side legs.
This one is the cutest!
Look at the ears.
- What an elephant ears!
- They are probably needed down there in the heat.
Here is my, endolo from Botswana.
-Let's see!
- No, that's your turn.
It's you when you were little!
You have painted Afrokull!
- God, what racist!
- You have cheated!
- It's not a competition?!
-Yes!
Daniel, is it okay if I have my teddy bear in bed?
I've had Rufus since I was five years old.
Surely it's not strange?
Then maybe I can have my doll in bed?
I've had Samantha since I was 14 years old.
Program text: Helena Habermann (C) Swedish Television AB 2004
- Hey, keep a little further out!
-What did you say?!
Let's go!