Yes ... my name is ... Ludmilla.
Do you think I'm sexy?
I like you.
Search partners
Partner found
Hi Snuging
Hello awesome woman.
What's your name?
Yes is called Ludmilla
Found name.
What does it cost?
If you want to see it cost.
Why it cost and how the misery?
My sister is sick and needs media.
SEK 2000 for sexually.
Stakar's sister.
But I'm not ready for sex now.
We can chat first.
Mysterious wakeful man, where Haru has been?
Been waiting to meet you
Cute you.
Want to see me?
Yes honey, I want to see you!
It cost 2000 SEK for 1 hour
Will be stretched.
Now have money.
Click Start Camshow.
Pure beautifulness !!
Roof, gorgeous man
I think I love you.
For real.
"Wow. May I see more?"
Do you mean filthy?
Chancellor ...
3000 for more filthy
I shit money from my millionaire
Eru ready my sexy man?
End of the fun
You are a woman of my caliber
Gonatt my dear.
See you soon.
Hello, do you hear me?
Hello Darling!
I've missed you.
Yes, I hear you.
- Have you fixed the camera?
- Yes, as you can see I have fixed the camera.
I've been thinking a lot ... I haven't slept that much.
You were everywhere in my dreams.
How sweet of you!
Thanks.
I am a bit nervous.
I have an important question for you.
-Have you?
-Yes.
Wait.
Do you see this ring?
I want to ask if you want to marry me, here on the internet.
- Oh, honey!
- I want you for myself.
You are very cute, but it will be expensive.
I have this job and everything ...
What does it cost?
Tens of thousands.
- Tens?!
-Yes.
Five thousand would be a better price.
We are dear.
- Tiot thousand or nothing.
-Okay.
Wait for a moment, honey.
Sorry you had to wait, honey.
I had to transfer money from the million account.
- Now I have the money.
- What good, honey.
Then I pay ten thousand here ... so there, please.
Well then...
-Are you prepared?
-Yes.
Do you take this man to your spouse for all the future and your whole life?
Yes.
Oh, how nice it feels.
Do you take this beautiful woman to your wife?
Yes.
Thanks honey.
Now I feel whole again.
Then it's time for you to see your husband for the first time.
I would love to.
Hello!
What is going on?
I do not hear you.
- I have to ... — love, do you hear me?
Do you want to delete your account?
Translation: Rebecca Simpson Sveriges Television AB 2018