How did it go when you were excluded?
Then I went in there.
And then there is a library ...
Straight to the left it is a library.
Inside, I sat and talked to the elder brothers.
You are 19 years old, and there are two men?
-Three.
-Three men?
This is the story    about all the children who have been injured -
–A of the religion    their parents chose for them.
those kids are everywhere.
They are raised in various religious    context and they are many.
All children who grow up    In Religious Home not bad -
- But now it is about    about those who did.
Now we'll listen to them.
Very many of the people we talk to,    regardless of community -
–Can tell about the threat of losing    all about sin is too great.
When David, raised in Pentecost-   movement, came out as gay-
- he was afraid    to lose his family.
I was afraid to end up in hell.
I knew I was different.
When I was going out ... I came out for my mom when I was 14.
... I was very scared of not being accepted -
- And get "lectures" in this, and it would be talked about and changed.
I was afraid that she and Dad would break contact with me.
The fear of a child, not to have their parents, their fixed point ...
That it would be taken from one was very busy.
But even if the fear was there    during childhood -
- did not pay David his parents    when he came out.
For many of the children I speak with    gets worse.
when challenging    the religious system -
- risers to lose    their families and closest.
Leija, who during the teens understood    that she was bisexual -
—in saw that she had to break    with her religion.
This meant she lost everything,    was subjected to threat -
–And now lives with protected identity    without contact with his family.
Both of my parents are very religious and active in the mosque.
For them it would be disaster -
- If it came out that I go against certain cornerstones in religion.
One of the most dangerous things available is when women in a Muslim context-
- Determines to leave Islam.
It can be followed by threats and violence.
This is something I have received help and support with escaping.
When you think about your parents' decision to raise you Muslim-
- How to look at it today?
I am obviously against my parents raising me Muslim.
I wished it was a more open upbringing.
It is very, that they are Muslims.
But in a democratic, secular society-
- So I think ...
... they could have given me the best conditions -
- To make your own decisions.
This Muslim upbringing that I received -
- had no room for unconditional love.
All love was conditional.
As long as I was a good Muslim I deserved their love -
–What made everything so much more scary -
- When you went against your family and religion.
When I left Islam, I had to do it in the hidden -
- And reflect on every decision I made.
In conversations with the young, it is    a group that is particularly afraid of -
- To be excluded and lose    Contact with their parents:
Those who have been children    within Jehovah's Witnesses.
Like Jonnah    they have grown up with the knowledge -
- that they lose their family    if they leave religion.
For Jonnah    the exclusion became a fact -
- When she began a relationship    with a guy without getting married.
The family was then allowed to come    to resign.
Then they came home to me on Monday -
- And then it was my mom, my dad and my brother.
Dad didn't say very much, he was very quiet and calm.
Defense mechanism, I think.
My brother didn't say anything either.
But then Dad said before they would go:
"You understand what this means?"
- "Yes, I understand what that means."
- And you have no contact?
-No, we do not have that.
It's a shame, actually.
An early morning it rings on the door and there is dad and mom - stands
- With a lactose -free princess cake and a pack of deep red roses.
Then I knew immediately that they would say hello then.
I cook coffee.
We sit down.
I understand that they will go and never come back again.
So of course I get really sad and cry in my mother's arms.
"I'm not an evil man, mom."
She pats me on the head and says:
"I know you are not, but this is how it will be."
That's what is so awful.
They are my parents -
- But most of all they are Jehovah's Witnesses.
I think they are in control of me more than they show.
They may check social media.
They have probably seen that I live with Oskar and have tattoos.
They probably think I live very dangerous.
- Are they worried about you, do you think?
- Yes, I definitely think so.
Their picture is ... it is so complex to explain.
Now I am "out in the world" as they say -
- And is under Satan's grip in their opinion.
Mm.
It is such a strange feeling to explain.
In Jehovah's Witnesses    Information material is described -
- how a person who is excluded    should be treated.
There stands:
In the case of one who does not remain    in Christ's doctrine, we read:
I know they miss me.
The first period was my parents who heard.
Me: "Obviously we're going to become a family again."
So I replied quickly.
But every time I met them, I saw their gaze on me.
It is this look that looks at an immoral person.
And it's so damn offensive.
Most young people we are talking to    have left Jehovah's Witnesses.
The ones we come into contact with that yet    have not left, dare not participate.
They are afraid of being revealed    and thus excluded.
But then we get in touch with a girl    who absolutely want to join.
She must be anonymous, but wants    her story to reach the outside world.
We call her Selma.
She    is still an active witness -
–And only 15 years.
My parents are divorced, so I live every other week.
My mother is a witness.
At her home, there are meetings, worship services and Bible reading.
At home with dad ... he is not with, and not his wife either-
- So there is nothing spiritual.
What is it like to move between two worlds?
That every other week is a witness and every two weeks not be?
It is probably quite strenuous for my mental health.
I have some anxiety: "Imagine if someone comes on me."
"Mom gets angry if she learns that I'm not at the meetings."
Now that we talk, you have to hide your identity.
Why is it important?
If you leave, you are considered evil and that you are on Satan's side.
Then you are not good socializing and become completely frozen.
I wish I was not part of this religion -
- It's pretty ... It's a pretty big weight.
/Crying in the voice/
It is tedious?
- But every two weeks you don't have to.
-Yes.
Are you sorry for losing everyone in the congregation who is close to you?
Mm.
-It is difficult.
- mm.
What do you think about in this religion ...
... end up in what you've ended up in?
That you can be excluded if you do not do as they say.
It is not at all fair.
It is well illegal as well -
- To completely close out a person and remove everything from it?
It's pretty awful.
There are those who are stuck in exclusion for several years.
There are those who have killed themselves because they have been so lonely.
When your dad was excluded, did you become afraid of what would happen to him?
I probably didn't really know what was happening.
I was pretty young.
I only knew that exclusion was a bad thing.
But it had never happened in our congregation.
But it made me be ashamed of my last name and that ... /cries /
They made me feel bad because ... my dad was my dad and stuff.
I was ashamed of a witness walked past me while Dad stood next to me.
I was ashamed of my dad.
That's something I regret very much.
If we again take Jehovah's Witnesses as an example ...
If you choose another religion -
- Another faith or to express yourself as an atheist etc ...
Firstly, you grow up with the idea that God will kill you on his doomsday -
- If you do not live up to the ideal.
And it is a death threat, it is violence.
It is mental violence that the children get with them from their upbringing.
In addition, they are threatened with -
– To lose contact with his family, friends and relatives -
- What is a social suicide.
It is clear that a child wants to be his parents of the team.
If the child feels that God will have to death it ...
The post -traumatic stress that comes with it prevents the child.
No man is free with a gun against his head.
Today Vera-Linn is a socio-economist    and expert on the situation for children-
- which grows up    in dogmatic, religious environments.
But she has her own story.
and when we get to know each other a little    better, that's one thing she wants to show.
I've been smashed all week.
As soon as I have thought about this, I have thought: "This is not happening."
Even on the train here I thought, "It's not really."
- Does it feel okay?
Do you want?
-Yes absolutely.
It will feel good afterwards.
It will feel "empowing".
But right now it feels a bit heavy.
Should you tell us about the car ride then?
One day when I drove home from work -
- So I did not drive home, but just kept driving.
I came out on this road and stopped at a nature reserve.
I didn't know why.
But then I realized that I was there to take my life.
Shit, here it is.
Shit, here it is!
Damn, what sick.
Now I recognize myself.
This is where I parked.
Vera-Linn himself grew up    within Jehovah's Witnesses.
But there is an occasion,    a place where everything changed.
It has been ten years since then, and    she has never been back before.
I was sitting in the car -
- And just looked straight out.
I just looked and ...
So I opened the glove compartment -
- Put out the razor blades and thought, "Now I'm driving."
I have the scars on my arm, which I have tattooed over.
It's ten years ago, just over.
You are still a member of Jehovah's Witnesses.
And you are baptized, so you know you can't leave.
What would have been the consequences if you had left?
Every now and then it would have been terrible.
I had nothing else at that point.
It would have been like going out in nothing.
When you are here and all this happens, what do you want away from?
I wasn't there.
I think it was.
I felt, "I don't exist."
The person I am does not exist.
I don't live, I'm dead.
If I'm already dead, why not go all the way?
Although I never thought the thought clean, I already knew it.
- What did you know?
- That this was not for me.
Somewhere within me I knew it wasn't true -
- But I didn't dare to think so.
And when you realize that this is not just a pain in itself -
- Out, in addition, it is a very high mountain you have to climb ...
What does the mountain look like?
You have to make a new life, new friends and a new meaning with your life.
You have to start over with all existential issues.
You are like an infant, you start again.
And all post -traumatic stress.
You feel that you are not feeling so good.
And in that situation will it be easier for you to take your life?
That is what is so difficult to explain.
At the moment I was just empty.
It didn't feel easier, it didn't feel harder, it felt nothing.
Nothing was for real.
Nothing felt like I was me, because I couldn't exist.
It was just a shell.
And what does a shell matter?
What happened next?
I sat looking out and thought, "Is there any reason?"
I thought and thought and thought, but didn't come up with anything.
"No."
But then I came up with a reason - my siblings.
They were quite small then.
I felt:
"If I do this, they will be trauma-tetted. They have not done anything."
For everyone else, I felt "whatever", but I couldn't do that to them.
But you first cut yourself.
But you couldn't complete it?
No, because I understood what it would have for them.
What did you do?
It was a disappointment.
I had thought of everything except them.
Then it was just to go into town and Sahlgrenska.
So it was with it.
- Do you meet your siblings today?
-Yes absolutely.
Vera-Linn did not take her life    when she was here ten years ago.
Instead, she climbed that mountain -
- left life as Jehovah's Witness    and acquired a whole new life.
How did it go when you were excluded?
Then I went in there.
Then there is a library ...
Straight to the left it is a library.
Inside, I sat and talked to the elder brothers.
You are 19 years old, and there are two men?
Three.
Now in retrospect it is tough.
Every now and then it wasn't.
It was tough, but you didn't think about it then as you think about it now.
There are many times I have sinned -
- And then I have confessed it several times and sat there with them.
So it was nothing strange.
It is not until now afterwards that I ...
Although I was 19 years-
- So maybe it would have been a woman with at least.
What do you usually confess when you go to the elder brothers?
It depends on who you are and what you have done.
For me it was often -
- I might have been too intimate with a guy.
And that I had smoked, I once told the elder brothers.
But mainly that I had been intimate.
So you sit as a young girl talking about sex with older men?
- What are you thinking about it today?
- Not to reduce it ...
... but for them it is so normal.
It is their truth to do it.
But it should not go so.
But they don't understand it.
So I almost feel sorry for them.
How has it affected you to have been involved in these things?
Yes ... shame, I would say.
Absolute shame.
Too often, it was also men that I have known all my life.
Not all, but some of them have seen me grow up.
You sit there and have the tail between your legs for being ashamed.
Not just for their sin, but also because it is someone you know well -
- And so you should tell you about this.
And afterwards when one has confessed -
- And then goes to a meeting at the Kingdom Hall ...
You walk past each other, and I remember the feeling: "They know everything about me."
So shame.
What do you think when you see this?
Exclusion is a very painful experience.
I'm a little divided in my view of it.
It is a terribly difficult period for the individual.
You do not know what is true, what values to live by -
–And you don't have the positive from the congregation or family:
Social support, community and so on.
But in the long term you get more an opportunity -
- To shape your life as you want.
It can be long -term comfort for those who end up in that situation.
It's so fascinating -
—That you value the collective, the religious congregation, higher-
- Every one values your own children or your partner.
It is in line with that reputation is so central to us as Art-
–At we even are prepared to give up a child -
- To maintain the rumor in the collective.
It is of course a terrible experience for the child -
–Ee knowing that you are away priority -
- That the parents have chosen the religious community over one's self.
What would you like to say to your children -
- That has grown up within Jehovah's Witnesses because you were a witness?
My love is neither less nor more than when I was a witness.
My mommy love has always been the same.
I hope they have a good life.
But I also apologize.
- In what community did the children grow up?
- In Pentecostal church.
It felt good.
It was fun that they wanted to get involved.
It is a good place to be, safe, with loving people.
Texting: Malin Westhall Swedish Media Text for SVT