c. sound mobile signal "Crazy Frog"
It's Leif.
Tjena, Micke!
Well.
Shouldn't they be in the hunting team anymore?
It was damn nice of you.
Yes, but that would be nice.
We say so, Micke.
See ya.
It was Micke.
Now we are in the hunting team again.
I don't understand why we can't hunt as we have always done.
Have you seen our chips?
Not a moose devil!
We have thinned out.
- I have shot three, so animals are available.
-Three Invalid Rims, Billy.
"My name is Billy and I am so good who has shot handicapped moose."
- I had shot them if I wanted to.
- Yes, but you tried.
And missed.
I shot warning shots to drive them away.
How do you think it looks if they run around and multiply?
We get the forest full of piss.
You get a tie mask only if you see the moose you shot.
It is called wildlife care.
If they want to see the licenses we are smoked.
God damn!
We have laser printers.
We can print what we want.
You are good at "Paint", so just print a license.
Then I'll take Tony's damn last year's record of three moose.
Did you hear that the wolf took two sheep at Matsson?
Soon you dare not release the kids.
- What the hell, have you invited them here?
-Quiet.
I owe Leif a favor.
- And we need people for the hunting team.
- You know how they set for me.
- Micke, damn what a wonderful to be with!
- Rocko!
How big you have become.
- Hunting license - do you have it, right?
- Yes, what the hell do you think?
It's done.
- We are probably no fucking amateurs.
- Yes, that's good.
- Hold still, then.
- But what the hell, let me go!
- Does anyone start to be afraid of competition?
-No.
We will shoot other than hedgehogs.
There are none, but you may have received the license on "9-Eleven".
Sharpen.
Now we hand out the passports and then we run.
- Check, a hedgehog!
Are you going to run?
-Have you become a standup comedian?
Okay, are you on the passports?
C.Teletext.urfjarran - JO.
- Yeah.
Yes.
Leffe Öhman is in position.
-Ready.
-Fine.
Then I go with Rocko.
C. soundlord
C. soundstigmer animal sound
Wait.
Something fucking sound here.
c. sound imitates animal sounds
C.Teletext.urfjarranet Anyone where the sound comes from?
I sound like a brown moose, so the cows get a little spiked in the berry.
Leif, shut up when you're on a pass!
You don't know anything!
You sound disturbed.
The dog gets completely confused.
Who the hell brings a confused dog that does not see a difference between man and moose?
That's enough!
Run again!
Leif, keep quiet if it confuses.
Well, okay.
Damn people don't know how to hunt.
c. sound imitates animal sound
Okay, calm and nice.
I will release you.
Go for it!
The C. sound dog barks
Rocko has got track.
Seems to move towards Billy.
C.Teletext.urfjarranbilly, pass up.
He's coming to you.
c. sound imitates animal sound
C. sound rifle shot
C.Teletext.urfjarranbilly here.
Shot a moose calf.
Located 75 meters in front of my pass.
Cursed!
C.Teletext.urfjarranden lies.
Over and out.
YES!
- Good, Billy!
Nice shot.
- was damn good.
- Congratulations, Billy!
- thank you, Ronny.
Have we started shooting moose children now?
Good, Billy.
No rifles are needed.
It had been enough with a dart arrow.
We have to find the mother who is feeling bad.
- Good, Billy!
-Stop.
It is an annual calf you see well.
It looks like a harmless turkey.
Not worth a twig.
Good job, Billy!
Really nice.
You have inherited your dad's hunting genes.
-Do you think?
-Absolutely!
The brother has inherited the mother's genes and fades like a girlfriend.
- A twig you should have!
-Thanks so much.
It sits well.
We get help to take this out and we will have lunch later.
There you have a racker too.
Cheers for Billy!
First moose this year.
Learn to become more.
- With such speed you hit my record.
-We'll see!
Where is Leif?
"It's a last year's calf."
Don't you think I see it?
But should you get a twig ...
C. sound rifle shot
Satan!
What do you say now?
160 meters, sneaky and fucking, but I "snapped" into his eyes.
- Fantastic, damn how good you are.
- Thanks, Tony.
How?
Time for the twig to Leffe Öhman?
Are you completely stupid?
For real?
We are on moose hunting.
You know what a moose looks like.
That is a Tjäder.
If we can shoot moose children, can we count on this one?
Right?
It is almost as big as the turkey he shot.
Still a moose.
It's a bird.
Just do I think it's strange?
This is not Stockholm with customs fees and trams and 7-Eleven.
It's the forest!
Here the animals run freely and you shoot what you see.
- It's the whole point of hunting.
- Tony is right, Leif.
God damnit!
You can't shoot a Tjäder now.
If you had come home with such a nice tether, I would have given you a twig.
Yes, I don't know ...
Happ!
The Skanenjägarn was right!
He won, we drive it.
How long should you be sipping - all day?
Fy fuck.
You can email when you are ready.
Well, it's time.
We're running.
Cheers, Billy!
Bowl!
Cursed.
Hell.
Leif, do you want to run your sex sounds or what it was?
My God, you can just get started.
I don't have my whole life.
Then you save them for next time.
I release Rocko, then we drive.
So, run away!
C. sound dog shell
Rocko has got some track.
Leif, he's on his way to you.
Closer.
Come on, your fat bastard.
C. sound imitates moose
Cursed!
Billy, don't shoot!
He is mine!
Billy!
Fy Satan!
YES!
- What the hell are you doing, Leif?
-Move!
Leif, what are you doing?
Leif!
- I ... - put off!
You've shot enough today.
This is mine.
Yes, Leif Öhman here.
I have taken it, at Billy's passport.
I shot, so he's stone dead.
Damn!
Nice, Leif!
Really nice.
I heard how Billy missed, so I ran after and shot the fanfare.
Now is the time for the twig, huh?
The big hunter should get the trophy.
Tony?
Say like it is instead, Leif.
Fy damn what a fucking ...
There we have it, the twig.
You know?
You can get this one instead.
You can just run and pick it up.
As you drove on the moose, we do not need a dog.
- What the hell are you mingle about?
- Billy shot, I saw it.
You ran around like Rambo.
You shot, Billy.
Right?
Well, it was, actually.
It is no more than fair.
It goes to you.
- Here we have the real hunter!
-Thanks.
Come here.
Leif, to shoot a tether I can agree to, but ...
... to twist a trophy in that way.
It is not OK.
Bill pan!
- bowl for the king!
- Yes, bowl for fucking.
Billy should come along the next time we go out and look for a wolf.
Leif can also come along.
He may be able to attract the wolf with his lure calls.
Or sound like a wolf!
Leif!
Run that goose or whatever it was, it was nice!
It sounded so alive!
For real!
Come on now, we hear!
- I go and piss.
- Now he got angry.
C.TELETEXT.Sangc.sanghelan goes C.Sangsjung Hopp Faderallan Lallan Lion
C.Teletext.sangc.sanghelan goes C.Sangsjung Hopp Faderallan lion
Idiots!
Sound like a wolf ...
C. sounded animals murmur
It's the Wolf Devil!
And then the old man said: Hi, I had no legs.
- Bill for Billpan!
-Bowl.
C. sound rifle shot
What the hell was that?
Do you know what this is?
The weapon I murdered the wolf devil with!
- What the hell are you talking about, Leif?
- Do you hear badly?
I murdered the wolf!
- Did you take the wolf devil?
- Yes, yes, yes!
The wolf pussy is dead.
- We must see that.
- Yes, go and watch.
Damn, how dark it is.
I don't see a shit.
Light the lamp, Tony.
Who is the big hunter now, huh?
c.kudleif Ylar like a wolf
- Oh, go to hell ... —Fy fuck, damn village!
Damn oyra!
Cursed BYRACKA!
Oh, hell.
Fuck.
Rocko.
- What the hell have you done, Leif?
- Fan, sorry!
I didn't see, Tony.
Damn, Tony.
Sorry.
- Forgiveness, we hear.
- You bastard!
Stop him!
Help, Billy!
Texting: Ludvig Köhler (C) Swedish Television AB 2019