Kristina ...
We have been together for a long time now ...
... but it has not been so exciting in bed lately.
-No.
- You might be able to live it up a bit.
I bought a toy for us.
You ... I have a radish in the jacket.
The radish is angry.
Angry!
The radish is very angry on you.
An angry radish!
Grrr!
But you should not stand here and freeze with the Tjillevippen bar!
Hang with me home so you can get a grogg and a hot bath instead.
I talk to you!
Come back!
Can you keep a secret?
- I am thinking of free to Frida.
- But God, what fun!
- Congratulations, Magnus!
How are you going to do?
-I do not know.
It must be a memory for the life of Frida.
Think like this:
Frida is alone at home.
Suddenly she hears someone singing opera.
She looks out and sees you singing opera from the roof hatch on a limousine!
You are climbing up for the fire steps and frees.
- Isn't that out of Pretty Woman?
-Yes!
The world's best movie!
Ulf, how did you free?
You have to build excitement and then surprise.
I was out partying and didn't come home all night.
She became very worried and thought that an accident happened.
At dawn it rang on the door, and outside were two police officers -
- Two friends to me, and said that an accident happened ...
She had to accompany them to the Bårhuset for identification.
There, under a sheet, I lay.
She removed the sheet and was devastated!
Then I shouted, "Kristina, do you want to marry me?"
- Was it successful?
- No, not as I had thought.
- I don't know where to start ... - take it easy!
One thing at a time.
He was completely naked under the rock.
You saw the whole lollipop and everything.
- How did he look otherwise?
- Card and with medium blond hair.
- Underwhelmed.
Do you know who he is then?
- I have to look at it later.
- Do you have any register?
- Yes, we have some information.
-Phone number?
E -mail address?
-No I do not think so.
- You should bake as often as you can!
- You might as well buy?
Do you hear!
Would you be able to fold out?
- Well!
If I got the chance!
-No.
Sometimes you may not get the chance, but you have to take it, as the girl said.
Think about how many would see you naked.
All children would say, "Why doesn't the aunt have any clothes on?"
- Her god, the kids!
- Children are natural creatures.
- They are naked all the time.
-Yes is not it!
Utvik is a way to market who I am and what I do!
- You work as a teacher, Jenny.
- All professions need a little puff.
Exactly!
It is an interview too.
- Don't you want to be a role model?
- Just that, a role model.
I want to be with my calendar.
"Ulf - Inner Seller of the Year 2004."
Twelve months, twelve pictures, an easy -to -dress Ulf - which God created me.
The products are in focus, it's advertising ...
You can get some items.
- Kristina!
- We have more at home.
Magnus, bring one to the company.
You can send them to your loved ones.
It's not so stupid.
You can have it in the teacher room.
- Imagine that it really will get rid of!
-I love you.
Then the menu is finished.
Should we fill in the name form, so is it done?
What should we be called when we get married?
We haven't talked about that, huh?
- Do you want to change my name?
- Yes, it's more practical.
Should I change my name and wipe out my identity?
We don't have to take my last name.
We can find a new one.
Yes we do.
We take "Hitler"!
"Frida Hitler. Hello. I'm married to a dictator" -
- "Who wants me to throw my old name."
Or better yet: "Nonym. Hello. Frid - a -Nonym!"
Do you want that?
So it will be.
You may want to block me?
We take the name "idiot".
I will be called since I married you!
- "Frida unsatisfied".
- "Magnus tormented by his frozen".
- I want to divorce!
-Me too!
My life is so bad, Carita.
But Per -Arne, what are you saying?
- I don't live fully.
- But Per - Arne!
Sometimes I wish I was someone else.
A young and strong man-
- As takes the initiative and is respected and successful.
But Per -Arne, it's yourself you describe!
What do you say, Carita?
You could not describe yourself in better words.
- Do you own it?
- Yes, I do, Per -Arne.
Yes, so you can feel there ...
... that you would like to be such a successful person ...
Be so beautiful and good and ... yes, so there ...
Not everyone can be, Carita.
There are few people spoiled.
But another ... yes, you!
There you are in shelter!
- It's been a nice wedding day.
-Yes actually.
- And it's not over yet.
-No...
I'll be coming to you soon, Kristina.
I'll just fix one thing.
I have got such hard skin under the soles of the feet.
Imagine that dead skin can be so hard.
- Are you in a good mood today?
- Yes, I was on a date this weekend.
I met an amazing woman!
- Is it anyone I know?
-Yes actually.
Her name is Gunnel.
- It's my mother too.
-Just.
It's your mom.
What the hell ... Have you met my mom?
I don't usually go all the way the first evening, but now everything was right!
- What the hell are you saying?
- We have loved each other.
How did it happen?
When two adults like each other and hug close ...
--... So the father's snoop can grow ... - How have you met her?!
It said click on your birthday party.
- Now when she divorced from Lennart ... - from my dad!
He did not affirm her femininity.
He couldn't give her pleasure.
I think you will see my and Gunnel's relationship as something beautiful.
- It's a lot to melt.
-Yes I understand that.
It must take the time it takes.
Now that we still talk about it ....
Can you stay away this weekend?
We want to spend time on your hand.
Is not it nice?
You are the apple of my eye.
- Should we go through the budget again?
- Why did you free if we can't afford it?
I did not know that we would pay the makeup and the hairdresser's living.
- Don't you want me to be nice?
- Yes, but we have to cut down on something.
- Did we have to have real champagne?
- No, we can have rosehip soup.
- "Oh, what original!"
- Now you are a little ridiculous.
We can buy the rings in a chewing gum automatic and save a lot!
Or buy a regular, great ring that does not have a carat diamond.
We can save on the wedding dress and be naked - "clothing: nothing!"
- Will you be happy then?
- Okay, we take a really long loan.
- The wedding trip goes to Osby!
-That's it!
I want to get divorced!
Great idea!
Me too.
You?
What is it, the guy?
Tiger?
You like football, huh?
- I have tickets to the derby.
- You're not my dad!
Do you know, this will be the happiest day of our entire life.
Now to the difficult.
Who should we iron?
We can only fit with 80 people.
- How many we have on the list?
–103.
- This is not easy.
-No.
Is it anyone you can iron, purely spontaneously?
Family, related ... No, it will be difficult.
- It would be Anders.
- He is one of my best friends!
- You know how he gets when he drinks.
- He talks and is very funny.
- What else should we delete?
- I like to iron Robert.
It's a bit hard for your old boyfriend to come ...
-We are friends!
- To my friends, I must say:
"This is Robert, he has seen my wife naked."
- Then we iron him, then.
-Thanks.
Then I iron ... Ulrika.
-My sister?
- She will be acidic all evening.
- No Robert - no Ulrika.
- It's my sister.
- POFF!
There, Ulrika smoked.
- Then I ask to have Amanda.
"Why do I never meet a normal guy?"
- "Because you're stupid in your head!"
Then I delete your countryiscs, so we all avoid stonewashed jeans.
So!
POFF!
There your aunts disappeared, then the spirits are enough.
There, your parents smoked.
Now we are 80. Are you satisfied now?
- I want to divorce!
-Me too!
Now to Bosses spark plug school!
Conny!
Do I look fat in this one?
-Hello!
-Hey!
Forgive me for being late.
I cut myself when I shaved.
I also cut myself before, but then I changed shaving delights.
I am smooth like a children's butt.
- Feel!
- No, I can imagine.
Hello!
Have you ordered a table?
--Ulf and Magnus.
- Here everyone is welcome.
We have slightly different menus to choose from.
We have the "business menu" ...
... "The Jubilee menu", "The Spring Menu" ...
- This looks delicious.
- It's "the love menu".
- Champagne and grated lobster.
--Ulf, not the love menu.
- Should we not have a gratin lobster?
-Okay.
It is noticeable who is the gentleman in the house.
Congratulations.
It's nothing strange to us.
There is nothing strange with us two.
No...
Do you see anything new with me?
No.
Nothing?
Well ... have you done anything with your hair?
I bought a new can!
Yes Yes.
It was nice!
- Nice, Britt.
-Do you think so?
I need a taste advice.
Kristina and I celebrate the six -year anniversary on Tuesday.
I bought a little thing.
What do you say about this one?
I'm not an expert, but ...
Oh this night this lovely night
As we call Bella Notte
- The servitude was a bit strange.
- I think the service was great.
I got a feeling that the waitress thought we were a couple.
- We are not gay at all.
- No, not a dew gay.
But the idea is quite exciting.
There are good features out there.
Livat.
It's good island.
There are good features out there!
Livat.
- Britt, come on now!
- I don't want to come along.
British ...
- I don't look wise.
- Lasse and Inger are waiting.
I have a pimple on my nose.
I look like a stop light.
Masquerade!
Welcome!
- What did you dress up for?
- Don't you see it?
I'm clown.
-Hello!
Hello!
-Gosh!
Nice costume!
- What are you dressed up for, Ulf?
- Don't you see it?
She who was on TV before ... Rosanne!
You should not be Peter Harryson anyway!
I'm you!
Don't you recognize yourself?
Now Jenny is coming.
- Hello!
What a coincidence.
- This is Isaac, my new guy.
-Hello.
What are you dressed up for?
- I couldn't dress up.
- Isak works as a rabbi.
Sieg Heil!
Achtung!
All the Jew Raus!
What then?
Come in!
- Magnus, coffee?
- Britt, you are a wonderful woman.
- Are you holding it, Conny?
Can't take off your can tonight?
- I don't know if I pallet.
- But it was so long ago, Britt.
Just for my sake, Britt.
-Who are you?
- I'm Leif.
- Where is Britt?
- She left two years ago.
Two years ago?
That time last fall at Birka Princess, then ...?
Sure it was wonderful.
Love Hurts
Love Scars ...
It is the person behind the can that you fall in love with.
Text: Cathrine Pettersson (C) Swedish Television AB 2004
Oh, you're so nice, Ulf.
I want you!
You are so sexy.
Take me!
- What is it, Kristina?
- I dreamed a nightmare.