Kristina!
Magnus said Frida always makes breakfast on the bed for him.
If you want it, you can sleep in the kitchen.
They are so cozy.
This is probably because Frida makes breakfast on the bed.
Here...
So.
Now you have breakfast on the bed.
-What are you doing?
- You get such a stupid hairstyle when you slept.
Ah ... it doesn't matter!
Now we have problems with the printer on level five again.
Hello!
I posed a question.
I have no memory that I have said, "Be so good and get on!"
Well, sorry!
It was not meant to rush in.
Should I...
... go out again?
I go out again.
I am busy.
Can you send the butter, Kristina?
Kristina!
Can you send the butter?
Can you send the butter!
Thanks!
- Now we want help with the printer ... - Set yourself in the taped box!
You should stand in it if you want to ask something.
Why?
Maybe because I will not help you otherwise.
You are standing on the tape.
Are you in the collection for Karin?
It is her birthday.
We were going to buy four orrefors glass, "Serenad".
She collects them.
- What have the others put?
–20 SEK.
Have they laid so much?
Yes ... it will be fun.
So then.
I write here.
Or you, by the way ...
I just want to spend SEK 10.
I don't like Karin.
Or 5 kr ...
... or actually nothing.
The printer flash at "Stand by".
We have changed tones and checked the magazine.
When you were little, were you out playing with your friends then?
Yes...
Then did you start training hockey and football?
And then you started running a mop, walking on hip and kissing girls?
Yes, what then?!
Had you been tinkering with computers instead, you would not have been here as an idiot.
Look at him.
There he sits - stupid like a log!
He has not a wise word he has said, yet he has the same salary as me.
What is it that smells?
Yes, Paul.
Day in and day in ... His ugliness knows no bounds.
Like a surveillance plum ...
- Is it okay if I turn off?
- No, I want to listen.
What is the fucking hairstyle?
God, Peter!
Check out such mini tomatoes!
God, what they are cute!
When I look like this, I get such a desire to have children!
-How are you?
- I feel low.
It was a heavy day at work.
I've got a new colleague ...
We can focus on shopping now?
Don't walk around and feel all the time!
What then feels?
First you are happy, then you are sad.
We're going to shop now.
- Yes, but now I feel ... - precise there!
Now you get so aggressive.
It is completely unsustainable!
- I want the jam!
- Now you changed the feeling again.
Typical.
We put you in the wagon and I'll drive around with you.
Then it goes faster.
This feels very pleased.
So.
You are employed to help us!
The printer bastard does not work!
- That where the error we know.
- Make something, then!
- It should not happen.
- Should it be so impossible?!
It is not impossible.
I know how to do it.
- Be so damn busy and do it, then!
-No...
... I think you have a very unpleasant tone.
I am in a hurry!
Okay.
Stand in the box and sing "You are the only one".
Come on now, for hell ...
I will not help you otherwise.
Please.
Can't you help me?
I'm sitting here waiting for a song.
You are the only one...
Are you sorry, the old man?
Is it because you have no girl or because you are so narrow?
your mouth, your eyes your soothing voice
and that's why i beg you now
mere you give me a single little word I am yours
Do you remember "I Will Always Love You" with Whitney Houston?
It was a long time since you heard.
I can't cope this.
Take it you!
You can lift now.
Test once!
You, it's already noticeable.
God, how nice!
I almost fall asleep up here.
You do a damn good job.
I admire you.
I feel I can learn a lot from you.
You are so sharp ...
You are a role model.
Good.
Hello.
-Excuse me.
Where were we?
- You said I was an idiot.
Phone signal
Who could it be?
Yes, hello.
It's Gun.
Huh?
If I can answer any questions?
Who is asking?
Bear?
It was a Grant Name!
A real Bamsebjörn ...
Yes ... huh?
If I want to subscribe to Svenska Dagbladet?
You ... can you ask a counter -question, bear?
Do you know what I am wearing right now?
No.
I'm purely naked, bear.
Yes it's me.
Just as God has created me.
What did you say?
Introductory offer?
If you pallet you here, you should get an introduction that you should not forget!
Yes ... do you know what I do while we talk about Svenska Dagbladet?
I play with myself.
I'm like an amusement park!
Come and go the jumping sofa with me!
Hello!
Bear?
And I
will always love you
and I will always
Love
You
Fairly good.
Take it again where you really mean what you sing!
Hi, my name is Gunnar.
Welcome to this Pantomim Course!
You have been commissioned to prepare each Pantomim.
We start with that.
What's your name?
Jasmine?
Can you mima for us?
Oh, what it blows today.
Full headwind.
It's hard to go when it blows.
Thanks.
Great!
You have nice motor skills, nice and soft movements.
Now you talked while you mimicked.
Can you try again and be quiet?
You are welcome.
Sch ...
Jasmine!
Try to be completely silent.
Oh, what it blows.
It's full storm.
Good.
Great ... But now you talked again.
Did you notice that?
It becomes clearer if you talk.
Yes, but Pantomim means being able to express something without words.
But that was good.
Okay.
Here we have the next pantomimics.
The scene is yours.
You are welcome.
Thanks.
A minimalist mim ...
- What did it imagine?
- I queued for the Social Insurance Office.
Well.
Good!
- Jasmine?
They would have understood better if he talked.
-Yes?
- It seems to be wrong with the mailbox.
- Is it wrong with the mailbox?
- Yes, I tried to get in ... the post.
You ... what could be wrong then?
Come in!
You see nothing in the stairs.
Can't you see what happened?
It seems to be okay.
Now I'll move on.
- Don't you borrow a toilet?
-No thanks.
Thanks anyway.
You don't get out.
It is wrong with the lock.
- But it worked just recently.
- Yes, but now it's wrong.
Ouch!
I got a shock.
There is power in the handle.
Yes ... I faint!
Hold me!
Help Help!
So yes.
Well, so yes.
Now we're talking.
What the hell!
You are sick!
Hello!
I will report you!
Post ... you took my post.
Oh, now it would taste good with juice.
Oh, it was good!
Good...
... though now you talked and so you used props.
It gets a little more luxurious then, and not just pretending.
- Jasmine?
- It was both clear and good.
We end there for today.
Kristina!
Can you pick up a pair of bigger pants?
These were too tight.
Kristina!
A pair of regular jeans.
Size 34 may work.
Okay.
Are you angry still?
Kristina is fat!
A little fat, Kristina?
Kristina is fat.
Look, Kristina!
What a wonderful meal!
You're not only beautiful - you can cook too.
Should I put on something more comfortable?
By all means.
FART!
When we meet the others tomorrow ... We celebrate our anniversary.
- Do you remember how we met?
- Yes, we met at the Sollentuna Fair.
- We drank coffee together in the dining room.
- Yes, and it doesn't hold.
It is the world's worst history.
It's not even a story.
No, but that's the truth.
If someone asks, we say we met in Venice.
Venice?
I have left my boyfriend.
I get lost and you help me.
We go gondola, you let me off.
You have fallen blindly in love with me.
You are looking through Venice's all hotels.
When you find me you climb up the balcony, and there we kiss each other.
"Shit, french fries"!
You're joking?
-Not?
They will never believe us.
- Yes.
Only we say the same thing.
- I never remember that.
- I have written it down for you.
- It's a whole book.
- I have filled with some details.
Plug on it, so I hear you tomorrow.
Then we went through an alley with a bookstore and came to Marcusplatsen.
There, my hand touched at yours.
And then ... No, I don't remember.
Get it together!
We came to an alley with a bookstore.
There you took my hand.
How did you perceive me in the gondola?
I perceived you as spontaneous and ...
-...soft.
- Warm, Magnus!
Should it be so damn hard?!
I think Magnus smells like a summer evening after a rain.
God, what a nice thing!
My new guy smells just like a bouquet of dewy lilies!
-Oh!
-I know.
It is absolutely wonderful.
Ulf, he smells a bit like ...
...boiled rice.
Stick -free.
- You've been together for so long!
- Time goes by fast when you have fun.
How did you really meet two?
Magnus, you can tell you!
It's a pretty funny story.
- We met in Venice.
- God, what romantic!
It was in April.
Spring had made its mind.
The sun's rays danced over the old house facades.
I drove planlessly around the old alleys -
- Driven by curiosity but also by a diff ... US longing.
I didn't think I would meet ...
...the love of my life.
Program text: Britta L Bergman (C) Swedish Television AB 2004
Good night, Kristina.
Good night.