C.Teletext. sound signc. soundkras
Sorry!
Excuse me, hope.
It does not matter.
It was Gustavs.
- What is this for wine?
-I do not know.
Chateauneuf you pape.
Robban bought it in France.
- Gustav like more rustic flavors.
- Yeah.
Spanish country wine?
Swedish brandy.
When I got home Robban lay in the bathtub waiting.
We had a lovely dinner.
Then we ended up in front of the fire.
There we lay all night.
Sleep nothing.
The last time I lay in front of a fire was when Gustav fired our tent.
He wanted to try a campsite.
We were under Mattsson's pear trees.
He had to extinguish the garden hose.
How long have you been together?
Do you get him as a neighbor?
No ... After four marriage I know that I feel best free.
I don't want a life where everything repeats.
I understand what you mean.
Since Gustav took the morning tours, he is over.
- I know what gets up to him.
- Gustav is incredibly conventional ...
You just blow gently in the ear.
It is idiocy.
-What did you say?!
- You blow in the ear.
- I start working in four hours.
-Go to bed then.
Before you started working, it was I who provided us and created our home!
You can't succeed with everything.
Take a glass of wine!
- What are you doing here in the middle of the night?
- The clock is a quarter to nine.
- Then I have to go home.
Robban is coming.
- It's a shame.
We probably have more wine.
-Go to sleep.
I'll be coming soon.
-Do not stress.
Enjoy life!
We postmen have chosen it for something bigger!
We go up before the sun.
We cycle miles after miles, so that people can reach each other.
Posten - We are where people are.
He goes on a charm course.
Posten wants more service -oriented postmen.
- How to go for Gustav then?
- He can become a flight attendant ...
- No, now I have to go.
-Good night.
Greeting Robban.
C. sounders laugh
But Robban!
Gustav ... Gustav.
Wake up, you have to see this.
Be careful, I'm free!
- You have to look.
- I had an open goal.
No, now they pulled down the blinds.
You would have seen.
- I have to fall asleep.
It says 2–2.
- Gustav ... she had done so well.
Lighted candles in the living room and set in front of the fireplace.
They get on the right ...
- Are you not happy that Sara is in love?
- She's not in love.
She is sick.
No normal person thinks about sex more than once a month.
Don't you remember how we had it before you took those morning tours?
Wonderful ... you could lie down until twelve o'clock.
We devoted ourselves to each other!
We don't have to have it this boring.
It should be boring.
Otherwise, you don't know what it feels like to have fun.
I've been bored for 42 years.
But soon it turns.
What fun I have.
- I try to talk seriously.
-I also.
Do you think I want to get up at three every morning?
We could lie in bed all weekend and just care about each other.
You and I towards the whole world ...
Close the window, it pulls!
Why are you not at school?
- I have a sleeping morning.
- I have math.
Why then do you stand and burn sandwiches?
You don't get any school!
I don't slip!
I know exactly what lessons I can ignore.
And what did Sara do tonight?
I could not sleep.
- She laughed for three hours.
- She was happy.
- Has she met a new guy again?
- This time it's serious.
I've never seen her so happy.
Where is it that has happened, Sara?
It was too good to be true.
And I who had done so well!
-Calm down.
- Line, handkerchiefs ...
I do not understand anything...
We had ... thanks.
We had taken a hot tub and drank champagne.
Everything was magical and romantic ... I had even bought oysters.
- And so ... he says no!
- We don't have oysters?
- He doesn't want to marry me!
- Did you free him?
Yes.
Silly, huh?
Just laugh!
I could not help myself.
I had planned everything.
Bought rings and booked a weekend trip to Paris.
- You wouldn't get married anymore.
-I lied!
I want it like you.
Have family and children and a man who loves me -
- Laws the car, has a workshop in the basement and loves to fix with the house!
There is some shit with the garage door!
You have to tighten the hinges properly.
- Sara is here.
- Wrap a glass of wine for me too.
-She's sad.
It is over.
- Don't we have a box parades?
I will die alone as an old young.
It's not fair!
- Has Dad drawn a funny story?
- This is only mature people!
-What are you doing here then?
- So there you are constantly!
You have fun all the time.
It's a family happiness.
- There is always someone who stands up.
- What is she talking about?
I've been doing this for ten years.
I want someone who wants to bet on me.
You wanted it like this?
Free and free, no norms, no morality ...
Be able to travel ... no duties, no to support.
Freedom ... if you now appreciate that.
I want a man who didn't see me as a body.
- As just wanted to sleep next to me.
- You can borrow Gustav.
- You don't know how good you are.
-No...
Listen to Sara now!
- You have a man you can trust!
- You have to tell you more later.
I am late.
- Listen to Sara!
- It will probably be math anyway.
Listen to Sara for once!
This is important.
- Frequent ... - help me.
You are a man ... you are kind and safe and reliable.
- Sara, you have a look for people.
-What am I doing wrong?
Two things.
Make sure the overall picture.
Take it easy in the beginning.
83 percent of all who have six first evening, separate within three months.
If you wait, you have a greater chance that it will be more than a year.
- How to know all this?
- Aftonbladet's Sunday appendix.
If you wait for the fifth meeting you have a 67 percent more chance ...
"Well -kept young veterinarian with good economy and summer place" -
- "Looking for you as tired of the nightlife. You and me and all the animals."
No...
"Sensitive, considerate man who values honesty and faithfulness" -
- "Looking for generous woman for cozy home evenings. I am your slave."
What day!
The entire computer system pied -
- And 6,000 were taken in a cash register.
What do you do?
- Blends after a man to Sara.
- Dad asked me to look for men at the bank.
Read the circled!
"You are beautiful, young and soft. Come and greet my ..."
-What is this?!
- Modern poetry.
- Sara's future is secured.
-What is this?!
Throw them.
I've found him.
Ragnar Lind.
-Who is it?
- Tredes sorters at domestic.
The world's most faithful.
Have worked at the post for 12 years and never been sick!
- Has Sara bit to get your help?
- We had a long conversation.
I don't think you really know her.
But as you see other things, small shades ...
That the chips are not properly grooved.
- Sara does not have a hard time meeting men.
- She doesn't hit the right men!
This one is perfect!
"Do you like uncomfortable guys in leather ..."
Ragnar is not like Sara's regular guys.
He is shy and sensitive.
I've never seen him with a woman!
You have met him at Posten's Christmas party.
- He who let the children ride on his back.
- The horse Truls?!
- And in Easter he was the rooster Rolf.
- As we taped the beak again.
He comes here at seven.
We just need to get Sara here.
- The hunt is over ... the slaughter can begin.
- And if Sara doesn't want to meet him?
-She wants that.
I know Sara.
-Let me go!
-He is pleasant.
- Here she is!
-Help me!
- It's no coercion?
Love cannot be forced someone more.
You are right in everything you said, but we can take it easy!
Ragnar is certainly nothing to be afraid of.
At Easter, he was the rooster Rolf and played with the kids for six hours.
He is very in love with children.
Kind and sensitive.
- Keeps most to himself.
- like the laser man ...
- If he doesn't fit, you can just go.
- If he passes, you can get what we do!
- Spring, Sara, Spring!
- Sara, trust me.
Ragnar can be the right man in your life.
You wanted to try something new.
But not like this!
What should I say?
What should I do?
Do you know what Björn Borg used to say when he was facing difficult decisions?
- Extremely but brilliant: "Don't think."
- It's closer to him than Sara ...
- How does this look like?
- yellow feathers and taped beak.
- Ragnar is a normal, nice guy.
- In rooster costume ...
I don't know if it feels right.
- Family life is probably nothing to me.
- Not for me either, but here I am!
Now he comes!
- Own: It will go well!
- It will go to hell.
I have a red skirt and chiffon ... I'm not at home eleven, then call the police!
Have fun!
- Is the marriage broker proud?
-Actually.
And as a cream on the mash, I have a surprise to just you and me.
In the bed room.
Now you, the old man ...
Yes!
10–2.
Now I won again!
We play again!
No.
No idea.
The game is not good.
My players are dewating.
Canada didn't toss when I had them.
It's Russians.
Canada has leaves on the sweater.
- We can play again.
- Switch with those childishness!
- I get revenge tomorrow morning ... —You should go the morning tour.
Ragnar Lind takes them for the rest of the month.
It's nice to be able to help people.
Sara hugged me yesterday.
We sat for a long time talking.
- She listened to what I said.
- What did you say then?
Secrets about men and women.
That they look different without pants?
More complicated than that.
But I promised it would stop between us.
I explained that you must not wear each other from the beginning.
- We met only once a month.
- You did the bump in Boden.
I'm talking about the principle!
You should not jump to bed the first night!
I have to check!
- They are!
- Let them be.
Come to bed.
Do he dare to follow her to the door?
Yeah!
- What hell now?
He goes in too!
- It shows that they have had fun.
- She breaks our agreement!
- She does what she feels right is right.
83 percent of all who ... Sara!
- So he's still cursed?
- He actually doesn't feel well.
Would I have let him in?
He was crazy.
Stood there in pajamas and screamed about the purifying fire of hell ...
He thought you had an agreement.
Hello, Gustav.
- Don't drink directly from the package!
- You can say hello to Sara.
Without you I would never have met Ragnar.
You have ruined him!
Now he is swinging around in fastened shirts and sings Julio Iglas.
- Talk with people without distinction!
- Sara has made him live up.
We don't have time with that!
We need reliable people who don't just think about bodies ...
He doesn't want to be the rooster Rolf anymore - and that's your fault, Sara!
- You would get to know each other!
- We did.
After an hour, it was as if we had known each other all our lives.
- No ... now I have to go.
- Do you have everything?
Passport, ticket, franc?
-Franc?
Where are you going?
- We take that trip to Paris.
You can't go!
Ragnar will take my morning tours.
Ragnar should end on the post.
He has discovered other values in life ...
Au Revoir!
Lie down now so you can cope tomorrow.
Dad!
There was a package to you outside.
"To my best friend Gustav - good luck! Ragnar."
Mom, guess who should be the rooster Rolf!
Texting: SVT Sub -text (C) Swedish Television AB