-What will you do today?
- Not a shit.
-Just take it easy.
- Fan what a nice.
THE PHONE IS RINGING
- It's Elin.
- Hi Elin.
- Hi, Leif.
Sorry for the nuts.
Next time it will be beef, not fox meat with nuts.
-What did he say?
- He apologizes.
He gave nuts to someone who could not tolerate.
What happens?!
- Stupid, you have given her nuts!
- How is it with you, Elin?
-Alright.
I may come home today.
- I was going to ask you for a service.
-Obvious.
Grandma is alone in the house.
Could you look at her?
Of course we can look at Gamkäri ... the little ... Grandma yours.
Thanks.
I'm back at three o'clock.
We will fix that.
We look at her.
We have to go over and look at 'Na.
-Hello!
- Hallå, Grandma!
It is Leif and Billy who come to look at you.
Hello, Anna-Greta.
- Here she sits in and day out.
- It is strange that she looks depressed.
What if she sits and starves?
She may be hungry.
- She would need some fresh air.
- Should we bring her out on a turn?
Just right, Billy.
Get the wheelchair.
Surely it will be nice, Grandma?
So you can join the village, in Volvon.
I have an alarm from Anna-Greta's home in Sörbäcken.
I check it.
- This is where you like, huh?
- She may want to go a little.
Do you want to go on a cord with Volvon?
-Satan, Leif!
- That was fun?
- Is she?
- No, she just sits there.
- Want Grandma go and eat at the grill?
-We'll do that.
Hello?
Anna-Greta?
I have been looking through the whole house and she is not here.
We call the police.
See if she wants any food.
Now, Grandma, we have a large teddy bear sausage going on.
Shouldn't you have some?
Anna-Greta, you have to eat, otherwise you die.
Sit back and enjoy the sausage.
Now local news.
A woman in her 80s has been reported disappeared by the home service.
The police have made a search.
A tasty sausage with a little mustard and ketchup and bread will be loaded.
It is not possible to get her to eat.
I'm not going to beed with her, now it must be good.
My limit is reached.
If she wants to set hard against hard, we must play that game.
- Maybe the last time she sees the sun.
- Or get good food in the stomach.
It is finished.
Now we go home and lock you in again.
Do you manage to stand up when you haven't eaten anything?
It's like taking care of an infant.
Now we go home to the cave hole.
- Write it down on the bill.
The police.
I've seen the wanted aunt.
I think she is kidnapped.
It is sad that you do not want to eat, drink or be out.
When given the chance, you should take it.
SIRENS
- Hell, Leif, the cop is behind us.
- What the hell is that now?
- You have paid the car tax?
- No, I happened in it.
The heat pump collapsed and I had to pay it too.
- Are they deaf?
Don't they hear the sirens?
- And he drives in the middle of the road.
- I get nervous, now the heart jumps.
- I have to try to maneuver.
Okay - I flash right, then I turn left.
He drives like a damn fool.
Call and hear what he is doing.
- They are still there.
Hell, Leif.
- Curse parasites!
THE PHONE IS RINGING
–Leif.
- It's the police.
Stop the car.
I'm not out driving a car.
I would never drive an untaxed and undeveloped car.
That's not why.
You have a wanted woman in the back seat.
Anna-Greta is wanted by the home service.
We see her in the back seat.
Wait a second.
-They say that Anna-Greta is wanted.
She has probably pressed the alarm bell on her hand.
Kidnapping, it gives 20, 30, 40, 50, 60 years ... It can be Guantánamo!
- Don't say so, Leif, I panic!
- Take it easy, I'll be on something.
- Hall again.
- What the hell are you doing?!
Stop the car!
What did you say, Anna-Greta?
You want to stop and tell the truth to the police?
She says she wants us to stop and talk.
She wants to tell you something.
- We turn in here.
- Yes, now he turns in.
- What the hell are you doing?
-We...
Leif, silent.
-Anna-Greta, how are you?
We should be honest.
We would look at the car, because it is not estimated or inspected.
But it was gone.
We took a walk down the village and looked, and we found it.
- Guess who was sitting in it?
- she put in the car?
Okay?
Yes, she has stolen the car.
- You say she has stolen your car?
-Yes.
Is that true, Anna-Greta?
After all, she is ashamed and gets a total heavy heap.
She is not doing well.
-Anna-Greta?
- We should not stress her up anymore.
- We drive her home, that's good.
- We do not want to make any notification.
She is spinning in the skull and does not know what she is doing.
- Then we trust that you drive her home.
-Yes.
Okay then.
Run legally.
And inspect the car.
Fy damn, it was close to the eye.
-What time is it?
-I do not know.
Elin comes home in a quarter!
We have to take the shortcut home.
Take it easy!
The girl is on the seat.
-Hello Hello!
-Hello.
-Hello?
-Hi Elin.
- How did it go on sickness?
-Good.
But ... no more nuts for me.
No, no more ... nuts for me.
- How has it been today?
-Good.
We have taken it easy.
-How nice.
What did the home service do here?
- We invited them to some coffee.
-We have spiced up Anna-Greta.
- She needed a little piff.
- Can you offer a thank you dinner?
-I do not know...
We go on a six-seven diet.
We have to go home and fast before the sun goes down.
- Thanks for you could set up.
-No problem.
Thanks.
- Hi, Elin.
-Oh.
Hello.
Has things been going well today, Grandma?
But, how do you look!
Have they made up you?!
SWEDISH SUPPORT: Jens Jakobsson (C) Sveriges Television AB 2017