My name is Brita.
This is Kalle.
Welcome to our farm.
Three years ago we decided that we and our children Björn, Essa and Glenn -
- Leave the town for a new life.
A life filled with animals, nature, cultivation and construction projects.
Now it's finally time to celebrate Christmas.
We were going to have a party for relatives and friends -
- Where we fix food and do extra nicely.
So this is our Christmas toy program.
Welcome to our Christmas special!
Hi, Brita!
What are you doing?
I'm looking for the Christmas things.
Now we should not be out at the last second.
- Not the day before Christmas Eve?
-Just.
Do you know what the best way to start in time is?
We have a Christmas party!
- I stand for the decoration.
- I fix ham, some type of sausage ...
And so something good to eat too.
- I have zero ideas for decorations.
- "Christmas is the feast of the eyes."
It says in the old scriptures.
We wish you all an eye-liking-Christmas
-Let's go.
Christmas party!
-Yes!
What is in the old scriptures about Christmas?
That it is eye -related?
That you couldn't know that text!
I believed more about you.
Let's go!
I start with the decoration and Kalle will probably start with mulled wine.
This is mead.
It's like wine made on honey.
- you?!
- I think it's still good.
It is from season 1. Then you were as old as Björn is now.
You may be wondering why I pour mead here.
I'll make mulled wine.
Now we will have more honey, so it gets sweeter.
It must not boil, because then the alcohol boils away.
We do not want to get rid of the alcohol like this when it is painting for Christmas!
Christmas food has changed for me.
It has become a lifestyle for me to fix food and produce food.
Before, I thought, "What am I craving?"
Now I think, "What do I have?"
If you have not mead at home, you can take a muggy bag-in-box wine.
It can be red, it can be white, it can be rosé.
Do you know which spice likes the worst about twins?
"No, equal!"
Where do I get everything from?
The sick thing is ... I'm starting to get drunk.
I've tasted so many times.
- Good Christmas, Kalle.
- Good Christmas, Björn.
This is a direct action to make sure Christmas gets nicer.
Christmas can get pretty ugly, and I don't want ugly Christmas.
I want sexy, good looking Christmas.
One thing that I intend to do is table tablets.
Exactly.
My sewing machine stands here, but I probably won't use it.
I will show a very fast way.
This is a trick to get all corners the same.
Type like this.
Then I cut like this.
Now it's super exciting.
God, what a good looking!
I who know what it will be like is very satisfied.
Now I will attach a band - stuff at your local grocery store -
- With a little textile glue, and follow this edge.
"It is the whole."
I love to celebrate Christmas on our farm.
It feels like Christmas here is equal -
- The one I want to create for my children, which I may have dreamed a little about myself.
But there is a lot of time to decide the rules around Christmas.
We do it our way.
It sounds incredibly diligent.
But is not Christmas also the feast -
- When you get to be pretty much with sentimentality and nostalgia?
Otherwise, Christmas has nothing.
This is getting so fucking ugly.
We can't show this to anyone.
This idea of not sewing was pretty bad.
Now we will try to get over mulled wine in these bottles.
If I make bottles with capsule it can be sparkling.
Surely there is?
Mulled wine and champagne?
Glubble!
I'm going to make glubbles too.
Now we are in unknown territory.
It may be that there will be bubbles in.
I have never done this before.
Now the most fun is left.
"Glave?"
With question marks, because it can also just be mulled wine.
It's cold in the winter.
It's so fun to sew.
Just to thread the machine - the adventure is in front of me.
Now we set the machine to max zigzag, max density on the stitches.
This was completely hell.
It looks damn good.
I can not...
So, I will not settle for "totally okay" when it's Christmas.
So now I'm trying to think out an alternative plan.
In the boiler room I have thawed back fat from a wild boar jyl I shot.
We will melt this.
We will make sebum balls.
You may think, "Do the birds eat meat?!"
It does.
If you have not seen a pigeon eating a hot dog, you have not lived.
This is usually cut away when you cut animals, but it is good to have -
- If you are going to make sausages, or sebum balls.
Damn fat.
I put this in the oven.
100 degrees in ...
...I do not know.
We'll have to check out soon.
It should melt, but not too fast.
Now I will take this home.
My brother linseed oil saves this.
I will paint the edges.
It gets tough and lacquered.
Why wouldn't it work on textiles?
There are some reasons.
But it's worth a try.
Check!
Like a lovely Boeuf Bourguignon.
Now we will make the sebaceous balls.
Then we go out.
God, it will be so neat.
Will it hold a wash?
I want to say yes.
But I do not know.
It is cozy to sit and play.
It is easy to be stressed over everything that needs to be done.
And then to force oneself to sit down and do something like this -
- And maybe let the children participate to their own level ...
So!
It was good looking, right?
Some little spruce and some nice napkins.
Maybe a little...
...food.
Okay, it went to hell.
Now I have to put in an extra gear.
For me and Kalle are quite different.
To me, what is seen is important, while he is more "function".
Then we make the sebaceous balls.
To make it a Christmas mood, I chose these.
I start with some sunflower seeds.
So.
And then we take some wheat.
Then I will take corn.
Now to the fat itself.
Hell, the cords I forgot!
I can take them later.
Then just wait again, then.
You can put them just outside the kitchen window, and learn the names.
Side tail, Rödhake ...
-Greenfinch.
Yellow-hammer.
- Screaming.
- Arrow.
- red hook.
- I've said that.
Now it must have solidified.
Nämen look.
Now the birds can come and ...
...eat.
I'll probably lie down for a while.
Wake me tomorrow when they have solidified.
They don't have to solidify until Christmas Eve.
You live closer to nature in the countryside.
Before you live here, it is probably a little difficult to understand what it means.
But you look differently at the world here.
You see the seasons come and go.
I sound old now, but you get as a relationship with the wild animals.
Like when waiting for the cereals -
- Or now in the winter when you fix food for the birds that have stayed.
I am a bit behind in fixing for Christmas, so it is important to maximize.
Can anything maximize Christmas more than casting your own light?
Stucking candles is the modern of all Christmas toys.
Still, we don't do it that often, because it's hard.
But I still try to do it.
Maybe it's not that hard?
Here is a saucepan of water.
I will melt beeswax in the one, which will stand in a water bath.
Flower stick with a lot of threads on.
I will put it here.
Then it was this with weight, so it becomes a straight light.
A small nut.
So, check out what straight.
I thought it was like cutting through butter.
There I mistaken.
No, bad ...
Now I have picked up the heavy artillery.
I'll be ax apart it.
- Hi, Kalle.
We will cast light.
-How cozy.
- Do you make light?
-Yes.
You should too, if you want.
-Of course I want to.
- If I ax a little first ...
Oh.
Essa has given up a bit.
But it is time to start dipping.
Okay.
What ...?
This is already the nicest Christmas piece I have been with.
Essa?
Check.
You dip like this, and then I hang this.
- Do you want to test once?
-Okay.
We sit under the traps  and the snow around us dizzy
and not until evening  We journey home control
Oops!
An egg.
Now I will test a thing that I have wanted to do quite a while:
To marble the lights.
Will it be full -
- Unfortunately, I will set Christmas.
Are you with me?
One two Three!
It is incredibly neat!
It's like a psyched plot!
Now I'm doing this.
Cuts ...
Yes, it's so nice!
The nicest lights I've seen.
she brightened  over the world's anxiety and battle ...
What a Christmas miracle!
Then we were running!
Tomorrow we will see if the tall is solidified.
Kalle gets to start with ham and sausage.
I was going to start an alternative Christmas tradition.
Jimmy and Anlin come here and cook with me.
Fun!
Now the sebaceous balls have hopefully solidified in the cold in here.
Now let's see ... Check out!
Birds do not eat with their eyes too but only with the beak?
Hope so...
We put it outside the window so we get fat stains on the window.
It's so cosy.
I have done this before with purchased sebum balls ...
Tjoho!
Powerful.
I start well and bake.
Time for Christmas ham.
I put a pride in making a lot of food myself in the yard.
Not everyone in the family thinks it is equal ... important.
Buttocks from our hybrid cultures!
I cooked the meat under pomp and standing and would invite the family.
Brita does not eat pork.
But maybe if it came from here?
Absolutely not!
Essa gave three thumbs down.
Björn screamed: "Remove it from my plate!"
And ... there is moose.
The rest is pork.
Hundreds of pounds no one wants to eat.
But for Christmas you may be able to serve Christmas ham even if no one wants it.
We will salt the meat.
It gives taste, helps with the preservation -
–And pulls out fluid?
Okay, this is nitrite salt.
According to some, it is hazardous -
- But it is bactericidal and causes the ham to retain its pink color.
Then there will be no dangerous bacteria in the ham.
If we have nine kilos of water ... we should have 5 % plain salt, 3 % nitrite salt.
450 grams of sea salt.
Nitrite salt: 270.
I am afraid of nitrite and take less.
230 grams.
So damn stupid ... sugar.
I don't know how much you should have.
Now we put in the buttocks.
You want them under the surface.
So!
Just to wait, four and a half days.
Another classic on the Christmas table is pig feet.
I only have one.
But it must be the foot itself.
Right?
- What is it, Hanne?
Hanne?
Oh yeah!
Disgusting!
Mele kalikimaka 'is the thing to say
on a Bright  Hawaiian Christmas Day ...
Kalle has cooked quite a lot of pork.
I don't eat pork.
My way of creating Christmas peace in this house is to approach another meat -
- which also Kalle is aware of: the ducks.
I will take the duck meat, which I have not yet eaten anything really good ...
Therefore, I have invited reinforcement in the form of Jimmy and Anlin.
Thanks.
Very nice to be here!
This is Jimmy Guo and his mother.
Jimmy is a master chef finalist, expert on Chinese food and generally wonderful.
His mother then?
She is the champion champion!
- You are professionals on Duck.
-I am.
Mom cooks duck every Christmas.
It is our Christmas tradition.
In Chinese cuisine there are two known ducks.
One is the Beijingankan -
- Which is very time consuming ... there is nothing you do at home!
The other known duck comes from Nanjing, which Mom comes from.
I grew up at that time.
It is very special for me.
It is called rhymed blasted duck from nanjing.
- How do you "blast" it?
- It is very undramatic:
It should be salted properly.
The salt pulls the liquid out of the protein.
After an hour, it starts to be sucked back.
And then the cells retain moisture, or water, harder than before.
- I didn't know this.
- So you have time: Salt in good time.
- I have chosen a fluffy sea salt.
- It's like snow!
Mostly because it is wonderful to work with and attaches well.
But you can take quite the usual salt.
Today it will be great fun, because today we will make Christmas sausage ...
... together with the oracle from Sunne!
Finally!
Patrick Sellman is the all -artist's all -artist.
He knows everything - everything -
- About farm life, prepping, animals and food.
Tighten you, good people.
Here he is!
Here we have back fat from pig.
It is a lot of pig products.
Historically, the pig was the resource that stood ...
You did not have many pigs, but a few.
It was a way to take advantage of food debris that you gave to the pig.
And it is in the season.
Then it is slaughtered when the temperature drops - before Christmas.
And then there will be different sausages, ham ...
... pig feet, dip in the pot - all that.
Okay.
Christmas sausage then, it's pork - or some other meat ...
Some fat ... and then there are pepper, white pepper ...
And onions.
Good!
We failed the onion cultivation this year.
We forgot to put onions.
- Then it will be unsuccessful!
- Don't let us dig into it!
Without let's make Christmas sausages.
Okay!
Then we will grind meat.
You, I think we should have a little more fat in.
–2 090 grams.
-Perfect.
- Onions?
- Now we'll have it.
What we will do today is to roast salt with sichuan pepper.
You have to.
When it is lukewarm you massage the salt into the duck.
- Then it gets easier into the meat.
- You should have type ... two fists on the outside.
And a fist for the back.
It feels reasonable.
- Was he always good at cooking?
- He has become there lately.
Well, we have seen that in various chef competitions ...
- He knows much more than I can.
- Sized words from mom!
We usually argue about how to make the duck, and mom wins.
- Sometimes we have different discussions.
- It's healthy.
Now the salt is warm, so we drive in sichuan pepper.
-God so tasty!
- Salt is starting to yellow.
It cools very fast.
We start by throwing in a fist ...
Don't just throw in!
You should rub it in.
It should be massaged.
It's sharp legs - beware so you don't cut yourself.
"A Christmas Glove" ... maybe the kids think is fun.
-They are a little fucked-up that way.
- Drive on here now!
All the way in there.
–Okay, hold it.
- Now you can drive there.
- You see how good I am on massage!
-Really.
- Salt, about 2.5 %.
- Realon with salt.
- Four grams.
–And spice?
- Something less.
-Slightly.
-What do you think?
- It is well mixed.
You have fun.
I almost get jealous.
Do you want to work?
I have to dissolve some muscle ...
The duck has had enough love now.
- You have moved on until next week.
-Yes!
Thanks!
Now we are placing it in and put it in the fridge.
See you in a few days.
At least two days it should stand in the fridge.
Oh, beware!
Kalle has tangled the intestines together!
This is then gut from pig.
As you have washed and salted.
There are well-hit material today, but usually it is intestines around ...
... around the sausage.
Did you know that?
Didn't you know that?
- Think about it when you eat KROV.
- Very synthetic today.
You eat plastic instead ...
Fill all the way so it goes up.
I tie with cotton cord at the end.
Good.
Try!
You have to get it in your hands.
You should not hold too much.
–Ekivokt ... - dip your hand in water.
- There it was over.
- You have missed an important ...
- Testing.
-Just!
-Okay thanks.
- Kalle ... you have made a merry Christmas sausage.
- It was delicious!
- I ... there will be really good sausage.
- Fan, what fun!
Yes!
oh, Little Town of Bethlehem ...
Now we are starting to get pretty ready for the Christmas party.
The only thing missing is to make your own crispbread and make Christmas decorations.
And you have to have a Christmas goat.
Or?
As happy as we were when the snow came, we were as sad when it was thawing.
But we live in Sweden and are used to it.
Kalle overcompensates with a Christmas goat.
I'm going to build the body of this pallet.
One challenge with living on a farm is to try to take what is close.
So, so, so ...
Here is a tradition around Christmas goats.
When you were a kid, a youth gang came and put this on one's stairs.
When you got out they threw snowballs on the window, so I got really scared.
Then we would put the goat on someone else's stairs.
There was a "relay" in Sorunda.
This may be the beginning of it.
Yes.
Some kind of feud must have the goat too.
Short Fejs ... or long?
The tail will not be super performance!
So damn uncomfortable with the head that sticks out!
If someone is probably wanting to make a Christmas goat, then my tip is:
Don't be afraid to take in the size!
At the Christmas Bock Building Gymnasium, they said that the size has no significance.
But I don't know if I agree.
So!
Much at work now, right?
Should we take some in the pile?
Then I busy it a little here back then.
It's a bit like when you "mancapear" - hard to know when to quit.
But now I'm starting to feel satisfied.
So!
The children may like to ride it.
Soon Pernilla will come.
She is an architect ...
... and great at tinkering.
I thought we would do some Christmas toys together.
She is coming now.
Hello!
Oh, you have some straw with you, right?
Just!
And I have a Christmas present with me too.
Pernilla Wåhlin Norén, architect and author.
She is incredible on crafts.
The crafts' Charlotte Kalla–
- Fixing Galadriel, Pyssli's Princess Leia!
- God, so nice!
- From our summer sheep.
I am very craving something that you do so damn nice, a straw ...
A crown of straw.
One can do the one that in the reach -
- With a round frame and then it hangs down like a necklace.
- Would you be able to make wool balls?
-Oh yes!
Yes, and I brought cards.
I got shuddered by my own idea!
Oh, what a nice one!
They are very funny.
No Christmas is complete without crispbread.
It will go away to the silo and pick up some wheat.
There we have it.
- Now we're going to grind this.
- Why should we grind it?
It will be flour so we can bake.
Today we will bake Christmas crackers.
It is plain bread -
- And then you have in anise and cumin ...
Anis with I, your sick fucking.
It's Christmas!
To my help I have this piece, a mill.
Okay!
- Is this a "worry"?
-Just.
These in gold, which my daughter thought would be with -
- Is the inside of a caviar can.
She has made Christmas decorations off the inside of a caviar ...
... a tube, and cut it up.
They are gold inside.
Immediately do your Christmas toys, whatever it is, of the inside of cavia art tubes!
Right?
Take a thread and then make a knot at the bottom.
- You can, like Hälla ... - exact, pour it.
The straw should be soaked for an hour before cutting.
Then it does not break.
There they get like that ...
- Here you have to attach them together.
- You can do with a spin.
Yes absolutely.
How nice not to have any knots.
-Pro!
The straw professional Brita!
- Thanks, Miss.
- But you have five children.
-Yes.
Just that ... it was just that.
I have nothing more.
I just wanted to say it and that we would think about it for a while.
When I bake, I let the water decide how much flour ...
I don't usually follow recipes so carefully.
I pour in a variety of water.
- That was maybe eight deciliters.
-Milk?
No, but you can pour in some flour.
We have forgotten the yeast!
Now the yeast will be dissolved.
Now you can have more.
Good, then you can get started.
Then we will have in this kind of flour until it becomes a good dough ... Run on!
- Check, a big lump!
-Perfect.
That's what we want.
The only cartoon movie on TV when I was little was Kalle Duck on Christmas Eve.
- you?!
- No other cartoon.
Otherwise, there were only aunts and uncles in the costume -
- That talked about politics.
-Ugh, how boring!
- You are an adult now, Kalle.
- I'm an adult now.
- You are an adult.
Then we will help you.
You are so damn please!
Check!
Nice, of course!
I felt that maybe I got a little blind in the craft.
-I am very pleased.
- In the heat of the craft.
I saw that you had a straw in the barn.
- Do you mean the goat now?
-Yes.
So fine!
- It's a tradition here in the yard.
-Is it true?!
Kalle has done it.
As of this year, it is a tradition.
The cutest thing I know with Kalle is his tradition the Christmas stone.
It is that he has a large, big stone that he carries a kilometer on Christmas day.
He just wears it.
End of tradition.
This feels so fun.
I think this will be ... so damn nice.
- Pernilla, what have we created?
-Right?!
So nice!
I think it's the nicest decoration someone ever seen.
Very nice!
Oh, I'm so embarrassed!
Quite strong cumin smell.
Dad!
Is it going well?
- Yes, how are you doing?
-Not good.
- The worst chaos.
- Wounds what the children do in there.
Exciting.
Ah, Björn!
You have to make a hole in the middle!
That's what crispbread is.
I realized you would have a hole.
Surely it is perfect?
Perfect.
I don't like the cumin so much, I think.
Are you craving crispbread?
My five best tips when baking crispbread is:
I have no more tips.
- Now damn ... Yes!
- Do you have crispbread?
You are welcome!
- Should you say it's good?
-No.
You can say as it is.
-Thanks but no thanks.
- Bear, just lick the butter now?
Delicious!
So you need crispbread, it's just to shout.
Then I can bake it to you.
Merry Christmas!
We got a lot - crispbread, Christmas sausage, fine decoration -
- ham, candle, goat, sebaceous balls, mulled wine ...
Tomorrow comes relatives and friends at Christmas party.
Mice!
This year's most important decision is to choose the Christmas tree.
We hand over that decision to those who decide.
Yes, I'm talking about our beloved little children.
Yes or no?
Thumbs down.
Essa, this one then?
Huh?
It was thumbs up!
Thumbs up for it.
Okay.
- Three chop and you lie '.
-Yes.
Huh?
Children, check out what was in the Christmas tree.
Björn, do you know what it is?
- A bird's nest.
- A real bird's nest.
- We might be able to bring this home?
-Yes.
- And look at it.
-Yes we can do that.
We got a bird's nest with us and a Christmas tree.
-Does it feel good?
-Yes.
We usually have the other Christmas tree foot.
I go and pick it up.
I do not get it.
People have gone on the moon.
We can split atoms.
We can't ... humanity cannot solve the problem -
- With a Christmas tree foot that can actually hold a spruce upright.
It's not possible!
It's a Christmas party today.
To-to-doo.
We have to fix a long table, because we have invited in each direction -
- So there may be a few.
Okay, good.
Table setting and check that we have cutlery, plates and chairs.
Then we start with it.
Ho-Ho-Ho.
It's the Most Wonderful Time  of the year
with the kids jingle belling  and everyone telling you
be of good cheer
It's the Most Wonderful Time
Yes, The Most Wonderful Time
oh, The Most Wonderful Time ...
It was a Christmas atmosphere.
Just missing ...
Fy damn, what a powerful!
- Is it your Christmas ham you have done?
- Christmas ham, if I can pray.
Then we will make the grilling to the ham.
Then we take an egg ...
... and then we remove the egg white.
Ah - it broke.
So.
And then we take sweet mustard.
A little neighbor ... and then we take dijon.
I take everything that is left in the jar.
But it depends on how much you have left, so you have to think for yourself.
There we have it.
Then we brush on the mustard and egg mixture.
Now it's the bread.
Of course.
A little while in the oven.
It should only get color up here.
It may take a quarter.
Thank you.
Hell!
I burned it.
But it can be extra good.
Some things are good a little burnt.
I am tasting.
It is better when it is not burned.
If I hadn't had another, this would have been a disaster!
I'm setting a clock this time.
I take an egg yolk mixed with mustard and dijon mustard.
Then on with bread.
I'll heat mulled wine.
Bock!
Hell, I was forgetting it.
-Hello!
- But hey!
What Christmas.
- Yes, it's still cozy.
-Welcome.
How nice you look.
- What a mood.
- Now Kalles Timer went.
Wonder why he burns things.
- It looks great.
-Check!
-Hello!
-Merry Christmas.
Kramis!
Fresh.
- How did it go with the ham?
- I forgot again.
I took it out.
- The anchor is not finished, but smells good.
- This is going to be super good.
We will make a witch brew with a lot of spices.
There are many chefs for this soup, so you may be able to ...
I know this, and you the ham.
Now we make this spice bag.
So we have cinnamon and bay leaves ...
This is a kind of white nutmeg.
-Oh!
- It smells great.
This is an Angelicarot.
It is reminiscent of ginseng.
- And fennel seeds.
- Why do you put them in one?
It is easier to remove them, because you do not eat them.
- As a small tea bag.
-Just.
It goes down there.
Here we have flavor enhancers, MSG.
"It's all good."
Salt.
This should be a five percent team, so 250 grams.
So much.
Now we will rinse the duck.
We remove excess salt and peppercorns.
Okay, fill the duck.
You are used to this.
It's just to drive in that.
We wait for it to boil, so it may go about half an hour.
Then I do some more.
We play that Polly is friends with a Santa's
- And the Santa Claus should visit.
- Why can't it be open?
- It boils, so the lid should be on.
But if it boils when we are not here, it is your fault.
It is important that you keep the same now at Christmas.
No, but mom is responsible for this being good.
- Lite family stress is well.
- It is Jimmy who always fights.
- Is there a beer somewhere?
-If it exists!
I think I have to have a beer.
Now I'm going to make a food box.
Mum and I did it in the summers -
- But now it's Christmas, and then it works too.
What is it in?
It's Matjes, of course -
- And eggs, cooked eggs, and then it is chives ...
And then it's yellow onion.
If you do it, it will be who when Jussi Björling runs high C: t in "Helga night".
It is the feeling of Sandberg's Matjes box.
- Enotically neat.
- "It's A Christmas Miracle!"
- I peel the eggs.
-How nice.
As an assistant.
So.
- Otherwise, this is perfect.
- Fan, hard boiled.
You had a job.
We take over.
Now the food is starting to get ready, and we will serve our homemade mulled wine.
We will check if it has become bubbly.
So.
Hello and welcome!
It's nice to see you all here at the Christmas celebration.
- You drink mulled wine made on mead.
- As you have done.
- So bowl and Merry Christmas.
-Merry Christmas!
He is the real plot and has hired me to Tomtenisse.
And me.
We are Santa's now.
I have never eaten Christmas sausages, because it seemed disgusting.
But it was good.
- A Merry Christmas sausage.
- As Patrik has helped me do.
I haven't made Christmas sausages ever!
A tradition that does not come from the farm is to make blasted duck.
It is from Anlin's hometown of Nanjing, and is with traditional Christmas spices.
-Very good.
- bowl for that.
Thanks, everyone.
Merry Christmas.
Hello, Santa Gubs, hit the glasses  and let's funny be!
A little time we live here  with much effort and great trouble
Hello!
Bowl.
-Are there any nice children here?
-Yes!
Is it the plot that comes?
- Is it the real plot?
-Yes!
Are you sure?
So, the real, real plot?
Merry Christmas, Essa, wishes the plot.
- You are welcome.
Merry Christmas, Sally, wishes the plot.
- Good Christmas, Alma.
Who is Alma?
-That's me.
Heaven luck, huh?
A school bus and a truck.
Then you can load and lift stuff.
Then it's time for a Christmas concert.
It's Glenn and Linn.
Glenn is my big child and Linn is Andrea's big child.
This is the new, slightly cooler generation that takes over.
Here you go.
It was Christmas Eve, Babe
in the drunk tank
an old man said to me:  won't see anchor one
and then he sang a song
"The Rare Old Mountain Dew"
I Turned My Face Away,  and Dreamed About You
The Boys in the Nypd Choir  still singing "Galway Bay"
and the Bells are ringing out  for Christmas Day
What I hope you bring is to get your own traditions.
You do as you please.
Make the food you want, have the guests you want.
The only common denominator is that you gather, have fun, eat something good.
Like to season with anise ...
--... cinnamon ... --... and carnation and ginger.
It does not matter.
Only they are involved, everything works out.
-Do it.
Start your own traditions.
- We throw in new ones every year.
Yes, but kind of that this is our family farm.
- It has not been for many years.
-For three years.
I hope it is for 300 years.
- Christmas Pussen.
- It was everything from us.
Have a really nice Christmas!
If you know someone is sitting alone on Christmas and you have a chair over, invite.
Do you light on it when I sit on it?!
From all of us to all of you, a really Merry Christmas!
-Have a good one.
Kiss and hug!
-Merry Christmas!
Take it easy.
Texting: SVT Language & amp;
Accessibility © Swedish Television AB 2022