Kronofogden, Debt Collection, Kronofogden, Pizzeria ...
The pension is int 'worth opening.
Check!
A letter from cousin Ronny.
-Where is he?
- Kao Laok, something.
Safe Thailand.
"Hello! Can you post a pair of logs snus to the hotel? Address below."
- With what money then?
- He lives life, he.
Damn.
Letter from the Employment Service.
- What the hell are they want this time?
- We should take some fucking course.
They want us to come down.
They serve with the a-box.
We have to go at once.
That they can never leave us in peace!
I have called you here as you have not applied for a job for a while.
How's your job searching?
I have taken some responsibility and applied for a job on my own.
I applied to be a personal assistant to Billy.
But I didn't get that.
I have looked if the pizzeria needs to reach 'security guards, but ...
It is difficult to get a job in today's society.
We have the farm too.
The other day it went down a badger and sat down in the course at the pasture.
He was dead when we found him.
It was electric shocks and colds.
We had to thaw him with his mother's hair dryer before we stopped him.
We usually try to sell them on the market and get some money.
I have contacted you several times for you to attend job search courses.
If you will not, you will not receive a cash register.
How should I get it?
I have the farm, and Billy should be seen after.
He seems to be adult enough to manage himself.
I see no other way than to withdraw your a-cash.
You send us straight down into poverty?
Fy fuck.
Oh, oh, what a fun message!
How, then, should I buy snuff and beer ...?
Or I mean milk and food.
Billy is a osteoporosis and needs nutritional supplements.
Where is the money?
I have lived with scurvy in previous poverty conditions.
Go on the courses I call, so maybe I can reconsider the decision.
Should it be like this, we go home.
These heartless people see us rather starve-
- Enter to stretch a helping hand.
Yes, it's Malin ... stomach ailment?!
Wait!
Would you be able to work today?
-Do we get back the A-box then?
- Yes, for a while to come.
We are not shaded.
We'll take it.
Jesus is a Friend of Mine Jesus is my friend
Jesus is a Friend of Mine I have a friend in Jesus
What good that you could come up with such short notice.
There is a stomach ailment here, and I will have a funeral.
Here is a list of what you have to do.
- Do you have no more decent clothes?
-No.
I go out and look for it.
Wait here, I solve it.
-Good job.
You have to dress up.
- Hope it is well paid as well.
You clean, so I put out hymn books and light candles.
- Remember: Don't sabotage this.
-It is quiet.
You can trust me.
It's Been A Hard Day's Night and i've Been Working Like A Dog
It's Been A Hard Day's Night, I Should Be Sleeping Like A Log
But when I get home to you i find the things that you do
will make me feel alright
You Know I Work All Day to Get You Money, To Buy You Things
And it's Worth it just to hear you say:
You Know, in Feel Alright
Now I am ready.
What do we do now?
Check that the microphone works, in which the priest devil should talk in.
Hello?
God?
Jesus?
No, it doesn't go.
You may well check if there is something gap or reach '.
Use the brain cells now.
Hello?
Satan.
- Leif, now it goes!
It echoes high
Hello!
The god Billy speaks to the people of Sörbäcken.
God damn, Billy!
Don't play in God's house.
Focus now!
- Day to pick up the coffin with Knut.
-We will fix it.
-Are you ready?
-Yes.
Psalm books, light and cleaning.
And Billy has fixed your microphone.
Hello!
Hello?
Hell!
-Oh my God.
What have we done?!
- God cursed.
- What the hell are we going to go '?
- We have to bring him life.
Water!
The little priest, do not leave us.
Satan.
- Throw it at him.
Satan!
–The power.
- You have to pull out the cable, Billy.
He is coupled high voltage.
- We have killed a priest in God's house.
- He is not dead!
–Satan.
- Something is coming.
What the hell are we going to do?
I have a plan, Billy.
Come.
Sit down.
Hello and welcome to my congregation in Sörbyn's church.
- Where is Nils, who would be a priest?
- Unfortunately, niles have left us.
Or ... he had to go home with stomach problems.
I had to move in as a priest ... priest.
We have gathered to honor the body ... or knot.
- Knut ... --... Jonsson.
Knut Jonsson was a big man, who is lately forgotten for everything he did.
- His job ... he worked within ... --... Rumpmoker.
He was a good craftsman, or artist and artist.
That was unbelievable.
We forget that late, Knut.
His interest in music and dance ...
But my God, he was deaf!
... was not at all.
But he probably wanted to hear the first hymn -
- If he heard ... lived ... or heard.
The organ man, you can start the first hymn.
God's star should shine ...
Happy music
Thanks.
We thank the organ man for the fine ...
Hockey break
Then we thank the organ man for the fine hymn.
- But seriously, what is this?
- Knut's funeral.
The most amateurish ever!
- Now we calm down.
- Lug us?!
This is a joke!
A lot is happening now, and we should not hold on to this in God's house.
We go to Knut and take our last farewell.
Js bach "toccata and fuga in d-minor"
Now take your last farewell to Knut and let Jesus receive him in heaven.
He enjoys Christ's presence and receives him as a little infant.
Now we can move on.
- Go, Knut!
Travel far from here.
In the coffin we now have an empty shell of a human being.
His soul has passed on ... somewhere else.
God, cursed!
-What do you do?
- It's an unusual event.
- Where is my dad?
- It's Knut that goes on.
Get out of church, so I'll give exorcism.
Then you got fired from your first job.
We should be a glamor that we did not kill that damn priest.
- We get to see it from the bright side.
-How?
In any case, we have tried to work and are justified A-cash again.
- Should we pull on the grill?
-We'll do that.
Swedish texture: T Olofsson & amp;
M Takala (C) Swedish Television AB 2017