Watch out for the fools.
The fools are closed.
Does he understand what he says?
Yasmin and dilek!
Take care.
Have a good day!
Thank you, the same to you.
We are in a hurry.
You also.
-See up for the fools - the fools are closed.
-Is it so hard to say the "doors"?
-You do not give a flattering image.
-The Swedish cowardice is well famous?
-Is this an unfortunate tendency?
-A in hell unhappy tendency.
-Is that your dad?
-Id a pattern?
I want to demonstrate with my dissertation how we overwhelm responsibility.
I thought it was him.
A society that encourages citizens not to intervene is rotten.
-A community that digs its grave.
-He is embarrassing.
Tjena, car tires!
You should not give up on my acid, because then you get to do with me!
Are you a police officer, right?
Spån head!
Stay!
Damn!
Damn shit!
What are you doing?
Are you not really wise?!
-I do not have time!
-Boken young people!
How did it go?
Are you dead?
Yes, I wonder if I'm not.
-Boken, what hurt it did!
And you?
-Yes...
-I'm intact.
-How nice.
Ouch!
-Com, I'll help you.
-Thanks.
-Are you searching too?
-Yes.
Yasmin.
Elin.
Now you are still!
Lay still!
Two!
God, how fast you were!
-"Patriarchal", what does it mean?
-Fatherly.
-Elin enecke.
-That's me.
- What is this?
-The call.
-What then?
Hi Elin!
You are Ulf's daughter, I understand.
Come here.
You will not remember this, but I met you when you were little.
-What has made you search?
-I was born with police genes.
I want to stir a bit in the macho pine.
Well, and why do you want to become a police officer?
Mom was robbed, so I want to stop the violence.
Then you help people and so on.
It is good.
-I want to work with people.
-I need a job.
I'm kidding.
My dad and my brother are cops.
I will be a good police officer.
-What is it for the mark on the sweater?
-Cinesian Marine Corps.
If I am going to do an arrest, I know exactly how the guy works.
I know how his mother thinks.
I know how he had it.
The most important thing is to know how citizens work.
-What has made you search?
-I want to change the view of the police.
-Is it a problem, right?
-No, but there is blood on the forehead.
-Then let's see here ... here, take this one.
-Thanks.
I got a bang before.
I collided with a girl.
Thanks!
Fuck!
You, this is not holding.
Come, we pull.
-Where are we going?
-To emergency.
My mom works there.
-DemiGllo, was that what you were called?
-TemoGlu.
-What happened?
-We crashed.
-Croken?
- Do you feel ill?
-No not at all.
Let's see...
It's not as dangerous as it looks.
You don't have to be sewn.
I'll take and wash and change.
It was forever since I did this.
Not bad for the ear-nose-throat doctor.
I'm actually trying to solve this!
How did it go on the test?
Good good good.
Now let's see how this goes.
My dad is also a doctor.
Although he does not work like it ... shit the same.
Can't I invite you to dinner?
That's my fault.
Come tonight.
-What have you done with your head?
-Nothing.
I slammed with a girl.
-The did they put you to call you car tires?
-No, "dilek, school horror".
A moment.
What happened to your head?
Come and sit down here.
Sit here.
Was it a butcher who did this?
This must be sewn!
-They said I don't have to sew.
-How can they do?
-No, not it!
Not the Turkish bag!
-Yes!
-Do we deaf?
-It is called be-deaf.
-And the answer is no.
-As you wish.
-You are always wet.
-Wear and horny.
I invited a girl from the samples to dinner.
Are you going on the floor?
Apparently.
I didn't know if it was okay, but the guys are on me.
I fix dinner for you before I leave.
-What have you done with your head?
-Nothing.
It is quiet.
- Hi, Sinan.
-Hello.
-Is everything packed?
-Yes, everything is packed down.
Good.
- But honey, you didn't say what happened to your head.
She crashed with a girl!
And it was the worst bang, she just flew!
She was bleeding from her head.
The girl's mother pasted the wound again.
When Dad got to see it, he got so angry that he Turkishly without stunning!
-So it wasn't.
I wasn't angry.
-Dad, you were fat angry.
Look, the old man.
The main thing is ... sorry!
Main ...!
Sorry!
The main thing is that everything is well now.
We have to go now.
- Come, old man.
-Erik sits and waits in the car.
-I must go too.
Put on the bandage first.
Put on the bandage now.
Put it on!
-Dard ... -put it on.
Listen to your dad.
-Thanks.
-Let's go.
-Hello Hello!
-Bye!
Thanks.
-Bye daddy!
I love you.
-Bye.
Chickedikow-wow-wow, who do we have here
-If not the adorable DI-Di-Di-dilek!
Put it on.
It protects against bacilli.
Of course you have to keep the bag.
Listen.
c. soundpip-pip
-I love you.
-I love you too.
-Heah so fun tonight!
-You too.
Bye.
- Bye!
-Hay, Yasmin!
-Hello!
Hello Darling!
-Dilek's second bagi-Di-Bagi-Di-bag.
-Bye!
-Have you badly in your head?
-Yes.
I thought it was some fly.
You going out tonight?
The guys will light up on the bandage.
Yowsa, yowsa!
Yes, now let's see here.
There she lives.
How nice!
Thanks!
-Are you coming?
The puddle is finished.
-I bring a couple of cold.
-I know her well.
-Elin?
-Yes, Ellen!
-Yes.
Elin ...
-Do you know who more lives there?
-No.
-Henke Larsson!
-Oh really?
Hello!
Welcome!
How fun.
-Good.
-My favvo.
Tell now, then.
We came to Sweden twelve years ago.
I was only eight.
Dad was one of Istanbul's best heart surgeons.
But one day the police came.
He had operated on someone who was on the run.
He just does his job.
We got a hell.
We had to escape.
We ended up here.
"Sweden also needs thoracic surgeons," Dad thought.
-But he was ttt.
-TTT?
Turkish thoracic surgeon running a subway.
-Is it true?
-To make a long story short.
He dips because he is not allowed to work with what he wants.
He has given up.
Mom, on the other hand, works as an optician.
One day a Svenne slips in and will try a pair of sunglasses.
She fell in love and left Dad.
And in addition, the little acid gets shit in the plug.
So it looks to me.
No wonder you want to become a police officer.
I want to do something important.
Something where I can use my background.
I believe that there is justice.
Do you think I'm a pretto?
No.
I just think it's so cool with your commitment.
-The bowl for it and for you.
-Bowl.
I'm tired of my family.
The Uniform family.
The brother is also military.
As if the other plots were not enough.
Am I independent?
-No, you probably have your reasons.
-What are they, then?
Actually?
-I'm not a shink.
-Fan, then!
They should see.
-Good!
Go, girl!
Bowl!
-Bowl.
Okay!
I have a dream!
-What is it then?
-This is ... it's ...
It is not to become a doctor, as Dad wants, and inherit grandfather's medical bag.
Oh, it's the worst trauma.
No.
I'm going to be jus ...
I will become Minister of Justice.
Your turn.
-You will think I'm ridiculous.
-Try me.
Do you have to talk English all the time?
SOR ... sorry.
Okay.
I would like to work with horses.
-But you already do.
-In a stable.
I mean like Barard.
-Bay-what then?
Baryard.
-Yes.
Damn, are you completely gone, right?
No, but that's not my thing.
Snobbly racing riders and such.
It's the horse.
Take the feeling of being one with the horse.
Speed.
The atmosphere.
It would not be entirely wrong to be a riding police officer, right?
You know?
You and I are needed at the police college.
It's just that.
-Bowl.
For us.
-For us.
-I am named Henke, and I live here.
-Hey!
-Ni is doing well?
-So damn good!
Sit down, panky!
-Hello!
-Here Yasmin.
- Henke.
Larsson.
-What has happened to your head?
-I was so customer.
She stumbled upon me who sat down.
And then we had to go to mom.
There we passed the whole queue without paying a splash!
Mom would sew.
But it didn't help, because then Yasmin went home.
Then...
... her dad brought out the anxiety bag with this bandage!
Which she has had to walk around!
Do you understand?
Worst sick day!
I'll get into that school easily as a plaque.
You probably need a cup of tea.
Yes thank you.
The c. soundtter door opens
-Are you awake?
-Where have you been?
Do you know what time it is?
Why don't you wear the bandage?
- Hall, wait a while.
Have you been drinking?
- Yes, I've been drinking.
- It's not good to drink in your condition.
- Otherwise, I'm getting mad at this.
What's wrong with you?
Why do you do this?
Why can't you speak Swedish?
I drive a subway.
It is enough to be able to: "Watch out for the fools."
Stop!
Just stop, stop, stop!
"Watch out for the doors!"
I get brain haemorrhage on you!
You are a fool!
Don't come with that bitterness.
"I'm a subway driver."
It's not even about it, but about making yourself a damn victim!
Yes.
You are a thoracic surgeon out at your fingertips.
I know you.
You know everything you want.
You're just so damn proud.
You are so damn idiot!
That pride made mom stack-
-and will make me stick!
How can you talk to your dad like that?
Dad.
I am not stupid.
When no one looks at, you do movements and mumble medical terms.
But I see.
I see everything.
And I'm tired of this.
For God's sake, Dad.
I love you.
But you have to sharpen yourself.
Good night.
-Good night.
Watch out for the fools ... Watch out for the doors.
The doors are closing.
YES!
Elin!
Are you coming?
Suede and sweep properly.
Petra!
Rinse and cool her, and then the green sweat cover.
-Do you on the course?
-Yes.
It went bad.
-Heh ... -But God ...
Is this you work?
How nice it was!
You forgot this.
I thought you needed it.
A hose bell!
-The fun ... -I couldn't help it.
Excuse me to just extinguished.
Was Henke Schyst against you?
You have the nicest guy in the world.
He made sure I got home by taxi.
"You should not ride a subway when you are packed. I know, I'm a guardian."
He probably thinks he's Clark Kent.
I don't want to be with a space hero.
It gets so magnificent.
"Kind".
I will soon spit on that word.
Turkish Delight?
May I take one?
-Does it taste good?
-So there.
Maybe I'm just in a boring phase.
Or I'm back.
We can't hold on and bend.
We have more important stuff ahead of us.
A little bird whispered in my ear-
-That we have obviously gone on!
Now the physical tests are waiting!
Don't take yourself out too soon, the bride.
Hello and welcome you should be!
Stefan Ljungsäter.
Today I replace Roland Hultberg who is sick.
I am the director of the operations but will today take care of the physical tests.
What a hottie!
Impossible mission.
Is that what we are facing today?
Answer No.
If you have trained properly, there will probably be no problems.
If you've been a little bit over the past two weeks: Throw yourself in the wall.
Good!
Do we have any questions?
- Yes?
Surely the results requirements for women are not the same as for men?
That is correct.
I will come to it.
-More questions?
- Yes?
-What does the test doll weigh to be lifted?
-Higher!
-What does the lifting doll weigh in the lifting test?
The doll you should lift weighs 77 kg.
Same for everyone, no exceptions.
Does it feel hard?
-Okay, are you tagged?
-YES!
-Are you tagged?
Come on!
Good!
-It is good!
-Come on now!
Come on!
Yeah!
-Come on.
-It's good, come on!
Good.
Damn, you were awesome.
Good work!
129 doesn't feel good!
Pick her off the track!
- Work!
What happens?
Okay?
Okay.
Yes, is anyone else who wants to try my mouth-to-mouth method?
-What are we doing here?
-Don't start again.
I don't pallet.
Tjena, young people!
- Hi, little!
Have you longed for me?
-Tjena, Henke!
How did the flooring go?
-We won.
I have threatened a new club.
It's my day, so I have to decide everything.
- You write, Yasmin.
I start, then Yasmin, then dad.
Then you can write DYP on the score card.
-What then "DYP"?
-Type type.
-Do you talk or are you going to play?
-I intend to do both.
Mom should not root among the bottles.
I know exactly what we should have.
Here, honey.
And now he comes!
Sinan, the swing's sultan!
-You don't boast about himself.
-Sch!
Dad concentrates.
-It became the nail!
-It is called nail.
-I said so.
-I give up.
Don't do it when I have my head in the nail.
-Whisky, Dad?
-Javisst.
Here, Uffe.
My name is Ulf.
-How does the dissertation go?
-No can say to me.
Not much resistance.
I lack challenges.
Been there, done that ...
Bought the t-shirt.
I hadn't heard it.
Lill-Lieutenant, what will it be of you?
The captain is me.
I was going to be general.
Sure, why not?
But you have to control the place.
The defense staff is a joke.
How do you solve their structural problems?
I had the second best result of the girls on the freezing test.
-Who had better?
-What does it matter?
-Yasmin.
She was damn good.
-Yeah, is that the Turk?
Demiro-Gl-Gl ...
Demiroglu.
Her parents are from Turkey.
How do you know her?
You have to go when your little girl is going out into the big world.
Check out the competition, talk for the item.
In this case you.
-And it doesn't hurt to be called Enecke.
-I don't want your help.
But you are likely to need it.
Why are you so mean?
Little friend, I care about you.
You are looking for a profession-
-Where you need to be stress -resistant, tolerant, honest ...
-Se something of it in on you?
-Ulf!
A little she has to tolerate if she is to become a police officer.
Patrolling police, it's no play.
She wants to become a riding police officer.
Nämen, Lilla Hjärtat, Now you have got it.
Baked together your dreams.
Adorable!
It seems wise, considering your experience.
Fully realistic.
What gives you the right to constantly turn on me?
Any academic points?
You laugh, but I know what I can do.
I'm not as cynical as you, and I'm terribly happy about that.
Ouch!
-Elin!
Did you just want to leave me there?
-Yes.
I'm so damn tired of your style.
If you pull, you pull for good.
Elin?
And then it gets off!
It worked.
I can breathe again.
Then we can only see if the other works.
Hi, you've come to Elin.
Leave a message and I'll call.
Call and say where you are somewhere.
It's so sexy, this line.
You are nice, you, Miss Enecke.
-Intensive.
-You are not so stupid either.
-Is it okay if I close my eyes a bit?
-You do it.
C. sounds
Hello!
I can not sleep.
I think of mom.
May I lie with you?
Obviously you get.
But we can go in to you, it's much nicer there.
Leave a message.
Hello.
I meant what I said.
It was damn bad style to just leave me with your parents, and ...
But I don't want you to be sad.
So that...
And then I get a little worried too, because you don't ... Damn, come home!
Do you think mom will come back?
I do not know.
But it will be good.
Try to sleep now.
c. sound signal
Yasmin!
Yasmin, wake up!
Your phone rings!
Yasmin!
Hurry, then!
It is ringing!
Hurry up!
Hurry, then!
Respond!
-Hello?
-It's Henke.
I didn't know who to call.
I don't know where Elin is.
-I thought she was with you.
-No.
-What is it, Henke?
-I hope you can fall asleep now.
-Good night.
-Who was it?
-A friend.
-Who is Henke?
-Is that your guy?
-No, it's Elin's guy.
Why does he call you, then?
Why does he call so late?
-Sleep now.
-He is probably in love with you.
-Stop!
-He is probably it.
-You are stupid.
-You too.
-Ravi!
-Heah, dilek!
- Hi, the doctor!
Always just as serious.
Someone has to drive the train.
Is it me?
Is it you?
No, it's you!
Come!
-You don't say "watch out for" ... doors?
Only in horror traffic.
C.Sangen Wonderful Morning C.Sangen Wonderful Morning we have here
c.Sangdet is you, it's me ...
She is, it's safe!
- Mom!
-Darling!
-The fun that you are here, mom!
-What are you doing here?
-I had the roads past and thought ...
I have a little run.
So I have to go.
Sure, of course.
But we see you at the play?
Nothing can make me miss Dilek's magic violin game.
-Mom, I have to go now.
-Bye.
-Bye daddy!
- How are you, Sinan?
-I feel good.
-Lite alone, maybe.
-We are all alone.
You have changed.
I must go.
-Where have you been?
What has happened?
-I am nothing!
Elin, I don't hear what you say!
I've been with him!
-With whom?
-With Stefan!
-What Stefan?
-Stefan Ljungsäter!
-It's not true!
-I wish it wasn't.
-I'd you in love with him?
-No, he's the worst mucus!
Elin, it's hard to keep up now.
What did you think?
I didn't think so much!
You, I have to take a customer.
I'll call you as soon as I can.
-Is it closed?
-Yes.
No.
I'll just open.
Thanks.
What are you doing here?
-She never came home last night.
-Yeah.
Well, what a strange thing.
The battery for the mobile is probably over.
And then she is stubborn and a little varnish.
Do you know what I think she has done?
-That she has moved out to the horses.
-Do you think so?
Damn, how smart you are!
And how fucking stupid is I?
I haven't even thought that thought.
-What long it took.
-He was here.
Henke.
-What did you say, then?
-You probably got to the stable.
I hate to lie, grasp it!
Elin, you have to tell me!
Where the hell have you been?
-Do you be at work?
-I will go soon.
-Where have you been?
-I needed to be for myself.
-I went to the stable and slept there.
-I know you slept in the stable.
-Why did you ask, then?
-You could have heard from you.
-Have you listened to the answering machine?
-No, because I have no batteries.
Damn sunny in today, right?
-Sorry.
-Who fuck are you really?
What do you want with me and yourself?
Check out Yasmin.
She is passionate about something, but you ...
Welcome!
I would have taken care of you on the freezing tests a while ago.
But then I got a flu, so Stefan Ljungsäter had to move out.
With that honor, I understand.
Hörni, last round you were 3,500 who fought.
Now we are down to 780 people.
The number of places we have to offer is 528.
Continue fight.
These two days you should do an acting test and psychology conversation.
You will write an essay and will be interviewed by two police officers.
Some questions?
Okay, then we drive.
Good luck!
-Are you a little happy today, right?
-To meet the idiot Pungsäter.
He doesn't remember you.
You are probably part of his mental email box.
-Swrit your impulsivity.
-I can bridle it.
Today I have control over my life.
What do you see most as?
Woman or immigrant?
Human I see me as.
Yes, Elin ... The police profession is not completely unknown to you?
-No.
-So what is your motivation?
-My motivation?
-Yes, your very own.
I think I as a woman can contribute another way of thinking.
Maybe with my presence I can have a calming effect in situations.
That I am perceived as less threatening than a male colleague.
You master the language extremely.
-Ar it been extra important to you?
-Yes.
-How do you look at your background?
-I'm proud of it.
-Do you feel that you blend in?
-Yes absolutely.
Conny: Should we train Muslims?
When talking about the troll: It's pork today.
Isn't it a little hard for you to be here on the immigrant quota?
I must not be provoked.
-Something doesn't match him.
-Type that his brain should be replaced.
-I think he's a criminal.
-Criminal?
What do you get it from?
If he is punished I will find out.
Oh really?
-To you're called Enecke, right?
-Just.
Check out a Conny Svensson.
Suddenly it fits with Dad's help.
Why would I do that?
It is an unpleasant racist devil that is entering school.
-Is he's been stupid against your Turkish friend?
-Do you hear how you sound?
He harasses her when no one sees.
-Is not the black skulls easily offended?
-What the hell are you saying?
Are you crazy?
Little, I'm just kidding.
You are so grateful.
GL-GL-GL-GL-GL ...
Life is not just a play.
It's a dance on roses too.
Damn too!
-Thanks, please singoalla!
-Yasmin was what my name was.
Yes of course!
Now I remember!
But you look like Singoalla!
-I know those who live there.
Ellen.
-Elin, yes.
Yes.
And do you know who lives there more?
Henke Larsson!
-But hi!
-Come in.
Elin said she would be delayed and you would feel at home.
-You do well by this time.
-Is I here too often?
Now I'm ashamed!
No, puck.
We love company.
It's cozy to have you here.
-In addition, I win over you in TP.
-In your dreams, Henke.
-Joho.
-No.
Damn, I have to take a shower.
-Can you fix tea for so long?
-Absolutely.
c. sounding pot piper
Can you pick up a towel in the large closet?
I am coming now.
-Yes, excuse.
Well ... -Gee here the towel.
I'm freezing.
"Ulla has a puppy. Kalle has a cat. Nisse sits still on a chair."
"Anna dances in her beautiful k-skirt."
-Waver skirt.
-Skirt.
"Eva is out with little brother."
"The sun is shining. Eva has a new k-skirt."
-Ny skirt.
-Ny skirt ...
I am home!
Hello!
What are you sitting here for?
-Is not yasmin here?
-No.
What is it?
Surely no one has died?
Elin, I have to tell you one thing.
I have kissed ...
... someone.
It was great that you told me.
We should be honest with each other.
In fact, I have also kissed someone.
-Have you also kissed anybody?
-Japp.
-What then, now?
-No not now!
It is not the whole world.
We have had it swaying, a situation arises.
A kiss ... it was just a kiss.
There was nothing more, right?
No absolutely not.
-Did you do anything more?
-No.
Nah.
-Do you want to know who it was?
-Absolutely not.
I think we just forget this.
-It was yasmin.
-Wo?
-I kissed Yasmin just recently.
-What the hell...
-Sorry.
-What then "sorry"?
Henke ... it's so damn run between us.
It has been so damn long between us.
You can just go to hell!
Elin: Cheers for us.
Turkey's new Foreign Minister Mehmet Ipekçi arrived today in Stockholm.
Thick Mehmet!
C. sounddörr clock
I thought we were polished!
-Hi Elin!
How are you?
-I feel good.
-Dad, Dad!
It was Elin who came!
-Hello!
Nice to see you!
Sit there.
Sit, sit,!
Excuse me, but I'm a little excited.
He is Turkey's new Foreign Minister.
We went to the same class at Galatasaray.
We called him thick Mehmet.
-Galatasaray is a football team?
-A neighbourhood.
We went on a boarding school.
-I have I told you?
-Yes, 75,000 times.
-Where was he who kissed on him?
-No, he wasn't.
He was just thick and smuggled in lots of sweets.
-And now he is Foreign Minister.
-How fun!
Unfortunately, I have to go.
I would just leave a few stuff to Yasmin.
Are you going already?
Yes Yes.
Farewell!
You follow me to the door, right?
One thing you should have clear to you: I never want to see you again.
-Joel Bergqvist?
-Yes.
Yasmin Demiroglu?
No Yasmin Demiroglu?
She is at home and rumors the camel.
No.
Can anyone imagine where she is?
Yes.
When she has applied here, she has suffered racist hopes.
Therefore, she does not want to come here.
Give me an hour and I have her here.
One hour.
That's all I want.
I interpret it as a yes.
Yasmin!
I know you're there!
But damn, open the door!
I knew you were here!
Do not leave because it hits me.
You ran at 8.30!
-8.48.
-8.48 or 0.7 does not matter.
No one is better than you!
No!
I will still end with Henke.
Come, we'll put a little racist there too.
We don't have time to stand here.
-Are you on the track?
-Definitely.
You have a seven hell's good friend in that girl.
You know, huh?
It goes well!
You do not need to worry.
You are the wet dream of the corps.
Young, talented woman of foreign origin.
Okay, bad jokes.
Oh!
Then it was lunch!
I'm going to daf that Conny bastard.
I go in and then you keep an eye out.
YES!
-Tjena Hi!
And here you stand.
-Yes, I'll take myself again a bit, just.
-Is it so strenuous?
-Yes.
No, it's stimulating.
-You get easily overstimulated.
-Yes, it can certainly be.
Drive hard, you can go a long way!
c. soundyasmin coughs
-Thanks!
-Are you okay?
I know a very good grip otherwise, inspired by the Heimlich method.
-It's calming down.
-Okay.
I keep your thumb.
-What just happened?
-You favvo fucks.
-Help!
Where is he now, then?
-He went in.
Here I have stuff.
-Is Conny punished?
-Is Pope Catholic?
Check this out.
Damage and gross abuse.
He sat at Österåker November 2002 to June 2003. Now we have him.
-And how did you get this?
-Does it play any role?
We must not go into the registers and check those who apply without asking.
You definitely can't do it.
This can have serious consequences.
-Is there anything we can do?
-No has already done too much.
We cannot see between the fingers of your illegal business.
Our illegal business?
You can do whatever you want with the information.
We have only taken our responsibility.
I'm sorry to have to say it, but you are loose.
Unfortunately.
c. sound "The flower time now comes"
Hi, what a good thing you had!
-Erik, then?
-He is not coming.
I'm leaving now.
I sleep with Nisse tonight.
It's probably best for both of us.
Yes absolutely.
Call if there is anything.
I thought you would know.
It is to cross the limit.
Thank you for looking past.
I appreciate your loyalty.
-I am happy to be at service.
-We keep in touch.
-Hello!
-Hello.
What the hell have you been doing this time?
Have you put in systems not to answer?
You have dragged my name in the dirt.
You can forget the police college!
-Mom, what kind of moving class?
-Do you know somewhere I can live tonight?
You come with us.
His world turned black since we moved to Sweden.
He closed me out.
I didn't reach him.
I couldn't stand anymore.
I need the joy.
-But he is happy now.
- Right?
-Yes.
-Will it work now?
-I do not know.
I want it.
-I love your dad.
-And you chose Erik.
-It's easy to be after -sound.
-You probably won't worry about Erik.
I don't think he gets depressed.
He is always kidding.
He is another kind.
The old man, what about yourself, then?
Shit it is.
We are totally interrogated.
We have sabotaged everything.
I wish I was eleven years old and you could do all the good again.
Sit here and every eleven years again.
Come.
You are amazing.
There is nothing you can't do.
Nothing.
-I admire you so much!
-There are things I can't do.
Hörtu, it is the same girl who would be Jusissi ... just minister.
Attorney General.
I will become Justice Minister.
Yes, Jussisisominist ...
Jesustisti ...
Jussistim ... damn Swedish languages!
You have to bring your eye stone!
Take it you.
It fits in the TV corner.
Then, then it wasn't much more.
-How big does it have it?
-A third.
His acid lives there too.
Hello!
I was just thinking I was going out and greeting.
-Sara.
-Nisses sister.
-Elin.
-I know.
No, I just wanted to thank.
-Thank?
-To you dropped him away.
There is no one like Henrik anymore, and then I got a copy.
Yes ... the world is full of shit boots.
Although I think you will find someone, with your lovely mood.
Henrik has told us.
Do you know that Sara is also horses?
She competes.
Very good!
Our next bayrad.
Baryard is called it.
I am selected as a reserve in the national team.
Great fun!
But I am most happy that I can join.
What fun it was to meet you, Elin!
Hello with you!
Fun!
Yes...
I pick up the rest late.
Nisse can help me with the sofa.
The keys.
Mom, I'm so tired of myself.
I go ahead, I scream and gap.
-It's not very attractive.
-Do not say so!
You are the only really brave in the family, the only one with civil remedies.
I wish I was little.
That you would do all the good again.
-Now you aren't.
-I know that.
-Is that police officer?
-I'm probably fried.
-Do you want that?
-Yes, I want that.
-What exactly are we doing?
-You have to trust my gut feeling.
-The guy is a stone sadness!
-Get it together!
- If Turkey changes, you must be part of the EU.
- Yes, and that's why we work on it.
- Do you still prison journalists?
- No, they are as free as you are.
Mr. Minister, now we're going for lunch.
Swedish buffet, herring and potatoes ...
Mr. Minister?
Call for the ambulance!
Turkey's Foreign Minister has collapsed.
c. soundsirenes
Listen.
I want Sinan Demiroglu.
-What did you say?
- I want Doctor Sinan Demiroglu.
He is a heart surgeon.
He lives in Stockholm.
-Elin, we're going home now.
-No!
Come on now!
He wants a Sinan Demiroglu.
-What is it?
-A Turkish physician living in Sweden.
-He is completely indefinite at that point.
-Can we get information on ...?
-What did you say his name was?
-TemoGlu.
-Sine Demiloro, something ... -Man in his 50s ...
-He is a doctor, not a subway driver.
-Suri, I can help you.
Pulse 140, blood pressure 100/60 and separation 95.
Heart disease in the genus.
A case at the highest government level.
You need your help as a surgeon.
-Now I do not understand.
-The patient wants you.
-Who is the patient?
-Turkiet's Foreign Minister.
Thick mehmet ...
Agility?
What the hell is that?
-Dog dress.
-In!
In!
Beware!
Gently!
Beware, beware, beware!
Suddenly he's just gone.
-It was you who ended.
-You can get rid of?
Only I don't have to hear.
The horses do not get abrasions in the ears.
You are funny, you ... yes, no ... otherwise?
-We suck.
We are completely useless.
-Yes.
What do you say about moving in?
I've always wanted to live with a comedian.
Do you want an ice cream?
I go shopping, you stay and guard.
We have a criminal over there.
The doctor!
I take over the train.
-I understand that we are in a hurry.
-Alt time just as serious.
Good.
Hurry!
Watch out for the doors.
The doors are closing.
Good luck!
-You don't want to look like me at the waist.
-I think you are beautiful.
Not many people do.
An old, thick, flabby guy.
-I need information about the case.
-I call Karolinska directly.
We must start mocking shit at Malin Baryard now that we are not coming in.
After all, I have it in the blood.
Damn too!
How could it turn out like this?
-We are nice people.
-Yes is not it?
Morally infallible.
Justice Minister ... Tjena ...!
Riding police: Hello then!
-Where there is a poem, right?
-Yes.
Verner von Heidenstam.
I thought I recognized it.
Hello Hello.
- Do not worry.
I'm here now.
Everything will be fine.
Do not worry.
-Where did he come from?
-He applied for a job here when I was new.
Surely you will operate me?
I just trust you.
-What are they doing?
-Weapons boxes.
Stay him.
Stay him!
Hello!
Would you look at that!
A friend and colleague!
I think I've been lost.
It's not really my neighborhoods.
I can't the country.
I get spinning of all the red cottages with white knots.
-You keep in my dog.
-I do.
Nice!
Welcome!
Nygård, thoracic surgeon.
I will perform the operation.
I have respect for your knowledge, but we can't let you operate.
I'm sorry, but we have to stick to Swedish legislation.
Unfortunately.
As a student, I saw one of your guest operations in Frankfurt.
It was extremely impressive.
But it would be an honor if you want to assist me.
SAW.
Diathermy.
Hook.
-Start heart-lung machine.
-The heart-lung machine goes there.
c. sounds many beeps
The back first.
- You also.
-Can he bring the dog with him?
-Mom can take it.
-What does she have for numbers, then?
-528 37 66. Her name is Ing-Marie.
-We'll fix it.
-Thanks!
Put yourself in the car now.
Watch your head.
In with the legs.
c. sounds many beeps
We must probably redo his anastomosis.
You do it.
-Watch out for the fools.
-You are thoracic surgeon!
I know you!
You know everything you want.
You're just so damn proud!
That pride made mom stack-
-and will make me stick!
Dad.
I am not stupid.
When no one looks at, you do movements and mumble medical terms.
But I see.
I see everything.
-Do it.
-Thanks.
So, the doggie.
We are not police officers and will never be.
Now we are done.
-We get off the heart-lung machine.
-I go down in flow.
We are holding on your thumb.
-Gratulates, Doctor Nygård.
-It I'm who will congratulate.
-Thanks, Doctor Demiroglu.
-Call me Sinan.
- Thank you everyone!
-Hi Elin!
-Hello!
What are you doing here?
Sorry, I didn't want to bother.
But...
I just wanted to say it to you directly that Conny Svensson is a lifting.
-He sits on the Kronoberg detention.
-Have they decided on me and Yasmin?
There will be no reprisals, despite your overtramp.
-Did you have anything to do with it?
-No.
-Nice horse.
It's yours, huh?
I have a brown, small pony.
The one I always had.
Yes, after all.
What happens to us?
I hope you come in!
-What are you sitting there for?
-I wait for the letter with the message.
There is a postal strike throughout Sweden.
Just kidding.
You looked so sad.
You have to laugh in life too.
- Dilek, hurry up now!
The old man ...
Come here, the man!
-DOKNA at the hospital!
-Thanks!
I'm happy for us.
I must go now.
- Good luck you with, old man.
- Bye!
-I will not come in, dad.
-Does it matter?
Nothing.
The main thing is that you have fought.
You have been so wonderfully good.
I may not have managed to show how proud I am on you.
You are so strong, my girl!
Both in the head and in the body.
What I am trying to say is-
-That already this is a victory.
-Doesn't it?
-Yes.
-Have you plugged in Swedish?
-I have read some Henry Mankell.
It's time for me to move.
Isn't it a bit early, my girl?
You are just the child.
Imagine that you have become big.
-You are an adult now.
-Yes.
My little girl.
Yes Yes...
Yes.
Good luck today.
Health Foreign Minister.
Good luck to yourself.
I really hope you come in.
Now you got away again, your thick!
What have you done to me, huh?
And all this because I didn't invite you to candy at school ...
No, you didn't.
Thick and stingy, you are in cubic.
But do you know what?
I give you whatever you want now.
If you want to buy you a whole candy factory.
Oh, so easy you will not get away.
You follow back to Turkey, right?
We really need like you.
How could I go back?
My whole life is here now, my friend.
Sinan, I'm so endlessly grateful.
You've saved my life.
c. sound gate opens at both
Damn!
-Yes?
-I got it.
See you in the middle.
Hello!
Okay.
Doctor Demiroglu?
We have met before.
Georg Lagerkloo.
I remember you.
You are the head of Thorax.
Right.
So you could say.
We are extremely happy to have you here.
So it didn't sound ten years ago.
Ten...?
Now we should not talk about the past, but look ahead.
This meeting takes place more formally later.
You have a competence that we are in strong need to have.
I have two questions for you.
Would you like to work with us?
And if so, is the language a major obstacle?
-The question one I answer yes.
-It's good, that's good!
On question two I say: It's a small obstacle.
There we have the needle eye.
The language.
You have to take an intensive course in Swedish-
-With the focus on medical terminology.
But everything will happen according to your needs and desires.
What do you say?
I say:
Fat well.
SWEDISH SUNTING: Jussi Walles BTI Studios for SVT