That is Axel von Fersen, the most powerful official in Sweden.
But it ignores the crowd outside - they want to tear him into pieces.
Now he hides for his life.
He was a close friend of Gustav III, interpreter for George Washington -
-And lover for French Queen Marie-Antoinette.
/ Banking/ But none of it helps him now.
At the beginning of the 18th century, Sweden is an exposed and exhausted land-
- After Karl XII's war.
But out of the ashes something new is emerging.
New ways of thinking beats root.
Trade and science flourishes.
With the enlightenment comes new ideas about freedom of the press and popular influence.
But it is a development that will encounter resistance.
This is the story of our country.
About the people and forces that have shaped it -
- Endure from the ice age until our days.
This is the story of Sweden.
/Upset votes/
Inside, Ulrika Eleonora - Sweden's Queen and Regent is located.
She will not gain as much power as her predecessors.
She has been forced to sign a new form of government.
It states that the Riksdag should appoint Sweden's king or queen.
The Riksdag has begun to raise its vote against the royal power.
The time of freedom is here.
The most important thing for the Riksdag in 1719 is to abolish royal monarchy.
The change can almost be called a revolution in Swedish state.
During the 18th century freedom, Sweden receives a constitution-
- As closest to a republic in everything except the name.
The background to the revolution is Karl XII's long war.
The nobility wants to break the king's monarchy and put more power at the parliament -
- To not end up in a similar situation again.
When Karl XII dies, at that moment the ball meets him at the war scene -
- Breaks up noble commanders and heads on to Stockholm.
Work on a new form of government is being started.
A chance they do not provide.
The nobles of the National Council manage to get Ulrika Eleonora -
- Giving up his right to inherit the throne of his brother Karl XII.
Instead, the Riksdag should choose her.
But after only one year as Queen, she is completely challenged from the throne.
Her husband Fredrik is elected king.
But he doesn't get so much power either.
He tries to strengthen his position through a coup attempt.
When things don't go as he wishes, he pulls back -
–And is engaged in leisure interests and hunting.
Fredrik I becomes a winged king.
He is a member of the national council, but participates without much commitment.
Maybe it's not that strange.
The King is no longer allowed to start war -
- Decide on taxes or enacts laws.
All things must be approved by Parliament.
It was greatly noticed abroad.
The enlightenment philosopher Voltaire considered Sweden to be the world's freest country.
Rousseau, who was also a philosopher -
- Called the Swedish form of government for an example of the perfect.
But the freest country in the world is not yet as free for everyone.
In Parliament, representatives of the four stands are:
Adel, priests, citizens and peasants.
But many Swedes are not a stand.
Those who are outside the system are those who lack property.
For example, all service caves, boys and maids in the countryside.
They are in turn represented by the farmer who owns the land where they work.
But the influence of the farmers in Parliament is also limited.
The farmers are allowed to participate in the Riksdag, which was unique to Europe.
But they were excluded and were not allowed to participate in decisions relating to foreign policy -
- Finance policy and defense policy.
They were not considered knowledgeable enough.
They were prejudiced that they would leak state secrets.
The 18th century is a time of change.
The farmers no longer accept the old rules of the game.
They do not want the nobility to decide on issues that affect their lives.
Outside the country, dissatisfaction boils.
It's emergency year again.
Many people have a hard time.
You miss the time when the country was ruled by a strong king.
It may seem strange that the Swedish farmers, omnipotence -
- Sized layers of the poor, stood on the king's side.
But for them, the king was a deputy for God.
A group of young noblemen are now drawing Sweden into a new war against Russia.
War costs human life, all farmers know very well.
The government's war against Russia was aimed at restoring the superpower.
One may have perceptions of how realistic that mindset was -
- But the war went to the forest.
Those who pulled Sweden into war have an unrealistic picture of a simple victory.
And they were not thinking about how these affected farmers.
They, in turn, wondered if it was not better to reintroduce a single empire.
A strong royal power could better protect their interests than the Riksdag.
The question is just who will take over after the now old Fredrik I.
He has been sitting on the throne for over 20 years without having children who can inherit the crown.
You have to find a follower of throne.
Now the farmers want to be involved and decide.
The question is important to them.
In Dalarna you want the gentlemen in Stockholm to respect their opinion.
On the part of the rulers, this is partly incomprehensible.
Farmers should take care of agriculture, they are unkind on political issues.
Here they mix themselves in the absolute highest political level.
The governor has been assigned the task of speaking the valley farmers to the right.
But it is an impossible task.
They no longer want to listen to the authorities.
They want to be heard themselves.
And not just on the question of the followers of the throne - the peasants require the stop at the war -
- And that the responsible generals are executed.
In thousands, they walk towards the capital.
Now the big valley uprising is a fact.
Here in central Stockholm, the farmers gather.
But the confident mood gradually transitions into concern.
The state power now decides to put the military against the farmers.
The rebellions had hoped to negotiate, but it will not be.
When it is morning, 90 farmers have been wounded and 40 have been killed.
Thousands are captured the days that follow.
The law states that rebellion should be punished with 120 sprouts.
And every tenth rebel is to be sentenced to death and executed.
But so far you don't go.
In this case, and usually it is so, the courts turn out to be gracious.
You do not want to create even more worry by executing a lot.
There are six leaders who are executed.
But you also take other methods to punish the farmers.
Instead of killing and tormenting, they are subjected to shame.
Those who have been imprisoned in Stockholm must eventually come home.
They are forced to go home without wearing a hat.
At this time, the hat is an important status symbol.
Not having a hat is like not wearing pants today.
It is an incredibly shameful way home that they get to suffer.
This is one of the last big peasant rebellions.
It does not end as the farmers hoped.
But there are signs of something new in the spirit of time, in politics.
Now the thoughts on influence have reached ever further down in society.
The valley uprising showed that the peasantry in general, not just in Dalarna -
- Began to have great political self -confidence.
They thought they would be involved and influence in all types of issues.
That they were knowledgeable and could participate on the same conditions as others.
During the freedom period, national policy is discussed in the country.
It is very important who is elected to the Riksdag.
There is increased political commitment.
It is not just in politics that new winds are blowing.
Now Sweden is seriously becoming part of the growing global trade.
Swedish goods are shipped far out into the world, especially iron.
Salted herring is exported to the Caribbean, as food to the slaves.
In 1731 the Swedish East India Company is formed.
A trading company sailing with goods from Chinese Canton-
- Written Africa's headland, and then to Gothenburg.
The director of the company does not come from the land -owning aristocracy.
He is a merchant, ie a citizen.
The citizens will take up more and more space during the 18th century-
- Special when some of them get rich - really rich.
Two to three expeditions were enough.
Then you could retire.
Now new, exotic goods are flowing into Sweden:
Tea, silk and cotton fabrics - and porcelain.
The item that the Swedes become extra fond of is coffee.
The coffee drinking spreads quickly in the population.
There is a practical reason: you could cook coffee again on the same sump.
As a result, both service people and poor people could taste this luxury.
But all these new foreign goods worry the rulers in several ways.
One is afraid that the kingdom will be emptied of assets, if the whole people -
- Even the simplest maids, get a taste for luxury goods that need to be purchased abroad.
In order to limit imports before you law for how to dress -
- What you can eat, and who can do what.
The new laws are not just about saving the country's economy.
The rulers also want to preserve the old order.
It is about a social order with strict hierarchies -
- And it was considered that the order at all costs must be retained.
You are almost obsessed with order.
You couldn't have people who acted as if they were better than they were.
Each would be in place.
An unequal society works worse unless the inequalities are visible.
So in the Swedish position society it was very important -
- The differences were made visible, preferably through the clothes.
Someone who challenges the order with their attire is this woman:
Maja Stina Kjellström will be nationally known as Bellman's Ulla Winblad.
But so far she is an unknown and poor woman.
Her fine coat of the most modern cut is not just a violation of the label.
It is a crime against the law, so she is arrested by the police.
Disorder feared man.
It was believed that society would go down if one questioned the order -
- or behaved in ways that did not fit.
It is mainly noble ladies that are allowed to dress in imported expensive fabrics.
Citizens are allowed to wear velvet caps, and also mittens and muffs in velvet.
Service people and farmers should dress in Swedish linen and wool.
The fine is high for those who do not comply with the laws.
Anyone who does not have money may pay with a body penalty or prison.
But there are loopholes in the law.
There were some exceptions.
If you worked with silk -
- You can get permission to wear these garments.
Maja Stina claims that she is authorized.
We also know that there were men who wrote false ones such conditions -
- Maybe to women who sold sexual services.
We also know that these garments were hard currency -
–And could be used as compensation in the 18th century sex trafficking.
Maja Stina shows a certificate.
How she got it we do not know, but she escapes punishment.
She is not alone in challenging the old order.
There were so many laws because people were inclined to break them.
And why that?
They might want up, maybe wanted to live another life -
- behaved in a different way than what was predetermined for them.
It becomes like a tug of war between the old and the new one that is emerging.
This is something that characterizes the entire 18th century.
The new one wins more land, and society is changing in many ways.
It is also the great century of science -
- Then the world is explored and explained.
Carl von Linné is considered to be one of Sweden's foremost scientists.
His way of systematizing and categorizing nature -
- Consider enormous impact in the world.
But in eagerness to classify he also divides the human race -
- In different varieties or types he ranked.
Something that many believe contributed to the emergence of scientific racism.
Linnaeus embarks on several trips where he studies plants and animals.
At the same time, he works for the state and studies geology and culture.
His most famous journey is the Lapland trip.
Linnaeus was not traveling just to map the flora.
He would map natural resources, what the state could make money on -
- So that resources in the state could be made useful for the good of the public.
State power has limited knowledge of what northern Sweden looks like.
When Linné returns from his journey with a thorough inventory -
- In a way, he bidders to the exploitation of northern Sweden.
Lapland's trip results in the book Flora Lapponica -
- As is an international spread.
Linnaeus believes in science, and is passionate about eagerness to explore nature.
But during the trips he sometimes encounters things that are difficult to explain.
The thinking of the time still has its restrictions -
- As most people believe that what is in the Bible cannot be questioned.
On Gotland, Linné finds boulders of a rock that does not belong there.
It puzzles him.
We now know that the inland ice brought the boulders -
- For over 13,000 years ago.
Linnaeus knew nothing about the ice age.
He believed, like others in his time -
- The earth was created by God for a short time and 6,000 years ago.
Of course, the ice age as an explanation model was not available.
So Linné tried many different explanations for these boulders.
Finally he wrote down a ...
Maybe it was so that they were moved with streams along the seabed.
It is believed in the text that Linné is not entirely convinced of his explanation.
One can also see in his notes that he would have given the earth -
- A longer, older history - if there had been support for it in the Bible.
It's typical for this time.
Linnaeus, like many others, has a strong belief in science -
- But they are also deeply Christians, and deeply rooted in their faith.
But Linnaeus had a very big impact.
His work affected botany all over the world.
And he was involved in forming the Swedish Academy of Sciences.
The Royal Academy of Sciences becomes an important force -
- And contributes to the researchers starting to think outside traditional courses.
Their research is solid, focused on practical benefit.
It's about streamlining beekeepers -
- And to dika arable land to increase production and make it rainproof.
It was the research they felt they needed.
The Swedish standing society had small margins, a lot of poverty, starvation -
- And a very underdeveloped agriculture in our eyes.
One constructs grain cleaning machines -
- Inspired by a Chinese model.
New tools and more efficient methods increase productivity -
- And facilitates the work for the farmers.
It is also now that you discover that potatoes are not just an ornamental plant.
The tubers of the plant in the soil turn out to be a filling food.
But they can also be used for something else, popular by many Swedes.
Scientific woman Eva de la Gardie's method of making spirits on potato -
- Spread quickly in the country.
She is the Society's lady, but beyond the glamor out on the estate -
- She makes both spirits and makeup of her newly invented potato powder.
With her knowledge of chemistry, she becomes the first woman in the Academy of Sciences.
But scientific discoveries and contacts with abroad-
- Not only the Swedes spirits and new agricultural machines.
It is also the spark of the 18th century idea movement-the enlightenment.
The scientific, critical look that has long been directed at nature -
- Now aims at man and society.
It is thought that man can shape and improve his own world -
- With the help of science, studies, enlightenment.
By extension - better politics.
When you take part in all the progress made in science and other -
- So you realize that development and change is possible, and desirable.
It will be at the heart of the age of reason.
Thinking freely is not without risk.
The old order is struggling against.
The state censorship tries to stop what the rulers consider inappropriate.
Now this man has been called for questioning.
He has written a text that disturbs power.
He is from Helsinki and is called Peter Forskål.
His writing will have significance for the free word in Sweden.
It is a short pamphlet, with some powerful paragraphs.
It speaks for strengthened legal security and ownership, equality before the law -
- Improved the training system, and free and unlimited freedom of the press.
They probably expect a remorseful trash, but he does not regret it.
"Next life can be nothing more than freedom," he writes.
And he intends to argue that.
He succeeds in part, and gets away with a warning.
But the power holders still want to prevent the spread of the text.
The authorities know that the script cannot be banned.
It will only increase demand.
So the last resort is to prohibit all handling of the script -
- With threats of fines, unreasonably large fines.
The idea is that many may be curious about the script -
- But maybe not so curious that they want to risk leaving houses and home.
This is one of the few copies that remains today, the others were burned.
The content of the text was considered far too radically, dangerous.
This scripture presents the Swedish Press Freedom Ordinance - -
- One of our constitutions.
The Freedom of Pressure Ordinance arises at a time characterized by political debate.
The capital is the pulsating heart of political life.
The discussions are lively.
New social groups are heard.
Not least the citizens, who are becoming more and more and want more influence.
Much of the politics is formed at the city's taverns and coffee houses.
Here, alliances are created, and political proposals are negotiated.
Conflicts between the various alliances in the Riksdag -
- Biders to make the Freedom of Pressure Regulation Swedish reality.
When the enlightenment ideas are spread, a power struggle is also underway
- Between two parties in Parliament: the hats and hats.
At the end of the time of freedom, the 1760s, the hats become the party for the nobility-
- While the caps were the party for priests, citizens and farmers.
The hats govern Sweden for a long time, increasingly powerful and corrupt.
The hats had prevented transparency in the state apparatus and the decision -making process.
In this way, they could have placed their allies on key positions.
When the hats still manage to take power in Parliament -
- They drive through extensive reforms to put an end to the hats.
One of them is the Press Freedom Regulation.
When introduced in 1766–
- Is Sweden's first country in the world to introduce such a regulation as a law.
It reinforces the already intense political debate.
A river of magazines, books and pamphlets are printed.
On the city's walls and planks you can now publish critical texts.
You dare to express yourself drastically.
Some authors are progressive, with far -reaching requirements for change.
Against them are more conservatives trying to turn the clock back.
We again have the tension between old traditions and new ideas.
But the new ideas gain land.
Criticism begins to be directed at the nobility:
Why should the nobility be allowed to keep their old privileges -
–And his exclusive right to prestigious offices?
There is a strong movement among the non-adequate stands.
Why cannot non-a-saddle that is merit and well-trained-
- Know the finest services?
Many nobles begin to feel that the privileges they have had are threatened.
For the nobility, this is worrying.
Now the three stands against them that everyone wants to take away from them their privileges.
They think that the radicalization of the political conversation has now gone too far.
The nobility begins to think that the time of freedom has become too free.
So the nobility changes foot.
From trying to limit royal power, they now want the king's support.
Gustav III is on the throne.
He has recently been crowned king.
The nobility hopes for an alliance with him.
Gustav III does not disappoint them, at least not at first.
When Gustav III comes to power all the reforms disappear -
-which was introduced during the freedom period of the non-a-adolescence.
The king is now for a more noble -friendly policy.
Gustav III exploits the new situation and takes back lost power.
He conducts a coup so that he gets freer hands to control Sweden -
–And gets enthusiastic support from the high nobility.
Gustav III calls it a revolution in the spirit of the Enlightenment.
But it is a revolution from above.
What he does is cancel -
- The social and political reforms that have taken place at the end of the freedom period.
At one time he restores what was before -
- With a strong nobility with undisturbed social and economic preference.
/Song at a distance/
It is a party in this guard house at Skeppsholmen.
At The party there is a poet who will soon get his big break.
Namely Carl Michael Bellman.
Together with officer friends, he celebrates Gustav III's bloodless coup.
Bellman has even written a show to honor the main character.
Gustaf's bowl!
the best king, which the Nordic countries own
he can't tolerate  that the weight bowl unevenly weighs
Gustaf's bowl!
Bellman's show quickly gets the king's attention.
Gustav III became very fond of Bellman's work.
Bellman was known before, but as the king is paying attention to him -
- It is like having one on the hit lists, to trend on Instagram.
Everyone knew who he was.
The king's attention benefits Bellman's poor economy, at least for some time.
Previously, Bellman had a service at the Riksbank, but it did not fit well.
At Bank you should be good on counting and mathematics, and he was not.
He was always lousy on numbers in every way.
So he has to stop at the Riksbank.
With his way of life, he pulls on large debts.
Probably his tavern visit to the strained economy contributes.
On an unpaid pub is one of his few preserved script.
The bill also reveals that Bellman did not directly spit in the glass.
Together with his friends he has one evening drinking eight bottles of wine -
–And a bottle nice arrack.
Bellman drank a lot, so did people.
You drank in a different way, spirits for breakfast for example.
But there is no indication that he drank more than others.
By the mid-18th century, spirits are part of the everyday diet.
It contains calories and also works painkillers.
Even children with toothache or sleep problems could get a sup.
I think we have a hard time imagining the amount.
You can see in different sources, diaries and letters, that it is huge.
A recommendation from 1754 says that you should stick to seven supar/day.
Then you could optimize the good effects.
You cleared the stomach upon ascent, for breakfast you took a morning desert -
- You triggered the appetite for dinner, and continued to the sleep soup.
You are happy to drink at the city's taverns.
Here Bellman finds her inspiration.
In Fredman's epistles, Bellman does something new and unique:
He writes about whores and drunk, groups you did not write about.
The people in Bellman's songs are taken from the real Stockholm -
—The people he knows, such as the military and musician Movitz -
- Or the watchmaker Fredman.
And not least the beautiful Ulla Winblad.
It is Maja Stina, she with the coat, who is Ulla Winblad.
This is how she calls herself when she moves in Stockholm's nightlife.
Bellman's Ulla Winblad is the most beautiful - she is Venus, the goddess of love -
- And also a regular woman and prostitute.
She is already known as Ulla Winblad, some kind of party princess.
She shows up at taverns and bales, called horbals.
It was scandal -ridden and unauthorized parties.
For these parties came both simple women, maids and public women.
Here men with money could meet sexually available women.
Many women at this time depend on men financially.
But sex is risky, especially if you get pregnant without being married.
Maja Stina gives birth to a daughter except marriage, who dies after eight days.
But her worries don't end there.
Maja Stina is reported.
In the 18th century, it is a crime for unmarried to have children.
It is a crime to have sex outside of marriage for both men and women.
But usually it is the women who go there, while the men swear free.
Bellman's songs make Maja Stina known.
Many now know who Ulla Winblad is.
It was probably too many humorous to connect this Venus figure -
- With the woman you recognized from the taverns and bales of reality.
For Maja Stina, it was a scourge that persecuted her life.
She did not want to be associated with Ulla Winblad, but did not get away.
Maja Stina marries and moves to Norrköping.
Maybe she hopes for a fresh start, far from Stockholm and poverty -
- Free from Ulla Winblad.
But Bellman's songs are spread far outside the capital.
The rumor that Maja Stina is a role model for Ulla Winblad pursues her.
She does not let comments that connect the two pass.
In a preserved trial protocol-
- Has Maja Stina reported a note on the city's bulletin board.
There she is portrayed as a cheap pleasure for everyone who is interested.
It was the end-shaving of the time.
It is reminiscent of the scribble in telephone kiosks in the 70s-
- Or how you can be suspended today on the Internet.
When Gustav III comes to power he is a young and modern king-
- With great interest in art and literature.
We probably would not have had a Swedish opera or our literature without Gustav III.
He had a huge influence.
He was not only interested but also knowledgeable.
Gustav III sets up performances here at Drottningholm Castle Theater.
He institutes cultural institutions such as the Swedish Academy and Dramaten.
Not least, he lets build the opera house -
–Ast form the scene of a crucial event in our history -
- Where King Gustav himself plays a lead role.
But we're not there yet.
Gustav III was a skilled power player.
Certainly there is a cultural interest.
He wants to develop the culture and the arts.
But it is also a demonstration of power.
The academies, the art projects, the buildings that are built -
- Also there to pay tribute to him.
Gustav III sees himself as an illuminated despot in the spirit of enlightenment.
He abolishes the reforms of freedom, but makes decisions that lie in time.
He prohibits torture, and in the face of an early form of religious freedom.
In 1775, Jews are allowed to settle in Sweden -
- The extent to convert to Christianity.
Later, they founded a synagogue, where the Jewish Museum now lies.
But there are no enlightened thoughts on religious freedom behind this.
They wanted the Jews to contribute knowledge, networks and capital.
In order to settle in Sweden as a Jew, you needed a security letter.
For that, they had to pay 2,000 riksdaler.
In today's monetary value equivalent to SEK 800,000.
Only a small, privileged group of Jews ended up here in Sweden.
It is not easy for the first Jews to establish themselves here.
There is a hostility, mainly at the Citizenship -
- Which is afraid of competition.
So just a few years later, the freedom of the Jews begins to be limited.
The Judae regulations from 1782 state where they are allowed to live, what they are allowed to work with.
They are not allowed to marry non-Jews, and they must not testify in court.
And they are not allowed to work with something that competes with established crafts.
As a result, most Jews came to commerce.
And the textile and textile industry became a Jewish niche.
Freedom is the greater for Gustav III and his closest men.
After a year -long trip in Italy and France -
- They show up art that they brought home.
One of the guests is Hedvig Elisabeth Charlotta.
She is married to the king's brother and lives near the center of power.
A diligent writer who writes sharply about politics and everyday things.
She wrote all her life.
One of the most important testimonies of time.
It is unusual for a woman so close to power that writes so much.
She writes about the young men who have been on Gustav III's journey -
–And that comes back to the Swedish court - spikes.
It was a common, comic figure in the 18th century:
Extremely fashion conscious men with large wigs and tight costumes.
Also on the trip was Count Axel von Fersen.
He is an obvious part of Gustav III's closest circle.
He has a deal with Charlotte, and with many other women -
-Not at least Marie-Antoinette, Queen of France.
At the court, both women and men had great sexual freedom.
Of course, it was about women who were married.
It was a common career path for young men.
They could ally themselves with an older, more experienced woman, with large network of contacts.
For a woman, it was positive to have relationships alongside.
Then she appeared as beautiful, popular, worthy of loving.
So it was positive.
From his journey, the king's company does not just have statues with him.
They have also succeeded in a deal that the king longed for.
They have negotiated with France, so that Sweden gets Saint-Barthélemy.
It is clear early on that the island is not suitable for plantation use.
There are no roads, there is no fresh water in large quantities.
But this island could offer a very good place for trade -
- Special during war, which was often between Europe's great powers.
In this neutral port, goods could be reloaded, not least slaves.
In Sweden, slavery has been abolished since the 1300s.
But the Swedish state power decides that other rules apply to the colony.
Sweden copies parts of a French regulatory framework: code noir, black teams.
There are extreme abuses against the Swedish slaves.
Sweden's history is full of oppression but characteristic of this system -
- Is one group so totally subordinate to another.
It would take until 1847 before Sweden completely abolishes slavery -
-By banning it even at Saint-Barthélemy.
But a lot should happen before then.
At the end of the 1780s, Gustav III's popularity has dropped.
These are times of turmoil and miscarriage years, the alliance with the nobility cracking in the joints -
- And the king's luminous power has begun to fall.
When he also starts war on his own, against the nobility's will -
- They turn to him.
The alliance between the king and the nobility is broken.
Gustav III is a strategist.
He realizes that if he can't bring the rebellious noblemen -
- So he can get support from elsewhere.
So he turns to the farmers.
He now gives the farmers the right to hunt on their own land.
They also get the right to buy the earth they usually from the nobility.
Something Gustav III abolished a few years earlier.
Because he is a skilled politician, he sells it as his own agenda:
He does this with conviction, to promote the little ones in society.
With the peasants on their side and other non-adequate help in the parliament-
- Gustav III glanced to strengthen his power.
It is a victory that annoys the nobility even more.
It will be expensive to him.
Now he becomes isolated and alone.
Gustav III's sister -in -law has a party, but the king is not here.
What happens here is a boycott.
A boycott where several from the king's innermost circle participate -
- Till and with his own sister, Sofia Albertina.
You organize your own parties, and do not go to the parties the king arranges.
A good example of how women at the court could exploit their power.
They do what they can.
They cannot lead parliamentary debates.
Nor can they be part of political clubs.
But they can exploit their absence.
When they are not there, it is noticed and visible.
It is an effective means of power, which they have not exploited in the past -
- To say to their friends: "Don't come at the king's parties."
Then he cannot invite to a party either.
The court life is a reflection of what is happening politically.
Gustav III appears to be lonely, ridiculous and weak.
The king's political game will cost more than loneliness and isolation.
When he lets out a noble officer who defied him and his war -
- So it is the drop that causes the beaker to run over.
Charlotta writes:
"The poured blood fears I will shout revenge."
"The King of Dutch may one day regret his severity."
She gets right.
A group of noblemen conspire about killing the king.
This costume carries the king on March 16, 1792-
- On a masquerade ball at the opera he himself had to build.
There he is shot by Jacob Johan Anckarström.
13 days later Gustav III is dead.
Three years later, the king's guardian Bellman also dies.
He is from a wealthy family, but is buried in an unmarked grave.
Maja Stina, who is said to rest here at Maria Magdalena cemetery -
- Make a reverse trip.
She marries, and up.
She ends her life quite well -off.
Then the year is 1798, and a new Sweden rests around the corner.
Many more will rise up in society.
The old rulers are no longer sitting.
Axel von Fersen is now a national marshal, the highest official of the court.
But he is in a country that has changed shape in several ways.
Finland, the eastern national half, is no longer Swedish - since 1809
- And won't be again.
As a result of yet another lost war against Russia.
It's not the only thing that happened.
Gustav IV Adolf, Gustav III's son, has been deposed in a coup.
There is a lot of concern in society.
It swings on all levels.
One tries to find ideologically and practically how society should be arranged.
It is questioned the value of the old hierarchies.
In 1809 Sweden gets a new form of government -
- Which means the end of the royal monarchy for good.
From now on, power is shared between the king, the government and the parliament.
What happens in 1809 is truly revolutionary.
1809's Constitution and Government Form -
- Not as before perfect, divine, infallible.
On the contrary, it is said that constitution and constitution must be able to change.
In the midst of this revolutionary mood -
- The rumors are spread that Axel von Fersen is counteracting the new board.
On the way through Stockholm, he is chased by a crowd.
He manages to escape into a house, but the crowd is after him.
At this time, his revelation for many is a pure provocation.
That he has been so close to both the Swedish kings and the French-
- Makes that he is largely a symbol of the old type of aristocracy.
The thought that the old order, with von Fersen in the tip -
- would conspire power, arouses an uncontrolled anger.
He dies on the street, disgraced.
The murder can be seen as a ritual murder on the old order.
An expression of the social resolution that prevailed in Sweden.
One has lost Finland, the king is deposed -
- And here is one of the highest officials of the kingdom Lynchad on the open street.
In here, at the Riddarhuset, the news strikes like a bomb.
The murder is a sign that the power of the nobility and the king is not what it has been.
It is soon over the old time and the old order.
In the 19th century, more and more people in society will require rights.
Sweden takes the first steps towards democracy and government.
Texting: Karina Berg Johansson Swedish Media text for SVT