Art - or weirdness?
Sweden's art history is part of the huge story of our country.
With some selected impacts, we will show art that depict changes -
–And Creation power.
Or what is art, really?
Is this art?
Nobody knows.
But we start here anyway.
In the shadow of Nämforsen's power plants there are thousands of tracks -
- Of the possibly artistic creation of our ancestors.
There is a lot of ship and a lot of moose.
461 moose out of 2,600 rock carvings.
The ships and boats are important to them.
But how it would fulfill some function to do this -
- If there is any magic, a hunting diary or mythology, you can't know.
Many have speculated, but you cannot lead it in evidence.
Gustaf Hallström, who made them famous -
- Called them for Sweden's largest monumental artwork.
There is no scientific method that allows us to get a year -
- But you can try to narrow it.
The simplest thing is when you can have started - it is 4,500 BC.
Before that, this was under water.
First everything was under ice.
Slowly, the people migrated when the inland ice pulled away.
Some places provided a lot of food.
There they stopped.
It is bad with water in the Ångerman River this fall.
But it should well arrange for floating and power supply -
- And in the optimistic spirit, Nämforsen's power plant has been inaugurated.
Antiquarian Hallström shows the princess the rock carvings.
The largest overall group you know from northern and central Europe.
Be careful now, Mr Hallström, when you paint in the old carvings!
When the rock carvings were knocked in thousands of years ago, they were white.
They could be turquoise, so it is realized that the painting is hit.
The advantage is that you see them, but you only see someone who has interpreted them.
It can be a little different how you have painted them.
Sometimes a figure has been done differently - right or wrong is difficult to say.
The figure where a moose kisses a salmon ... or is it the salmon that kisses the moose?
We don't really know that.
But where they meet it is like an elevation -
- So probably they have not been done at the same time.
But it's a nice picture.
Fine, new pictures are still discovered by the researchers-with modern 3D technology.
Behind this mossy surface, this huge ship hides.
Maybe it was travelers who were looking for new settlements along the northern coast.
The most common motif in Nämforsen is the moose.
Important food, of course, but perhaps also spirit.
Was the carving in the stone a way to advance the meat?
Art as a vital part of everyday life?
It raises many thoughts.
I move in the forests where the people chased.
If you encounter any catch pit or shard, man - - knows -
- That it was an old man or girl there before me.
It's amazing when the sun goes in clouds and one settles on a cliff-
-And the sun comes at a certain angle and it just explodes with pictures!
What you want with ancient times is not their arrowheads and axes -
- Without how they lived and thought.
And closer than the pictures you will not come.
They are not very clear, but they raise more thoughts on it.
Texting: Britta Landén © Swedish Television AB 2023