The men here have been defeated in battle.
They sailed from Mälardalen west of the Baltic to plunder and war.
But they lost.
But their fate should not deter others from trying again.
On the contrary.
Many Norwegians will follow after-
- And the world will know them as ... Vikings.
We are now at the end of the Iron Age, and a new era is on the way.
Viking Age.
Farmers from our country leave to sea-
- And is known throughout Europe, and further away than that.
The Vikings bring wealth and new knowledge back here to the Nordic countries.
But over time a new religion will be root-
- which challenges the Vikings' way of life.
This is the story of our country.
About the people and forces that have shaped it -
- Endure from the ice age until our days.
This is the story of Sweden.
It's actually August, and it's in the middle of the day -
- Even if it doesn't look that way.
The year is 536 and a disaster has occurred.
It is one of the worst crises in our history.
For three years, the sun's rays cannot penetrate the cloud cover to the ground.
It's like a three -year winter.
A climate disaster has hit Scandinavia.
Away half of all people living here die from cold and starvation.
A series of major volcanic eruptions have fateful consequences in Scandinavia.
In 536, somewhere in the Northern Hemisphere, comes a gigantic volcanic eruption.
And then a volcanic eruption in the tropics.
Together they throw up so much gas particles in the atmosphere -
- The solar energy for the earth's surface is declining.
We get global cooling, especially strong up here on our latitudes.
We know that in Scandinavia the population is almost halved.
It must have been a terrible suffering -
–And it is possible that the memory of the event may be preserved -
- In ancient Nordic mythology.
In the ancient Nordic myths, Ragnarök begins with the Fimbul Winter -
- The big, powerful winter that lasts for three years without summer.
People probably thought the downfall of the world was close.
It is said that nature makes rebellion - winter storms, sea is flooded.
They turn to the gods, who have abandoned them.
How should they regain the help of the gods?
They sacrifice, they pray to the gods.
The Norwegians have many gods.
Odin is the most powerful, and it is mainly the warriors who worship him.
But for the peasants, Tor, Frej and Freja are the most important gods.
They are the ones who have power over weather, greenery and fertility.
Probably the people believe that their victim gifts help -
- For several years of malnutrition, nature recovers.
The climate is slowly but surely returning to the normal-
- And the crops are starting to grow again.
The great starvation is over.
Northern residents slowly rise out of the disaster -
–And for a few hundred years the culture and the community - are formed
- Which will be the Vikings.
Sweden is not a country at this time.
It is a lot of small kingdoms that are controlled by different families and kings.
There are places where people are gathered, so -called.
Central places.
One of the largest is Uppåkra, five kilometers south of Lund.
What characterizes Uppåkra is a residence -
–Dvs.
A large hall building with a cult house next door.
In the cult house we have found lots of gold guys.
Two fantastic beverage cups show that they had ceremonies.
And these ceremonies tie society together in a common worldview.
The central places are important meeting places.
There, the rulers can control trade, plan war and ship justice.
The most important central place in Mälardalen is located in Gamla Uppsala.
Here was the royal seat of the Svers.
And these piles are royal tombs from about 600.
Building such huge monuments requires great organizational ability -
- And a lot of labor.
Such central places are found throughout the country, near rivers and streams.
Or by the sea, where it is easy to get.
At this time, large parts of the country are underwater.
In some places, the sea level is almost six meters higher than today.
The most fastest way to get ahead was on water, not land.
The waterways were like highways, and that was mainly the way the trade took.
The trade routes are profitable.
The kings are competing to control them.
People are already traveling over the ocean-
- But the trade routes also go far up in northern Scandinavia.
Trade is becoming increasingly important -
–And during the mid-700s Birka occurs at Björkö–
- As will dominate trade throughout Mälardalen for over 200 years.
Birka is not a central place like the others.
It is more of an early city -
- Where you mainly deal with long -distance trading and crafts.
A place where people meet and change goods with each other.
Most often you change utensils -
- But there are also amber and expensive fabrics -
- As can come far from the south.
It obviously happens that there will be disputes about business settlements.
But where many people meet, other conflicts and fractions also arise.
To curb violence spirals and avoid blood revenge -
- So the Vikings resolve their conflicts on court places like this.
You select important places that you have returned to generations.
There you find out injustices and make joint decisions.
Coming to a thing for the first time must be a great experience.
You end up in the center of events.
Here men and women meet with power a few times a year.
This is where the big decisions are made.
The word lives in Swedish, as in "county council" and "district court".
Written sources provide an insight into what the Vikings take up on the thing:
Divorces, thefts, murders and ground disputes.
The law was oral.
The laws did not write down until the Middle Ages.
The laws were in verse, and they were repeated to remember them.
The judges were collective decisions.
Most often there were probably twelve officials -
- As the law interpreted and made a joint decision, and that was the verdict.
Women also participate.
They have inheritance rights and can own large assets.
Much indicates that every tenth court is a woman.
In ancient Nordic, "man" means man, regardless of gender.
A town can thus be a woman.
It was a form of democracy -
- Then a relatively large part of society had the right to bring an action on the thing.
It was common with inheritance disputes and ground shops.
Because one had no written contracts -
- So they had a stick that represented the ground.
And when the stick had changed owners, the land had also done so.
When you gather at the thing, you take the opportunity to talk about something else as well.
For example, Viking trains and looting.
Looting were important for young men, who could travel out a few years -
–And come home with riches, set up a farm -
- And get a new, rich life.
Plundering trains are large companies.
They require planning, supplies and weapons.
And above all, you need to build a large number of boats.
The boats are one of the keys to the Vikings' success.
The carpenters who built the boats were incredibly skilled professionals.
Their main tool was the ax.
They could get to plank or table-
–As 15-20 mm thick and at the same time durable and agile -
- What these boats made these boats light and sustainable at the same time.
With their low weight, they are quick to rest, they are basic and silent.
They are nice to sail in headwinds and get pretty good speed.
They are really perfect for the waters around here.
They had many different kinds of ships, but the spine in all was the keel.
It was strong, but flexible to withstand the forces and movements of the sea.
It could go far out in the open sea without breaking the ship.
In the smithy, axes, swords and spears are manufactured.
Here all the rivets of the ships are also forged.
In excavations of the Viking ship, the wooden hull itself is rarely left.
However, the rivets remain.
And their placement at the excavation can reveal what form the ship had.
But what is new about the Vikings' ship is that they set sail on them.
And the sails mark the start of the Viking Age.
The sail is a prerequisite for embarking on that type of travel.
But it also requires that society has reached a new organizational level.
Making a single sail takes one person two full working years-
- Seven days a week, eight hours a day.
We believe that those who manufacture the sails are a labor force -
- Of female slaves, slaves or free, which produces just sails.
Slave labor is a very important part of the Viking Age society.
It is usually talked about that one fifth of the population is non -free.
A ship takes many months to build-
- But when all preparation is clear, it's time to leave.
It is usually young men traveling with the ships.
Because only the eldest son inherits the farm -
- Is the Viking trains particularly attractive to the younger brothers.
They can travel out for a few years and then come home with reputation and wealth.
We have many written sources, including the so -called.
the King's
- which tells about the Vikings' travel and ravages.
They were traded orally, and then there have probably been people -
- As has been the task of passing them on to the next generation.
In the details you get a general picture of how people lived at that time.
There are stories about individuals that we know have been on real -
- Among other things one of the early Uppsala kings, called Yngvar.
It is said that Yngvar was a great warrior -
- As a result of Svea kingdom against attacks from Denmark and the Baltic Sea.
He belonged to the famous Yngling House -
- Which ruled in Central Sweden, Mälardalen, the area around Uppsala.
Yngvar had recently quit peace with the Danes -
- When he went out with several ships to plunder and war in Estonia.
This is how it says ...
King Yngvar made peace with the Danes and then began to ravage east.
One summer he sailed to Estonia with his warriors -
–And ravaged a place called Stein.
The Estonians gathered many warriors to the defense -
- And they began to fight each other.
The Estonians were so many that the Swedes could not resist.
King Yngvar fell.
Yngvar and his men defeated -
- And according to the royal stories, they are buried in their ships on the beach.
In another source it says that Yngvar was killed by the inhabitants of the island of Eysysla.
It is the old name for Ösel in Estonia.
1,250 years later, a spectacular find is made just on Ösel.
When to build a cycle path outside the SALME -
- You can find the remains of two tombs with 41 dead warriors.
The find is a bit of a sensation.
The wood was not left-
- But the iron rivets were neatly lined up.
You see exactly what the largest ship has looked like.
The ships and warriors can be dated to the middle of the 7th century.
It is exciting, because that means the largest of the two boats -
- Is one of the oldest sailboats in the Nordic countries.
For a long time we have learned that the Viking Age began -
- With the looting of a monastery in northern England in 793.
But there was no such sharp limit.
The discovery of Ösel shows that Vikings were out and looted on Estonia's coast -
- More than half a century earlier.
And they have probably looted around the entire Baltic Sea long before that.
Analyzes of the skeleton say that the crew has come from Mälardalen.
They seem to have been quite rich.
The dead were certainly warriors -
- And they brought gifts to life after this before the trip to Valhall.
41 dead warriors.
Each of them has a sword by the side of them.
And game pieces, hundreds.
Someone has posted them on the dead.
There is a game piece that is the king of the game.
Unlike all other pieces, it has been put in the mouth of the skeleton.
Obviously you ask if it can't be King Yngvar -
- As is there in the boat in Salme on Ösel.
We can't be sure that it's really Yngvar's skeleton.
But that's a tickling thought.
These game pieces are also interesting in themselves.
What is fascinating about them is that they are made of the election legs.
And whales are not found naturally in the Baltic Sea.
So where do they come from?
It is here, in Northern Norway, that the elections are chased.
It is from here legs, roller coaster, trans oil and other goods are transported further.
Also to Sweden.
The Vikings live and work along the entire Norwegian coast, up to Lofoten.
But they are not alone.
Here also lives Sami, who chase choices and wildlife.
Choices are an important resource for both Norwegians and Sami.
We find, for example, the ribs of choices, as one has been made of woven by -
-And very beautiful whale tiles found in women's tombs.
We also see it in the form of game pieces.
Those who are specialists in hunting and catching are the Sami.
Nordic society has turned in a direction that is towards the farm, agriculture.
Here are two groups that have two different special features -
- which is in a context and an interaction, as quite equal parties.
The Sami also manufacture ropes and processed horns and legs -
- which are sought after by the Vikings.
In exchange, the Sami get fabrics, axes in iron -
- And buckles, buttons and other metal objects.
On the other side of the mountain chain, eastward, in Swedish Norrland -
- The Vikings also trade with people groups living here.
Among other things, Sami, and a Finnish -speaking group called Kväner.
In the Swedish mountains, along the rivers, in the deep forests down to Uppland-
- established a collaboration between Sami and other Norwegians.
There were groups with different cultural identities.
And the meetings were a prerequisite for the Vikings' trade activities.
The goods are shipped south, along the coast and through the inland of the rivers.
In the end they are replaced by silver and other valuable items -
- Maybe many hundreds of miles away.
But the Vikings are not just traders.
They are notorious for their ravages and looting around Europe.
In the 8th century, the Vikings make raids in today's United Kingdom and France.
They start with single attacks, but after a while they establish themselves -
- And becomes a real power factor throughout Northern Europe.
The Vikings go far west, all the way to America.
But they also travel east.
In over Baltic rivers, and rivers in today's Russia and Ukraine.
As the North residents settled in the area.
There, together with the local population, they built fortified trading venues.
The area is usually called the Rushes Kingdom.
The name probably comes from Roslagen, which the Vikings came from.
A long time later, the Rushers' Kingdom became part of the foundation -
- To what would be called Russia.
Northern residents were committed to successful trading in the east.
A prerequisite was -
- The large rivers Volga and Dnepr in today's Russia and Ukraine.
They were like a highway, the combined factor in the trade route.
There are no easy trips.
The rivers have many difficult rapids -
- And sometimes you have to pull the boats long distances over land.
But the Vikings' boats are relatively light-
- And can be taken past the obstacles with muscle power.
Along the rivers DNEPR and Volga, the Norwegians take on with their precious cargo -
- For sale south, all the way down to the Black Sea and the Caspian Sea.
But the Vikings are not just about furs and crafts.
There is something that is even more profitable.
Trade in labor, or slaves.
And slaves do not have to pay for.
They take them.
The word "slave" in the Swedish comes from the slaves, the peoples -
- which was taken prisoner along the way to be sold as a slave worker.
Slave trade was probably a very important economic factor-
- In the Viking -Age society, more important than we may have understood.
It took the Scandinavians on very long trips.
All the way down to Constantinople, or Miklagård -
- The big place, "The Big Place", which the Vikings called the city.
Constantinople was the Eastern Roman, or Byzantine Empire's capital -
- Where the emperor had his palace.
And there were jobs for the Vikings.
Some Norwegians took up the Emperor -
- And became a kind of elite garde, bodyguards.
They were called Values.
They were known to be skilled warriors.
When the Norwegians are out on their travels, they not only collect wealth -
–On also new impressions and thoughts.
Everything eventually finds here to Scandinavia and Sweden.
Birka during the 8th century is a thriving trading venue-
- With goods and people from all parts of the then known world.
It is not only trade, but also crafts, ie production of goods.
And with all the people moving will also come new ideas -
- New customs, new ways to do things and new religions.
The Asa gods are starting to get competition for space.
His name is Ansgar and is a monk who came from Germany -
- To the Christian people in Birka.
He is the first known missionary in Sweden.
His arrival is the starting point for a change that cannot be stopped.
Christianity will eventually replace asatron -
- And when that happens, the Viking Age is over.
But there we are not yet, because it should turn out that Ansgar's task is difficult.
Ansgar is the first missionary in Sweden, which we know of.
He had pretty big problems with Christian Swear.
But Ansgar is stubborn and makes several attempts to establish a congregation.
You let him mission in peace.
Probably to keep up with the mighty Christian kingdoms in Europe.
It is simply good for the business.
The Vikings are practically laid.
And maybe you are not so worried about the competition either.
A god more or less.
But despite its stubbornness, Ansgar has no great success.
Asatron continues to be dominant.
Asatron was strong and was not only practiced in Gamla Uppsala and Uppåkra.
Throughout Scandinavia there were cult places where they were blotted to the gods.
The word "grove" in a place name may indicate -
- Vargerits took place there, on sacred trees.
They were blotted regularly, ie
one sacrificed to the pagan gods -
- To have success in war and good harvests.
Animals and humans are sacrificed, and with their blood you want to appease the gods.
The bodies are hung in a holy grove.
The cult sites were found all over the country.
What was going on there was not just a matter for the men.
On the contrary.
Women could have important religious functions -
–And act as a cult leader.
Some women were considered to have the ability to put themselves in connection-
–With the other world, where there were creatures and beings -
- That could affect people's lives.
It is clear that Viking -era women played an extremely important role -
- In ancient cult, in magic.
Völvor were called women who were specialized in getting contact -
- With the other side, with the spirit world, to look into the future.
They were both highly acted and feared.
A vault can be likened to a shaman, a wizard woman.
She could get in touch -
- With the dead, look beyond the human eye.
A kind of oracle.
There is an interesting story in the ancient Nordic mythology -
- If Odin has to awaken the killing of wobbles to gain knowledge about the future.
Odin was the god of war and poetry, a master of sorcery -
- But above all, Oden was the omniscient.
Yet he had to raise ordinary deadly women -
- To get hold of a knowledge they had, but he was missing.
The woman knew more than the greatest god Oden.
The stories depicting women with this ability -
–As often recorded by Christian-
- And they are not always positively produced.
On the contrary, they are often badly liked.
But there are reasons to doubt these information.
A new belief comes easily in conflict with the old one.
Here at the height, on Frösön in Jämtland, was an important place in the Viking Age.
Here, a trade route from Norway passed, through Hälsingland to Birka.
But it was probably not primarily trading you devoted to here at the height.
Since the 13th century, Frösö church has been here.
In 1984, a rebuild of the church began.
When you started digging here at the choir, you found something interesting.
In the soil layer under the altar, which belongs to the time before the church was built -
- If you have found a birch stump, and around it lots of animal bones.
There was also the human bone, which indicates that people may also have been sacrificed.
This cult has probably been devoted to the god seed, or frej- -
- For it is seeds that named the place Frösön.
There are probably reasons why the church is built on top of the old cult site.
Perhaps it is a way to mark that new thoughts have had to replace the old ones.
That the belief in the Asa gods must leave room for faith in Jesus.
Or on "The White Christ", as you say at this time.
Now, in the early 9th century, Christianity is starting to enter the country-
-differently.
From the south, west and east.
More and more people are taking impressions home from their travels -
- And begins to confess to the new faith.
It was a time of mixed religion and certainly great uncertainty.
Some sacrificed to the old gods.
Others took on the new Christian faith with only one God.
In the eastern parts, Asatron dominated.
In Västergötland, Christianity was attached as early as the 9th century.
Here, next to Varnhem's medieval monastery church in Västergötland -
- If you have found some of the first and oldest Christian graves in the country.
They are from the beginning of the 900s.
The findings in Varnhem clearly show:
Christianity took root in Västergötland as early as the early 9th century-
- Over it then spread to the rest of the country.
It was a big step to change grave -
- And start treating their dead in a completely different way.
Probably it required a strong conviction to dare to take the step.
They stopped cremate.
The dead would be put unburned in the soil in east-west direction-
–To to resurface on the outermost day -
- With the face to the east, where the Lord would show up and judge the people.
Religion came to Scandinavia in different ways.
On the one hand, missionaries were sent out of England and Germany -
- Along the Western Goths on their travels west with them priests.
They wanted to become part of Western European Christian culture.
They see the developed communities and meet the Christian culture -
- And gets impressed, of course.
They feel that this is the future.
Near the early Christian graves -
- The remains are found after one of Sweden's oldest known stone churches.
It is from the 11th century.
Building a church in stone was something completely new.
This ruin shows that there was a very early Christian congregation -
- As a living and thrived here in Varnhem.
Adjacent to the church ground were found the remains -
- After those who probably let the church build.
North of the cemetery -
- We found a wonderfully fine walled limestone chest with a women's skeleton.
This grave also includes a run -carved tombstone, which has been on top.
It is a Christian cross in the middle and a run loop around, where you can read:
"Kättil made this stone after Kata, his wife, Torgil's sister."
No ordinary people were buried that way.
The design of the coffin shows that Kata belonged to the elite in society.
The skeleton is very well preserved, so we can create a picture of -
- How Kata looked like a living person.
She was 160 centimeters tall, 30-35 years old when she died -
- And from the shape of the skull, her appearance can be reconstructed.
Through DNA we can also determine that she was blonde and blue -eyed.
Probably Kata and Kättil, or their family, built the stone church.
One of Sweden's first.
Such a demonstration of power and wealth must have known the king.
Olof Skötkonung.
Olof is usually counted as Sweden's first Christian king.
With him, Christianity takes another big step into our country.
But for a while, the Asatron and the Viking Age will bite.
Olof Skötkonung lived at the same time as Kata and Kättil-
- And he was baptized in Husaby just a few miles from Varnhem.
We can arrange that Olof has existed through the coins he left behind.
Olof was inspired by England and took English coin master to Sigtuna -
- To characterize coins.
On the coins it says "Olof, Rex Sveorum".
It means "Olof, the King of the Swers".
And these were the very first Swedish coins.
Olof Skötkonung is the first Swedish king -
- Which controls both Svealand and Götaland.
He had a ruling seat in the newly formed city of Sigtuna -
- That was the new hub of the Mälar area, after Birka.
Sigtuna is a Christian city.
People here move from near and far to shop and live.
Half of the residents are immigrant.
Olof also established contacts east.
In order to strengthen their power base -
- He built alliances and networks to trade.
Marriage between influential families was an effective shortcut.
This young woman is called Ingegerd, and she is Olof Skötkonung's daughter.
She marries a king from Rus, where slaves and Viking Estatles live.
And from there she will affect Europe's history.
At the age of 20 she is married away, as a result of the good conditions-
- As has long been between the Ruskish and Scandinavia.
She then becomes a prince, first in Novgorod -
- And then throughout the state, which also includes Kiev.
As a prince in Kiev, she gets three daughters -
- As she marries into the royal houses in France, Norway and Hungary.
Her descendants are long in power around the medieval Europe.
One of her sons founded the Tsar family -
- As in Russia for a long time.
Ingegerd gets great influence -
-And is one of Europe's main characters during the 11th century.
Olof was a skilled power person.
And he did what he could to recruit new souls to Christ.
But Olof's attempt to convert the swearing is not going well.
He tried to burn the temple in Gamla Uppsala, but failed.
He may promise not to mission more in the Uppsala area -
- And he moves back to Västergötland.
There things are going better.
In Skara, Olof founded a bishop's seat -
- As is the oldest preserved diocese in Sweden.
Christianity has come to a halt - and is now starting to take over.
But not really everywhere.
For the Swans in Mälardalen, asatron does not want to give up asatron completely.
A pagan king is still said to rule in Old Uppsala in the late 1000s.
Blot-Sven.
In Gamla Uppsala, they continued to be far ahead in the 11th century.
According to the sources, Blot-Sven is the last pagan king in our country.
But Blot-Sven is not long like king over the Swans.
After only a few years, the Christian Inge comes to Old Uppsala-
- From Västergötland with his men.
When Inge comes, he burns the farm and lets the dead Blot-Sven.
It is said that Inge is taking power over the Svearna -
- And that he finally faces Christianity as a religion.
Blot-Sven is the last pagan king in our country.
After that we only have Christian kings.
When Christianity victories, it means that the Viking Age is definitely over -
- And the Middle Ages can begin.
Sweden will change and become a new kingdom.
The kings become powerful, and the new faith gives people a new meaning -
- And the opportunity for an eternal life.
God gives and God takes.
Texting: Ulrika Jansson Båving Swedish Media Text for SVT