In tonight's section of Ifs, immigrants for Swedes:
Sweden's most fun Chinese: Evelyn Mok.
The country's second best celebrity dancer: Filip Dikmen.
Instagram India from Östermalm: Anitha Clemence.
Gothenburg's best Somalis: Assia Dahir.
Iran in banana salad, salmon sungae Simon Garshasebi
Serbian Humortorpeden Branne Pavlovic.
The grizzly bear from Iraq or really Botkyrka: Musti Jaralla.
Arab equivalent of Ernst: master chef Zeina Mourtada.
Humor Grek Thanos Fatas.
The world's Swedish Arab: Elaf Ali.
Last but not least, our program manager Ahmed Berhan.
Welcome to IFS, where SVT looks like Hornberg's beach in the summer.
Hookah for the whole slant.
My name is Ahmed Behran.
You see quiz from not only 1, 2 or 3, but all culture in Sweden.
/WOLF WHISTLE/
Keep up the applause for today's competitor: Eveline, Daniel and Sigrid!
The contestant chooses one in the panel that I ask another question.
Then the contestant decides whether they are lying or not.
The two with the most points move on to the final.
Me and the competitors have been drawn up who will start.
It is a small advantage to start.
- The advantage went to Daniel!
- What a pressure.
- Who in our panel do you want to start with?
- I want to start with Zeina.
Swedish as a second language.
No!
The last decades -
- Arabic has gone about the Finnish language.
So Arabic is Sweden's second language.
/Ululates/
Daniel, what do you say?
Is Arabic the second largest language in Sweden?
I want to trust her, but I don't think that's right.
- Or do you not hope?
- Grave.
I do not think.
You don't think.
You chose not to believe in Zeina and you did it completely wrong.
Arabic has passed Finnish as the second largest language.
Researchers estimate that over 200,000 speak.
But don't worry, that's only 2 percent.
Better luck next time.
To the next competitor: Sigrid!
Sigrid, which of these ten do you feel you can trust?
Everyone looks credible, but I believe in Simon.
- I drive at Simon.
- Blonde girls like Simon.
Simon was happy like she chose him on a date.
- She just should ask one question, brother.
- Error program, Simon.
They launched a garment for children with the Wild West/Sheriff theme.
The problem was that the garment was similar to the catch suits in Auschwitz.
- Sigrid?
- I believe in him.
- Simon already has citizenship.
-Damn it!
You chose to believe in Simon and you were completely wrong.
- But, Simon!
- It was false.
What he described has happened, but it was Zara.
H & amp; m had a dark child with the t-shirt "Coolest Monkey in the Jungle".
And that child was Ahmed.
Sorry, sorry!
Don't challenge me to an afrospus.
Sigrid, better happiness next time.
Two have driven, no one has any points.
- Eveline, time for you to shine.
I am automatically drawn to the girl up there to the left.
I feel we have color coordinated tonight as well.
You are the Swedish version of me: narrower, sweeter and whiter.
My Parents would be so proud.
Evenlyn will send you on its job interviews in the future.
If you are invited to a Chinese New Year celebration, you might get a Hongbao.
What is it?
Type a dumpling that has dough as content.
It's dough on dough.
It is a steamed bread that you eat on New Year that "saturates" for the rest of the year.
As you can see, I have eaten a lot.
It sounds too logical to be a lie.
I hope that Evelyn does not betray me now and that we get the first point.
You believed in Evelyn and you were completely wrong.
So, my heart is crushed!
Hongbao is small, red envelopes with money that you give each other on New Year.
For Chinese, it is Hongbao, but for Syrians Tax Situation.
- Daniel, time to collect points.
-Thanos.
Thanos!
- I just become more convinced.
-Thanos?
Which blatte would pay for the food.
The kebab riot was in Örebro.
One person hit another with a kebab roll in the head.
Then it completely degenerated.
One hit another with a kebab roll in the head and then it completely degenerated?
- I think he is lying.
-Why?
It feels too small.
For such a brawl you must have more than one roll.
You didn't believe in Thanos.
You did absolutely right.
Tonight's first point!
The kebab bracket revolved around an exclusive restaurant on Hornsberg's beach.
Accommodation tried to evict the restaurant because they were disturbed.
Congratulations to the first point.
Welcome into the match.
Sigrid, your lamb Simon betrayed you last.
I continue in the middle to the beautiful woman there.
Elaf.
Iraq's national law, mine and mustis, is called bache.
It is that you eat the whole sheep.
The face with eyes, ie the head.
All organs and intestines.
Then you fill the intestines with different things.
- Jarre as well.
- Everything on.
After all, we jaw crayfish and suck, so I believe in that.
That we eat intestines, brains and eyes.
You think Iraqis do?
Why not?
Consider when taking off the crayfish ...
I compared with crayfish.
I still say yes.
Heavy are you standing on you.
You've received your first point.
Neither Elaf nor Musti lied to you.
It is sheep with Balls and Everything.
- Eveline, ready to go into the match?
- Day for revenge.
- Who do you choose to trust?
-That's the question.
- Filip, we drive on.
- You are already shaking his head.
- What the hell are you laughing at?
I love this program.
No one else can have such a question.
Bastard...
--... is an insult.
- What do you call horny?
This is how the kebab brawl began.
It is used in the typography when writing -
- And the last word ends up on the next page or alone in the next paragraph.
Then it is called a horn.
It's not hose.
"Check out that horid! Fucking Horunge, you stand out."
It is a trade term, not fuck term, but a professional term.
YES!
-Yes!
We drive on it.
- Sista The Word is called "Horunge"?
It makes sense.
Type anyway.
You want to get rid of it, if it is in the way.
Eveline, do you know what?
Congratulations!
You got your first point.
-Cruelly.
Welcome into the match.
-Finally.
- Daniel, who do you choose in the panel?
--Assia.
It's Somali for "Eat Your Dad".
- Why do you laugh at my language?
- We just need a context.
- See your dad.
--Assia, can you say that?
That means that.
It's too stupid.
It must be "eat your dad".
You can be a stupid.
I dug this grave myself.
You did absolutely right, Daniel.
You got one more point.
It make sense.
Syrians marry cousins and Somalis are hungry.
- When do you have to eat your father?
- When your mom is cross -on on you.
Many swearing has to do with mothers, but in Somalia we are feminists.
We insult dads instead.
You have done something that I get shit for.
"Eat your dad!"
- We have something similar in Arabic.
- Extreme, you see.
- Sigrid?
- I think Anitha glitters up there.
I have to take her.
The Brazil fever was ...
A horoung.
It was an astronomical chlamydia outbreak.
An aggressive form of chlamydia who came with the sailors from Brazil.
The destruction of many people's sex life in Sundsvall.
- I was close.
- It sounded awful.
Lucky you were not in Sundsvall.
But I don't believe it.
- Why don't you believe in Anitha?
- So much chlamydia in Sundsvall?
I'm almost the only Swede.
You have to believe me.
I'm sorry, but no.
I'm from Skåne.
It's not possible.
No no.
You did absolutely right, because you got one more point.
Brazil fever was the newspapers called the 19th century trend-
- Emigrate from Sundsvall to Brazil.
Eveline, your turn again.
Who in the panel would you like to talk to?
- I think I take Musti.
- Yeah.
Dirty money.
Nämen ... I see many Arabs here and you will confirm what I say.
It is the high -rise cake with floors depending on status and wealth.
It can be so high that you have to cut the cake with a sword.
So it's Dabke.
- Wear at a Middle East wedding?
-Unfortunately not.
But it's never too late.
/Cheer/
- It was not a passport.
- The lady can stand with the sniper somewhere.
It sounds so random, but also too random to make it ...
It's so random, so it's probably true.
It's a little reverse psychology.
I believe in him.
- You were completely wrong.
Unfortunately.
- No wedding for you.
It is Arab folk dance that is usually danced to drums.
Filip, show!
Eveline, when you did not score points, it is run for you to go to the final.
But Daniel, you can take the lead as it says 2-2 between you and Sigrid.
If you take the next question, start the final round.
- What do you put your card on?
- Branne.
-My childhood.
- All recognizes.
I'm about to be shot.
No, it's very simple.
Foreign homes have spicy food, you want to protect the sofa ...
- You buy a sofa and have it ... - in 40 years.
...the rest of life.
An investment.
What does Daniel say?
If you protect the furniture from spicy food, I do not know.
- But you are afraid of the stuff you have.
-Okay, autist.
I believe in him.
I buy the car.
Not every day a Serb hears it, but you did absolutely right.
Congratulations!
It is a way to protect stuff.
You wrap the sofa, the TV control, the child you like ...
My dad did not remove the plastic from the TV.
He had the advertising from ...
Dad didn't remove it from his iPhone.
He advertised it and said the sound was not working.
We had a fantastic living room.
We only had to go in when guests arrived.
An entire room that could never be used.
Keep up the applause.
We thank Eveline for competing.
Unfortunately, you will not move on.
A huge applause to Daniel and Sigrid who run the final round!
You did a good job of taking you through the first round.
In others you will collect five points.
First to five.
But there is a small twist.
If you answer wrong, the opponent will receive your score.
- Daniel?
Yes.
I try new faces.
I start with Filip.
- Hello, sir!
- Filip ...
It is an excellent expression of scornful distaste.
Do you understand what I mean?
Imagine that a short, weak man at a club challenges you in fights.
You don't want to beat him.
After all, he is short and weak.
You point him in the face and say, "What a hood!"
Or if a guy goes up to a girl gang and should impress.
He flashes money and invites them.
Instead of being upset, they can laugh and say, "What a hood!"
- you?!
- A scornful expression of distaste.
One hundred percent lie.
It is too long and for elaborate.
- Of course it's lying.
- Filip, what a hood!
- I maintain that it is lying.
-A tip?
There are variations.
- Sicked face!
What a pan!
- Forely lying.
- If you answer wrong, Sigrid gets points.
-I know.
I'm getting cocky.
Self -confidence on top, but points to Sigrid.
What a hood!
You got a free score.
We see if the train continues to tough for you.
We'll see.
I think I choose ... Simon.
Simon, please.
Invite her, brother.
Behind this table He's Hard Like A Rock.
Every time she says Simon you see his nameplate "Du-Dum".
- I have a girl.
I'm sorry.
- Why didn't you say that before?
If you move around Persian cuisine you can be offered Tahdiq.
You are offered a plate.
No, then ...
It is when you leave the saucepan for a little too long.
If you cook rice, let it be burned -
- So they become like a crust that you eat for the rice.
It's delicious.
- The Irranes' response to crispbread.
-Okay!
No ... - sorry, Simon.
You've Already Broke My Heart.
So you say no?
You choose not to believe in Simon.
Well, you did away with it.
Daniel did this.
He got a point.
So slippery is Iranians.
They burn your food, turn it and serve it.
Daniel, you got a point.
Congratulations.
- Who do you choose to talk to?
–Alaf.
I thought they were younger.
They debut when they are around 17, the second year of high school.
Ish.
How old is that statistics?
Now they debut when they are seven.
-Difficult!
- When you debuted?
I was 17, so it could be true.
I say it's true.
I think many people pull down the age, but many people pull it up.
- So 17 may be true.
- All Muslims pull up age.
What are you talking about?
We get married when we are 13.
Daniel, you did absolutely right.
Elaf doesn't lie to you.
16.9.
Sigrid!
Who do you want to talk to?
- Simony.
- He is driven.
The master villain Thanos.
Isn't that in Marvel?
I think so.
Thanos ...
Nose Job.
I know.
Nämen, joking aside.
It is a Persian expression of when a person looks at you obliquely.
So for example ...
Chap chap at Elaf right now.
I'm doing chap chap all the time, then?
/Howks and applause/
Evelyn, you don't look obliquely.
You pee straight.
Started badly and got worse.
There will be no season 2 of this program.
The name, so ... I think Chap Chap is something else.
-What would that be?
- Isn't they cutting them?
Sigrid, what did you say?
That they cut up?
- No, circumcision.
-She means chop-chop.
-Why?
- It's good to think outside the box.
But this time you chop-chopped yourself.
You are wrong.
Thanos did not lie.
Chap chap means to check obliquely.
So Daniel, you got one more point.
It's called Chap Chap Negah Mikone.
Which one does when someone has burned even fakking rice.
That's how it is.
Musti.
Two cig and an adidas suit.
- Or am I wrong?
It's Rakija.
Haram.
I haven't been drinking.
There are spirits on plums that are used for everything.
From cold to ordinary wounds on the arm.
Everything.
Raki is located in Greece too.
There can be something down the Balkans and that peninsula.
I think he speaks the truth.
It is the house cure.
You believe in Musti?
Congratulations, Daniel, you got one more point.
Sigrid, before we continue.
If you are in control of the scoreboard ...
... so it looks dark to me.
What happens is that if you guess wrong, Daniel gets your score -
- And he has won the entire competition.
- Attempt not to do away with you.
- In will try.
- Zeina.
Oh!
Thus, it is one of the world's oldest flags.
The first copies were found sometime around 150 years after Christ.
Many people think it's an eagle on the flag -
- But it is a grilled lamb that you have fan out.
This is because the lamb is the National Animals of the Syrians.
One of the oldest flags available.
- I don't think that's true.
-Not?
Why?
Just a feeling.
This time it is.
That is absolutely right.
You've received a point.
Zeina drew a little white lie.
The Syrian flag was created in the 1980s in Sweden.
Huh?
The first was created by the Syrian National Association in Stockholm in 1980.
The design was nailed in 1982 and the flag was adopted internationally in 1983.
-What did you have before the 80s?
- We had no country.
- We ran for freedom and justice.
- Syrians, did you come from nowhere?
We are actually the indigenous population in first civilization Mesopotamia.
- talk to me nice.
- You weren't!
- Check what you started.
Take it easy!
- It can be war.
Stop it quickly.
You have the chance to lock the game now.
I will take someone I have not taken, Evelyn or Anitha.
Anitha looks too tricky with her eyebrows, so it will be Evelyn.
Evelyn?
Many.
And everyone is Iranians.
No, but there are actually exactly 1,051 people.
There are all old soldier names like post, proud and spear ...
Clearly you can be called Swedish by surname.
1051, yes.
I believe in you.
You believe in Evelyn.
You said it's an old soldier name?
You are so fakking right.
Congratulations, Daniel!
That's right.
It is an old soldier tradition.
An extra name the military gave the congregation so not everyone was called Olof and Johan.
It became difficult to give orders then.
A big applause for tonight's winner!
Sigrid, great work.
- Daniel, came here.
You should get your IFS diploma.
You get flowers ...
A huge applause.
Thanks to the contestants, the audience, you at home -
- And not least our fantastic panel.
Don't forget to look at us next week again.
Texting: Cristel Nyqvist Swedish Media Text for SVT