I have always had the feeling that we who attended Solvikskolan were lucky.
The children should not live in a pure life -
–And learn to become peaky people.
But through a Facebook group I got in touch with former students.
It was good to be crazy, many games were about being crazy.
After hearing their stories -
- If I started to see a completely different side of Solvik.
Those who wanted to bully me had free hunting season.
"Clearly she gets bullied, she is who she is."
"Look what she said, what he said ..." It is to look in a trash can.
The school had a grand plan for us.
They should not be adapted to society, they should change society.
But the plan only suited some children.
She loved you as a student.
It was very "jasper here and jasper there".
Hello!
The school has a very dark side -
- With ideal and how to change people.
Was it that the school split us into the right and wrong kind of children?
There were some who were not in principle attributed to any human value.
Each new story is like a puzzle piece -
- As step by step, I take me closer to an answer.
If I say Boll-Ove, what do you think about then?
Yes, that is one reason why I thought I wanted to be interviewed.
What was we really about - we who were children at Solviksskolan?
Up through the air
away over the seas
over the earth
In a staggering journey!
The queen of the morning
with the rosy rod
Waving us out
against a waking world
Solvikskolan is a Waldorf School.
The Waldor Movement was started in Germany in the late 1910s-
-And came to Sweden in the 1930s.
In 1980 it was started which over time would be called Solvik School -
- And just like other Waldorf schools, freedom and art were put into focus.
For the whole pedagogy is a matter of awakening the young man.
But at my school they took that much, much longer.
Instead of regular teaching, we had plays and great spectacle -
- So could take over the whole school.
Like the dragon game.
Or the antelope dance.
More art above all, more play.
Common teaching is fatal.
People become idiots of being educated in the way we do now.
I loved the time I was selected for death antelope.
Summer closing performance.
The death house is coming!
"The death house is coming!"
Those who were selected for death antelop could move beautifully.
You had to have a silk shawl to dance with when you were killed by the arrow.
That was the lead role.
High status.
I recognize that feeling of being selected.
My class teacher Merete often chose me -
- To the lead role in our school pieces.
But many of my schoolmates had the feeling of -
- That they were wrong in the eyes of the teachers.
What was it that decided - -
- If you were seen as right or wrong kind of child?
When I was little, Lavinia, I went to a school called Solvik School.
- I don't want you to talk about it.
-Why?
- I want you to dough with me.
- What should I dough for something?
A cat?
Check out, here is the cat's head.
But at my school you could not do so that you made your head first.
It would be in one piece.
Then you had to do this.
You had to model out ... so.
Now I could shape my ears.
The entire school was permeated by some anarchist attitude as well as -
- As the outside world.
While it was incredibly regulated within this system.
We had very determined opinions, after all freedom thinking and so -
- If what was good and not so good.
We painted a lot.
You were not allowed to decide what to paint -
- The way you would paint layers in layers with different colors and shades.
One would start from within, spread out -
- And find where the edge went with the crayon.
If you painted a horse, you did not paint a horse and then filled in.
Without you started with a clue, and then "here the back should be".
It was: "How to do it, so it should be. This is a good person."
It could be things like "piano is bad".
It is a static instrument and you do not see what is happening.
You were not allowed to play football, but on the other hand, fireball went great.
As a child, I didn't think much about the rules.
But with what I know now -
- Can I not help but wonder how they affected us.
There were a lot of rules, but they were not recorded, so finding them ...
... it was impossible.
Either they had them in themselves, you were already according to the rules -
- Or so you were not, and then you couldn't ...
You couldn't ...
Or, there was no manual.
It was completely impossible to live up to that, because I didn't take ...
... how I could do it.
It happened that people came in from the outside in the class who got it damn tough.
Because they could not, the codes, the language could not, how to behave.
I was a little scared -
- And didn't really understand how things were connected and so on.
And so I noticed very quickly that I was not such a student -
- As you would be at Solvik.
Because my teacher said.
"When you started in class, I thought,"
"Hope it's not a shy, scared girl, but a brave and tough girl."
Then she discovered pretty quickly that I was a shy and scared girl.
So I really felt I was wrong.
When I meet Linda I realize -
- It wasn't just about rules for what we had to do.
It went deeper than that.
It was like we children in the eyes of the teachers -
- Kunde be wrong, without really being able to do anything about it.
We all sat around the wood stove sometime ...
... and so just: "But you are reading."
Or like: "You can't talk."
And it was on that kind of as well ... downwear in some way.
I was incredibly popular with my friends, but she like ...
... tried to peel me out of that.
I wasn't good enough according to her ideal.
Where did these ideals come from?
Why was it so important for school that we would live up to them?
Hello.
In the Facebook group there are several BC
Students who talk about the teacher Helena.
How she used the ideals to lift or lower students.
When the Facebook group came -
- What was the pieces that took the hardest or that felt the most?
It's that I manipulate ...
... and have favorites.
That I favor and manipulate and that those who do not go out go out.
I may have done it, but completely unconscious.
I just joined something.
My ignorance of how I was myself, it has hit them.
My uncertainty has affected other students.
I have apologized several of them.
I didn't know better, didn't know any better.
Helena was only 25 years old when she started as a teacher at school.
Maybe what she says is that she just went into something.
That she simply unconsciously embraced these ideals.
As I look now with my adult eyes on it -
- Then it was very much that I would be able to join the gang.
That I was seen and would be able to help create this new school.
"What does Pär say? What does Merete says?"
They were great authorities for me.
Jasper: that with the assessment, categorizing and ranking -
-What is that?
I got that ...
... really really smeared around the nose all the time.
I know it is true that students have felt sponsored or not.
That you should be like that, and you are judged very strongly.
I understand that at least many have felt that way.
- Where do you think it comes from?
- I don't understand it completely.
I don't recognize it.
It's like all roads lead to Pär.
But then it stops when I come here.
I think about what Merete said.
The school has a very dark side -
- With ideal, how it should be and how to change people.
"How it should be, and how to change people."
I think of all the games and all the exercises we had at school.
The children sat around the walls.
One or two children were moving in the middle and the others watched.
What was the idea with everything really?
You were not allowed to put in your heels, not swinging or that the buttocks stuck out ...
You were not allowed to go too fast, not move as mechanically.
And then they could suddenly say:
"God, so ... what she goes! Look how she goes!"
And we just ...
It feels like a door has opened in to my childhood.
Inexplicable things that have been going on at school -
- I now start to see in a different light.
We had something called the "bench".
Mm.
It was always an invisible threat.
You knew that "I do not take care of myself, then it will be the bench".
You sat on a bench in the middle and then everyone sat in a ring around.
First one would tell you something about yourself that was a secret -
- Or that was hard to tell.
Then you would go around and say to your classmates -
- How to experience your relationship.
When you were done, everyone would in turn tell you -
- What they liked about one.
And that was what became ... it could be very sensitive.
I was often in the middle of the ring.
And there was pretty much hot to try to dig and so ...
It was incredibly hard, I thought.
It felt like an experiment.
I felt very experimented with.
I don't know how long, but it felt like an eternity -
- Where all the girls sat and just explained everything that was wrong with me.
All students had to say something.
I talked to a friend who was then, and she broke.
She had nothing she wanted to say -
- But she was forced to say something by the teacher -
- Otherwise, there was a risk that she might be put there.
If you said something really sharp, you got a little ... Thumbs up from her.
It sounds almost like the teachers are consciously trying to expose us -
- For painful situations.
And that in some way it would help us change.
Then we had Merete.
When it was about the bench, it was mete.
There were several teachers at the school who had exposed their students to the bench.
But both Linda and Elsa had my teacher Merete in that exercise.
It's hard to take in.
Why did she subject the students to this?
She who had always been my guarantor of security?
It was so much bullshit, so it was an attempt to ...
"Hello, let's calm us down a bit and say what it actually is."
–And clear the air in some way?
- Review the air.
They probably thought it was a little scary.
I do not know.
But was it like you tried "we see how this works"?
More ... don't see how it works, but ...
You hear, you see how it goes, and then you see what people ... what they ...
What comes out, and ... or ...
Many thought it was very nice too -
- To finally be able to say something you have not dared to say to anyone.
- But they haven't heard of them?
- No, people are just angry.
- To feel compelled, right?
- Exposed, I think.
To sit in the middle and that people said things that were nasty.
They felt hounded, I think.
You didn't have to say anything.
You did not need to go if you did not want to.
Maybe the bench was just what Merete says.
An attempt to resolve conflicts among students.
But I get the feeling that it's not the whole truth.
As I remember it, so I and the teacher have conflicts.
One thing that started during the school days -
- It was that one of the other students had to beat and kick me -
- With his approval.
She was very aggressive.
She chased me or was after me all the time -
- So I tried ... When I tried to get away from her, I know that ...
It was like hammocks in the ceiling.
I searched up to those hammocks pretty actively -
- For that, it was easier to defend yourself.
- He allowed she to beat you?
- mm.
Mom asked him the question sometime: "Why do you allow this?"
"She's having a hard time at home, that girl" -
- "So she needs to get her aggressions out."
The counter -question from Mom was: "But Maya, then?"
"No, but she needs to learn to say."
So it was like some kind of win-win situation ...
... in this responsible adult version of it all.
Eh, yes ... strange.
Maya's teacher does not want to be interviewed.
He says he has not used such methods in the teaching -
- And he doesn't remember the conversation with Maya's mother.
It became so incredibly strong when you created this Facebook group -
- And other students started writing and telling and testifying.
I understand when I read the stories -
- I am not alone in having trauma from there.
And it was an incredible relief!
We were so taken, so obviously taken, of what was talked about.
This was something we almost all thought we were carrying for ourselves.
That it was our image of something -
- Fast it was a whole system that was like harmful.
Almost everyone I talk to, mean that Pär had the last word -
- In which teachers got to work at the school - also Maya's teacher.
He was a terribly bad teacher, put it with students a lot.
He had been sustained for himself.
What to call it?
To be honest, a psychotic dictator, as surely ...
He was very gymnastic.
Did things with trees, and climbed and adventure.
It was really fun, really good.
But then there were back sides where he ...
... drove hard with the kids.
It was not good.
These are dangerous things, when it is not really right.
Skilled and talented people with severe errors ...
... are dangerous.
But interesting.
Great.
This fantastic teacher who had walked through the desert.
Survived one with the other.
Great at telling stories.
A very charismatic person.
No one was interested in hearing -
- "That there are things going on there that are not good".
- Why did he have to stay?
- I've always liked him.
I like him, although at the same time I was not so impressed with -
- His spiritual career, but it is interesting.
Maya's teacher thus had to be left -
- Because "his spiritual career was interesting".
What are I missing here?
I'm still thoughtful how they could carry on like that.
Were the students so important?
Was it more important?
There was...
There was something behind it.
I don't know what the school was for.
And you felt that "here at school something other than what we see" - is that how you mean?
Mm.
After all, they had the Waldorf pedagogy, which Rudolf Steiner had written.
And I wonder about ... it was ...
You can interpret it in many different ways.
Rudolf Steiner.
This face has been present throughout my upbringing.
I think almost everyone I knew had his portrait at home on the wall.
Still, I've never really known who he was.
More than it was he who had created anthroposophy.
I got to know anthroposophy without knowing what it was.
I found in my mailbox ...
It was a book in it - no address, nothing.
The book was of Steiner.
I had no idea ... I didn't know who he was.
But I started reading the book and it was damn good, I thought.
It was called in German Geheimwissenschaft Im Umriss.
In Swedish it is usually called the knowledge of the hidden.
I liked it sharply.
I thought there was ... "So there it should sound."
We will look at something called anthroposophy.
To come to Järna is to get other perspectives on man and the world -
- I what we are used to.
As a child, I only knew we were anthroposophists -
- Or "antisers" as we were called.
But never ever had I explained to me what anthroposophy was for something.
They have started schools, so -called
Waldorf schools.
They invest in herbal remedies.
On several small farms around Järna -
- Investing enthusiastic youth in biodynamic agriculture.
For us, anthroposophy was primarily something -
- That made us very different from the other children in Järna.
We ate strange food, we had strange clothes and we were not allowed to watch TV.
That it was linked to anthroposophy I had enough -
- But how, I never understood that.
I realize that if I are to understand Pär and the vision behind Solvik -
- So I have to understand Rudolf Steiner.
In the early 1900s, Steiner created the life view-
- He called anthroposophy.
He left a comprehensive material:
Books, lectures and drawings that describe his thoughts and ideas.
A central part of anthroposophy is that there is a spiritual world-
- Which should be just as real as the physical one.
When you meet a child and know, "You're not just what you look like."
You are not just the one standing and talking.
We are much, much more.
Rudolf Steiner wanted children's spirituality to be affirmed.
That was one of the reasons why he created Waldorf pedagogy.
Spiritual life was taken seriously as a reality.
Angels are not a small kids talk about, but it is ours ...
... friends that we can have contact with.
For Steiner, the spiritual world was not religious.
He meant it could be proved.
In his books and lectures he spread his so -called.
spirit science.
But none of this we got to learn at Solvikskolan.
Pär: You do not teach it in a Waldorf school, it is not a subject.
Anthroposophy is not taught, but anthroposophy is practiced every day.
This is Dorothea, a f.d.
Pupil at Solvik School.
She too has had a hard time understanding -
- Why we did as we did at school.
For 26 years I have not been given an explanation for anything.
Why do you make the Christmas game?
Why do you do the antelope dance or the dragon game?
Why is it better to have some colors on clothes?
Some materials?
It is only now that I have started to find out things - read and ask.
Which is provocative for many.
But I feel that I have to know the truth about why ...
... Everything has happened that has happened.
Much of what happened during our school hours was natural for us -
- For we had nothing to compare with.
But when today I look back -
- On some things we did, it sounds almost absurd.
As the different temperaments.
Do you remember the way to divide children into different temperaments?
Yes...
Yes, I do very much.
Oh ... yes, the personality types.
What was that?
Phlegmatic...
Do you remember this?
Flegmatic, sang -wine, choleric and ... ah ...
-Melancholy?
- Yes, melancholy.
According to anthroposophy, there are four different temperaments.
In the 6th or 7th, Pär came to our class and showed us the temperament.
"What the flower is nice! It's yellow! Look!"
"I know you should not talk loudly."
The sang winery, the child's temperament, is the one that is a bit volatile -
- As sparkles and is usually happy.
"Wait, I'll ... Oh, it's itching!"
They don't want to sit still as well.
And then there is the cholerician.
Very determined, often small people.
They usually walk with the heel before.
They think they themselves know a little best.
Napoleon was a cholerar.
Hitler may have been cholerics.
The melancholy, it is a bit difficult.
It feels a little sorry for itself.
They don't know that ...
... I am the guilt to everything.
Everything.
World War.
Never forget injustices.
- Was it almost like a rating scale?
-Yes you could say that.
Flegenmatics are those who enjoy taking it easy and working with something for a long time.
A little comfortable as well.
Ha-Han ... he sits ...
He may not say right that one was finer than the other.
But his way of telling the elements -
- I made it understood that one was better.
Hay-hay ...
It is a one -sided phlegmatic.
How good did you quickly read?
Very capable.
I got really good at it actually.
Steiner went pretty far.
He said that phlegmatists often have a big head.
Yes, but that is often the case when Flegman considers.
It may happen that the head is bigger.
It feels bigger anyway.
Steiner said that one can often look at a child's appearance -
- which temperament they belong to.
That the melancholy is narrow and slender.
That the sang winery is the most normal.
And the cholerics are short and powerful.
There is an educational idea in Waldorf that the temperament takes each other out.
Put together two choleric violent types, so they will not be able to end up.
Then they can calm down.
Do you know it and can work a little, turn to the temperament properly -
- And take it into account, so it's a very good tool.
Steiner said that the teacher would respond to the students based on their temperament.
Against a phlegmatian, the teacher should be unengaged.
And the cholerics need to be arrested.
They feel good about getting bruises.
- But you are convinced that they exist?
- Yes, what the hell ...
It is no conviction, it is pure knowledge.
What I think is problematic with temperament ...
It becomes very easy categorization.
We all knew what temperaments we were.
I was choleric because I was pretty ... I got pretty easily angry.
I was kind of the one who is a little leal and a little dreamy, I think.
- Flelegatics?
-Yes maybe.
- What were you?
- It was probably some form of sang wine.
The best.
- Was it?
-Yes.
We had lessons with Pär where we would paint colors.
He would check out the picture and say:
"You are most sang -wine" or "you are most choleric".
I struggled to take the right color, it should be yellow for being sanginical.
Nevertheless, it always became that I was choleric-melancholy.
And the melancholy ... I had such anxiety because I was a melancholy.
This student is ...
... Probably Sanginical.
The one that is most implemented is the yellow one.
It was more than me who fought.
God, what I struggled with the drawings!
I never managed to become sang -wine.
Flegmatic, it was ... It was nothing good.
I remember this how I had got the label from being a phlegmate.
It was something we talked about outside the school.
I remember how hard it was when someone pointed out or could say like PIK -
- I was a phlegmate.
You can have temperaments.
It is no shame to be a choleric or melancholy.
Flegmatic is one of my ideal temperaments.
The occult temperament.
You were stuffed into a compartment: "You are this one, so you need this."
I felt that I had no chance to change.
You were sentenced ...
...I feel.
You are sentenced, and then you remain in that union.
If I say Boll-Ove, what do you think about then?
Yes ... it's just a desert name I've heard now.
The desert name I remember was thick Daniel.
Yes, that's a reason to -
- I thought I wanted to be interviewed.
Daniel attended a couple of classes under me.
In our class he was called Boll-Ove, others said thick Daniel.
I remember that as a child I thought of him as the archetype of phlegmatics.
The worst thing you could be.
And I have vague memories that we were awkward to him.
But strangely enough, I can't remember feeling any guilt for it.
Everyone was, even teachers.
I felt that thick Daniel was an expression supported by my teacher.
And when we were really small -
- Then she used to pick us up at the school bus and go with us.
Since we were so small then, she went with us on the way to school.
We walked a small cluster with classmates.
Behind us suddenly two older guys came and then they grabbed Daniel -
- On each side, in each arm, and then they shouted like that ...
"Now thick Daniel will be allowed to run. He needs exercise."
And then they started to drag him between them.
My teacher shouted and laughed.
Our little cluster also shouted:
"Now thick Daniel will have to run."
"That's good. Run with him, so he gets exercise."
Yes, but it was mental abuse.
Clearly.
I think it was - as I remember it - everyday.
A freezing and a peak.
We were in the classroom, and suddenly she rushes up to Daniel ...
... and then she hits his head between her hands.
Like this.
And at the same time, she says:
"Are you totally fucking stupid in your head?"
I think we thought that what happened to Daniel was self -inflicted -
- Because he was who he was.
He was very busy with his ... he had video games, TV and all that-
- As we did not have then, because it was forbidden.
He represented everything we thought was wrong with the ordinary world.
He had not gone there from the beginning, but he was a bulge.
And so he did ... You can't report to the police for violence.
You do not go against.
He reported his teacher for the teacher to beat him.
I do not know.
Gave him an ear file or something - at least used violence.
I remember she told us -
- That she had been reported for child abuse.
We students thought it was very horrible by Daniel's parents then.
It became a trial, and I remember that many from school joined.
How they bused pupils to the district court -
- To show solidarity with the teacher.
We went in, including teachers, to sit on this trial -
–And more or less make fun of the ball-Ove.
We were on the teacher's side all
- The person to have someone at all about the situation at all.
Terrible!
And this was not something that came from us students, but ...
That's how it was said that "So it is-Boll-Ove is lying".
The school thus chose to stand on a teacher's side -
-In an abuse case with a 10-year-old child.
Why do you do that?
After all, there was a picture of Solvik ... it was against them ...
... there "we who were Solvik", we did right.
Everyone else was wrong and everything else was reprehensible.
It was therefore -
- You would not read comic books, have pressure on the sweaters and watch TV -
- For it was those who did not understand, who did it.
Those who did not know what was right.
And they were worthy of mockery.
The question is whether the violations were an expression of the teacher's shortcomings -
- Or if there was a conscious thought in what she did.
She might think she would make him stop enjoying video games.
There was that way of salvation in it.
And it was a prestige in that there -
- What to transform these people into.
There is something about what Robin says, that we would transform us into something.
Like this with video games.
As a child, I just remember that it was forbidden.
But maybe it had to do with anthroposophy?
It's like small, seemingly insignificant details -
- Starts to have new meanings.
At my school you were not allowed to make cats so -
- That you made your head first.
It would be in one piece.
It could be such things like piano being bad.
When I designed people, I drew with a line around.
Head and so on ...
... and it was very wrong.
In our class you were a hundred times better -
-If one dared to jump between trees or do dangerous things -
- It if you were good at reading and writing.
Everywhere in Steiner's books I see connections to our time at Solvik.
But when I talk to Pär, I understand that Solvik's interpretation of Steiner -
- separated from how other Waldorf schools interpreted him.
We plugged Steiner.
We did not plug what the Waldor Movement Ville -
- Out what Steiner said and how he worked.
We tried to understand what it was.
And we probably understood a lot.
And it became a conflict.
After all, we were removed from the list, from the Waldorflist.
Solvik was excluded from the Swedish Waldorf community -
- And went his own way.
After all, there was also a pride that not being counted as Waldorf school.
That you were not part of it, but something much better -
- And something much higher.
In Sweden, Solvik ended up in the cold.
There were plans to try to get rid of us.
Although it was not possible, because there were lots of protests -
- Out of all the world almost.
"Should that school be away, then Waldorf is gone."
The school in the forest went from the black sheep of the Waldor Movement -
-A pioneer example on the international anthroposof stage.
Pär is still touring the world with workshops on the school's pedagogy.
We children who have attended Solvik were sold as the evidence of the school's success.
One has such high thoughts about yourself and indoctrinating everyone to believe -
- That "this is fantastic", that we are involved in something outstanding.
That it like: "Wow, here's something!"
"Something is going on," as you often said.
The term "something is going on here".
It's like you puncture something when you say this.
Do you notice it?
-Yes.
I almost want it.
- As a balloon like man: "Pfju!"
Some of these people write -
- The school time has had a harsh consequences for those in life.
Yes, it is popular.
It is simply in that childhood means a lot.
I can only say, "Oh, then. So pity you were injured in the soul."
"I've been lucky to never be injured in" ... do you believe it?!
That I have never been injured in the soul?
What is it?
We are so damn injured in the soul!
Otherwise, we would not sit here now and try this project.
What would you say that the school is responsible for those stories?
Nothing.
Pär does not think that the school has any responsibility in what happened to the students.
But the fact remains that students happened to be bad.
Like Daniel.
What has been so strange is how the school reacted.
- There is a ... - yes, exactly.
... a ten-eleven-year-old boy with a whole school against him in a situation like ...
... which must have been tough anyway.
Yes, what a thing to sit there and try to defend yourself before something.
Daniel had accused his teacher of abuse.
She admitted that she slammed to him on the cheek -
- And drummed with his fingers on his head to get his attention.
But the district court acquitted her anyway.
We had won.
Daniel had lost.
I don't remember that anything further.
I know about it, but I have no personal memory.
I wasn't involved so much, I think.
I was never present, for example.
- You were not in the trial?
-No no.
So I can't say that much about that.
I would like to know that more about that.
What it was that happened, and ...
What happened to Daniel.
Where he is today.
- He is dead.
-Okay.
Uuh ...
Daniel ended at Solvik.
He died in 2006, as a 25-year-old.
He never got any redress for how the school had treated him.
His teacher has chosen not to comment.
Now I was a little badly affected, but ...
Yes...
And you want more ...
... had made police reports.
There was a lot to take off.
There was a lot of violence on the part of the teachers.
Suddenly some teacher-
--Able throw something against one so that you had to duck, or so there.
Has there been a physical discipline ...
...in school?
The answer is yes.
Many students today are critical of how they were treated by the teachers.
One of them is Gudmund, Pär Ahlbom's own son.
Some who were adults then-
- They knew it was something that was going on.
Then I will be, "Where the hell were you? What kind of person are you just looking at?"
If you have now known that these skewed stuff has happened -
-And all the children who have broken lives because of this fucking school ...
This violence that many have described from teacher to student ...
- You know that it has been going on, huh?
- I have not experienced that much.
I think it's exaggerated.
But didn't you know when it was going on?
Yes...
I did.
But I knew more afterwards when I got it confirmed.
I don't understand why we didn't do anything as parents.
I really don't understand it.
What kind of person are you?
After all, it is such a person who is filming while someone is raped.
Everyone was so damn addicted that no one made any notification ever.
So your material could make me make me ... to a damn pig.
-Yes.
- It's no art.
There is proof of that.
It's just watching.
Everything was sanctioned, and then it becomes a tremendously strong culture of silence.
Did you report him?
No, then it would not have been possible for my siblings to stay.
It is far too great consequences to do such a thing.
It probably could have been dangerous.
It is very strong loyalty.
"What a fucking man! What he says. Hear. Hear himself."
You understand!
Or vice versa.
"What a wonderful person! Think, what the open and open."
You know...
It's just to take care of it.
I think so ... you should know that.
- Yes, that's it.
- All is always right and completely wrong.
It does not matter.
I don't touch it in the ass.
Here, anything can happen and no one knows.
It was any situation when you hid?
The pain and horror would be so strong that the child woke up.
Children could have died!
Why isn't it important?!
You have not arrived for the first time on earth.
They sat down in the teacher's lap, and so the teacher held too.
Everyone has murdered someone and everyone has raped someone -
- So then maybe it does something if you get a little frightened in the forest.
Texting: Barbro Garneij Hansson Swedish Media Text for SVT