You are all welcome to the elevator.
I'll sing some earrings.
We start with "The Girl and the Kråkan" by Mikael Wiehe.
I saw a picture of a girl with a damaged crow in her arms
She ran with crow ... the crow ... runs ...
Drum sound
Please, I'm trying to sleep.
Hello.
Hello!
Yes ... yes ...
- What the hell are you doing?!
-Hey sweetie.
This is Christer Broström.
- Christer.
Frida.
- Yeah?!
- He is one of our most important customers.
The sauna at work was clumsy.
- Where were we?
Yes exactly!
I have the annual report in the computer.
So.
- Honey, do you fix some cuts?
- You haven't kissed in the bath?
-Yes.
The Only Way to Happiness is to find your Inner Landscape ...
... and then you travel there, and then you stay there.
Listen to your inner voice.
Let's make a sound.
Oum ...
A Sound?
Yes, Your Inner Voice, Your Inner Sound.
Oum ...
Eh ...
Mööö!
Bars
What is feminist self -defense?
You will soon know that.
My name is Rebecka, but I am called Robin.
We will go through effective ways to defend against an attacking man.
My brother -in -law Mike is nice and sets up as an attacker.
We will start by saying loud and clear.
Mike, came against me.
NO!
So.
Now you have to try my signal yourself.
Here I have written some typically male replicas.
- Mike, a replica.
- I want sex no matter what you want.
-No!
- Better you can.
Do you want sex?
-NO!
Good, so it should sound.
Okay...
Another effective way of defending itself is a purse park.
Okay, Mike.
You get a replica.
- You place is at the stove, woman.
-NO!
There you go.
- Is it okey?
Good.
Great.
Another good way to defend yourself is with one stroke.
A firm fist.
Came against me.
I'll just mark.
A firm fist aimed at the larynx.
Okay, Mike.
You get a replica.
Your menstrual monster, women drive worse than chickens - and then hear!
NO!
If it doesn't help - a purse park.
So yes.
Great!
Good resistance!
Finally - a series that I came up with, if I should now boast a little.
What do women usually have in the handbag?
Some tampons, a bottle of water.
Okay.
Then you take the tampons and put them in your nose ...
... and in the mouth.
- Gapa.
Then you take the water bottle ...
... and spray on water.
As you see, the tampons swell up in Mike's nose and mouth.
Mike gets difficult to breathe.
That's when we take the opportunity to do ...
... just that - a purse park.
Then I think we thank Mike for his participation with a small applause.
So, Different Personalities Should Eat Different Food?
Yes.
The Food is important when shaping your inner countryscape.
There Are Three Types of Different Human Beings:
Vatta ...
... coat and pitta.
- Pitta?
- Pitta.
-The Pitta Personality ... - Pitta!
I'm a pitta!
Today it is Thursday.
I said today is Thursday.
Thursday.
"Dear Mr. Smith ..."
Dear Mr.
Smith
"... in hereby confirm ..."
In Hereby Confirm
Dear Mr.
Smith, I hereby confirm my love for you!
- "... our agreement."
- My love for you!
- "My love for you."
And send.
You wanted to talk.
This project is starting to end, so we should have a development call.
- Yeah.
- We give each other constructive criticism.
-Yes Yes.
- You start.
God, what a hard time!
No, I probably have no criticism for you.
It has worked well.
Sometimes you have been late for a meeting but then you have always called.
- Do you have any criticism for me?
-No not really.
Sometimes I may think you ...
... that you smell a little bad.
So, an acidic scent from your body.
Well.
Oh.
Jump.
It's not something I think about myself.
- I take care of my hygiene, I think.
- It's not noticeable at all.
Well ... okay.
I hear you.
Now it's up to me to do something about ...
—... Stench.
-Yes exactly.
Now I came up with a little criticism for you.
Sometimes you are a little stupid in your head.
—Esla, so intelligence ...?
- Yes, lay intelligence, like a 7 -year -old.
- A Smart 7 -year -old, but under the average.
- It's not something you think about yourself.
No, you can't understand that.
-Nothing else?
-No.
I said you smelled disgusting?
-Yes.
- Because it's really an odor!
It's as if you had a dead animal inside the shirt.
Sometimes I think you have pooped on you.
So funny that you use that word -
- Sometimes I think you have poop in your head.
-In the head?
- A poop sausage instead of a brain.
Your head is like an empty shell around a poop.
It's not something you think of yourself.
- nice to talk.
- Yes, some constructive criticism.
And then ...?
What HAPPENED THEN?
Your Father Told You That You Were Worth Nothing.
We have all the Experienced Hard Times.
But you have to navigate your inner countryscape.
Deep Inside Your Heart You Will Find Peace.
What Happened to Your Father?
He ... Disappeared ...
... Into his own ass.
ALARM CLOCK
Oh no!
No no no no!
ALARM CLOCK
Aaah!
Do you have any imagination that is a little special?
- Sex fantasy?
- MMM.
Yes.
I would like to try to ...
... to have sex with another woman at the same time as with my boyfriend.
I fantasize that often.
And you?
- No, I can't say.
-Come on.
I did say.
Okay.
I ... Ugh!
No!
Stop.
Say it now.
I...
... would like to put a thin piano wire around Niklas Penisrot ...
... and pull on both ends so it just - fourth!
Thus, it or threesome.
It also goes well.
Excuse Me, Madam.
I'm Lost.
What's The Closest Way to the Station?
NO!
A Very Negative Experience.
A cup of coffee and a glass of red.
I wonder if it's full moon tonight?
Or why am I so sensitive?
Outside my clothes I am quite skinless
Without shell, without mask in a box
What happened with...
Is "the horse's empty" enough rhyme on "I want to hang with Thåström"?
Huh?
Look like you did now!
Svensson!
Were you sick yesterday?
You were home?
Care of sick child, right?
-No.
I stood here as usual.
-Oh really?
I can't really look in your direction.
I'm stiff in the neck.
Laughing
- Paul ... what's your zodiac sign?
-The wave.
The wave?
We will see what is here.
Your incompetence and an unfavorable exterior make you unpopular at work.
It's time to look for new opportunities.
Why not in the cleaning or sewer sector?
That's right!
About me it says: Your day is darkened by a stupid colleague.
If Thåström had been an animal on the savannah
Then Charlotte Permell had been on the bang
ALARM CLOCK
No!
- You, should your mitt lie on the floor?
- Night ... does it?
No, I just asked.
- Can I take the last cake?
-Yes.
- You don't want it?
- No, take it.
-Then I will take it.
- Don't think about me.
- You can get it.
-No.
Why break a millennial tradition?
Do as you have always done.
-Which we?
- Yes, the white man.
What do you mean?
It is a typical example of how the white man takes what he wants from others
- You usually use violence against other cultures.
- You must not believe!
I don't think anything.
I know you are part of an oppressor culture -
- As I have oppressed me and my people since ancient times.
This cookie story is a betrayal of the Third World.
--Ulf, you interpret too much in it.
-Yes is not it?!
Just so the slave traders thought when they came to Africa and hit us in shackles.
- You come from Lund, not Africa!
- You are so damn naive, Frida!
Can you try to widen your perspective a bit?
-Can you?
You're so damn naive!
--Ulf ... Take the cake.
- I want you to have it.
- Should you buy my silence?!
Thanks, my good gentleman, for getting the cake.
Give him a cake and he becomes silent.
Should I dance too?
Give the boy a cake and he dances.
Here is the cookie dance for the white man!
Thanks for the cake.
I dance for you.
You enjoy humiliating others!
- Now I think ... - you, I've moved all my life!
From what then?
From slavery, torture, an oppression that you can't grasp!
You are from Skåne, just like me!
- Give him the cake!
-Take it!
I am so fucking tired that every time we meet be some house gear!
I'm getting pissed off!
We will release it.
I'm going home.
Thanks for being here.
Bye!
- Ulf!
--Ulf, come back.
You know I don't mean it that way.
- We never offer blacks here!
- They are unreliable.
- Have you seen the new bride here?
- Yeah, it's a real good thing.
I do not know.
She seems a little stiff.
Laughing
It was good.
—Rälskling ... —Mmm?
I'll probably be a little late tomorrow.
- I thought Pierca me after work.
- I thought you were against that.
I've been thinking about.
It's probably not that stupid.
Where are you going to pierce yourself?
Here or here?
The foreskin.
It is probably most practical.
Practically?
What should you have for jewelry there?
A key ring.
I always find it difficult to find the car keys.
- God, what good with princess cake!
-Yes indeed!
I can eat it almost as much as possible without gaining weight.
- Surely it is cranky?
-Yes.
And I don't need to exercise.
I look so well -trained anyway.
Everyone says, "I have to know where you exercise. You have such a nice body."
Then I say "but I don't exercise".
"You're joking?!", They say.
Look at my stomach, it's completely flat.
On the sides it is narrow.
Feel.
-Right?
-Yes.
Some work out type all the time -
- And yet I, who never exercise, look much more well -trained.
Like you, then ... you exercise two days a week about.
Three to four times a week actually.
I mean you actually have a bigger stomach than I do.
Check if we compare.
Your thighs are outside the chair seat, though mine are inside.
-Yes.
- This princess cake you treat yourself.
You have not been able to eat cake for several weeks.
And you who are not so narrow have to train several, several days a week now -
- To be able to compensate for it.
Old man, do you know what?
I have to leave.
I'll meet Nathalie.
- You look good?
- Yes, you are very nice.
- TAKE!
ALARM CLOCK
Imagine getting wake up
Early one morning
hear a blackbird singing his song
I love the song
The carbon black sings
Thanks, dear father, for the song you gave
Imagine to - to - to - to - to - to - to ...
Imagine getting wake up
Early one morning
Hear a carbon black
Sing his song - NG - NG - NG - NG ...
Hello?
The sound continues
Fire alarm
SVT Program Setting: Barbro Garneij Hansson
Help!