After the Second World War
Want the Soviet Union to increase its influence.
They install communist governments in several
Eastern European countries.
These countries are formally independent
but hard controlled by the Soviet Union
They are Soviet satellite states.
In 1948, the Soviet Union crashes a democratically elected
government in Czechoslovakia and then cut
of the supply paths to the Democratic West Berlin.
The United States and Western Europe are starting to get nervous.
What is the Soviet Union's next goal?
In April 1949, foreign ministers meet from 12 Western European and
North American countries in Washington D.C
They sign an agreement where it stands
That an attack on one of the countries from eg.
The Soviet Union will be considered an attack on them all.
The agreement is called the North Atlantic Treaty and
The countries that sign form North Atlantic Treaties
the organization or NATO.
Soon, contradictions arise between NATO
and the Soviet Union over Germany status.
Germany has been a split nation since
the end of the Second World War.
Americans, the British and
the French occupy different zones in western Germany
And in West-Berlin.
The Soviet Union controls
Eastern Germany and East-Berlin.
Now the Americans are beating, the British
and the French together their zones in order to
form a new country, the Federal Republic of Germany.
The Soviet Union responds by forming.
German Democratic Republic in Eastern Germany, although it
is democratic by its name so everything is determined by it
East German Communist Party.
US and their allies want West Germany
forming a separate army and joins NATO
In this way they can help defend
Western Europe against the Soviet Union.
The Soviet Union does not like this idea at all.
They warn that if West Germany forms an army
and joins NATO,
So the Soviet Union will create its own defense alliance.
Germany still joins NATO and begins
build up your own army.
So the Soviet Union does just that, they warned about.
In May 1955 the Soviet Union invites you
their satellite states to Warsaw in Poland to sign
Warsaw Treaty on Friendship, Collaboration and Mutual Assistance.
Warsaw Pact
Like NATO, the Warsaw Pact Countries are required to come to each other
defense if they are attacked by an enemy.
Pact also establishes a military headquarters in
Moscow for all signing countries,
The desire clearly signals that the Soviet Union decides.
When Hungary and later Czechoslovakia and Poland
trying to oppose the Soviet rule
Uses the Soviet Union troops from the Warsaw Pact to beat down the uprising.
The pact will apply to 1991.
NATO and W Arszawa Pact two agreements that bring together the Western
democracies on one side and the Soviet Union and its
Communist satellite states on the other although these
Alliances are not explicitly in conflict with each other is that
clearly that a dispute between two members from
opposite sides can easily escalate to
A much greater conflict.