You are one of the main authors to it
Chapter in the synthesis report which deals with anchoring.
What are the most important conclusions there?
The most important conclusions
is just that we have to
press much more on openness and dialog
Both in permit processes and planning processes
Thus, in overview planning for wind power.
We must have an open posture
And not dismiss the public's questions as stupid or
problematic, without truly seeing the value of that
Get them into the process.
Where people can feel this I understand, now I understand why
The wind turbines should stand here.
I may not love it, but I understand why.
And to be able to answer the question "Why?",
That's the important thing.
Then it is also so that you might not just go out
And talk to people without having an understanding of their landscape, so you have to do your homework.
A tool to understand the landscape and
have something with them in the dialogue,
It is precisely landscape analysis
As we press pretty much on the report.
Now we are on our way out on a boat trip through Luleå and Kalix archipelago.
It is part of the dialogue -based landscape analysis conducted within the context of
A permit project for a wind farm on Bergön in Kalix municipality.
I work as project manager
At WPD Scandianvia. Today we will focus
In the landscape and how we experience it.
As we entered this project with those
special conditions in an archipelago
where there is a richly moving outdoor life, so we felt that
This was a good method
in order to
Develop a good decision basis. It is also a good shape
for our consultation process
where we can cooperate with people
found in place, instead of
Just use
Expert expertise available
with our consultants
at the County Administrative Board
And the municipality
We are going to do a dialogue -based landscape analysis and we do
In accordance with the Landscape Convention
directive
about how landscape analyzes should be done
And what methods
You can use.
You have received these compendiums.
If one browses to
Page three
So you see the tour we are going.
The route is laid out so that we can look at Bergön from different
distance
And in different contexts. Where there are very small islands around
And from open bars. On the tour we will
stop and talk a little extra
In four different places.
Landscape,
It's not just what we see,
Without what we hear, smells, tubes,
Experiences. We have our own unique
perspective.
What did you get out of the boat trip today?
Good information about the project you want to implement.
Clear and good information.
We know the area well before. We have had a boat for many years and
visited this island on many different occasions
So we know the environment very well
But then to see
Photo montage,
how it will be able to look about if you build
the wind turbines, how it
will look in reality.
Good information.
You have holiday homes here and wind turbines
as you see
already
Today from the house.
How does it affect you?
Nothing.
We don't notice it.
We sometimes see
That it stands still, and says "now it stands still".
Otherwise it is common to
Leisure residents have views on wind power?
I understand that. If you have a very scenic environment,
Beautiful and nice views. Then I understand that people may react to the fact that there is a wind farm.
But
As we experience it so don't have it
been troublesome for us.
I think it's been good to get
look with your own eyes
these
The sketches
When it has sketched in
The intended establishments.
It makes a lot for visual impressions,
and that we got to look
Based on different
distance and understanding
because one moves
In the archipelago for example, which makes
that it's not like sitting still in a cabin and watching
on a fixed vantage point.
I think it has been very valuable.
But almost the best I think is that they have chosen
the dialog -based process, so one becomes
Invited to that
partly fill up with knowledge
So that you can have better opinions yourself,
but also that man
may come to speak.
It feels very important.