Welcome to a conversation about a research agenda with a focus on microplastics.
As we have recently published on our website.
We have put the link in the description during the film.
It is interesting reading this research agenda.
We want you to download it and that you take your content.
And with me here today to tell you more about the research agenda so I have
Åsa and Julia
-—-—-
Tell us a little more about what you work with
Yes my name is Julia Taylor
And I work at the Swedish Environmental Protection Agency
With our national plastic coordination where I work mostly with
Microplastics
And then I am Åsa and I also work within the national coordination where I coordinate the issue internally
About microplastics
And then I work some with environmental monitoring of microplastics.
My name is Henrik Löwenhamn and I am a communicator at the Swedish Environmental Protection Agency.
Yes but then we start with
What is a research agenda for something and why is it needed in the microplastics area
We saw that in our work on developing instruments and action had
Large knowledge gaps in order to perform our work in a good way
And that's why we saw that a research agenda was needed as
Calls in the areas where we need more knowledge for
Be able to
Perform our work to better reduce emissions.
Do you have examples of areas or what could be for something
Yes but we have we have divided the research agenda into different areas partly then
Microplastics overall, what is needed.
Which areas
Or so ... we need
Knowledge on an overall plane since then we also have
Divided into the agenda after the largest sources.
So it's road and tire wear
Littering that is treated rather overall
Textile wash
Artificial green
Who is it to read this
the research agenda, which do we want
Shall take it to
But it is really everyone who works to develop knowledge
So it can be
Research funders, it can be scientists
There may also be different product developers who work to
Develop new products or improve existing products.
Åsa, how do we want it to
be used in concrete terms
But we want it to be used as an inspiration, we think.
That it should like
Point out the direction forward
Where we see that this
Here you need power -gathering efforts
-—-—-
The microplast area is very wide so we have identified
The areas where we see this we need to prioritize the efforts in order to this way
When we make power collections together we can take big steps
In knowledge acquisition
Instead of it happening
Slightly
A little onto the pö that makes it difficult to
Simply collect knowledge
-—-—-
What do we want as well as in the longer term what do we want it to lead to then, what do we want to
happen if several years or in even longer term
Yes but it is just to get a better
Knowledge ..., a better foundation
For us that we can use when deciding on different instruments and measures
And we know that there has been a lot of research in this area in recent times
But just because it is a fairly new research area so it is
Still quite large knowledge gaps
As we are tamped with so when we are going to make our decisions
-—-—-
If I
Works with plastic
But perhaps not just directly related to research
What do I have to pick up in this research agenda
Why should I read it
I think that if, for example, you work with product development or innovation
At a plastic company
So it may well be good to read our agenda and see, but where are there
deficiencies in products or what to say but what can you contribute to developing sustainable products
that makes that
Microplastic emissions decrease
It can be within a huge number of different areas
As such as within the road and the tire industry
There maybe there is the opportunity and we have
As we said with artificial turf for example where we see that there will be a lot of microplastics from both rubber
granules and from itself
Artificial grass
There you might be able to find new methods to
Make better durable
Products
Yes exactly.
It can be, for example, alternative materials for infill
Or construct the artificial green and so that the beach does not release
As much or if one then takes Åsa's example with the tire wear
Thus tires that are worn less for example
We have already talked about
-—-—-
What do you know about the biggest sources.
Who are them and
Can you develop more about it
what is it that
Spreads microplastics
In nature
Yes but we have worked a lot on mapping different sources we had two different government assignments where we have
Looked at that.
What we have seen is that it is very difficult to put an exact figure on how much is spread
But the biggest sources
It is littering, road and tire wear
Synthetic textile fibers and artificial green and also to some extent pellets.
And different intentionally
added microplastics in products.
What do we know
What happens later
These
the microplastics
So if it ends up in nature and waterways and maybe finally also the sea.
How much do we know and what do we know about
What is happening there
But you know that it is after all
Huge amounts that are released
It is at least 150 million tonnes and that it
Increases by every year and plastic use has increased enormously
So it is being built up
In the seas and the breakdown of plastic occurs very slowly
So even if we stop the supply of microplastics today or within a few years, the formation of microplastic articles will
continue for a long time as there is already so much plastic outside
In our waters
And we have a problem too in that we ...
It is very difficult to clean away microplastics
Once it is in the environment
So we know that after all
But then how
Dangerous
Microplastics are for human health and for our nature
There are still great knowledge gaps
So there we still see the need to develop or expand our knowledge in that area so it needs more
Research within that for
To get better knowledge really.
-—-—-
But we know that
Microplastics are spread
And it remains in nature.
And then it is and then the content of microplastics increases and then you can think
They may not be at that level right now
Some areas may be a health hazard directly without, but they can have a very effect on the ecosystem level, for example.
They do not disappear ...
No
There has been research that we said we have just finished
an effort.
Can you tell me a little
What happened there
Yes exactly we have just finished a perennial microplastics
Research effort.
Locking word.
And there the researchers looked at
Slightly different areas and it was partly about method development in order to be able to
Using improved methods in environmental monitoring
But it was also about nanoplasts
Mapping different flows in urban environments
And microplastics in freshwater
And also just this with effects and health
Health effects
It is just completed and it was a performance conference in January
If you want to see those presentations, we can link to them in the description here as well
And those reports
Will well come soon?
They are now fully written by the researchers.
So that they will soon be published on the Swedish Environmental Protection Agency's website.
-—-—-
And as we always do when we talk plastic on
The Swedish Environmental Protection Agency.
I would like to remind you of the roadmap we have for a durable plastic use
-—-—-
It is a lot to find if you want to
Help Sweden to
Reach a durable plastic use
And so I want to say that
Are you not already with the national plastic coordination
Do you think I will
Join
There you can keep up to date on what happens in both microplastics and macro plastic and
-—-—-
And what happens at the Swedish Environmental Protection Agency when it comes to plastic
But also you already get on a lot of what is happening in
Sweden
And internationally.
Do I have something more to add to say that we send out these letters.
There you can keep up to date through them and then we have a lot of information on the site
And if you are in the coordination, you also get the chance to participate in
working groups and reference groups if you are interested in it
Is there anything more you want to add about the research agenda more than I think
Are you interested in plastic and above all microplastics
So think one should read
I as a layman
As a communicator
Can take me it
It is easy to read, it is easy to
Understand
Download and read
Something more to add ,, Julia and Åsa
No yes i agree with you that it is
It is divided into different categories as well so that you can choose to go directly
In the area you are
Interested in one can look at it at an overview
Not read it in its entirety unless one wants to
It's not a huge thickness either, it's really easy to do.
If one has questions about
the research agenda, it is ok to contact you then
Yes of course
Yes but what good
Then I want to thank you
To thank you for looking.
And then you hear from you
If you have any questions.
Thanks