My name is Michael Nilsson and I am chairman here in the Nature Conservation Association in Härryda.
I have been involved in these environmental issues for 35 years and it started in this area, actually.
I thought I just saw a streamer here.
For 10-15 years we have invented and documented natural values.
And then we have had individual logging that has been discussed and one of them went up in the European Court of Justice-
- After it was appealed by the Nature Conservation Association and protect the forest.
There came the verdict a year and a half ago that not only affects this area -
- On how to handle the protected how to handle the protected species but also throughout Sweden.
And other EU countries must also follow that judgment.
The judgment is called “protect the forest judgment” and now it is used by-
- Different authorities, courts and also different associations to ensure that species protection is followed.
With these issues that were in court processes and with authorities and so involved.
It was that we had a good documentation and that we presented it in a good way that made it possible to accept it.
It must not be too complicated either, but it must still be with good illustrations and maps -
- So that you can see these conflicts and what values are.
Visualize it in a good way so that it becomes clear what it is about.
It is not enough to have just a lot of species lists and such, but you have to somehow -
- Clarify and then you can choose some species and show effects and such with that particular species.
Preferably with pictures and maps.
Then you can work with film and present it in a different way as well.
Hope and a goal with this work is in a way that you discontinue yourself.
And that society and the various activities -
- It themselves makes sure that in connection with various issues, nature is maintained to a sufficient extent.