We arrange various activities for people who are newly arrived here.
We think nature is important.
Everyone who comes here may not have knowledge, so we need to inform.
Right now, we will inform about the public right.
Now it's the eighth year in a row that Antonio and I have done this.
It is a popular activity.
We are open to everyone.
To cook together, get to know each other and get to know the environment where the children play.
Now we will go through question number five.
What do you think?
This is what we do, we call at -covered vocal. You get close to nature. We open another world for the kids.
And for adults too.
It is to come really close to something.
A loupe is an opportunity, you don't need that much. And then you get close to nature.
At the nature school we will have different themes every day.
Among other things, we will have flowers, aquatic animals, beaver safari, fire and butterflies.
You become an expert on flowers as well.
So you can get these pins and become an expert on every thing we do in nature.
And also just being.
It is not so common when you come to a country that you just go out and are in nature.
It is important to move. Feel how healthy it is in nature.
This is the first time I am here, in this forest. So it's great fun.
It tastes better in nature and the kids have fun.
Dare. Dare to test such activities.
In the beginning it may not come so many, but then when people start to know the activity ---
- Then the number of participants is constantly increasing.
Have it open, and listen to everyone.
And let the participants be free in the activities.
I would recommend that.
Then comes the knowledge of everything else we want to convey in between.
I like nature myself. And my dream is for everyone else to love nature as I do.
It's the only dream I have. And I think most people appreciate nature.
So it's just to continue that way. And use nature a little more.
Bye!