My name is Eva Eiderström.
I work at the Swedish Society for Nature Conservation and I work in a department called "Shop Environmentally friendly".
We work very much with important issues for all of us.
How can I live in a better way that makes us cope with all the challenges society faces?
And how can we with our way of living actually support the change needed?
Then we can use such concrete tools as what we do daily -
- And we can make it through what choices we make.
We have developed an eco -labeling system that helps in these everyday elections.
It's called Good Environmental Choice.
Our eco -label has ...
The first criterion was presented in Sweden's nature number one 1990.
So we have been around for quite some time.
We still try to encourage people to do what you can.
Not to make demands that you do everything right, because it is quite unreasonable.
And if it gets harder, at least do something right.
There are both cheap and expensive eco -labeled products.
Ecolabelling itself does not lead to the products being more expensive or worse for that matter.
So then you can choose what suits your economy -
- And maybe at least buy every other time if you have previously bought every time.
But everything you do is better than not doing anything at all.
If you talk about some kind of theoretical long -term goal, it would be ..
If you see shop as both buying and acting -
- So we worked on how we look at gaining access to what we need.
If we can do it in ways other than buying your own gadget, for example.
Actually, by extension, a way to try to reduce the entire large resource consumption that is the consequences of -
- That we use things for a very long time and then replace them with something new.
It is very exciting and it would be very fun if it took off and favored in different ways in society.
There are many tests in different places among different companies and different phenomena that already exist that mean this.
But that it was scaled up and became the new norm would in some way be very, very good.
And it would also mean that climate emissions dropped dramatically as this entire resource sales -
- As we do, a lot of resources cost.
And then when we have used them, they suddenly become hopelessly mixed and we cannot benefit from them again.
Instead of using them for as long as possible and finding ways to make sure we don't have to replace everything -
- Without just replacing parts and so on.