This season we will follow Nazi Johan
I start the adventure and head to him in Stockholm
The dream is well to find someone to share the hatred with
Hi johan!
Hello
What have you been doing lately?
Resistance
I have with me three letters to you
I have no special requirements
As long as it's a purebred, submissive, Holocaust -denied girl
that takes care of the household
Amen she might be something
Well
Note the picture got much darker when I scanned it, she writes
Aa, you hope that
mm
Eh, she is not convicted of incitement against people group
Mm, there is a little PK warning on it
Is that it?
It is it, mm
It's hard, you don't want to get too dear and lose focus
In the fight against the traitor of the Jewish conspiracy
What do you think about her?
Tall, a beautiful long -bald skull
I am interested
"I long for someone to develop my Nazism together with."
"Mein Kampf is to meet you !! Hell, Lisbet!"
She can be the right one actually
Is that so?
Exciting
Aa!
I am happy with those girls I selected
I give them 8/8
Now is the time for Speed-Date, and the girls have arrived in Stockholm
I really hope I get to show Johan how Nazi I can be
Hello
Thank you
You are welcome
I appreciate the gift
Adde (?) Got similar by Eva
You wrote well in the letter
But you did not send with any family tree
Oh, eh
Sorry
And you wrote that you are not Nazi
But is interested in it?
Yes, I get so incredibly inspired when I heard you talk about persecution of homosexuals
and expulsion of racial stamps and dissent
She probably has a little Nazi in herself anyway that girl
So, would you be prepared to move home to me and
do some Nazi stuff?
Yeah i think it might suit me
Johan makes me feel like I was in the Third Reich
I want to meet Johan because he seems aggressive and hotful
I hope I get the chance
to bring his violent genes on
Aa
Will this body handle four children do you think?
Aa, but, aa I think that
Will be needed in the fight for the survival of the breed
Absolutely
Do you have regular menstation?
It started a little stiffly, you don't want to be for
You want to give them a little lebensraum
But have you had many conditions before or ...?
What is this, the Nuremberry Trials or?
(laughs)
Then it lit up, clearly
Now I think the time is out
No! I want to talk more
We have to do that later
Yes, Mein Führer!
Yes, but it was really like this flirty atmosphere and
We were a little spinning
He thinks I have to throw out all adoptive children
And I think it's a little more like this, from case to case
So it also gives a little extra spice to the relationship
But as I really liked that I was so much more hateful in reality
Yes is not it?
And the Aryan arms, you want to squeeze them!
Eh, yes thank you!
Next week, Sara will be sorry for Johan taking Lisbet to the Goebbelsfestival
and Johan and Lisbet have their first trouble
We would have a cozy evening and see the first half of Schindler's list
Do you think bombing plans themselves or?