We have filmed a lot in Rinkeby to change the media image.
In the media, Rinkeby is always portrayed to be a "no go zone".
You can't go there, it's dangerous and it's always just a lot of negative things happening there.
There is never anything positive that comes from Rinkeby and I think it is very shame.
When we have talked to people living in Rinkeby, everyone really says that the media picture is very skewed.
Their everyday life is not reflected in the media reporting at all, but their reality is quite different.
Some think it is completely different and that they feel that the media invents.
It has been very interesting to make these videos and we have received a lot of response.
We have received both positive and negative comments and I really encourage everyone to comment on your thoughts.
Even if you do not feel the same, it is through conversations that you move forward in some way.
Some of you have commented that we should talk to the police in the area.
They have an overall picture, are there every day and see the worst.
I have got in touch with a guy named Hanif who is a police officer in Rinkeby and I will meet him.
Now I'm going to Rinkeby.
-I met Rickard here. You have lived here, right? -Yes exactly. The first year as newlyweds me and the lady.
-Do you well thrilled then? -Yes I did.
Then we moved because we would plug and such, so now we live in Småland.
-Do you find that the media image of Rinkeby is correct? -In Rinkeby lives the people and people are who they are.
Some are Koko and some are very wonderful, it is mixed here just like elsewhere.
There are absolutely problems, but there are opportunities as well.
Great fun!
Rickard arrived because he saw the video, damn fun!
-A small sequel. -Yes, exactly so now we're going to film with Hanif.
-How long have you worked as a police officer? -I have worked for seven years as a police officer.
Rinkeby is one of the areas I worked within.
What is the best thing about being a police officer?
The best thing is that you represent society and to help everyone who needs our help.