[class chatter]
Okay, okay...
LISTEN UP!
Alright
Glad to see everyone so bright eyed and bushy-tailed first thing in the morning.
As you might recall
this mid-term is worth fifty percent of your final grade
so hopefully you studied.
Alright, go get em!
[hallucination] hey Alex...
[hallucination] hi Alex -- my man! --
[hallucination] it's been a while...
[hallucination] I told you I got your back...I wouldn't let you fail...
[hallucination] you never study...you don't have to worry about this...velocity...mass...
[hallucination] acceleration...what is that?!
[hallucination] you don't even study...you know you don't know that...
[classmate chewing]
[hallucination] you don't know this answer...so stupid...
[hallucination] the answer for number fourteen is...
[teacher] Eyes on your own page.
[auditory hallucination attack]
[hallucination] you look like a cheater...you look like a loser...
[classmate chewing]
[hallucination] A or B? Did you just steal my answers?
[hallucination] trust me...the answer is A...
[hallucination] Alex...
[hallucination] stop looking at my test...you're a freak...
[hallucination] you're sweating profusely...Alex...you suck, you should've studied!
[gum chewing]
[pencil breaking]
[increasing auditory hallucination attack]
[hallucination] you've always been a freak! Don't put them on!
[hallucination] tick tock tick tock tick tock tick tock...
[hallucination] stop! stop!
[hallucination] You're running out of time!
[hallucination] You can't get rid of us. We're not going anywhere--
[bubble popping]
[music drowning out voices]
[music blaring loud]
[timer ringing]
[music playing loud]
[hallucinations returning]
This is not a night club, Mr. McKay.
Thank you.
Is that what the kids are listening to these days?
WAH, WAH, WAH...
[hallucination attack] you're not going to do anything?! He just took your headphones!!
[hallucination] You think you are alone? You're never alone with us!
[hallucination] No, don't put them on!
[hallucination] Give up, you can't get rid of us--
[music blocking out voices]
[classroom ruffling]
[classmates laughing]
Hope you read the book, it might be your last chance to pass this class.
[door opening]
[library ruffling and keyboard clatter]
[blaring loud music]
[music getting louder]
[tinny slam]
[loud music returns]
[blaring loud music]
[book slam]
[book cart crash]
[Alex] I'm sorry--
[Librarian] What are you doing?
[Librarian] Turn down that music--
[Alex] Okay--
[Librarian] I can hear it through your headphones!
[book rustling]
[heavy breathing]
[Librarian] What...
what is wrong with you?
Oh, you have an accomplice now. Both of you
pick up those books! And turn down that music!
And you, you be quiet!!
Pick up the books!
Um, you okay?
[Alex] Um...
Oh, for me?
Thank you.
[ominous noise]
[no voices]
[Alex's music playing]
[rising orchestra]
["We Are The Things" playing]