A short story has a single, clear plot.
Novels tend to be longer, more complex,
and have more slowly unfolding events.
In a short story, the protagonist
is usually introduced very early on.
There is no upper limit
for how long a short story can be.
It can be anything from a couple of pages
to over a hundred.
Keep this in mind
when you're writing a short story.
Make sure you have a theme throughout.
Stick to the plot, and don't digress.
Plan the story before you start writing.
Think about the characters,
events, settings, and ending.
Would you like to convey
any particular message or moral?
Introduce the characters and any conflict
between them as soon as possible.
Come up with good settings and details.
It's a good idea
to use pop culture references.
For example, don't just write
that a character is listening to music.
If you specify the song or artist,
it can evoke something in the reader.