A new school year and term
can feel like getting a fresh start.
Similar to New Year's resolutions,
many set new goals-
-to change or improve
during the new school year.
KEEP THE ENERGY UP ALL TERM
It's common to set new goals,
but also to eventually lose motivation.
It's hard to maintain the energy and drive
you feel after a long break.
But there are things you can do
to make it easier.
Improving your results
requires effort and determination.
So, think carefully
about what you want to improve.
Do you want to get in to a certain school-
-or maybe just prove to yourself
what you're capable of?
Anyone who is good at something
has invested a lot of time in it.
That's true for everything, whether it's
math, writing well, or running fast.
To keep it up throughout the term,
write down your goals and think about-
-why you want to achieve them.
Just like everything else,
motivation requires regular maintenance.
To reach your goals, you have to
perform maintenance on your motivation.
Write down what you want to achieve
and what is important to you.
Later on, when your
drive and motivation are fading-
-you can revisit what you wrote.
Write down the reasons behind your
goals and what is important to you-
-in as much detail as possible, to help
you access that feeling when revisiting it.
You'll spend a lot of time at school
with your classmates and teachers-
-so make a special effort
to help create a pleasant environment.
You and your classmates
might not have a lot in common-
-but always treat everyone with respect.
Keeping your energy up is much easier
if the classroom atmosphere is positive.
So do what you can to contribute
to a pleasant atmosphere.
Remember: However easy or hard you
find school, you can achieve your goals.
That depends on your motivation,
drive, and perseverance-
-rather than the talents
you were born with.