When writing an op-ed piece, your goal is
to make the reader agree with you.
Choose an issue you feel strongly about,
where something needs to change.
Use clear, fact-based arguments
to make the reader react and act.
Op-eds are most common in newspapers
but also occur on blogs and other sites.
Unlike a column or letter to the editor-
-an op-ed piece is less personal
and more fact-based.
Keep this in mind
when you're writing an op-ed piece.
Use a short title
that will spark the reader's interest.
What do you want to say,
change, affect?
Start your piece with a clear thesis.
Use arguments to convince the reader.
Choose your best arguments,
and get rid of the rest.
Can you think
of any counterarguments? Good!
Address those to show that you're able
to see things from different perspectives.
Use source references
to strengthen your arguments.
Don't be afraid to cause a stir
with your piece.
Making the reader care about the issue
is a positive thing.
Finally, summarise your piece. Repeat
your thesis, and use your best argument.
You can also finish by asking the reader
to take action.