Questions for systematic reviews
Being able to ask good questions
is an important asset-
-and people's interest in how nature
works has led to major discoveries.
In all science subjects,
you work on formulating questions-
-in order to perform systematic studies.
In order to assess the quality of your
work and give you things to improve-
-your teacher consults
the knowledge requirements.
The requirements for all science
subjects, grade nine, include:
"Being able to formulate
simple questions and plans"-
-"from which to work systematically."
Before performing a systematic study,
you need a proper plan.
Identify a variable to alter.
Common variables are amounts,
temperature, time and pressure.
It's essential to only change
one variable at a time.
All others have to remain constant.
An example:
There's ice by the door.
Someone could slip and fall!
We have to get rid of the ice
as soon as possible.
Is there anything in the chemistry lab
to make the ice melt quickly?
Salt?
Salt is used on roads in the winter-
-but maybe that's special salt.
Would table salt work?
How would you formulate
that question-
-in order to enable a systematic study?
What happens if we pour salt on ice?
Then you would be studying\hif the ice
would melt, but not how quickly.
How quickly does ice melt
when salt is added?
How much salt would you add?
That's what we want to study.
Oh, right! So the question would be:
How does the amount of salt
affect how quickly the ice melts?
That would work! And that would make
the amount of salt a variable.
Have you got a hypothesis?
Mine is that the ice will melt
more quickly, the more salt we add.
We need to measure how much water
melts during a given time span.
And how will you measure that?
Now you have to plan your study.
We'll take two paper cups
and make holes in the bottom.
Then we'll fill them with 1 dl of
crushed ice and place them in beakers.
We'll add 1 tbsp of salt in one
and mix using a glass stirrer.
We'll add 3 tbsp in the other and stir.
We're checking how quickly
the ice melts, so we have to time it.
Using a ruler, we'll measure the water
level between cup and beaker-
-and document how much has melted.
So you'll measure the levels regularly,
using time intervals.
That's right.
We're going to document our findings-
-our measured values, in a chart.
We'll use the timer on my phone-
-and every three minutes,
check the water level in both cups.
We can make a graph too,
to present our findings more clearly.
Great! And if your hypothesis
seems accurate-
-how can you be sure
it wasn't a one-off?
Right. We'll have to perform the study
again to be entirely sure.
We'll perform the same study twice.
I'll add that to the plans.
Let's leave the pupils and their study.
Good science questions are formulated
in such a way that they can be studied-
-for instance answered by measuring
or observing changes.
Questions that start with "why"
are harder to answer in studies alone.
More theory is needed for those.
A systematic study measures
one variable at a time-
-and requires a plan
for collecting measuring data.
In this example,
the amount of salt was studied.
Other variables, like the amount of ice,
temperature, size of the ice cubes-
-and stirring frequency,
were kept constant.
The pupils' planning is of good quality.
The question is studied-
-through observing and measuring the
results of changes in the salt amount.
They are planning
a repetition of the experiment-
-as well as
the documentation of the study.
The study shows that the salt amount
does affect how quickly the ice melts.
And that's not the only result
of mixing salt and ice.
You could also measure
the temperature.
Studies usually give rise
to new questions to study-
-and there is always more to learn.
Subtitles: Sofia Sundqvist				www.btistudios.com