How to argue				a source's credibility and relevance
You argue the credibility and relevance
of sources in many school subjects.
But being source-critical
is also important throughout your life.
Your arguing explains
and strengthens your idea or opinion.
You can make a claim about
a certain source not being credible-
-but what supports your claim? Why do
you think the information is unreliable?
Is it biased? Is someone spinning
the information for personal gain?
In order to assess the quality of your
work and give you things to improve-
-your teacher consults
the knowledge requirements.
The requirements for Swedish,
grade nine, include:
"To find, select and summarize
information from varied sources"-
-"and find support to argue for/against
the sources' credibility and relevance."
The quality of a source-critical
argument is made up of many things.
It's important to get a wide scope-
-by describing several strengths
and weaknesses of the source.
Credibility is one perspective.
You can also assess the relevance:
In what way is the source relevant
to your query?
You should also demonstrate links
between source content and your claim-
-by offering concrete examples.
Another way of developing
a source-critical argument is-
-to use your knowledge
about the topic or the general context-
-in order to assess
the contents of the source.
An example:
Argue the credibility and relevance
of three different sources.
The topic is anonymity
and online surveillance.
The first source is
a blog entry by an IT security expert.
She describes how anonymity
can protect as well as cause harm-
-and demonstrates both pros and cons.
The source is relevant, as it provides
information about both sides.
It's also credible,
because it's not one-sided.
Your source-critical argument
will be more developed-
-if you present concrete examples
to support your conclusions.
Which pros and cons are mentioned?
The IT expert says
that anonymity can help people-
-to report on matters which they would
otherwise be unable to talk about.
But criminals can also use anonymity.
Also, lies and prejudice
are spread by anonymous people.
Good! By making your claims concrete
through content references-
-you're showing that they are supported.
Is it fair to assume
that the author knows the topic?
Yes. An IT security expert at the IIS
should be familiar with the topic.
She also references studies
that support her claims.
What about source number two?
It portrays a one-sided and biased view,
as it only describes the bad things-
-that can be done anonymously online.
When a source offers a one-sided view
of reality, it is tendentious.
Your argument will be more developed
if you use concrete examples.
In what way is the source tendentious?
It is positioned clearly
in favour of increased surveillance.
It is uncritical of the Police being
able to access communications data-
-even without criminal suspicion
or a court order.
Can you still use the source?
Yes. It's still relevant
within this context-
-as it offers the arguments of those
who want to make anonymity harder.
Using information from other sources,
I can also describe the advantages.
Do you know anything else about the
source that can develop your argument?
The origin is an organization
that fights certain online crimes.
They want to increase surveillance
as it would help them in their work.
And the third source? What strengths
and weaknesses does it have?
The third is a Wikipedia article.
Anyone can contribute to it,
but volunteers check the entries.
The quality is varied,
so each article has to be scrutinized.
-How?
-Like always.
I pay attention to wording
and how the problem is described.
That way,
I'll know if the article is tendentious.
I also have to see if the article offers
relevant answers to my questions.
When it comes to Wikipedia articles,
there are three other things to check.
First of all, the article has to be
based on several quality sources.
Second of all, there is a conversation
to check under the Discussion tab.
Third of all, the history shows me
that there are many contributors.
Those were three good tips
for checking articles on Wikipedia.
The article also includes-
-the latest decision from the CJEU
about surveillance.
The decision came only a month ago,
so the article is up to date.
Good! There you developed your
argument by using your own knowledge.
A source-critical argument-
-can be developed further if you know
a lot about the topic at hand.
Moving on.
A wide scope requires many strengths
and weaknesses to be identified-
-based on the perspectives
of credibility and relevance.
Source criticism
is not about finding the ultimate truth-
-but about being able
to assess different sources.
Make your claims concrete
by offering examples to support them.
That might be carefully selected quotes
or accurate summaries of the text.
Put your argument into context
by using your knowledge about the topic-
-or the source's context,
and assess the source with that in mind.
Your source-critical ability will help
you in all subjects and all your life.
On social media,
we all work on that ability every day.
It is, after all, important
to check anything you share.
Subtitles: Sofia Sundqvist				www.btistudios.com