Source evaluation and analyzing the
information we get is always important-
-especially at a time like this,
when many people are worried-
-and the entire world is talking
about the same thing.
We're receiving a constant flow
of information about the coronavirus-
-ranging from news articles
to some influencer's views on what to do.
We also absorb news from abroad,
rumors and speculations from friends-
-and advertising,
disguised as news or a solution.
But how do we determine
what is true, essential information?
Source evaluation is important. Always
consider the author of the information-
-and why they want to share it.
If the info is linked to someone trying
to sell something, get more followers-
-or get you to change your mind,
be critical of the information.
Find out what sources the author used.
If it's unclear, be critical of the information
and research it thoroughly.
The purpose behind the info
may be propaganda or advertising.
Did you get info from a primary source?
Or from a friend who heard it from their
friend's neighbor's parent's cousin?
That's called a secondary source.
The info is likely to have changed along
the way, like in the game "telephone."
If what you learn sounds strange
or too good to be true-
-double-check the information.
Rumors can spread very easily.
Be aware of your digital footprint.
Algorithms online ensure that everything
you see is tailored specifically to you.
What you normally view is used to shape
your feed to give you more of the same.
That can be helpful sometimes,
but don't forget-
-that you are only being served info
that the algorithm thinks you want-
-and not all the available information.
That's why you should actively search
for information you trust-
-from the authorities, for instance.
These are examples of reliable websites.
Make sure to stay informed by watching
the news and press conferences.