Right now, life isn't like it usually is.
Many of our activities are being cancelled
and it's easy to get disheartened.
Uncertainty can make us
lethargic and restless.
Maybe you're wondering
how things will be in a few weeks-
-or feeling disappointed
about what you're missing.
Feeling listless or depressed
is hardly strange.
With a little creativity, we can adjust
our plans to fit the situation-
-and in this way, regain our energy.
If you play basketball, and team practice
is cancelled for a while-
-go outside and play anyway.
Maybe you can't play in your gym
or with your team-
-but you can get a teammate
and play on an outdoor court.
Besides being fun, we feel better
when we're physically active.
Exercise and physical activity increase
serotonin levels, which regulate mood.
This means you feel less stressed
and happier after physical activity.
Many feel sad they can't see people
in a risk group, or who have symptoms-
-but you can still hang out
without meeting in person.
If a friend, or Grandpa, can't go out,
make a video call.
-Hi, Laura!
-How's it going?
Seeing the people we miss
can also help us feel better.
Times are strange, but one tip for feeling
better and having more energy-
-is to keep doing things you think are fun.
For example, talk to your friends,
read a book, play video games or draw.
Keep your strength up
by eating regularly.
Keep up your routines. Wake up
and go to bed at your normal times-
-so you get enough sleep.
Then things will seem much easier.