Doing multiple things at the same time
in order to be more efficient-
-might sound like a good idea-
-but there's a risk that
that might make you less efficient.
The brain's working memory
is limited in how much it can handle-
-so too many things to focus on,
too many disturbances-
-can lead to you losing focus.
You're actually not focusing
on multiple things at the same time-
-you're sharing and shifting focus-
-and you lose your concentration
every time.
It can take time before you find it again
and for your brain to reset.
Time that you could've used
in a better way.
You might miss important information
in class-
-find it harder to learn,
accomplish less-
-and might need to bring
more school work home.
At home it can take longer
to do homework or other tasks-
-than it really should.
That's not very efficient.
So it's best to do one thing at a time-
-and reduce the number of times
you're disturbed or change tasks.
So try to reduce the risk
of you being distracted.
Find a place that suits you.
Think about what distracts you
and what makes you focus better.
A calm place often works well.
Planning what you should do, and when,
reduces the risk of you changing tasks.
Split large tasks into smaller chunks.
This increases the chance
of you staying focused.
Set aside a special time for tasks
that require a lot of concentration.
Then it's extra important
not to be distracted.
If there's something on your mind-
-you can try to set a time
when you can think about it.
Put your phone away,
turn off notifications-
-and tell your friends and family
that you're busy.
By focusing on one thing at a time
and relieving the working memory-
-you can increase your focus
and concentration.
That can then make you more efficient-
-both when it comes to learning
and time management.