Going to school can be demanding.
They expect you to be focused in class,
to memorise homework and exams.
At the same time, you have to interact
with classmates and teachers.
If your head is spinning
with negative thoughts and feelings-
-it's hard to focus
on what your teachers are saying.
It's normal to feel low sometimes
and to feel that everything is wrong.
But if your negative thoughts take over
or refuse to go away-
-you may need help and support
getting to the root of the problem.
A lot of people feel sad or low at times.
These last few years, I've noticed...
...that staying at home, not going
to school, can make matters worse.
Sometimes it's better to be in school
and be a bit passive - that's okay.
You don't have to deliver
and perform well every single day.
Sometimes it's okay to just show up at
school and be a part of the community.
I've seen a lot of students
benefit from this.
There are no set rules that say
how you have to interact socially-
-or that you have to bring
a lot of energy to the group.
Sometimes you're sad,
sometimes you're in a bad mood-
-sometimes you're happy,
sometimes you're angry.
All feelings and emotions are okay.
Come to school as you are.
Talk about how you're feeling
I think that when your worries
almost become overwhelming-
-and take over your life
and drain you of energy-
-and prevent you from doing activities
you enjoy, and you feel kind of listless-
-that's a sign that maybe
you should go and talk to someone.
But I'd like to stress:
Talk to an adult. About little things,
about big things - doesn't matter.
You shouldn't be afraid of putting
your feelings and emotions into words.
And if that's the case,
that you need some help...
If you find it scary to put them into words
and get that process started-
-that's probably a sign
that you need to talk to an adult.
You probably need support
moving forward.
Confidentiality
You should know
that school counsellors-
-are bound
by professional confidentiality.
This means that whatever you tell me
is confidential. It goes no further.
Unless you're in some kind of danger.
Then I have to take the matter further.
Maybe talk to your parents or to
the authorities so that they can help you.
This doesn't necessarily mean
that you're initiating a huge process-
-just because you talk to your counsellor
about how you're feeling.
With some students, I have maybe
3-4 sessions and a follow-up meeting.
Three tips to help you feel better
Here are some tips for those of you who
aren't feeling 100 per cent right now.
1. This is pretty normal.
Sometimes, you feel low.
But it will get better.
2. Exercise. Give it a try, at least!
Exercise, diet and sleep - start there.
These three things will have an effect
on how your brain works, too.
And, of course: Ask an adult for help.
And your friends, too.
If you're worried about yourself
or someone else-
-you should put these feelings into words.
Sometimes, the first step to feeling better
is to talk about your feelings.
You can always
turn to an adult at school-
-and there are
lots of organisations that you can turn to.