Sometimes, your maths solution
doesn't match the answer book.
This is good. It's important to know
how to calculate accurately.
It's also important to have strategies
for understanding what went wrong:
To know how to troubleshoot.
TROUBLESHOOTING
Have you understood
the maths problem?
Read it once more, to make sure
that you haven't missed anything.
Have you chosen the right method?
Maybe there's another way to do it?
Have you made any calculation errors or
written the wrong signs?
Maybe you've missed a parenthesis
or a minus sign.
SIGN ERROR?
Still can't find the error?
Then please do the following:
Write down the maths problem
and recalculate it.
If you get the same solution twice,
you probably haven't made an error.
But if you get different solutions,
you should compare your calculations-
-and reflect on what went wrong.
Compare!
Read it once more! Right method?
Wrong sign? New page. Compare!