Democracy means people's rule.
That means we together decide
how the country should be run.
Through free elections,
citizens elect politicians-
-representing the will of the people.
But living in a democracy
means more than voting in elections.
You have many rights, such as
the right to express your opinions-
-to look however you like,
to access news of all forms-
-and to speak up
when something seems wrong.
People in a functioning democracy
can forget how fragile democracy is-
-because it feels so natural.
But in some countries, the democratic
development has gone backwards-
-and people's freedom
has been restricted.
When propaganda and lies are spread
and sources are missing-
-free speech, and subsequently
democracy, is restricted.
So it's important to know
how to be critical of sources.
Make sure to tell fact from opinion.
When you read or hear something,
question whether it's fact or opinion.
You'll find both facts and opinions
in newspapers and on news sites.
You need to know what you're reading.
Many newspapers have editorials where
their political views are expressed.
Two editorials might concern
private schools-
-where one is for and the other against.
They're expressing political views.
There's no right or wrong-
-it's only their opinions.
On the editorial, culture and letter to
the editor's pages you'll find opinions.
The news pages will include
source references and are fact-based.
Who is the sender?
Even if it's someone you trust,
who normally has clever ideas-
-you should still be critical.
Where did they get the information from
and why do they want to spread it?
Sometimes friends, parents,
celebrities or people in social media-
-spread opinions as facts by mistake.
Public persons can make statements
about things they know little about-
-just because it means a lot to them.
Find the original source. Who benefits
from the information being spread-
-and is it still relevant?
Before you share the information,
make sure that you know it's correct.
Is it really true?
On social media it's hard to tell
if something is true, fake-
-a misunderstanding,
a lie or a half-truth.
Things that look true might be false-
-and things that appear to be false
might turn out to be true.
Influencers and viral clips,
e.g. on TikTok or YouTube-
-can be shared to many more
than what a news reporter writes.
Does the information seem
relevant, urgent and true?
Then you often forget to be critical of
the source, and share the information.
It might be taken out of its context
and concern something else.
With a different sound or text,
or if part of the clip is edited out-
-it might have a different meaning.
Confirmation bias is a subconscious
psychological mechanism-
-which makes us pay more attention-
-to information
that confirms what we already think.
Here are some tips
on how to check content:
Question yourself. Do you believe this
because you want it to be true?
Google. Search for something that
confirms or disproves the information.
Question whether the information
might be taken out of its context.
Citizens in a democracy should
be able to make well-founded decisions.
In order to do that, you need to be able
to evaluate and analyse information.
When you're focused on source
criticism, it's hard to trust anyone.
But there are sources you can trust.
A reliable source has references
and is independent-
-and the sender's identity is clear.
Översättning: Jenny Gregory
Iyuno-SDI Group för UR