Put off studying
until the day before the test?
Here are some last-minute tips
You'll be studying the whole evening.
Start by thinking, what do you need
to make the best out of the evening?
How do you study best?
Alone or in company?
Do you want someone to test you
after a while?
Where do you study best?
Find your ideal place.
Somewhere you can focus
and won't be bothered.
Do you prefer a desk
or your bed, perhaps?
You decide. It might be worth
making it that little bit extra cosy.
You're going to be there for a while.
Eat something before you start,
but make sure to have some snacks.
You'll need some extra energy
during the evening.
Do you like listening to music?
Throw together a quick study playlist
and put it on repeat.
Treat the evening as a race.
When it's over, you've reached goal.
Try to find ways to make it easier.
Something nice to drink or eat
and a cosy place to study
might make it feel a bit easier.
ELIMINATE DISTRACTIONS
It might be a good idea to tell everyone
that you're studying.
Your family might stay away, and your
friends will know why you're not replying.
Put your phone in flight mode
while you're studying.
If you need to use a computer,
block sites that you normally visit,
that you won't need during the evening.
THE STUDYING
Study in short bursts and take breaks.
Since you only have one evening,
there might be quite many sessions.
But you can handle it.
Take notes of things
that you don't understand.
Save them, and ask someone else
to explain when you get a chance,
or try googling for a good explanation.
But remember to be critical of sources.
A lot of text? Write your own summaries.
They're great for revising over breakfast
or on the bus to school.
And use the breaks
on the day of the test.
Give yourself a reward
at the end of the night.
Maybe you finally get your phone back,
or perhaps you bought some sweets.
ENERGY
Prioritise sleep. Don't stay up all night.
In order to best remember what
we've learned, our brains need sleep.
That's when noise and
unnecessary information is cleared out.
A lack of sleep will only make it harder
to remember what you learned
the night before.
Don't forget breakfast,
and if the test is in the afternoon,
don't skip lunch.
You'll need the energy.
Remember, if you paid attention in class,
you often know more than you think.
You can do it.