An information text is full of facts.
It can be difficult
to remember everything in a text.
But there are strategies
that can help you-
-and that also make the book
more interesting.
Your first step is to decode the book:
to get an idea of its contents-
-before you start reading it.
This is how:
Look at the cover. What does it say?
Read the text on the back of the book.
Check the table of contents.
What's the book about?
Browse through it. Look at the pictures
and the infoboxes. Read the captions.
Look for summaries
and words in bold or italic print.
Decoding a book is giving yourself
a pre-understanding of the subject-
-and acquainting yourself
with the subject.
So, when you start reading the text,
you know a bit about the contents-
-which helps the learning process.
Besides browsing through the book, you
can read newspapers and magazines-
-watch films and YouTube clips
and search the Internet for more info.
Thanks to your pre-knowledge-
-your new knowledge
will be both deeper and greater.