Here are some mnemonic techniques-
-that can help you remember
what you've learnt.
One good method is the ten-minute rule.
The key to remembering better
is repetition.
Without repetition,
what we learn is quickly forgotten.
And remember to review
before you start forgetting.
The first repetition should be soon
after learning, after ten minutes.
Or you will quickly forget.
Next repetition should be the next day,
and the following the next week.
If you want a memory for life,
review again-
-after a month
and again after six months.
A good method for repetition is
to test yourself with flashcards.
Notes where you write the word, name-
-or concept that you're learning on
one side, and the answer on the other.
If you're learning English vocabulary-
-write the English word on one side
and the Swedish word on the other.
Flashcards are easy to take with you-
-so you can test yourself
during recess or on the bus.
Another efficient memory technique
is association-
-connecting new knowledge
with something you associate it with.
That makes it easier to remember.
Let's say you're learning a new word.
What does it sound like?
What does it make you think of?
Try to make a picture in your mind.
Or try to make up a rhyme
that ties together the associations.
The weirder the better -
then you'll remember them easier.
You could also try using a memory walk,
also called the loci method.
Imagine yourself placing the facts
that you need to learn-
-in different familiar places-
-in your home, perhaps,
or along the way to school.
You'll connect what you're learning
with the places-
-and create associations.
During the exam,
you can walk the walk in your mind-
-and retrieve the facts
linked to the places.
Make sure to stick to the same order
as when you placed the facts.
One last trick to remember during an
exam is to use a permitted cheat sheet.
Once you've sat down,
ask for a piece of paper.
Write down all facts, words, or formulas
that you think you might forget.
That way you can avoid
unnecessary stress during the exam-
-and use your energy
to answer the questions instead.
Översättning: Jenny Gregory				Iyuno för UR