If you want to share an opinion,
write a letter to the editor of a paper.
Have a clear thesis and be subjective,
since it's all about your opinion.
Get the readers' attention. Convince
them you're right by using arguments.
Anyone can send a letter to the editor.
Whether or not it gets published
is up to the paper.
Keep this in mind
when you're writing a letter to the editor.
Have a clear theme throughout to make
your line of thought easier to follow.
Weigh arguments
against counterarguments.
If you think some people may not agree
with you, explain why you're right.
Finish your letter by reconnecting
to the beginning of it.
Use that to urge the readers
to take action.
Sign it using your name or a signature
to give your letter a personal touch.