NUANCED ARGUMENTS
AND COMPLEX CONNECTIONS
You form arguments in many
school subjects and other situations.
That means you develop your thoughts
and opinions about something.
To help you develop within a subject-
-your teachers always consult
the knowledge requirements.
For social studies, these state that "the
student has to form nuanced arguments"-
-"and describe complex connections
between different factors"-
-meaning how different things are related.
And that can be a bit tricky.
Here's an example of students
forming nuanced arguments-
-and explaining complex connections
on the topic of influencing public opinion.
They will use relevant terminology-
-and address different factors
affecting a person's influential ability.
They will offer concrete examples
which they will also analyse.
Complex connections are formed when
they reflect on how factors are related.
Right, we have to name the factors
that affect a person's influential ability.
Starting a group on social media
for like-minded people is easy.
But how do you make a real impact?
It's about power.
It still matters who you are
and who you know.
Interesting start. They use terminology
that is relevant to the subject-
-and have already mentioned two factors
that affect a person's influence.
In this case,
those factors were status and network.
Can they use an example
to elaborate on that?
True, status does matter.
If a celebrity I like speaks out for
or against something, it influences me.
And not just me - think of all the people
following that person's updates.
Yeah, many followers equals power.
On the one hand, celebrities get
loads of followers right away.
On the other hand, social media levelled
the playing field with regard to influence.
If the timing is right, I think anyone
can go viral and influence public opinion.
Their discussion is becoming nuanced.
Students are analysing examples of how
social media can be used for influence.
They use "on the one hand/
on the other hand"-
-to describe different sides
to their argument.
Developing your thoughts in several
steps forms a chain of reasoning.
That brings us to complex connections:
How arguments and examples
are related.
Let's see how our students illustrate that.
Let's forget about the celebrity
and try a new perspective.
If two regular people
want to achieve the same goal-
-like improving school lunches, is there
a difference in who we may listen to?
Sure. How you convey your message
matters, for instance.
Maybe your upbringing has prepared you
to present and phrase arguments well.
So you could say a person's
socio-economic background matters-
-since it affects their expression.
But a person can also be
more or less credible.
I don't think background matters if the
person was present at a certain event-
-either as a victim or a witness.
How a person's statements are received
depends on things like gender and looks.
The same story may be received
differently depending on who tells it.
Also, a person's background can
determine who that person knows.
Even if you're not famous, your network
can be more or less influential.
That affects your chances to reach out.
And you have to reach
someone powerful.
So you have to be strategic
and choose the right channels.
Right. Complex connections are created
by explaining how factors are related.
That helps you describe similarities
and differences in several steps.
Our students are discussing
complex connections-
-from a socioeconomic standpoint.
They connect the background to other
factors like credibility, gender, and looks.
They've also mentioned
networks and strategies.
But let's leave the example and examine
the knowledge requirement.
As in any subject, you need to know
terminology that is relevant to the task.
Find out what the important terms are
before you get started.
Identify factors that somehow affect
the topic you are discussing-
-and explain how those factors
influence each other.
Offer real examples. Show that you know
what you're talking about.
Things are rarely black and white, but
can usually be viewed in different ways.
What perspective did you choose?
Finally, how are your arguments
and examples related to each other?
Describe connections by highlighting
similarities and differences-
-thereby pointing out connections
that are more or less complex.
Being able to show connections and
forming a nuanced argument is useful-
-in several school subjects
and in situations outside of school.