TIPS BEFORE
THE ORAL NATIONAL TESTS
If you've paid attention in class,
you should know the basics-
-i.e. what's covered in the national tests.
Remember that for English and
Swedish, it's not so much about facts-
-but rather the ability to converse
and reason with other people.
The test result makes up a considerable
part of your grade, but not all of it.
If you've already shown what you know,
your teacher will bear this in mind-
-regardless of how you do in the test.
Teachers consider the whole picture.
Try instead to think of the test
as a way to improve your grades.
Since there are several of you,
you get to lead the conversation-
-but also to listen
and participate several times.
It's important to listen actively
and show that you're paying attention.
It's not a competition.
If the group succeeds, you succeed.
Help each other so everyone
gets to speak for a better conversation.
The test isn't there to catch you out.
Your teacher wants you to succeed.
The teacher often even adapts the group
to ensure a good dynamic.
Remember that a lot of it are things
that you already know-
-for example speaking, listening and
answering questions and statements.
The aim here is to do just that, maybe
just with a little more commitment.
For the English test, study synonyms.
This will give you a bigger vocabulary-
-and a more advanced way
of expressing yourself.
Practise by having discussions and
conversations with people around you.
Practise listening
and asking follow-up questions.
The stress associated with the test
can feel difficult and scary-
-but it can actually be a help too.
When we experience short-term stress,
adrenaline is secreted-
-which makes us extra alert,
making us think and reason faster.
Try to visualise the national test
and that it goes well.
It's a mental preparation
that can help you feel calm.
And give yourself
the very best prerequisites-
-by going to bed early,
and don't forget to have breakfast.
You can do this, good luck!