How to resist false rumors.
Here are five pieces of useful advice.
Listen and read carefully.
The risk of misunderstanding or making
your own interpretation increases-
-if you don't read or listen carefully
to what is being said.
Just reading the headline,
sentences out of context-
-or only half paying attention
can make you misunderstand-
-and subsequently contribute
to false information being spread.
Use reliable sources to double-check.
Always double-check claims that seem
exaggerated or unlikely to be true-
-using sources you can trust.
A reliable source is always independent,
factual, neutral-
-and can show you where
its information comes from.
The authorities are one example
of reliable sources.
Trust facts, not feelings.
Feelings have more control over us than
we think, and we tend to trust feelings-
-over facts when we assess information.
"I feel like this is true."
We are especially vulnerable to this
during a frightening event.
You see, fear makes us less critical.
We react instinctively, seeking safety-
-and don't remember
to assess information critically.
Keep your bias in check.
Nobody is completely neutral.
We all have preconceived notions
that affect us and how we see the world.
Confirmation bias, for instance,
means we have a tendency-
-to look for information that confirms
what we already believe to be true-
-and unconsciously disregard
information that goes against our beliefs.
Think for yourself. It's crucial to practice
assessing information critically-
-and to constantly question
what we see, hear, and read.
During dramatic events,
rumors are particularly likely to spread.
Follow up on any claims
and find out the facts.
It's important not to get carried away
and spread false rumors.