NEWS ARTICLE
A news article is a text
that describes a particular event.
The introduction
has to catch the reader's attention.
The article's headline and the lead
are followed by the body.
You can also use pictures, charts,
and explanatory fact boxes-
-to help the reader understand.
Keep this in mind
when you're writing a news article.
Including interviews
makes the article more substantial.
They can, for instance, be in the form of
eyewitness accounts or expert opinions.
Your job is to relay an event to the public-
-so people have to understand and want
to read the article. Explain difficult terms.
Don't include your personal opinions,
and stay objective.
Describe what has happened,
not how you feel about it.
Articles should ideally include more than
one perspective on the issue at hand.
Account for the event chronologically.
How did it start? What happened
during and after the event?