To systematically examine				and re-examine - Technology
These days,
technological knowhow is critical.
Technological improvements
solve many problems.
The subject lets you develop your own
technological ideas and solutions.
Technological solutions require
creativity and problem solution.
For instance, an architect has to first
identify and examine the needs-
-and then try out proposals
using sketches and models.
Perhaps the building needs to be green
as well as practical-
-but still look nice
and be financially sound.
From the finished draft, a blueprint
is made and the house can be built.
Technology development in school
is a lot like the architect's process.
In order to assess the quality of your
work and give you things to improve-
-your teacher consults
the knowledge requirements.
The requirements for technology,
grade nine, include:
"To perform simple technology
development and construction"-
-"by systematically examining
and re-examining proposals"-
-"as well as design well-planned
physical or digital models."
Systematically examining
and re-examining ideas-
-means to develop and adjust solutions
according to different needs.
Here is an example task:
Make a digital blueprint of an Attefall
house that you would want to live in.
The house needs to be energy efficient
and made from sustainable materials.
This is a map of the area.
We've talked about Attefall houses.
They can be no larger than 25 sqm.
The neighbour's house is quite close,
so I'll move mine to the other side.
According to Boverket-
-Attefall houses need to be 4.5 metres
from the edge of the property.
That's a good spot.
How tall should the house be?
They can be no more than 4 metres,
ground to roof ridge.
There's no room for two floors-
-but I can put in a loft,
freeing up floor space for furniture.
Good! Using the map
and the Boverket website-
-you examined
the conditions for your task.
You also factored in the need for space
in the form of a loft.
Last time,
we learned about solid constructions.
What will you do in this case?
I'll use the roof truss
to make the loft.
They will give it stability.
Any ideas about the foundation?
I'll pour a concrete slab,
and in that, place a grid of rebars.
That improves the tensile strength
of the concrete.
Solid foundation.
Your use of words like concrete slab,
rebars and tensile strength-
-shows
that you can use proper terminology.
Are there any adjustments to be made
to make the house energy efficient?
The key is to minimize heat loss
and maximize heat gain.
For instance, the house should not
be built in a shady spot.
Does that make you re-examine
anything?
Yes. I have to move the house away
from the shade of the forest.
-Anything else?
-Yes, select the right wall insulation.
Implementing energy efficient solutions
gave you new ideas-
-which you show on your sketch.
But some work still remains
before you can make a blueprint.
All the measurements have to add up
and be according to scale.
Let's leave the example.
Technology development in school
can be divided into stages:
Defining the need, examination-
-proposals, constructing a model-
-and tests and improvements.
In the example, we first defined
the need: to build an Attefall house.
The need was then examined
with different requirements in mind-
-like building regulations, stability
and energy efficiency.
The proposal was examined
and re-examined.
New ideas
made the pupil examine new aspects.
The ideas then developed
into a sound proposal.
In the example, the pupil
communicated with a teacher-
-but the process usually needs to be
documented, so save all sketches.
A physical or digital model may be
needed to see if the proposal works.
Written documentation is needed-
-so your teacher can see what choices
and improvements you've made.
So remember to motivate your choices.
Technology development
is a reflective process-
-where you assess
and develop your proposal.
It's innovative work that will be
of use to you in several other subjects.
Subtitles: Sofia Sundqvist				www.btistudios.com