Look at the hare, rushing, hopping
and running, but getting nowhere.
But what's this? A tortoise!
Methodical, clever, focused,
taking one step at a time.
Now that's something else!
That's kind of how it is with maths.
Doing maths can be hard,
even feel hopeless at times.
When that happens, don't speed up.
Instead, take it slow.
One step at a time. It's not a race.
Don't be like the hare: rushing,
guessing and hoping for the best.
Think like the tortoise.
Be methodical. It won't be quick, but
you're not being judged on your speed.
And in the end, the tortoise gets it right.
There are a lot of strategies to use
in maths.
The most important one is perhaps
to take it slow.
Take a deep breath and examine
your result. Does it make sense?
If it's an equation, substitute x
for your answer and count again.
That way, you'll know if you're right.
That's pretty smart.
So, take it easy.
One step at a time, like the tortoise.