Oral discussions and arguments are
a natural part of many school subjects-
-and your teachers assess your skills
when they grade you.
But how do you broaden
and deepen the discussion-
-in order to reach
a well-founded argument?
Here are some great tips:
Keep a friendly tone and contribute
to a positive conversational climate-
-where everyone feels comfortable
talking and participating-
-and where everyone's opinions
are respected.
It's important to let many different
perspectives and ideas be heard.
That way
you broaden and deepen the discussion.
Be an active and engaged part
of the conversation-
-and adapt your language
to the subject at hand.
It's good to have a grasp of important
terms associated with the subject.
Try to articulate your thoughts
and make them clear.
Be matter of fact, by using
well-founded reasons and arguments.
And remember: Stick to the subject.
Don't forget that it's just as important
to listen to the others, as it is to speak.
Invite everyone into the conversation
and ask them follow-up questions-
-as a way to help develop
the conversation.
In order to broaden
and deepen the discussion-
-pay attention to everyone's views
and build on them.
If you find it scary
to talk in front of people-
-try to speak and say something
early on in class.
It might be scarier if you wait too long-
-but adding a short statement early on
can help make things easier for you.