Do you ever think, "Math is just not
for me"? You're not the only one.
But the right strategies can help anyone
get better at math. These are a few tips.
Learn the words.
Math has its own language-
-and like with any language, you have to
look up the words you don't know.
So, when you have a math test
coming up, study up on the words.
That will help you
understand the problem faster.
Ask questions.
But try to make your questions specific.
Instead of saying, "I don't get it"-
-think about what it is specifically
that you do and don't understand.
That helps you formulate the question,
for example:
"Why is there an equals sign there?"
"What does that word mean?"
"What do I have to do?"
"What are you asking here?"
Take it easy.
You're not supposed to do math quickly.
You have to think carefully, and be
thorough when you solve the problem.
Trying to solve problems quickly
by just guessing-
-will make us get stuck,
trying solution after solution.
That can make us freeze up,
panicking because we can't get it right.
Solve problems slowly and methodically.
Take your time, and really think.
Simplify, and divide up.
Maybe a problem looks
super complicated and long.
Take the time to divide the problem up
into smaller pieces, and simplify it.
A large problem may need
to be broken down into many pieces-
-to be solved individually.
Double-check.
Always double-check your answers.
Try using your answer
in the equation you just solved-
-to make sure it works both ways.
If something's not right,
you have to investigate.
Start by reading the problem again.
Did you understand it correctly?
Read it again
to ensure you didn't miss anything.
Blank page.
Write down the problem
on a blank page, and solve it again.
If you get the same answer twice, the
issue is unlikely to be an accidental slip.
Compare your answers. If you got
a different answer the second time-
-compare your solutions
and try to figure out what went wrong.
The right method. Ask yourself
if you chose the right solution method.
Maybe you could try a different way?
Symbol errors.
Make sure you didn't make a counting
mistake or used the wrong symbol.
Maybe you forgot to add a parenthesis
or subtraction symbol?
When we challenge ourselves
and learn new things-
-it helps our brains develop
and get stronger.
So don't give up.
Math\h can  be for everyone.
Good luck!