We all put things off now and again.
Sometimes because we have no choice.
But doing it when we don't have to,
knowing there will be consequences-
-is called procrastinating.
Maybe you put off studying for an exam
because you don't have the energy-
-knowing you'll have less time tomorrow-
-which means you won't be able
to study as much as you should.
We base decisions on the short-term
benefits of putting something off-
-and fail to use a long-term perspective to
see the benefit of just doing it right away.
Identify your own patterns
and any excuses you tend to use.
"I'm too tired right now." "I'd rather read
that text when I'm in the right mood."
"I work better under pressure anyway."
"I'll do it after I've..."
Get an overview.
A common reason for procrastination
is feeling overwhelmed by the task.
But it helps
to divide your work into segments.
If you're doing maths, start with a single
page in your textbook, or with ten pages.
Plan and structure your work.
Make a plan for when to study,
and when to have time off.
It's great to schedule short sessions
and allow yourself breaks.
Make sure your plan is doable.
If you plan to do too much,
you won't want to do it at all-
-and that increases the risk
that you keep procrastinating.
Learn to live with not wanting to study.
You won't always be excited
to sit down and study-
-and we're all great at finding excuses.
But you actually can study even though
you don't feel super motivated.
Five minutes.
If you notice that you keep putting off
a specific thing, try giving it five minutes.
Maybe that gets you over that first hurdle
so you can finish the task.
If not,
give it another five minutes a little later.
"Good enough."
Sometimes that's all you need.
Demanding too much of ourselves
keeps us from getting work done-
-but every single thing we do
doesn't have to perfect.
Lowering the bar can be a good thing.
Study with a friend. If you schedule
a study session with a friend-
-you're more likely to actually sit down
and study instead of procrastinating.
-Want to do that biology thing today?
-Yeah, see you at my house later.
Give yourself rewards, however small.
One reward could be getting to watch the
latest episode of your favourite series-
-once you've finished the first two pages
of your Swedish essay.
Sometimes we do need to put things off,
but try to ignore the short-term benefits-
-and use a long-term perspective:
"What's actually best for me?"