Be on Time
Oh, God! Of course they're sitting there
when I look like a mess!
Oh, my God...
I can do this. I don't need makeup
to look good. Natural beauty.
Okay. It's going well. Smile.
Not that much. I want to look tough.
I'm killing this.
Why is she walking like that?
-Oh...
-She thinks she's hot.
-Thinks she's hot. Thinks she's hot...
-Just walk like normal.
Okay. That wasn't so bad.
You work that runway.
No! I'm going to be late!
I can't be the last one in!
Ahmed will see me looking a mess!
-Hello, Freja.
-Hi, Stina.
-I really have to go. I'm in a hurry.
-You look tired. How are you doing?
-Fine.
-You had an appointment on Monday...
I have to go...
Nothing can distract me. Oh, God...
He's so hot! He's coming towards me!
He might talk to me! I look awful!
No, he can't see me like this.
How can anyone be that perfect?
My hair is so greasy!
Why won't this zit go away?
What's wrong with my eyebrow?
Oh, shit! He's checking me out!
Or maybe not...
You're the hottest girl in town.
In town? Not in the whole world?
-You don't get it.
-I don't get it?
So now I'm stupid, too? Great, thanks.
Really nice. Thanks.
Jasmin, don't leave. Let's talk...
-What's up?
-Hello.
-I'm so ugly today. It's embarrassing.
-God, I'm embarrassing myself.
My class! There's no point in going in.
Everyone will see me.
Subtitles: Sofia Anulf
www.btistudios.com