Are you behind with your schoolwork?
Are your teachers reminding you about assignments
you haven't even started?
Right, reading log 2 needs to be done
by Tuesday. Make sure to hand it in.
-What? I thought it was next Tuesday.
-No, this Tuesday.
Perhaps you meant to study yesterday, but instead
you hung out with a friend.
It's easy to put things off until later.
But the longer you wait, the harder it gets.
Here are some tips for how to catch up if you're
behind with your schoolwork.
The big picture.
Start by thinking through everything you need to do.
List your assignments to make things clear.
English is this week, right?
Write down when they're due and estimate
how long you think they'll take.
-Swedish, that was quite a lot.
-I'd say five days.
When a task is done, tick it off.
It's motivating to see that you're getting things done.
Hang in there. Is your to-do list long?
Try to visualize how you'll feel when you're done.
It might be intense right now, but try to see the bigger picture.
It might seem far away now, but you'll manage.
Prioritize.
A good way to start is to figure out
what's urgent and what can wait.
The chemistry test is important.
That's next Friday.
Yes. And the second language test
and the reading log in English.
Even if everything seems urgent, prioritize.
Decide what to do first. You can't do everything at once.
Talk to your teacher if you get stuck.
Try to hand in all assignments on time.
But if it seems impossible, talk to your teacher.
-We don't understand the assignment.
-We won't be done in time.
Perhaps, you'll get some guidance and
help with how to get started.
Start by describing Coraline...