The chronicle is a short newspaper text where you share your views.
While a debate article is factual, a chronicle must be personal.
You who write should be seen in the text with your experiences.
A chronicle wants to arouse reactions.
It is a text form that is often shared in social media.
Tips to think about with a chronicle:
It is a personal text.
Dare to show it with your own perceptions.
What do you think?
How do you interpret an event?
What did it look like?
How did it make you feel and think?
Argue for your opinion.
Think of possible counter -arguments and treated them before they occur.
Adapt the language to the reader.
Use metaphors and parables, but they should be relevant.
Dare to be fun but at the same time serious.
Take on heavy topics with humor.
It's a great way to reach.