Is the energy over?
Do you feel tired and maybe grumpy at the lessons?
Are you thinking more about going home than about what your teachers say?
Nothing strange about it!
You get tired of being in school.
After sitting on lessons that require you to be focused
You may just be longing to go home and rest.
- How far is it left?
- Now it's 25 minutes left
It can be difficult to sit still,
hard to let you talk to friends
And hard to concentrate on what you should do.
- Then we will take and finish!
But you actually don't just have lessons on the schedule
Without also breaks.
Take advantage of them!
It's easy to just sink down in front of the computer or mobile
and play or scroll away the time.
If you often sit still the whole break
Try to break that pattern!
By doing something active you will be more attractive and happier.
And then it can be more at the lessons!
- Are you going?
We'll play ping pong!
For when moving, substances are released in the brain
such as serotonin and dopamine
that counteracts depression.
And besides being happier,
can memory improve, stress decrease
And then you will sleep better!
Also think about whether you feel best about spending time with your friends
Or if you would feel good to be for yourself for a while.
- my best tip on what to do on the break it is to
Play basketball and be with friends.
So to cope more on the lessons,
Take advantage of your breaks.
Feel free to stir and go out for a while to get fresh air.
Often it is enough to just go for a short walk for more energy.
- When I just sat inside I have felt that
lessons are much boring
You get unjustified to work.
- Feels nice when you have been moving a little
so that one can concentrate more on the lesson
- I think the best thing about being active on their break is to
You can be a little more motivated for school work.
- I think the best thing about being active on the break is that you
becomes spiked on the lessons
- And you can work more because you are more attractive!