You know the feeling
when you're taking a test.
You get the test, look at it,
and you're absolutely clueless.
If you haven't studied,
you can suit yourself.
If you have studied and still don't get it,
there are strategies-
-to rid that brain fart feeling.
If you find it impossible to focus,
you can try a relaxation exercise.
Close your eyes.
Work your shoulders up and down.
Put your hand on your stomach
and breathe deeply.
Massage your fingers.
Carefully move your head
and rub your shoulders.
This will make you relax
and alleviate stress.
You start your circulation, get oxygen
to your brain and clear your mind.
Take another look at the questions.
Still nothing?
All right,
never mind the questions for now.
Write down what know
on a piece of paper.
That way you brainstorm
and think more freely.
It may help to draw pictures,
as this uses another part of your brain.
Go back to the piece of paper
once the stress is gone-
-and the answers have
a better chance of coming to you.
Don't force words you can't think of.
Write something else in the meantime.
Leave it as a placeholder
and continue with the test.
When you read through your answers,
the word might suddenly come to you.
You can also ask your teacher for help.
Ask questions. Don't just say:
"I don't get it."
Be more specific.
"What does this word mean?"
"What is the question about?"
If your teacher elaborates the question,
you may remember the answer.
If sounds cause you stress,
you can try to block them.
There might be some ear muffs
in the classroom.
Or you can bring your own earplugs.
Some tips to rid the brain fart feeling:
Relaxation exercises can
alleviate stress and help you think.
Write down all you know on a
piece of paper instead of getting stuck.
Draw pictures.
If you get stuck on a question,
write down a placeholder.
Ask your teacher for help,
perhaps to read the question aloud.
Block out stressful sounds.
Wear ear muffs or earplugs.