ASSOCIATING
In order to remember maths concepts,
I use a memory strategy.
I invent a story to remember the word.
This is useful in all subjects. I use it
in maths to remember the concepts.
I think about the word. What does it
really mean? What does it sound like?
To do this, I must do something first:
I have to close my eyes.
Pythagoras' theorem.
Pytha... Python... Yes, a python!
Pythagoras' theorem is a python.
Is that snake long or short?
How would I know?
Pythagoras. That's when you calculate
the sides... The sides of what?
Pythagoras
sort of rhymes with 'grimace'.
A cat's face when it makes a grimace!
The face looks like a triangle.
By thinking of a python
and a cat's face-
-I remember
what Pythagoras' theorem is.
Cylinder. Bike wheel.
A rotating wheel.
A hamster wheel. It's round.
Cylinder, that sounds like 'hinder'.
Sanitary pads hinder the blood flow.
I put them in an empty toilet paper
roll, which is shaped like a cylinder.
Now I won't forget it.
I put my sanitary pads in a cylinder.
Now I'll never forget
what a cylinder is!
CONE
What rhymes with 'cone'? 'Telephone'?
'Cony...'
'Conny', that's my guinea pig.
He likes a good crayfish party.
That's when you put on those silly hats.
They're shaped like cones!
My guinea pig...
I only need to think of Conny
to remember what a cone is.
That's what I do
to remember different concepts.
Everyone can make up their own stories.
There's no right or wrong.
By associating words and making up
a story, it's easier to remember.
Images are often easier
to remember than names.
Give it a try! The crazier, the better.