HOW TO STUDY MATHS
In maths, you can't fool yourself. It's
better to do a few problems thoroughly-
-and to fully understand them,
than to do many.
If you don't get it,
be honest with yourself.
Turn back a few pages to stuff
that you do get. This is important.
TURN BACK A FEW PAGES
Mathematics is a language.
Just like with any language-
-you must look up things
you don't understand.
Look it up in a book, google it,
or ask someone who knows.
THE LANGUAGE OF MATHS
Divide the problem into smaller parts.
A big problem can be divided into seve-
ral parts that you solve individually.
SUBPROBLEMS
Always verify your solutions-
-for example by putting them back
into the equation you just solved-
-to verify that it works both ways.
VERIFY THE SOLUTION