TRYING AND RETRYING
To try and retry ways to solve problems
is a part of life.
When you play games,
you try different solutions to challenges.
When you cook, you try different spices
with varying results.
And sometimes
you may turn a T-shirt into a tank top.
Learning things at school involves trying
different solutions over and over again-
-and coming up with new ones.
Getting everything right straight away
is neither possible nor particularly fun.
To assess the quality
of your school work-
-your teachers consult
the knowledge requirements.
These are part of the curriculum,
which governs what our schools teach.
The requirements
for craft, art, and technology include-
-being able to systematically
try and retry solutions.
In craft, this relates to how you can
combine materials and techniques.
When you do that, you also have to
formulate different plans of action-
-to move your work forward.
That means you constantly
have to think about new solutions.
Here, a student has been tasked with
creating some form of storage unit-
-using recyclable materials.
And the unit has to, at least in part,
be made using a braiding technique.
That sounds like a task
with loads of possible solutions.
That makes it especially important
to systematically try and retry ideas.
I could use a place to keep my chargers,
earphones, and game controllers.
I could make the box out of wood
with a lid made from recycled fabric.
And with handles made of wood, I think.
Or would another material work better?
Won't a wooden box be a bit too heavy?
Yeah. My initial thought
was a regular wooden box.
But then I started sketching a box
with thin strips forming a sort of grid.
It will be a little trickier to build, but I
think I'll end up using that one more.
That was a good question. So
the student retried the sketch early on-
-or more specifically, the material.
The first option would be quicker to build.
But the other is a better long-term choice
because the material for it weighs less.
That is exactly how to go about trying
your first idea when making something.
Examine the pros and cons
of your material.
And ask yourself how
the finished object is going to be used.
There. I'll combine the wooden box
with cotton-strap handles.
I can make the straps from my own
discarded clothes, thus recycling fabric.
Oh, cotton straps? I thought you had
wooden handles on your sketch.
I did. But I'll braid the straps
to make them stronger, look.
Besides, they're more comfortable to use
than wooden ones.
I made a model and tested it out.
You have to compare your original idea
with other solutions.
So make several sketches
of what you're making.
You can also plan to make a prototype,
which is a simplified model.
You will probably choose to combine
different materials and techniques.
Justify and explain your choices.
What are you planning for the lid?
I'm going to put fabric over a frame,
like this.
This fabric looks good, but it's too thin,
so I don't think it's going to work.
But I've got some back-up fabric,
so I can try both.
Great! Make sure you have options
before you get started.
So: Give yourself time
to try different solutions and materials.
To systematically
try and retry something-
-is all about planning
and choosing between different options.
And make sure to document
your process and your choices.
That will help you assess your work and
show that you've worked systematically.
Finally, let's review the working process.
Proper planning is important.
When do you have to complete
the different stages? And in what order?
Is there time to make a simplified model?
Which materials should you work with?
Which are best in terms of function?
Can you combine materials?
Make several sketches
and compare alternative solutions.
How should you go about it? Which
techniques are appropriate to use?
And which methods and tools
would be best?
Analyse your options
and justify your choices.
That is what "formulating and choosing
between different plans of action" means-
-in the knowledge requirement.
Finally, document your entire process
by taking pictures and making notes.
Share the reasons behind your choices.
Also share any technical or aesthetic
issues you encountered along the way.
Being able to systematically try and retry
solutions through planning and analysing-
-will serve you well in many situations.