A source is something where information comes from.
But how do you know which sources make sense and which ones are not?
There are some things you can think of.
If you search for healthcare for example ...
And comes into this page ...
How do you know that what is there is right?
Well, if we check who is behind the page ...
Okay, here it was kind of impossible to see who is behind it.
It can be advertising, politics or whatever.
Therefore, that source may not be trusted.
Because we don't know what they want.
But if we go into the care guide instead.
So we see that it is the authorities, which take care of the health care, which is behind the page.
Thus, that source can be trusted.
For healthcare wants to provide good care.
So if you can't quickly see who is behind and for what purpose -
Skip that page and move on!
In addition to being able to get help from a teacher or a parent, so can
You get it from a librarian. - Right?
- You can get that!
- Can you trust what is in books?
- When it comes to fact -based books, the books have usually gone through
An editor or other researchers reading to do a look at.
Then it is also a lot about why the author has screaming white book.
Is that to get a political message, get their views
about something or is it more for entertainment?
I can ask these!
- Hi, excuse. Do you know what a source is?
- No.
- Do you know what a source is?
- A source ... to what? To happiness or?
- Either do you mean a person who is a source of something that has happened
Or that sit on information.
Or it's that little nice water source.
The ones that answered now are primary sources.
That is, the information comes directly from the origin and
have not gone through any filter.
Besides, they are oral - thus not written down.
But if I now take a small clip out of what they say and have with
In this program. Then it becomes a secondary source.
Because I have filtered in what they say as I have removed things.
So this with sources need not be so complicated.
To know if a source is something to use, you can check who is behind.
And what do they want with the information, is it opinion or facts?
Is it an original source that you have found or is it just a reference?
It is usually a good idea to check out the basic source!
But remember that you can always take help from your teacher!
Good luck!