There are strategies that you can use
before, during and after you read texts.
Here are some strategies you can use
while you read.
First of all,
turn off everything distracting.
If it's hard to get started, or to keep
focus, follow the text with a pen-
-or place a ruler below the line.
Skim past slow bits rather than
stop reading completely.
Set a timer and read in short spells
with breaks in between.
Start with five minutes
and extend them as you go.
Another good strategy
is to divide the text in shorter sections.
Read one section carefully
and then take a break.
That way the brain can process
a smaller amount of information.
While reading,
it's important to ask yourself questions.
What did I just read? What is
most important in this paragraph?
How is it connected
to what I read before?
Formulate the text in your own words
to understand it better.
Be patient when you read. Becoming
a good reader takes practise.