Sleep yourself smarter.
Yes, you heard right.
If you get sufficient good-quality sleep-
-you can actually become smarter,
because sleep affects learning-
-and performance.
But why do we sleep?
You could say
sleep is the price for being awake.
When you're awake,
your brain is fully engaged.
It's exposed to a constant flow
of new sensations-
-whether it wants to be or not.
Sleep is the body
and brain's chance to recharge-
-and create the right conditions to face
the next day and learn new things.
Sleep is like a superpower-
-which maximizes your brain
in different ways.
1. Strengthens Memory
During sleep, the brain sorts
and processes impressions-
-and information received during the day.
Things that are important to remember-
-are moved from short-term
to long-term memory.
You can help the brain
know what's important to save-
-by repeating the info several times
during the day-
-such as when studying vocabulary.
REPEAT
When we sleep, memory is strengthened
and information is saved.
2. Your Brain is Purged
and Cleaned
Your brain is like a hard drive.
Information the brain judges unimportant
will be erased-
-so there's room for new information.
During the day,
debris builds up in the brain-
-which must be removed
for optimal brain function.
3. Emotions Are Defused
During REM sleep,
difficult feelings and impressions-
-received during the day
are processed and defused-
-which helps you handle them better
and become balanced.
This leads to better concentration-
-because you can focus better
and not be controlled by impulses.
4. Strengthens Creativity
During REM sleep,
your creativity is strengthened-
-because the brain opens up
and is allowed to associate freely.
Old memories are connected to new.
The brain sees how things are related-
-and comes up with new solutions
and ideas.
You may have heard the expression:
"Sleep on it."
But for this to work properly,
you need to get sufficient sleep.
For teenagers,
that means at least eight hours.
Sleep consists of cycles
of 90 to 120 minutes.
Each cycle
has four different stages of sleep-
-which are equally important
for your brain.
We need to sleep through a number
of sleep cycles for effective sleep.
Quality of sleep is as important
as getting enough sleep.
To make your sleep as good as possible,
so that it has all of the important stages-
-we need to follow
our natural circadian rhythm.
Man's biological clock is programmed
to sleep when it's dark-
-and be awake during the day.
Reversing the clock worsens sleep
as well as a number of bodily processes-
-which can lead to poorer health
and performance.
Tips for better sleep:
Keep it as dark and cool as possible
in the room where you sleep.
Do nothing in bed other than sleep.
The brain is highly associative-
-and this helps it
associate the bed with sleep.
Spend a lot of time in the daylight.
It affects your internal clock
and makes you sleepier at night.
Avoid using your mobile or computer
right before going to sleep.
With their blue light,
mobiles and other screens-
-trick the brain into thinking it's daytime.
Spend time in the daylight.
It can help compensate-
-and reduce the negative effect
of the blue light.
Try switching the screen to "night mode,"
so it has a more yellow, warmer light.
Sleep well!