When searching for facts and information to a task-
-Is, for example, environmental impact-
-Can it be good to know basic search techniques.
These help you get the best possible result.
Here are three tips on how to optimize your search.
When to search for a concept consisting of several words-
-Can it be good to write the words within quotation marks.
Then you limit your search to just show out results-
-which contains the words in sequence.
If you write "global warming", you will get results with the concept.
Instead you search for “global warming” without quotation mark-
-can some search engines display results where either "global"-
-or "heating" is included.
A method that can help you get a wider search-
-In some search engines are truncation.
By adding a star to the word stem-
-Do you hit all words with the same beginning as your keyword.
For example, you search for "environment*"-
-can you get search hits as "environment", "environment"--
-"Environmental issues", "environmental impact", etc.
In many search engines you can control how you want to combine your keywords-
-by using booles search.
It means you write the words:
"and", "or", or "note" between your keywords.
For example, if you are to search on-
-My environmental impact in Sweden you can write:
"Environmental impact or climate change or carbon dioxide emissions and Sweden".
In order for the search engine to know which word-
-which should be searched together with the word "or"-
-Do you turn the words into a bracket.
Then you get search hits containing "Sweden"-
-and some of the words “environmental impact”-
-"Climate change" and "carbon dioxide emissions".
Thus, to optimize your search you can use:
Drawing, truncation and booles search.
These are some tips to help you find-
-This you are looking for on the internet and can make you save time.
Swedish texture: Jenny Berglund Iyuno-Di Group for UR