Should you learn glosses using Flashcards
so would I like to tip you that you are writing
one word on one side.
How to write the translation on the other side.
It is common to use flashcards to learn gloss,
But it also works to learn, for example, the periodic system,
historical events or really anything.
- But if you are going to learn about Greek gods,
So you can write the name of the god on one side,
and a description of the god on the other side.
So you write a heading, person, year, rule
Or concept on one side of the patch.
And on the back you write what you need to know.
Such as “Artemis” on one side
And that she was the goddess of the hunting, the wild animals and the moon on the other side.
Then test yourself if you know the answers.
And check if you answered correctly by looking at the back.
- If you answer correctly, you put it in a 'can-high'
If you answered wrong, put it in a "cannot-high"
Then train on the patches that ended up in "Can't-Högen"
When all the patches end up in "Kan-Högen".
Take a break and test yourself at a later date.
- the next time you are going to plug with flashcards
Try starting with the back first, ie Facit!