Is it time for national tests and other tests?
Maybe you have a lot of plug right now and wonder how to catch up.
Here are tips on three methods that streamline your plugging.
An effective method to see what you can and cannot.
It is about starting to read a chapter or some pages.
Then put away the text and bring out a paper-
-And scribble down everything you remember.
It can be like a mindmap or short sentences.
So it doesn't have to be a finished text.
Take the book again and compare:
What did you get with and what have you missed?
This will give you a quick answer to what you need to plug more on.
The method is also good because you activate your brain-
-and have to produce what you remember.
It makes it you learned-
-Fastes better and you will have easier to remember on the sample.
Explain in simple words: to try to explain something in a simple way-
-is effective to learn something new-
-or increase understanding of something you already know.
Write down an explanation with simple words-
-As you should tell someone who can't do anything about it before.
You can even
Imagine it is a child that you have to explain to.
Go through what you missed and see if you can simplify it further.
The more knowledge you have, the easier it is to explain in simple words.
You can also orally tell someone about what you just learned.
If you can explain something in a simple way with your own words-
-Ths that you have understood and know what you tell you about.
And since you actively recount and repeat what you learned-
-Will you remember it anymore.
Answering questions about what you just read can make you remember better-
-And learn faster.
Instead of reading a text several times-
-and just try to wear in what you read you can try to interrogate yourself-
-periodically.
Start by reading a number of pages-
-And then write down questions on what you read.
Put away the text and try to answer your questions without watching.
Then check up your answers and correct.
Then it becomes clear what you remember and what you need to go back to-
-and plug more on.
The next time you plug you can start by check-
-If you remember the answers to your questions.
The advantage of plugging in this way is to strengthen the memory-
-and causes the knowledge to get stuck in a more effective manner-
-Stheft you force the brain to immediately pick up what you have learned.
Thus: quickly write down all you remember-
-Af to have read a piece.
Explain in a simple way what you learned for someone else.
Ask questions and interrogate yourself on what you read.
Good luck!