FORMING AN ARGUMENT
You form arguments in many subjects,
and you can use those skills all your life.
Think about how often you have to make
decisions and weigh up pros and cons.
To form an argument means
to develop your thoughts and opinions.
You can make a claim, like "meat
consumption harms the environment"-
-but why is that true?
On what do you base that claim?
An argument should always explain
and give depth to your thought or opinion.
To help you develop within a subject-
-teachers consult
the knowledge requirements.
These describe the different levels of
knowledge and skills a student can have.
The requirements are also used
to determine your grades.
The requirements classify arguments-
-as either simple,
developed, or well developed.
Crystal clear, right? No? All right,
I suppose we need an example.
Let's use a book recommendation
to illustrate a well-developed argument.
Why do you recommend this book?
I really like this book.
It's interesting and deals with important
issues like courage and loyalty.
It made me realise
I shouldn't be judgemental.
Hang on.
These are all thoughts you can develop.
Explain what you mean by them.
Why do you feel that way?
Offer examples. That will develop and
improve the quality of your argument.
You said the book was interesting.
Why do you think so?
Hm... The story keeps growing,
in unpredictable ways.
For example, new information
is revealed about the protagonist.
-What does that result in?
-The protagonist grows as a person.
I didn't like the person at first
but ended up sympathising with them.
Great! You developed your argument
by defining what you found interesting-
-and offered examples. You also said
the book was about courage.
Elaborate on that
by using different perspectives.
Saying "On the one hand/
on the other hand" shows-
-that you can look at things
from different angles.
On the one hand, the protagonist is
forced to make difficult decisions-
-like leaving a safe place
to move to a new city.
Making a fresh start is courageous.
On the other hand-
-the person ran away from problems
and left friends high and dry.
That's not very courageous.
It won't make the problems go away.
You mentioned not being judgemental.
Why is that important,
and what can judgement lead to?
Does the book send a message?
Having an open mind
helps me understand other people.
It may introduce me to new situations
or people I wouldn't have met otherwise.
If more people had an open mind,
the world would be nicer.
In what way?
More people would make an effort
to understand each other.
Ah! Now you told us
what the book made you reflect on-
-and you used generalisation by showing
what others may learn from the book.
The trick to forming an argument is
to stick to one thought or claim at a time.
Then develop your message by using
the words why, how, when, and what.
You can clarify your argument even more
by using examples.
Use conjunctions
to make your argument cohesive.
You form arguments
outside of school ,too.
These tricks can help you
get your point across to others-
-and be a useful tool
in developing your thoughts and ideas.
You can use those skills for other
subjects, too, and in your spare time.