Describe your feelings
about the national tests.
I'm really stressed-out
and scared that I'll make mistakes.
If I mess up the maths for example,
I might drop down, which I don't want.
You can't really study for it-
-so it's OK. But it's still stressful.
It affects your grades quite a bit.
For me it's stress first and foremost.
Then it's nerves as well.
If I'm really nervous,
I have a blackout and forget everything.
I'm more nervous about saying
something wrong or not remembering.
Often I know what to say, but then
it's like: "What was I going to say?"
That's not a great feeling.
It varies individually, students'
approach to the national tests.
Some are stressed-out, others not, and
there are those who don't care much.
One piece of advice is:
Believe in yourself! Trust yourself.
Believe that you're capable
of doing a good job.
And try to visualise the test,
the day of the test and the outcome.
That's a key component. What happens
when you get a tricky question?
How will you tackle the problem?
It's common to have a blackout,
and your thoughts go elsewhere.
Then it's good to have visualised
the situation in advance-
-so you know how to deal with it.
As well as visualising the test,
you can utilise some strategies-
-in case your brain goes blank.
Start by taking some deep breaths.
Try to lower your stress levels.
Remember that the test isn't everything.
When your stress levels have reduced,
it might be easier to think clearly.
If you struggle to find the answer
even though you actually know it-
-ask for a piece of paper and write down
everything you know about that topic.
If you still have no answer,
leave the question for now and move on.
You might think of it a little later.
Read the instructions carefully
so you don't miss anything.
Mark everything that's expected of you.
That way you'll know it's all done.
My top three strategies are: study,
eat and get a good night's sleep.
My teacher says
to take it easy and rest.
Recharge, so I can do my best.
Like sleep, so I'll have more energy,
eat well, do a bit of exercise.
Take it easy and think it through
so you don't make any mistakes.
Stressing through it isn't good.
Reading comprehension
might be an issue.
It's not only about
understanding the text.
It's also about even starting to read
and taking in all the information.
It's too much, it looks messy.
A piece of advice:
Try to change your way of thinking.
Not: "That's a lot of text!" Instead:
"Great, I get to read this now!"
"What will I learn from this?"
When we change our way of thinking,
our brain behaves differently.
And hopefully this will help.
It's hard to study
for the national tests-
-but a good way to prepare
for the linguistic parts-
-is to listen to podcasts
and read books in that language.
This makes you practise the habit
of listening and absorbing information.
Remember that the tests are long,
so prepare for that.
Check with your teacher if it's OK
to bring some food or drink.
And perhaps most importantly:
Believe in yourself and try to relax.