People say that today's youth
doesn't read enough.
But why is it so important
to read books, specifically?
To handle regular adult life, meaning
to be able to follow news broadcasts-
-follow instructions and directions,
and understand newspaper articles-
-a person needs a vocabulary
of around 50,000 words.
If a 17-year-old hasn't read
or listened to books regularly-
-their vocabulary will consist
of around 15,000-17,000 words.
But regularly reading
different types of texts-
-will stimulate and expand
your vocabulary.
That means
you can express yourself better-
-since you will have access
to more linguistic nuance.
This is really helpful in school-
-where you will often need to use
your own words to explain your thoughts.
Reading comprehension is the
foundation for every school subject.
It's obviously important in Swedish,
but it will help you in other subjects, too.
Understanding instructions and texts
is required in basically every subject.
Strong reading comprehension also
helps you review statements critically-
-and thereby avoid being manipulated.
FAKE, FACT
Reading books helps your brain stay fit.
Your brain has to work a lot harder
when you read than when you watch TV-
-and that boosts your brain capacity.
Reading also stimulates your
imagination and analytical ability.
Finally, it enhances our ability
for empathy, since it helps us-
-put ourselves in someone else's shoes
and understand how they feel.
Make sure to read
different types of books and texts.
And of course:
the more you read, the better.