Each autumn, pupils in grade 9
take the oral national test in Swedish.
The objective is
to test your oral language skills.
Your teacher wants to see how well you
can converse and reflect on the subject.
You will get to read or watch something
that you then will discuss in a group.
Here is an exercise and a few tips-
-to boost your confidence
ahead of the test.
Gather a few people-
-and pick a text for everyone
to read quietly to themselves.
For instance, a one-page short story.
Then try to write a summary
in a few sentences.
Note down any questions that you have
and write a discussion question.
When everyone has written
their summary and questions-
-start by having everyone present
their summary of the text.
Then you share your views on the text
and the questions that you had.
Finally, read the discussion questions.
Try to take turns both leading
and participating in the discussion.
Tips:
Try to actively listen
and participate in the discussion.
That makes it easier
to follow the conversation-
-ask questions and follow-up questions
and reflect on the topic.
When presenting an opinion,
it needs to be backed up.
So consider the reason
behind your opinion.
You could also use an example
when sharing your view.
If you liked the text,
what was it about it that you liked?
Was there a specific part,
a character description-
-or a specific paragraph
that you liked in particular? And why?
You could also compare the text,
or your views, to your own experiences.
Have you been in a similar situation
to the character in the text?
Try to find parallels between the text
and your everyday life-
-and ask if anyone in the group
shares your experience.
Good to bear in mind:
Listen carefully to the instructions and
participate actively in the discussion.
You might feel nervous talking in front
of others, but you're not alone.
It's the first time
for everyone in your class.
Remember to listen
and show respect for others' opinions.
And make sure to eat
and get a good night's sleep-
-so that you have enough energy
for the test.
The National Agency for Education
has mock tests on their website-
-that might be helpful to read through.
Good luck!