Feature stories share similarities with
news articles, but are more descriptive.
Describe the setting.
How does it smell, feel, and look?
Anything that lets you create
the scenario you want to describe.
Use an attention-grabbing lead
to make the reader want to read more.
Keep this in mind
when you're writing a feature story.
Choose where to focus the story.
What is the best way
to say what you want to say?
Decide on settings and interviewees
that are relevant within the context.
Make sure to quote your interviewees
as accurately as possible.
Record the interview, so you won't
have to worry about forgetting something.
Just jot down keywords to help you
navigate the interview later.
Experiment with the rhythm
in your writing.
Mix long and short sentences,
and don't repeat phrases.
That makes reading the piece
more enjoyable.