For me, it was a pretty big thing to quit at the health center.
I had worked there for a lot of years.
It was important to me now that I decided to do something else
that it was something that felt meaningful
And who felt like it was good for society.
This day is very important for those who come here.
It's a very special day.
Many are nervous and may not have been from home so much before.
The first time they are in a completely different city.
You have walked around with our nurse, life, right?
Yes.
It is important that we who work here make them relax and do their best.
And get it for an exciting day and a fun day.
Something they will remember.
It's part of the job.
And since the slightly bigger purpose, that we take the right person to the right service
In two organizations that are important to Sweden,
The Armed Forces and the Police Authority.
What is fun about working at this authority,
It is, after all, that this is an authority that is under development
And is getting bigger and bigger.
It feels fun to be part of that development.
In my former workplace, I often did not feel ready.
I always had what I call a "bad conscience high".
I don't have that here,
but when we are ready for the day we are ready for the day
And the next day it is a new day.
When I sit on my bike I feel the job runs off
and I can focus and concentrate on my second life, my private life
And my family instead.