From having been doing very old technology, we have switched the past year
If and now we are at the forefront of development.
So it's very exciting. The journey we are on.
I don't want it to sound like a cliché, but you make quite a lot of social benefits.
Especially in today's situation as it has deteriorated.
This to make social benefits,
It is evident when working at the duty of the duty.
With the duty process, most young people are around 18 years.
This means that our technology maturity must be adapted to those in society that may be
At the front of technology.
What is exciting is that we are on our way to a brand new
Reference architecture that is just micro service based.
This means we have a container platform,
Thus, a Kubernetes platform that we operate inside our walls.
Since we work with the safety that we still do, we have, among other things, Air-Gapped environments
Thus, air -grated environments.
After all, we look at brand new frameworks both in backend and in Frontend.
In addition to Frontend developers, we have also started using UX designers,
To find both new work methods and new ways of presenting information
To meet the needs of our young people.
So it will be a lot more
modern interface from the Java Swing components that look like they come from
The 90's that they now do to something you recognize as any modern application.
This creates completely different forms of work, which has made us share teams
which has skills from all these areas.
We work according to Devsecops, that is, we have system development,
We have techniques but also skills from the security area to cover all of these
The parts of our development chain.
The Purchasing and Trials Agency has a good personnel policy there
We actually strive to get a balance between working life and private life.
We have paid training here which is very much appreciated by many of our colleagues
But since we also work team -based, it gets much better for
Individuals if you can actually collaborate with and solve the task.
You are not exposed in the same way, I feel as you may be if you work individually.
Above all, the very nice atmosphere and it is all over the authority.
There is not a person here who does not greet when I meet them in the corridor.
There is not a day that I do not think it is fun to cycle to work.
Otherwise, it is our fantastic wellness hours we have every week, and long holidays.
As soon as you tell you where you work
Then people become curious. What, do you work there? Is it the defense?
Is it security rated? This workplace it is surrounded by someone
I don't want to say mystery, but it's something special.