Hi, Philip here again!
Today I will talk to Emelia Lindh who works as a preparer at Nektab -
- And she has completed the same education as me.
Come along!
Hi Emelia!
Can't you tell us a little bit about what you are working on?
Well, I work on projects within Electric power, where I plan - project -
- And I do everything, so when I'm done they should be able to start digging the day after.
What they dig down is the mains, they change the air line. - -
- Then I will prepare everything needed for them to do so.
What does your usual work environment look like?
It is very varied, it is everything from being out in the field to looking at how to dig -
- To sit in the office and draw in map programs and such.
Why did you choose to plug in engineering in sustainable energy?
I am environmentally interested, but at the same time wanted to read to an engineer -
- And this program combines it. So then I felt it was just right.
How nice!
If you were to choose something that was the best thing about study time in Halmstad, what would it be?
It is that, before some steps I felt "how should I do this?" - -
- So that I stood there and had managed everything.
So it felt very developing and strengthening.
I recognize that.
How was the class? And with the focus on sustainable energy? Did it all in the class?
Yes, I think so, it could be interesting discussions even between the lessons.
Which I appreciate it, also with the teachers, which was fun.
Yes they also feel like -minded.
Why do you think you should read this education that you and I have read?
I think it is right in time and more education is needed in this.
A change to the climate goals is required and at the same time -
- So you can work in most things in the energy industry if you become an attractive worker.
Yeah what good!
Thanks so much!