Meet ying fu, professor of applied electromagnetism
Hello! My name is ying fu and am professor of applied electromagnetism
at the Academy of Information Technology.
What is your research about?
For the most part, at least 50 percent, I research and work with technological development
in quantum technology and communication technology.
Quantum technology is advanced in the sense that
We try to work with photonic technology to pick up signals.
The simplest examples are today's infrared cameras that we can use for
to measure body temperature. Instead of using regular thermometers at close proximity on patients,
Can we now meet remotely, like a fairly quick screening.
So this is mainly quantum technology, advanced photo detectors.
Another part is communication. We need fast communication,
For example, out in the field. Then you do not carry a large machine or drive big cars.
In most cases, we talk about distant areas, such as health care systems in remote locations.
So part of this with distant areas is, of course, that the people live there.
Not all people live in big cities. So we have to give all people proper care.
The second question is in the big cities. You get sick and you go to the hospital.
But there are many patients around the cities and in the hospitals so you get a health -related infection.
So that's today's problem with viruses. You are already ill, and then you are exposed to extra viruses and
Then there is a great risk that you will be worse. So don't go to the hospital.
We try to provide a type of diagnostic small unit with quick communication.
We try to find solutions for the smart city and the smart home. We live healthy and we live longer.
What is your most important role as a professor?
An important task is to disseminate information. The real information about
education, for example, knowledge, that we are researching and received money
From society so we try to give the community back the right information and education.
This dissemination of knowledge is very critical. At the academy I am happy to coach
The junior researchers and colleagues, doctoral students.
And in the teaching of the young, for the labor market of the future,
So we look at the opportunities for what future jobs will look like with today's technology.
We are moving towards a new society with a lot of new technology. We need to adapt
us with the right knowledge so that children and young people
After education can get a good job and a good life.
We have this role, an obligation to society, to provide information.
What are you doing in your research?
Most often, my research activities are about collaborations with companies.
A biomedical sensor with AstraZeneca. They develop new technology for drugs such as
inhalations against asthma. So they must be able to determine the effectiveness of these drugs.
I try to develop some technical meters that can
determine the effect of these drugs.
Many fun gadgets! Early we built a small portable machine
for the Swedish Road Administration to assess roads in the spring.
In the winter we have a lot of snow, and we spread a lot of salt to melt the snow.
But it is corrosive material, not good for the bridges.
So the machine is testing bronze
Lifetime and corrosion to see how long it can survive, another 50 years.
So these small machines are needed everywhere. We see the results quite clearly.
And I try to develop many small units to
Products at some companies.
Why the area applied electromagnetism?
Partly it is about an interest. Another part is about the development needed
of society. So this is the challenge for sustainable social development.
We live in a world with great challenges.
We have the energy issue, we have the health care issue.
We also live longer so we have an aging population that places demands on society.
And then I've talked about this with my interest. I like technology, so from the beginning
When I was little and later at university
Have I always liked to play with these electronic things, photonic things, photos, cameras.
So photograph a great deal, such as the moon
on the night. I can do it with my mobile phone. So I play at home around the clock.
But then I get paid to play with these things that I love. It is the best!