RDA (Resource Description & Access) It is the international standard
We use resources in Libris when describing.
And the content of this presentation:
It will be a review. But not the rules in detail, but an overview of how the content of the RDA is structured.
And about the conceptual models behind it.
There will also be something about RDA and Libris.
Where to find libris practice for RDA
And where to find instructions for cataloging.
RDA nationally and internationally
From autumn 2017 there is a national RDA committee with representatives from research,
Special and public libraries around the country.
KB is a member of the European Cooperation Group Eurig,
European RDA Interest Group, which meets once a year to exchange experiences.
Eurig is represented in RSC, the RDA Steering Committee, which is the main organ of RDA.
There is a beta version with a new version of RDA.
It will start to be used no earlier than 2021 internationally.
But KB is awaiting the new version of RDA until further notice.
RDA will be used in primary catalogization in Libris.
Descriptions in Libris may be made according to different cataloging rules:
Before RDA, KRS (cataloging rules were followed for Swedish libraries).
Imported items may be made according to RDA, AACR2 or national cataloging rules.
The main rule is that descriptions in Libris that follow other cataloging rules other than RDA
not to be redone according to RDA.
The RDA is developed by the RSC (RDA Steering Committee) consisting of representatives from different countries.
The goal is for all continents to be represented and it is a work that is ongoing.
RDA was completed in 2010 and then replaced AACR2 on which our previous cataloging rules, KRS, are based on.
The Library of Congress was the first to switch to RDA. They went over 2013.
KB switched to RDA in 2017.
RDA is gathered in the online service RDA Toolkit.
Swedish, publicly funded libraries have access to RDA Toolkit through a subscription that KB has.
Via the link: https://www.kb.se/rdakatalgization/rda-litaction/rda--toolkit
If you get information on how to access RDA Toolkit.
RDA contains data elements, guidelines and instructions to create well -formulated metadata.
RDA is based on internationally recognized models, especially IFLA's models:
FRBR (Functional Requirements for Bibliographic Records)
Frad (Functional Requirements for Authority Data)
and frozen (Functional Requirements for Subject Authority Data)
RDA follows principles for linked data.
RDA's elements and vocabulary as linked data in RDF can be found in a service called RDA Registry.
Element. To each entity a number of elements are attached.
Example: Main title, publishing site, type of carrying, medium type are elements that are linked to the manifestation.
And further examples: Gösta Berling's saga - it is the main title of a manifestation.
Kalmar - It may be the place of release for a manifestation
Elements in RDA are the same as properties in Libris.
By having basic knowledge of the FR models, one also gains a better understanding of how RDA
Is structured and it becomes easier to navigate in Toolkit.
KB's RDA instructions also follow the structure of RDA Toolkit.
RDA is divided into ten sections.
Sections 1-4 include the elements, as well as instructions for the elements, used to describe the entities:
1: Manifestations and copies
2: works and expressions
3: families, persons, institutions
4: Subjects, objects, events, locations
Places are the only chapter in section 4 that contains information.
It was thought that the other chapters would be added after the release of RDA Toolkit, but it never happened.
Now that you have launched the beta version of the new RDA Toolkit, there is only space left of the entities in section 4.
Section 5-10 gives you guidelines on how to describe relationships between the entities.
A number of appendix that contains rules for upper and lower case, for example,
Abbreviations and symbols are also available.
There are also appendix with different types of relationship designations to indicate more
specific relationships between the units.
Appendix I-M (Relationships)
Relationships between a resource and agents linked to the resource. It is available in appendix I.
When you talk about resource, you mean the work, the expression, manifestation and copy
When you say agent you mean person, family and institution.
Relationships between works, expressions, manifestations and copies can be found in Appendix J.
For example, a work can be based on another work.
Relationships between agents can be found in Appendix K.
For example, a person may be a member of a family or be employed by an institution.
Relationships between concepts, objects, events and locations - Appendix L.
Unfortunately, there is no content there because these entities never developed in the RDA.
And subject relationships can be found in Appendix M. e.g. A work may be the subject of another work.
Appendix I-M (Relationships)
Libris practice is not to use the relationship designations in the Appendix I-M in RDA.
The features we use for agents in the new Libris are based on the function codes in Marc21.
These largely overlap in the appendix in the RDA.
It is possible to specify more specific relationships between e.g. Works in Libris.
Description methods
The new RDA talks about four description methods.
Please note that the description methods are about how to specify the value for a particular element.
They should not be mixed with description levels, which we will talk about later.
But the description levels are also available in the current RDA but there they are not as clearly pronounced.
The four description methods are: unstructured description, structured description,
Identifier and uri.
Unstructured description
Yes, there may be remarks, quotes from different sources and information transferred from the manifestation.
"Mechanical" transfer, ie That you write what stands.
They are manipulated according to certain rules that apply to punctuation, upper and lower case, etc.
And unstructured description cannot be understood by machines.
Structured description
We have an example under publishing details:
"Take what you see" applies to each individual element, ie. Follow the formulation of the resource, but
Enter the elements in a particular order.
Example: Stockholm: Bonniers, 2019
Structured description can partly be understood by machines.
The information is retrieved from the manifestation and you enter them as they look in the manifestation,
But you specify each task in specific elements, in a certain order.
There is an element for publishing site, one for publishers and one for publishing year.
Identifiers
Locally unique and assigned by an organization, so -called. default number.
For example. Issn, ISBN and EAN.
Also publishing number, such as Disc mark and number are counted as identifier.
Identifiers can partly be understood by machines.
URI (Uniform Resource Identifier)
They are globally unique and they can be understood by machines.
Description levels
In KRS, which we used before the RDA, we talked about three description levels.
They indicated which elements must be stated at each level of description.
In Libris, the description levels remain.
In RDA there are really no description levels. Instead, talking about nuclear elements
Or core elements as it is called in English.
The picture shows the element title (manifestation) in RDA Toolkit. Title has several sub -elements.
The main title is a nuclear element. All other titles are optional, e.g. Other title information, variant titles.
Nuclear elements - what does RDA say?
Well, a description of an entity should contain all nuclear elements that are applicable and easily accessible.
It should also contain all other elements necessary to distinguish
the entity from other similar entities.
Think about the user's needs and use the catalog's judgment.
Not least important.
Libris practice
In addition to the nuclear elements in RDA, the cataloging instance can define
Additional elements that are mandatory to indicate.
KB has defined a number of elements compulsory in Libris. Who they are found in libris practice.
Librispraxis is found in RDA Toolkit, such as KBSP, and in instructions for cataloging (RDA).
Librispraxis in RDA Toolkit
When clicking the KBSP button, in yellow and blue, in RDA Toolkit,
KBSP thus stands for the Royal Library Swedish Practice,
So you get into the document that contains libris practice, and SMDB practice, for RDA.
Librispraxis in instructions for cataloging (RDA)
Yes, here is also libris practice in the RDA instructions at https://www.kb.se/rdakatalogization
The description levels in Libris
Minimum level = nuclear elements in RDA
Library level = nuclear elements + the elements stated as mandatory in Libris.
National bibliographic level = nuclear elements + the elements stated as mandatory in librispraxis +
a few more elements specified by the national bibliography.
NB practice can be found in the RDA instructions.
Important aids in cataloging
RDA Toolkit is at the address https://ecess.RdoDoolkit.org
Contains the RDA instructions and all RDA's entities
And the elements for the entities and KBSP which are libris practice.
Libris practice talks about which elements are mandatory and briefly how we apply RDA's rules in Libris.
Instructions for cataloging (RDA)
Available at https://www.kb.se/rdakatalgization
Contains more extensive instructions with examples (in Marc)
For the most common elements and rules in RDA including authority work
Here is also stated which elements are nuclear elements and which elements are mandatory
according to libris practice. There are also workflows for a number of material types.
Another tool for cataloging is help texts in the cataloging tool.
which is at the address https://libris.kb.se/katalization/help
and they contain, among other things. instructions on how to insert and add properties to the cataloging tool
As well as workflows for a number of materials.
Work is underway with new cataloging instructions adapted to Libris.
Yes, that was all.