As much as every third species of wild bees are threatened in Sweden.
It looks about as bad for many other pollinating insects.
So what can you do? Well, you can grow plants that they like-
-and that we'll talk about here from the botanical garden-
-To together with Lina Herbertsson, who is pollination scientist-
-And Julia Borg, who is the curator of the Botanical Garden.
-Welcome. -Thanks so much.
And welcome to you who listen. There have been several questions in advance-
-while we'll do our best to answer-
-And it is also possible to ask questions during the broadcast.
We hope to catch up with as many as possible, but we start with those who have come in-
-But first of all, we will sort out one and the other about pollinators.
After all, not everyone is threatened the same way, right?
No, that's right. The honey bee is what we talk mostly —-
-And that is often allowed to symbolize endangered species when there are different reports.
The honey bee is not a threatened species, but it is much like livestock.
In Sweden they live above all in the hive
-Where we have them to harvest honey.
There are also dark soil moods, which have increased very much-
-In Sweden over the past 100 years.
Okay, so there are many like ...
In the past, many reports came that it was Tambin that disappeared-
-But that's not true?
What happened was not that Tambina disappeared-
-Os whole communities could collapse-
-And it was mainly in the United States that it happened.
This is partly due to the use of neonicotinoids-
-while is a pesticide that has been used very-
-But that is being phased out.
In the EU, most of the substances have disappeared.
Okay, so even in the US, the situation is starting to be under control?
Yes, and if we talk about diversity then you should remember to mention-
-The honey bee is not naturally occurring in the USA-
-Why it has brought the Europeans brought with it, and it could have-
-A quite serious negative impact on wild pollinators there.
If you think about which plants to choose.
How to think if you want to benefit those who are threatened?
You can start, then you can fill in.
I think above all that one should look at what is found-
-For if you think of those who are threatened, you want the wild diversity.
The threatened species have been here for a long time-
-And is often dependent on plants found here naturally.
If you work in your own garden then maybe you don't want to do if it-
-To a meadow or natural pasture land.
You rarely have cows in your garden.
You may not want to do the whole, but what you can do-
-Is that if one mow the lawn a little more rarely-
-So often brown and white clover.
They start blooming already after one or two weeks-
-and then you can see that there will be a lot of bumblebees and other small creeps-
-and eat from them.
So you can put away the lawnmower to late summer?
If you want a lawn, then you can look to-
-That this is allowed to bloom in it.
The lawn does not have to be this short.
Then you can try to build a meadow-like place in the garden-
-and then you should not cut it on the whole season-
-What you mow it at the end of summer or at the beginning of autumn-
-And remove the grass when cut.
There will be two different types of habitation then, the wild-flowering, nitrogen-rich lawn-
-And then the meadow land that you have to work a little more with?
Yes.
There maybe you can have some red clover.
It is a little too high to have in the lawn-
-But it is liked by many.
In both cases, domestic plants apply.
Julia, how do you know if a plant is domestic?
It is a great question, because it is not so easy to know.
A good thing you need is a really good flora-
-When Lina has included here.
In a good flora so you can look up a plant-
-And you can read whether it is a resident or not.
For example, if it says it is distorted or naturalized-
-To you know that it is very likely to have escaped from our gardeners
-or otherwise lost in nature.
Then it is not a resident, and sometimes it stands from which land-
-or part of the world it comes from, so a flora is completely indispensable.
If one does not have a flora, or are out and do not bring it-
-But you have the mobile phone with you, there is a great website-
-which is called Swedish cultural plant database.
It is only called a shade.
There one can search, and enter the plant name-
-and so you get information, and there also stands-
-If it is a resident in Sweden.
It is as Lina said that the domestic plants-
-Haves developed for thousands of years with all other living around us-
-So they have a completely different context.
Then there are many garden plants that can cause nectar and pollen-
-But in order for the insects to be able to fulfill their entire life cycler-
-So the domestic plants that are important for, for example, larvae.
You know that more.
By getting that kind of diversity, you make a great effort.
Can you see the difference between garden plants and domestic plants?
There are those who are so refined.
Yes, if you look at ...
For example, if you look at this peony-
-The has double petals, and there are many petals.
It is a typical sign that it is refined-
-and it does not have insects so much pleasure.
Often it is the stamens who have been converted to petals-
-For purely genetically, it's not a big step-
-To go from stamens to petals.
It is the same with roses and other plants with double petals.
Then you know that it is refined.
Then there are also processed domestic species-
-But you want to help the insects, you should not plant more of them.
Now I get a bad conscience, because I have lots.
You should not have that, and it is an important thing to think about-
-That you have them do not destroy the insects.
What destroys the insects is if you do not have the others.
We should not remove what we have because we think it is nice.
I personally think that the very finest is like this here-
-But I'm a little colored by my interest.
If you like this, you can have it-
-And you should also make sure there are some bluebells-
-As is also very nice.
The bluebell was voted to Sweden's national flower last year-
-And I think most people think that bluebells are very nice.
It can try to have it, and even give room for the other-
-For example in the lawn or in a part of the garden where you do not go.
You can try to work with both and, for the garden is a place for recreation-
-Where you want to enjoy being.
One can have both parts, but one can try to be cared for
-For invasive plants.
They do no harm in the garden, but if they come out from the garden-
-The there are many who can put it out there.
We will return to it, and there have come some questions-
-But first a question with two different variants.
It is, if we back down, to Tambin versus wild bees.
Can you say they compete with each other-
-Or do they strengthen biodiversity?
We may be able to see some beekeepers that withered.
How to think there?
I think it is important that you distinguish between different things you want to do.
The one ... now it sounds, should we take a break while we wait for it?
Now I don't have to try to overwhelm it.
It is important to distinguish between different goals.
One goal is that we want to preserve the diversity of plants.
Then there is another goal that is the diversity of wild bees.
In these two goals, I would say that honey bina-
-has probably no positive impact, but rather there is a risk-
-That they have a negative impact.
Honeybees can pollinate wild plants-
-But those who risk being without pollinators-
-Not those pollinated by honey bees.
Since the honey bee is common, it is not a problem.
However, the honey bee can contribute pollination-
-For example, fruit trees, bushes and other things you want in your garden.
You can get honey if you are a beekeeper.
There are many reasons to be beekeepers and have honeybin-
-But one should be aware that there is a risk-
-That they compete out the wild bees.
We have seen when we have looked at hops in flowering agricultural landscap-
-and more flowering agricultural landscapes, so it has become significantly fewer-
-wilded bumblebees in the places where one has put out honeybin-
-If it's flower.
But we don't really know where the limit goes-
-or what determines when competition arises.
You should also know that competition is not something new that came with honey bees
-Or competition is a naturally occurring phenomenon in ecology.
That there is competition is not necessarily negative-
-But when the competition makes them push away ...
There is a risk, and a little more knowledge is needed-
-To you possibly set a goal in how many cups to exist-
-or a roof ...
We don't know exactly where the limit goes-
-But one should be aware that there may be 100,000 bees in a cup-
-And then you can understand that there is a risk that the flowers will end.
Make sure there are not too many cups, and plenty of flowers-
-So I don't think honey bees are a big problem.
We have a specific question here, someone is wondering about Kärringstand.
A small yellow flower is that?
Is it good for diversity, wild bees and other pollinating insects?
Yes it is. It is a plant that many different insects think-
-and especially butterflies.
I think Kärringstand is worthy of the most butterfly species in Sweden.
It is absolutely good, so you like it then it is top-
-Plant it in the garden.
I'll probably do that too.
It is also great for many bumblebees.
There is someone who wonders if suggestions for appropriate hedge-
-What can benefit pollinators.
There are many different plants-
-So it depends a little on how high hedges you want to have-
-And whether or not to choose a domestic species.
If you think of the domestic plants, which benefit the Swedish diversity-
-So you can think of, for example, mulberry or oxel-
-What both bloom.
Hawthorn is a beautiful hedge if you can live with all the tags.
-So for small birds, I think? -Yes, it gives berries too.
You can also imagine, if you don't need a very high hedge-
-Oland token, which has yellow flowers and blooms all summer.
-You can also have it as a hedge. -There were several good examples.
Someone wants tips on how to benefit both the pollinators and the kitchen-
-So kitchen plants, we suppose they mean.
In order to have pollinators in their garden one must benefit them-
-and that in turn benefits most of the crops that we grow-
-for the vast majority of vegetables, fruits and berries-
-As insect pollinators.
For example, if you grow blueberries, you need to bumblebee-
-And growing pumpkin, you would like to have bees.
For the strawberries, which bloom and ripen now-
-Is solitary bees completely indispensable.
I think of all herbs, which are often wreath-flowered-
-For example, oregano or royal mint which is the domestic.
Thyme is also great.
Mints and chives.
All this is, as you say, insect pollinated.
Then you can, if you are interested and want to dig a little deeper-
-and want to grow new plants that one has not had before-
-So there is very good literature about wild edible plants ...
... if you want to experiment. -You can search for that word?
Yes, you can do that, and there are different books.
It has become a bit hot, that you should use more ...
Frame onions is one of the more common wild plants that have come in the cry.
-Whots are very beautiful. -Yes indeed.
All efforts that one makes to benefit pollinating insects in the garden-
-Has also an opportunity to benefit the kitchen.
We have built a small sand bed just below the apple tree.
-What do you mean by sand bed? -We have excavated the lawn ...
... and filled it with sand, and planted sandy plants there.
We did this two years ago, and this year is the first year-
-Then I've seen there are bees there.
-So they live there? -Yes exactly.
The vast majority of solitaires ...
You often make a bi -hotel with questionable importance to the bees.
Above all, it is uncertain whether the threatened species-
-Should want to live in bamboo.
You can often get ordinary species to live there, and it can be ball-
-And good for pollination in the garden.
For example, red walls that pollinate strawberries.
But the vast majority live in the ground-
-And then they would like to have lightly excavated and sandy soil.
So we have dug out, it should be sandy and sunny-
-And so we put some sandneys and other nice ones that bloom there.
Of course, we hope that they will pollinate our apple trees.
-Have have you seen that they have moved in? -Yes, this year I have seen that they moved in.
-Is it hole in the sand? -No, you have to sit there and watch.
That's what is so amazing with wild bin-
-for when you do these measures, you start to look for them-
-And you see that they might be there from the beginning.
They do not buzz as much as bumblebees.
Bumblebees are wild in most cases, but they are very much noticeable-
-And honey bees are not wild either, but they also buzz a lot.
Many of the solitary bees are quite small and anonymous-
-So you have to wait for them to come, and keep your eyes open.
An ignorant person I might have thought that there were flower flies.
-They are a bit similar. -I probably don't think so.
They move in a different way, and are a little more like this ...
-You have to put you and watch. -It was a good tip, to dig out a bit.
So wide and depth?
We dug so deeply, and so deep in another part.
-50/50 soil and sand? -Yes, a little mixed.
Most often it is about as much variation as possible-
-So it will be good for as many people as possible.
Exactly, I think that is an important point-
-That it should look different.
One often has a lawn throughout the garden-
-And some bushes planted around.
You need more variety, and let it be a little more wild-grown-
-Th then comes a great variety of both plants and animals.
Many people want tips on plants, and you can refer to the flora.
At the same time, it is good for some.
We have mentioned bluebell and girlfriend, but you also have some.
Is there something that you can show-
-which could also be appropriate to have in the garden, and that benefits diversity?
Yes, what should we start with?
We can start with goat-zeal-
-As you can definitely have in the discount.
It is closely related to Kärring tooth, and is appreciated by many pollinators.
-In all cases those who have a little longer heavy. -Who have longer tongue?
We can look here. Now I take from Botaniskan's property ...
Here you see that the flower is quite deep-
-So you have to have a long tongue to reach all the way down here.
-What animals have long tongue? Or animals ... -Yes, they are animals. Bumblebees.
There are long -heavy bumblebees.
The most long -heavy bumblebee we have in Skåne is the garden bump.
I got some brain drops there.
There are also short-heavy bumblebees, who like to bite holes here-
-In deep flowers, and then they drink nectar down here.
They are nectar thieves, which do not pollinate the flower?
No, but they don't do any harm-
-So you don't have to be sorry if it happens-
-Out only fascinated over nature's wonders.
Butterflies also have long tongues, so they like deep flowers.
Should we take an example of one that does not have such deep flower?
Blood root.
It has a lot of pollen.
It gives pollen to the insects that collect it.
After all, pollen gives protein to the insects.
-You can have as a ground cover. -It's the best thing in the diet circle for them?
The nectar and the quick sugar ...
It is needed both.
If they had only invested in protein, they would not have been able to fly.
We know that a lot of energy is needed to leave the earth.
It is just like the aircraft using a lot of resources-
-And it also makes insects when they fly around.
They must have a lot of sugar to fill that need.
Not many of the insects of the insects need pollen?
Well, pollen is important as they grow.
They need protein as they grow, especially the bees' larvae-
-Rechaver a lot of protein.
Everyone needs protein, but just pollen ...
Many springs feed their larvae with other larvae-
-or spiders, or anything else containing a lot of protein.
But bees larvae only eat pollen.
-What was this name now? -Blood root.
I think we can mention Gullviva. It is not with, because it has bloomed over-
-But it is a fantastic plant in many ways-
-And it is very beautiful and appreciated in gardens.
It may be a good thing to think about, to have flowering all season-
-And then Gullviva is one of the previous ones.
So you don't have all the flowering in the middle of summer, but ...
I have grown from seeds, it is great.
Here is another plant that is easy for many insects to land on.
It is completely open, unlike the goat-zeal-
-Where they have to dive down, so they can land on this one.
I don't know how appreciated it is of bees and bumblebees.
I know it can be used, but I've seen it used few times.
I think i've seen bumblebees use dog breeding as many times-
-and dog switching is a grass.
I would not say that it is giant poppis-
-But it has a value.
Then one should not forget to think of the diversity-
-for there are many species that do not pollinate-
-But that is still going to be, and is part of the natural diversity.
There are still many species that are linked to the particular parsonage.
We may have forgotten to say that this is a parsonage.
It is important for diversity-
-An if it is not the bees and the favorite of the bumblebees.
But it is definitely a good plant.
We can take one more, then we move on to more questions.
-Do we take it, or it? -You can choose that.
We take it, and we will take the other later.
-What is this one for something? -It's summer fiber.
It looks a little weed-like, and resembles dandelion
-When you just see the leaves, but then get these nice flowers.
It is also a plant that many different insects appreciate.
Here is even a small beetle-
-and something else green, which I don't know what it is.
Fibles are generally something that many insects enjoy.
Gray-fibble is one that one often gets up in lawn-
-and they like when it's short cut.
Then you can't cut too often, because then you cut the flowers.
I think it should be nutrient-poor, and rather short-cut-
-So they can still bloom.
It looks like a smoother variant of dandelions.
The gray fibers are so low, and I think they are very fine-
-and they really don't see ...
Should you stop fertilizing your lawn?
I'm not sure they require it to be nutrient-
-But the places where I know they are growing, it is relatively nutritious.
I know there are other fiblies coming pretty early-
-What can handle nutritious lawn if you just let it grow.
There are many species of fibers, and they probably have slightly different needs.
So if you see these, you can leave them.
Here comes another question from a person who has-
-A sunny raised corner dominated by lupin-
-Akleja and evergreen.
It borders on a nature reserve, and the person wants to remove the lupines.
What should she do with this bit of garden?
Could it be better for the bees than it is today?
Yes, of course it can be better.
Many different plants are always good, which we have been in.
-Do you have anything special? -Start digging the lupines.
It's not as difficult as many people think.
I dug them away with my mother, and it required an effort a year-
-I came back a month later, and a year later-
-The I did a follow -up of it, and now I don't think there are lupines.
I think it's worth acting before they have been able to spread-
-And it is so close to a nature reserve then it really is a position to remove them-
-For the invasive plants are not a problem in gardens.
The problem is when they spread to nature-
-And no one takes care of it, and they destroy.
Lupines I had definitely taken away
-Th then I would probably have removed the winter green too-
-For they are also problematic.
It is difficult for other plants to get up as long as they are left.
-Winter green and lupines. -Yes, and they are at risk ...
Now we have not talked about it, but a risk classification has been made
-As introduced species in Sweden, and the winter green is one of de-
-while is problematic.
It is a paradox, for garden enthusiasts want to ha-
-fine ground cover that can handle in all mod-
-And then you realize that they might be a little too good.
This brown herb also manages in most situations.
White clover too.
I agree, it can be problematic in some cases.
The difference between brown and winter green-
-Is that the winter green is there all year.
I had tried to get rid of the two, and then the question is ...
Aklejan is not domestic, but it is very fine-
-And it's pretty tough and durable, so it may be worth having a little left.
The question is whether it is possible to do any meadow vegetation there-
-Th then it could have been valuable to try with-
-But if there is a lot of lupine then they have probably been able to fertilize the ground there-
-And then maybe it's easier to ... -They take nitrogen from the air.
-It's what is problematic with them. -Exactly.
So you might think about turning it into a king's coin.
We have that at home, there is no room for much else-
-But it is nice when it blooms and it is very butterfly-
-humlehans, a lot of different small creeps-
-And bonnet and other things that I think are nice.
Is organic farming better for pollinators?
There is one who has told us about a cultivation landscape that the person has.
I don't read the whole question, but can you see any difference there-
-If you use toxins or not?
It's not just the poisons.
-The control can damage insects. -Is if they are allowed?
Yes, there are pesticides designed to kill insect-
-And then they often kill pollinating insects.
But it is not only the problem, but it is also that we use-
-The pesticides that remove the flowering weeds.
Since we have access to artificial fertilizers, we do not need to grow so much clover-
Otherwise clover can fix nitrogen from the air-
-To to enrich the ground with nitrogen-
-So that you can grow there, and get better harvester-
-and then they have a particularly important meaning-
-When you can't use artificial fertilizers.
If you grow more pea plants and clover they are more food for the pollinators.
So did you want to see more of that even in conventional agriculture?
Yes, and one must not necessarily grow organic-
-To it will be good for the insects, but to use more of pea plant-
-while, bloom.
Sometimes you grow clover, but cut it before it can flower-
-And then Klövern has a fairly limited value for the pollinators.
-So clover is one of several pea plants? -Yes exactly.
Can you get municipal gardeners-
-To invest more in plants for endangered pollinators?
That thing with threatened pollinators can be a bit tricky-
-For most often they depend on plants found only in a certain environmental-
-And it is not certain that that environment is in the city.
I believe that one should think more generally in favoring the diversity-
-and think a little wider.
In this way one can do a lot to benefit pollinating insect-
-And other insects and spiders.
But how to ...
It is about both knowledge and tradition-
-When we need to change in some way.
I think it is happening.
I don't know if it is Dave Goulson, who is a scientist ...
He has written some books that have become very popular-
-which is about bumblebees and the like, so I think he has sown a seed
-And the Swedish Society for Nature Conservation has run a campaign for the bees.
There are many who are in the process of, and I think many such things-
-Have made there an increased interest and consciousness-
-and I feel that people more often hear from themselves-
-And says they want to make an effort.
It may be some garden engineer or landscape architect-
-whow want some more meat on the legs and do something that is good and right-
-If you want to benefit biodiversity.
I also have a feeling that there are more and more people who interest sig-
-And you want more than just the nectar -rich plants.
You want to take it a step further, and think ...
As we have been in, if you think it is for the aesthetic-
-The I imagine that the preferences change.
-It's a little interesting in itself. -Exactly.
There are several who wonder about this with sand bed.
We showed with hands, but how deep it should be-
-If you intend to build one?
They dig much so deep.
-Unchy three inches? -Yes.
It should be so deeply, but everything doesn't have to be sand-
-What should be the Locker land, which is easily excavated but at the same time stable.
It must not be like on a sandy beach, where the sand is completely loose.
There they cannot dig and build nests, but they should be able to dig walking-
-As still well, it consists quite well.
You may not even have to dig.
We were digging because we wanted to get rid of cherries that grew there before-
-To we would rather have a ...
-You have cherries there? -Yes, exactly, should we talk about it later?
You can talk a little about it now.
We did not want to get out of all the cherries from the garden-
-For even though it is an introduced plant, it has been here for a very long time.
Not long enough for insects to evolve with it-
-But there are many solitar bees who like it-
-And it is very beautiful when it gets flower.
We fight against it in some places, and in other places it gets flower.
You can make nice bouquets of cherries instead of bridal veil.
I think you can think about that, especially if you have ...
Now you had picked this beautiful but quite useless-
-Ur biological diversity point of view.
They can become a very nice bouquet together-
-and I think you can open up for the opportunity-
-No let some weeds be left.
You can have them for different things, and you can eat this too.
-In the beginning is it best then? -Yes, but if you pick it all season ...
... then it continues to get new, nice and dilute leaves.
You mentioned Sandnejlika, can you give more examples of sandy plants?
Thyme.
-What is there more for some ... -Sand lily.
I would say this, it's a very good book if you want to ...
The Flora of the Nordic countries, can you search for sandy plants there?
Otherwise, there will be a lot to read.
You can find those who start on the "sand" in the register.
-Many starts on "sand". -It's a good tip.
Then you get ...
Is there any other place where one can find-
-specific sandy plants?
You might be able to think about stone party plants.
-Can you do it? -Perhaps.
But then you get into a lot that is not domestic.
You may have to be so interested that you sit and browse a little ...
You have mentioned a few, so there is something to start with.
You have been into the fact that the distribution between processed and domestic plants-
-Not have to be 100 % domestic in order for it to be any point-
-Why it's just that you have the domestic too.
Are seed bags that you can get from SNF good?
I don't know what SNF is.
The old abbreviation of the Swedish Nature Conservation Association.
Now they are only called the Nature Conservation Association.
I have not checked what the seed bags contain.
I don't know either, but one could start from-
-To if they come from the Swedish Society for Nature Conservation then think ...
I dare not swear on it.
How can you think if you want to buy seeds from domestic plants?
You can pick seeds, but then maybe you have to take a course first.
But if you want to buy them?
There is a company that sells Swedish domestic wild plants.
You can google it, "domestic plants seeds".
If you google it, but it will be.
Yes, but there are many different ones that may say "wild plants" and similar-
-But there is a company that sells ...
You have to google it so that we do not happen to advertise.
I myself have believed that a plant has been wild, and then understood-
-That it has not been natural, and you might think it is ...
Then it is important to think about why you do it-
-For if you do it in your own garden, you can buy seed bags or plants.
They also sell ready -made plants that we have used in our research.
You can do that, but if you are going to take this out on a large scale-
-So you have to think a little more, because even if it is Swedish origin-
-So it's a pretty narrow genetic origin.
If everyone orders from a small seed company ...
It is an aspect of multifaceted on a deeper plane as well?
Precisely, because if we talk about the value of plants for the polliners-
-So they do not care if the plants come from Småland, Skåne or Lapland.
But if one should instead think about the conservation of-
-the genetic plant diversity, which is also important to preserve-
-So maybe you have to work a little more locally.
Maybe we should explain a little more why diversity is so important.
I usually compare with us people, which is a species-
-and we look different, and we work slightly different-
-and in the same way one needs to preserve the genetic diversity-
-In each plant species as well.
Some may be more adapted to grow in a particular position-
-or is more dry-resistant, while someone else is more resistant-
-mot a fungal disease or virus.
This is the diversity we need to preserve for the future.
That is what will be the future, and that evolution works with here and now.
A plant that comes from a particular environment is perhaps better adapted to it-
-An if you take seeds of the same plant from a completely different part of the country.
So it's still good to buy seeds, but you might be able to do both?
Yes, and the important thing is to distinguish between garden business-
-and outside gardens.
In gardens it is no problem if you test a little different things-
-But if you think you should do it large scale ...
... thus municipal initiatives or large grasslands to be made om-
-So it is much better to contact someone who takes care of a local meadow.
Ask to get hay of them when they hit it.
Place the hay on a tarpaulin and allow it to dry.
You may need to dry it under roof.
Then you shake it out, and then you have a good foundation-
-To start a local meadow.
It is much better to work where you stand.
If someone who listens is working on this, is this a advice from you?
-Yes. -There are several who wonder here.
Are there wild bees in northern Sweden?
Yes, but the honey bee is not like a wild species in northern Sweden.
It is the yours by ...
It has existed as a wild species in southern Sweden?
-I thought it came from Asia? -There are honey bees in Asia too.
It is from there the honeybean genus, apis, will-
-Then there is a European honey bee that we use in hive
-and so there is a Nordic honey bee, which is a subspecies-
-which is adapted to our Nordic conditions.
It has not occurred naturally throughout our country.
I don't know if you know exactly north border-
-But I would think it's around the Dalälven.
Is it more vulnerable to be a beekeeper?
It sounds like a greater risk to the biological diversity-
-Having bees in Norrland.
I think it's a bigger risk, so there ...
What I said before about honey bees applies to southern Sweden.
I dare not comment on what it is like in northern Sweden.
There is probably a greater risk of competing wild ...
Is it the same wild bees in northern Sweden as here?
No, that's not really it.
There is Polar Humla ...
I'm bad at this-
-I have been up there and looked at hops once.
Alphumla, I think maybe.
I can't their name, tundrahumla there is someone named.
Polar Humla? Now I am unsure, but there is also up there.
Where do hops and bees sleep?
-Blue bells are there any who sleep in. -They sleep in bluebells?
Some sleep in bluebells.
Red walls usually sleep in hole-
-They type of holes they build in to their kids.
I don't know if they sleep or just rest.
They can't close their eyes with their eyes, and just like flies-
-So they have facet eyes.
I don't know if they sleep or just shut down their business.
"We live in the countryside" ...
How can they think to benefit diversity?
It is a little different from urban cultivation, but it is probably the same tip there-
-To you bring in what is in the environment naturally?
Yes exactly, and you were in.
If you just have it in your garden, it doesn't matter that much.
Then you do not have to think so much, but you live next to a nature reserve-
-while the other family or couple made-
-So you have to think a little more, and beware of those who can spread-
-Ot from the garden.
Otherwise you can mix the domestic plants with the favorites you have-
If they are steady, for many are designed to be ...
-You have to think about that too. -They don't have to be at the same discount.
You can distinguish them in the garden.
I think everyone who has a lawn-
-Can let a piece of the lawn be a meadow.
It could either be ... a lawn is nutritious
-and it does not immediately get a meadow with fine meadow plants-
-For they assume a nutrient -poor land.
It is a larger project to build such a meadow ...
You don't have to despair if you have a bold clay soil under-
-On then there may be others like ...
Then, for example, brown or bluebell can come.
White clover, priest collar and other fine plants-
-Wom appears in the lawn if you just leave it.
-This I think you can test. -Or mercury.
Mercury can come.
Yes, there is that too.
What about different sedums, from the aspect pollination plants?
I think they are pretty good.
They give more nectar than you think, given that there are so small flowers.
-Sedum are they thick leafy? -Yes, fat buds.
Large fat bud, yellow fat and many others as well.
Moose grass, which is often found in ditches, is it good for pollinators?
-They are big, and turn white. -I would believe it.
It blooms vigorously, and is domestic.
Sometimes it may be a problem that it grows in old mower-
-and perhaps competing out what is to be there-
-But then this is not where it should be, but elsewhere.
I think that one might want to choose the plants-
— as most insects like, but it is also important to have plants-
-Som maybe just a few pollinators want.
So none of the insect -pollinated plants are wrong to have, on the contrary.
I think that everything of domestic is good to have in the garden.
Just choose and choose from what you like.
"I have a summer cottage site at a lake where we have planted meadow land."
"I was going to make a discount there, what flowers for insects fit in zone 5?"
Maybe it's hard to answer?
-I don't know where zone 5 is. -It's far up.
Yes, it is difficult to respond specifically to it.
Then maybe you should look in the flora where there are distribution maps-
-And see what is happy there.
Then you can see, and search for ...
You often talk about plant zones.
It also depends on whether it is a protected and sunny location in the garden-
-or if it is a vulnerable position where it blows a lot.
What was she ...
They have a discount on a lake.
But it sounds like there is a lot to choose from.
Yes, and it was a bit unclear, were there wild plants they wanted?
I think they want that because it benefits pollinators.
I dare not say which ones are wild and fit in a discount in zone 5.
No, okay.
There is one that has bird networks over strawberries in pallet collars. Is it stupid?
It does not belong to the subject, but if you have something to say?
I don't think it's stupid, because that's probably the blue nets-
-What should protect the strawberries?
I have also posted it this past week.
I had intended to paint red stones, and so the birds would learn-
-They they should not eat the red in strawberry-
-But someone still learned that they can eat it.
I don't know who it is, so I tried to post it.
What I have seen, the insects fly down anyway-
-But I haven't put it on until now that the strawberries started to mature-
-And then there are not much flowers left.
I don't know if they asked if the birds got stuck, but it's ...
Well, it was about birds?
What to think about, and now we go away a little from the subject-
-But this is also important because we talk about the wild diversity-
-and hedgehogs are an important part of the wild diversity-
-and they have decreased a lot.
Hedgehogs may risk getting stuck in such a net-
-So you have nets so it should be stuck properly-
-And you should check it often enough.
I had not left such a net ...
You may have strawberries in a solder, and there are not the hedgehogs.
Hedgehogs can probably climb up there too-
-And so I think there are many who grow strawberries on flat ground as well.
If you use such a network then one should be careful-
-To not animals can get stuck, but the insects are no risk.
Then we will see if it has come in ...
If one has a lawn with a lot of moss that one wants to do to a meadow-
-Is something special to think about then, or is it just to throw out the seeds?
-I's not really? -No.
If there is grass left, it is difficult to build a meadow based on it.
One can let it grow, as we talked about the before-
-But if you want a real classic meadow-
-This you have to remove the top soil layer completely.
It depends on where you are somewhere, because in some places ...
For example, our neighbor has a very nutrient-poor lawn-
-Where the grass does not get very high.
There had been no problem-
-But if you have moss, you have to tear it off.
Yes, and so there, because then you have to wear soil quite easily.
That's good.
Then I don't know why it's moss there.
I'm not very good on lawns.
It may be that it is shady, then you should think about which seeds you sow-
-and that they can withstand shade.
There are different types of shadows and soil-
-S then maybe lime does matter ...
A wise key rule can be-
-while you try to find seeds around, because you collect in the immediate area-
-So there is a greater chance that it is suitable for the ground you have.
If it is shady then you can look in the shade.
It is not as difficult as many may think-
-Collecting seeds yourself.
It's easy for those of you who know, I found tuber bell-
-and they look like a blue clock reason.
-You have to know what it is you gather. -Yes, you have to do that.
You should be absolutely sure what you gather, and check in a flora.
You risk picking something that is protected-
-And you may not collect its seeds at all, but on roadside and road branches for example.
You can...
This by getting some seeds or hay of any-
-Is a pretty good way around it, because then maybe you can-
-Lite threatened plants on the purchase, which you must not go out and collect.
You can also buy from the company selling seeds-
-and test it.
They also have different seed mixtures for, for example, moisture or shade.
There has been a comment, but you have already said what you were thinking about-
-If beekeepers in southern Sweden can pose a threat to pollinators.
-It's no more aspect of that? -I don't know how big the problem is.
One should keep in mind that honey bees have been here for a long time-
-So what has changed is that we today have less flowers-
-and higher densities of honey bees.
Normally you can't have so many nests in one place-
-As you can today, when they live in beehives.
So the conditions have changed, but the species we have in southern Sweden-
-Shey manage to coexist with honey bees.
Otherwise, they would not have been here, because there have been honey bees for so long.
How do you best cut a meadow? Should you go with Lie as before?
The best thing is late summer when it starts to seed off-
-But how to do?
At the ecology house they have cut with edge mowers in the past-
-But now it is usually a mower guild, and then they beat with scythe.
But it is mostly a romantic thing, do you have to go with scythe?
One must not do that, the important thing is that it is cut down-
-In the end of the season, and that it may seed off
-But then moved away before the industry has returned to the ground.
The lean earth becomes more diversity, because there they can do here?
There will be less competition.
It might be good to mention-
-that in a nitrogen-rich soil so some plants grow very fast-
-And they take over, and there is no space for the others.
If you have a nitrogenous soil instead, they grow slowly-
-And then it can fit a lot more.
That is why we biologists and ecologists want nutrient-poor ground-
-In the place of nutritious land, while farmers want nutritious ground-
-Then you can produce more.
In a garden you want both and, because you want both diversity
-and some vegetable cultivation.
Then you can put over the grass clip on the vegetable cultivation-
-So it gets more nutrition.
We'll tie the bag together and finish, but I thought ...
You often have a small garden, and many want to make efforts-
-And farmers need to focus on cultivation.
Who will get to the diversity on a larger plane?
How to think there?
It is probably not wrong to start with yourself.
Many have garden and live in the city-
-But there is very little insects in cities-
-So even if you only have one balcony it can help-
-That you choose domestic plants there.
Do they find here? After all, it is far for them to fly.
-I think they find the plants. -After a while.
They have good sense of smell?
It depends on which ...
Those who live here, for example, have all this below.
I believe that continuity is important, and that one looks to-
-Do when there is something in one place, there may be there for quite long-
-for sooner or later the species are spreading-
-and then it can show up ...
-Patience. -Yes exactly.
There may be large landowners who can also think about this.
Then we also have agricultural support designed by elected politicians-
-So it is also about how to choose to push their politicians-
-Or where you choose to cast your vote.
Do you have any message that you want to convey here?
I think that as a gardener and private person-
-Not should make it a whole science, but you should make it easy.
After all, it is not wrong to have these exotic plants-
-or a seed mixture that you do not know where it comes from.
-You can start, so it will be fun. -I feel hopeful about this.
So I don't have to have a bad conscience for my roses at home?
No.
I also think it is important to give yourself permission-
-to relax in the garden.
That one does not need to mow the lawn so often-
-or clear away all flowering weeds.
Take a cup of coffee, their down-
-And enjoy the little insects that you haven't noticed before.
It sounds inspiring, I think.
Thank you so much, and thank you to you who have listened.
Subtextning.nu