Hi, Elza here from Elza's bookshelf. It is October, which is the type of Halloween horror month and I am very hungry for horror books.
I thought I would ... On Goodreads they have listed type 66 of the most beloved horror books in the last three years.
I have gone through that list and thought I should tell you what books I am very curious to read.
Because I'm a little craving for fear, I feel. So we go through that list, I think, and then you hear some of those books.
I have ... I saw in that list that I have type ... The majority of those books are in my goodreads list that I want to read.
So we shouldn't go through everyone, but maybe top five, top six? Yes, as I really want to read. And of course I want to hear your thoughts on those books.
The first one I think of and that has several books in this list is T. Kingfisher. He has books like A House with Good Bones,
The Twisted Ones, The Hollow Places are just three of the books I know I really want to read him.
And I know they should be mild, horror, a lot of atmosphere and the one I think I will start with, The House of Good Bones I think,
Where it is about a mother ... yes, or daughter, son whose mother says it is ghosts in my house and then you find out a lot of things.
Yes, with a little mild, atmospheric horror, I like that. So here we have a book that I have on my TBR too, which I really want to read for a long time,
And that's The Sundown Motel of St. James, Simone St. James. After all, I have read two other books from her and liked her very much.
And she also has this atmospheric horror, where you like mysterious ghost stories, where you kind of, is it really ghosts or what is I reading for something,
And this one should be really good. Another writer that I am very curious about and whose one of the books I am just about to start, and it is Grady Hendrix.
I have just started how to sell a haunted house. It is the next book we will read in the book club and I am so peppy.
He is the one who has written a horrors. It is this book anyway, that is type IKEA catalog, it feels like.
He has several books that I have on my TBR that I really want to read, and I will finally start my first Hendrix, so I'm so peppy on it.
Then we have a sci-fi horror, Dead Silence, by Barnes something, and look at the cover, I just love it and it is included on this list as well,
And I'm super happy when I saw this one. So the one, I don't really know what it is about except that you are out in space simply,
And the sci-fi took over, so I am bad at reading although I like it. So here, this combination I think is perfect for me.
A pictures too, such a horror that was included on this list which is also a book I want to read.
So, I don't really know what it is about more than it is a child, a boy, there are pictures, not so ...
It should be unpleasant, it is good looking, like atert, and seems to be very, very good.
Just the cover and the feeling it gives me seems to be a book for me. So we'll see.
The only good indians by Stephen Graham Jones I have heard very well, and it should also be such a book that is uncomfortable.
Like this kind of thing, atmospheric horror. Should it be a little disgusting too? I don't know, but I've heard incredibly well about this one.
And it is also such a book that just climbs up in my TBR that comes closer and closer that I really want to read and grab it.
I don't know who has read it, but I think I've heard several pieces that have read and liked it.
So now we have two. In this list I found two books that are like Latin American feeling.
And one of those I've had for a long time is Mexican Gothic. Check out how good it is.
Yes, it is very cover. You know how I am. I like cover. Scary covers, stylish covers.
And here we have a really, really nice cover that really attracts me.
And that it is such a Mexican, South American horror or mysticism I like. And this seems great.
And another who was in this one like I had not seen before and who makes me very exciting.
House of Hunger. And this vampire books.
A book that I also found here that I had forgotten that I had put last year more clearly when I put it in.
And it's The Book of Accidents by Chuck Wending. It should also be some kind of dysfunctional family.
Past present. Yes, but it should be uncomfortable.
That said, I added this last year, April 2022, and had totally forgotten that it was there.
So now I saw this and it seems very, very interesting. And check the cover as well.
Hello. And of course, all Stephen King that is included in this list is of course an absolute must.
So that goes without saying. So I don't have to say anything.
And this book, The Last House on Needles Street by Katrina Ward.
I have it when I saw it on the list. But I've heard and seen it like everywhere.
But this is how serial killers, Revenge, Death, A chair Child, all that.
I just, wow, this sounds very, very, very good.
I have to say, overall this list is incredibly, incredibly good.
I have found a lot of new favorites like that. Or not new favorites, but books that I really want to read.
And all Kingfisher are there, almost everyone I want to read is on this one too.
So it was new acquaintance too that I had not really seen so and I am incredibly, incredibly curious about.
One who, a book I want to talk about in this Sundial Katrina Ward again.
And this one was also such a book that I added last year and which I had forgotten.
Check out the cover. I mean, how unpleasant and good looking is it?
I do not get it. This made me fall for this book.
Twisty Psychological Horror. So psychological, twisty.
It's just, I have to read it at once.
And it has got pretty good and high grades anyway.
So Katrina Ward may be a writer that I should look out for.
Have you read anything from her?
I think this list was so good. Really, really good list at all.
For especially me, who is like the craving for terror but don't really know where to start.
But I am very happy that I will start on Hendrix books now.
Then I think I should go and take some Kingfisher books.
But this list I thought was so fantastic and I just wanted us to go through it a little neighbor.
And I took some books that I'm curious about.
I look at the list, that's why I look down and not at you.
I don't know, what do you think about horror? Do you get extra sucked now when it is October or do you hate horror at all?
I am the one who loves terror and can read horror in April or March, it doesn't matter.
But I feel that this year, October, I have got such a ghostly feeling and I have had a strong suction.
So when I saw this list I became like this, thank you so much goodreads, now I'll go through it.
And look, and there were many of them like me, it's totally sick, I don't know if you can see, so many of them stand like this
Want to Read, Want to Read, that I put it on my goodread list.
I am so flatly curious about what you think about horror at all.
The books I have talked about, have you read any of them or are you so curious about them too?
Talk to me in the comments field and we will hear there. We will be visible next week. Take care bye!
Bye!