It was on Sunday 18 June
2023 approximately 740 kilometers off the island
Newfoundland in Canada as the submarine Titan,
Built by the company Oceangate began its descent into the sea.
On board were five people and the goal was to dive down to the wreck
of Titanic, which is at 3800 meters depth.
On board was Oceangate's founder
and CEO Stockton Rush, 61 years Shazada Dawood, 48 years,
A Pakistani British businessman and his son Suleman Dawood, 19 years,
Hamish Harding, 58 years, a British businessman, pilot and space tourist,
and Paul-Henri Nargeolet, 77 years, member of the French Institute for Marine Research
And director for
underwater research for E/M Group and RMS Titanic Inc.
He was on titanium as a guide.
The descent itself would take 2 hours, but after 1 hour and 45 minutes
Had been lost suddenly Titan all communication with the crew on the surface.
A few days later,
June 22, you could confirm that one found
wreckage from titanium near Titanic
And most likely all five people had on board.
Died.
The cause is believed to be an implosion.
What was Oceangate for companies?
How was the submarine Titan constructed and what risks were there?
What really happened and what is an implosion?
We will find out today.
Titan was built by the company Oceangate
which was founded in 2009 by Stockton Rush and Guillermo Söhnlein.
The company offers, among other things, diving tours down to the Titanic wreck.
Titan actually made his first diving down to Titanic in
July 2021 and a total of at least ten
Various diving between 2021 - 2022.
Each diving consisted of a pilot, a
Guide and then three paying guests.
The cost per person for a ticket was 250 \ H000 \ HDolls,
which corresponds to approximately SEK 2.5 \ hilmins.
The submarine itself
Titan was 6.7 meters long and 2.8 meters wide.
It weighed about 10.4 tons and
was made of carbon fiber and titanium.
It was equipped with four electric engines,
Two vertical and two horizontal.
These could steer the boat forward, backward,
up and down and rotate it.
The maximum speed was 3 knots,
which is about 5.5 km/h.
Oxygen to the entire crew would last for 96 hours if something
Would go wrong and it was built to cope with a depth of 4000 meters.
The pilot steered the entire submarine with a modified wireless game control.
A Logitech F710.
The boat was equipped with cameras externally that led to screens
Inside on board so that the pilot and crew could see the outside.
The submarine also had a window at the front that you could look from.
Because GPS
not working underwater so sent the crew on the surface
instead text messages down to titanium about their position
via a so -called ultra short baseline system.
What risks were there then with such a scuba diving?
To begin with, everything happened out on international water
Which meant that you did not have to have any special security rules.
Titanium was not approved as seaworthy by any authority or organization
And all passengers on board must also sign an agreement
where you confirm that you are aware of all risks, that it is all an experiment
and that it can result in physical harm,
trauma or death.
The agreement briefly gives the Oceangate back free
If something would go wrong.
One of the founders, Stockton Rush told in an interview from 2021 to quote
I have violated some rules for building titanium, carbon fiber and titanium.
There is a rule that you do not do that way, but I did.
End quote.
In 2018, David Lochridge wrote the then head of Oceangates
marine operations, a report in which he expressed his concern about titanium
He wanted the submarine to be inspected and be certified
by an authority, but Oceangate did not want it.
They refused to pay for such an inspection.
Another thing he expressed in his report was that the window that was on titanium.
was just certified and approved for a depth of 1300 meters,
About a third of the depth required to get down to Titanic.
Oceangate did not like Lochridge's statements so they sued him and kicked him.
Then we have to
Also talk about the choice of material for titanium,
Carbon fiber and titanium.
Carbon fiber is an extremely strong and lightweight material that is known for its high
tensile strength. Thus, the ability to withstand forces that pull the material apart.
However, it is not as strong when it comes to pressure strength
which is the ability to withstand the power that compresses the material.
At extremely high pressure that one encounters down in the sea
Can carbon fiber based structures crack.
Titanic, on the other hand, is known for its high compressive strength,
Which makes it a good choice for vehicles that will dive far below the water.
But it is much heavier and more expensive than carbon fiber.
To combine titanium
and carbon fiber may seem like a good idea to take advantage
of both carbon fiber's ease and titanium compressive strength.
But at these extreme pressure down in the sea, the parts can
Two materials meet. When titanium and carbon fiber meet -
It can be a weak point.
If it is not carefully designed and constructed, this may lead to a disaster
And this is now we have to talk about water pressure.
Up at the surface, the pressure is what is called an atmosphere.
When you dive below the water surface, the pressure on the body increases
And this depends on the importance of all the water that lies above it.
For every tenth meter you dive down
so the pressure increases with an atmosphere,
so at 3800 meters depth is the pressure
380 times larger than at the sea surface.
This never can handle a human body because one would die
immediately and hence we need something that can protect us from the pressure,
For example, a submarine.
But then it is important that the submarine is designed to cope with the pressure.
At 3800 meters depth the pressure is so great that the submarine is pressed together
From all directions and edges with a force corresponding to about 10 \ H000 tonnes.
It's like having the weight of the Eiffel Tower pressing against the submarine,
But not just from above but from all directions.
Back to June 18, 2023.
When the time is on its way down to Titanic
When 1 hour and 45 minutes had been lost Titan contact
With the crew on the surface and now a fight against the clock began.
No one at this point knew what had happened.
Titana had the following security system on board.
It was equipped with different sensors that senses how the hull
affected by the pressure when it dives further and further down, which would warn prematurely if
The hull was cracking and then you could interrupt diving and return to the surface.
It also had fire extinguishers and smoke machines
to everyone on board in the event of a possible electric fire.
It also had ascent aid in the form of an air balloon that could be inflated
And you could also manually release weights
to help the submarine return to the surface.
There was also a special material on the outside designed to be dissolved
In the salt water after 10 hours and release sandbags from the underside of the submarine,
which would help return to the surface.
So this system works even if all on board were unconscious
If time had received a power outage that cannot be remedied
So they knew that the crew had 96 hours of oxygen left.
But if the submarine has no power, it cannot be heated internally.
Water temperature outside which is around 1 to 4 degrees
Celsius would quickly cool down the submarine and probably
everyone in the crew would die from the cold before the oxygen ended.
However, since found wreckage of titanium near Titanic
so is the most likely explanation that the pressure based on
Got the hull to crack and the entire submarine imploded.
And what is an implosion?
It is the opposite of an explosion.
An explosion means that energy is released outward,
which often results in a pressure wave and material being sent outwards.
An implosion occurs when the pressure from the outside
of an object exceeds the pressure inside, which gets the object
to quickly collapse inward.
Look at this clip where a
Implosion takes place with an oil tank.
Note how fast it went.
This is thus the pressure from the outside that compresses the thought, which has a vacuum inside.
And this is just the pressure from our atmosphere on the surface.
Thus, the pressure from only one atmosphere.
Implosion that happened for the crew inside the titanium
was exposed to 380 atmospheres.
So you can only imagine how fast it went.
They never even got to react to something happening,
Which might be just as good.
It was a brief summary
by the company Oceangate. The accident with titanium ..
And the dangers down to the depths of the sea.
Feel free to subscribe to this channel so you don't miss when I release more videos.
And as always, thank you for watching!