What is afantasi?
We will find out today.
Close.
Imagine you stand on a beach.
The waves are booking in front of you and the sun is going down.
Can you see it in front of you?
Can you imagine this scene in your head?
If you can't, if you don't see anything at all in front of you,
Then you can have what is called afantasi.
It is a neurological condition where one cannot
visualize images in their head.
One cannot imagine a beach or room
Or something else in their imagination.
In short, man has an inability to create mental images.
This phenomenon was already described in 1880 by Francis Galton
A British anthropologist and psychologist.
In his study published in 1880,
called the Statistics of Mental Imagery, he examined
How well people could produce mental visual images.
He asked to visualize and describe their breakfast tables
As carefully they could.
Then he discovered a surprising variety
in the person's ability to create these mental images.
Some could create clear and vibrant images in their senses,
while others reported a total inability to visualize.
They couldn't see anything at all.
The very term “afantasi” first got its name and became
more widely known after a study named Lives Without Imagery
Congenital aphantasia from 2015 by the professor
Adam Zeman who worked at the University of Exeter in the United Kingdom.
The vast majority of people who have afantasi are born with it,
But there are reported cases where the condition has been developed, for example
after a brain injury, a stroke or an operation.
Characteristics if a person has afantasi is as
Said the inability to create mental images in the head.
They don't remember events the same way
And can't play a memory in the head.
A person with afantasi may also have difficulty with expression
Like counting sheep before falling asleep.
It can be confusing because the person does not see any
Sheep in front of them who skip a fence.
Persons with Antasi are not as afraid of scary stories either
Because they can't see the scary in front of them.
Avantasi can also affect several senses.
People with afantasi may also have a reduced ability
To imagine sounds, smells or flavors.
But one should not misunderstand it as persons with afantasi
is not as creative or good at problem solving.
Those who have the condition have adapted to it and taught themselves
to think and remember in a way that is not dependent
of visual mental images.
Some people first discover that they have afantasi much later
in life and may also be surprised that others can
see things in their head.
Today we know that the ability to visualize pictures
in its head is on a spectrum where Avantasi represents one end
with a total or close total inability to create mental images.
And on the other side of the spectrum we find hyperfantasi
Where individuals have an exceptionally good ability to create mental images.
Between these two there are a variety of different levels
of the ability to visualize things in one's head.
A tool used to explore this spectrum is
VIVIDNESS OF VISUAL IMAGERY Questionnaire
It is a survey that helps researchers measure
And compare individuals' ability to create mental images.
About 2 to 3 \ h% of all people on earth may have a fantasy to a
some degree, but many are not even aware that they have the condition,
So the actual figure can be higher.
We still know very little about Avantasi, but the research is ongoing.
The important thing to take with you is to aphantasi
should not be seen as an obstacle to living a full life.
Many who have the condition are not even aware of it and have successfully
learned to navigate through everyday life without the need
of visual mental images.
I hope you have learned a little more about what AFANTASI is for something.
Feel free to subscribe to this channel.
And as always, thank you for watching!