It is 21:45 in the evening, Friday, April 6, 1990.
The ship "M/S Scandinavian Star" had just begun its journey from Oslo in Norway to Fredrikshamn in Denmark.
On board were 383 passengers and 99 crew members.
Before we move on, we need to go through some short information about the ship.
The ship was built in 1971 in the city of Nantes in France.
From the beginning, the ship was called M/S Massalia and was a combination of a passenger ship and a ferry for cars and railway cars.
The ship was about 141 meters long and about 21.9 meters wide. In total, the ship was able to take on board 1152 passengers, of which 100 in the crew.
The ship has changed its name and owner several times since she was built.
In March 1990, she was bought by Vognmandsuten and put in traffic between Oslo in Norway and Fredrikshamn in Denmark.
Okay, again until Friday, April 6, 1990.
The ship left the port of Oslo at 21:45 local time - 2 hours and a quarter delayed.
The journey would have started already at 19:30, but work on boarding passenger cars and trucks took longer than expected.
The journey to Fredrikshamn goes painlessly at first until it was between 01: 45-02: 00 on the night of April 7.
The ship was now out on open water in a part of the North Sea called Skagerack and most of the passengers were sleeping.
On deck 4, some passengers are suddenly awakened from their sleep when they hear a crackling sound out in the corridor.
A few doors away is a pile of bedding on the floor that burns. Fortunately, they manage to extinguish the fire together with the crew.
One of the crew members went up to the command bridge and announced the first mate who at that time had the guard.
He in turn went and announced to the captain of what had happened and told the captain that "someone is playing Pyroman".
After captain Hugo Larsen was announced, the first mate was sent down to the fire site to check.
It was made sure to be properly extinguished and cleaned up. After that, the first mate called the captain on the bridge again and announced that everything was under control.
But it all didn't end there. Sometime just after 02:00, one more fire arose on deck 3 outside a cabin in a corridor on the starboard side.
This was near the stairs leading up to tires 4 and 5. Within a few minutes, the fire had spread so much that the entire corridor was in flames
And thick smoke looked up the stairwell and began to fill the corridors on tires 4 and 5.
There were alarms from a number of different fire alarms in the corridors on decks 4 and 5 when the passengers there had discovered the fire.
When the captain learned about this it was around 02:15 and when the first mate entered the bridge he received orders from the captain to send out the signal "fire alarm" all over the ship.
The captain triggered the self -closure of the fire doors in the areas where the fire alarm buttons had been pressed by the passengers.
But since no button had been pressed in where the fire started on the starboard side by deck 3, the fire doors were left open there.
The walls and ceiling on deck 3 were covered with plastic laminate and when it burned there it created a smoke that contained high levels of hydrogen cyanide and carbon monoxide
And after only 10 minutes, the corridors had reached a deadly concentration of the two gases.
At 02:24 they now turned off the ship's propulsion and then started the fire pumps but the fire was already out of control.
Captain Hugo Larsen sent out an emergency signal to Tjøme Radio in Norway, announcing the fire on board and that the passengers and crew would now start moving towards the lifeboats.
On board, there is currently total panic among passengers. Many are struggling through the smoke -filled corridors.
Some people have already died of the toxic smoke and passengers may step over them in order to reach.
Here, even more problems began to arise. According to the Accident Investigation Board's report, there was no superior leadership that made sure that things went right from the fact that the fire was discovered until the ship was abandoned.
The entire evacuation and mood of the lifeboats were panicked according to witnesses and were mostly managed by the passengers themselves.
At 02:25 Denmark ferry “M/S Stena Saga” which was nearby going to Scandinavian Star, which was now 11 nautical miles west of the Weather Islands.
02:27 The Sea Rescue Center at Gothenburg Radio in Onsala has heard the conversations from Scandinavian Star and offers help with Swedish helicopters and vessels. It is accepted.
Between 02:36 and 03:10, the Sea Rescue Center sent out three helicopters and 12 different Swedish coast guard, pilot and sea rescue boats.
Norway sent out 3 helicopters, as well as coastguard vessels and engine torpedo boats and also a rescue cruiser.
Denmark sent out two helicopters.
At 02:50, Stena Saga is in front of Scandinavian Star.
After that, M/S Dana Regina arrives at the site and the aforementioned vessels. Now the vessels began to take on survivors from Scandinavian Star's lifeboats.
At 03:28 Captain Hugo Larsen announces that he is currently sitting in a lifeboat on his way to Stena Saga and that all passengers and crew
is in the lifeboats and that no person is left on board Scandinavian Star.
But unfortunately, that information was not true. There were still people left on board.
03:38 Fire personnel with professional smoke divers are sent from the fire brigade in Gothenburg to Scandinavian Star.
It takes a while before they arrive and while this is ongoing, staff from several different connecting rescue services are sent to the site.
05:30 the first smoke divers are celebrated at Scandinavian Star via helicopter and almost at once are discovered 5 pieces
Survivors aboard the burning ship that was rescued immediately.
When the firefighters then enter the ship, it was like stepping into a burning nightmare.
There were dead bodies everywhere ... both adults and children.
A view that no human should have to experience.
Unfortunately, there were no more survivors left on the ship.
It is believed that more people could have been saved if the smoke diver effort had come 2 hours earlier to the scene.
159 people lost their lives that night.
The investigations conducted afterwards by the forensic authorities show they probably died quickly.
It was a combination of a number of causes, partly the fire itself but also of high carbon dioxide content as well as the toxic smoke containing carbon monoxide and hydrogen cyanide.
It is estimated that the passengers who made their way out into the corridors had not been able to get to any exit before collapsing on the floor.
Most of the dead, which were 99 people, remained in their cabins.
About 50 people were found in the corridors and most were in aft on deck 5.
323 people were rescued from Scandinavian Star that night and only about 30 were injured.
Most had mild smoke poisoning or other lighter injuries such as splits and bruises.
Some were taken ashore via helicopter and others were brought with the vessels to Lysekil, Sandefjord, Fredriksstad and Fredrikshamn.
11.55 During the day, Scandinavian Star was towed to Lysekil and is 21:17 in the evening.
The day after April 8 at 16:30, the fire is finally extinguished and the dead can start to be lifted ashore.
Since the majority of passengers were from Norway, the dead bodies were transported in large white cooling cars with police cards to the Forensic Institute in Oslo.
Two questions quickly appear in the head. Who built the fires and why did everything go ... so wrong?
Sadly, it has not been possible to determine who or who built the fires on the ship.
After the disaster, an official fire investigation was conducted and there it was concluded that the most likely perpetrator was a passenger on board
named Erik Mørk Andersen, 37 years.
He was previously convicted of murder. However, he himself died in the flames after the second fire so you couldn't be sure it was he.
An interesting investigation from 2006 by two fire engineers at Lund University of Technology concluded that there were not only two fires on board ..
Without six and that all fires were constructed.
This also shows that it was probably not Erik Mørk Andersen because several fires were built after his death. If he was, he was not alone in any case.
The person or persons must have had a good knowledge of the ship and access to a number of locked spaces.
Another theory is that it is an insurance fraud.
An American company named Sea Escape had bought the ship one week before the fire for $ 10.3 million
And the same day as the purchase, they assured the ship for $ 24 million.
According to this theory, the company Sea Escape can thus be the cause of the fire and got some of the crew to set fire to the ship and later get the insurance money.
Why did everything go so wrong then? How could the fire on board get such a disastrous outcome?
According to the Accident Investigation Board's report, this was due to several things.
Partly that when the captain of the command bridge is notified of the fire, the alarm within the ship is incomplete.
No proper attempt at all extinguish the fires was carried out…
It was even so that the fire manager on board did not know that it was his task.
There were seven smoke diver equipment on board, but no one was used to extinguish the fire or to save any passengers.
3 of them were used in the evacuation of the ship.
And that smoke divers should have been called to the Scandinavian Star in connection with the emergency signal being sent out.
It is believed, as I said, that many more people could have been saved if smoke divers had been called earlier.
You still do not know who or who built the fires at Scandinavian Star that night that killed 159 people.
The fact that such a disaster is and perhaps remains unresolved is a great sadness for those affected, but also their relatives.
For all the people who survived the disaster at Scandinavian Star, that night has become a memory ..
that burned stuck .. forever.
Don't forget to subscribe to this channel. New episodes are released every week.
Also, don't forget to listen to my podcast quick facts. You can find it at podplay.se or in the app.
And as always ..
Thanks for watching!