Then we are back with five
Pieces of moral and ethical dilemmas.
I will give you five different dilemmas.
The task is how would you act in these situations?
And remember, there is no right or wrong answer.
Feel free to write your answers and justify why in the comments field.
After looking clearly.
Pause the video if you need to think.
Try to also keep you in response options in those dilemmas
As I describe.
It is easy to find another solution,
But then the very point of the exercise disappears.
But then we start immediately
number one.
The doctor you are a doctor in a hospital.
At the hospital there are two patients, one patient
Which is 90 years old and a patient who is 20 years old.
Both have the same deadly illness and are only expected to live for another month.
But there is a cure
That can save them and you have this cure.
But the problem is that there is only enough for one person.
What are you doing?
Do you give the cure to the older patient and let him live the few
years he has left and sacrifices the young patient?
Or do you give the cure to the young patient?
He has a long life ahead of him.
The old man would soon die anyway.
Or do you do nothing and let both die?
For a life is probably no more worthwhile
something else?
Number two dungeons.
You stand at a cliff and at the edge of the cliff hangs one
Foreign pregnant woman and stays stuck.
She will soon lose grip.
If you don't help her up a few feet away from her hangs
Your best friend, also unable to get up on your own.
How they ended up there is unimportant in this context,
But now it is important to choose who to save.
If you save the woman then your best friend falls down and dies.
If you save your buddy
Then the woman falls with the child and dies.
What are you doing?
Do you save the pregnant woman or you rescue
Your best friend?
Number three the secret heritage.
You find that you have inherited a large sum with money from a distant relative.
You also find out that this relative earned
This money through criminal activities.
The police know nothing and you could receive the inheritance without
Some problems if you didn't say anything.
What are you doing?
Would you accept the inheritance?
After all, you are the only one who knows where the money comes from.
Or would you refuse to receive them?
Right should be right.
The police must know where the money comes from.
Number four children of the future.
In this dilemma, researchers have managed to develop a
Type of gene modification that allows parents to have the opportunity
At a cost, of course, to adjust things for their unborn child.
For example, you can see if the child has any genetic disease and remove it.
At the same time, parents can also change other things in the child.
Eye color, hair color, length and so on.
But can one play God in this way
may you change these things without
Children's permission and science.
What do you think?
You think it's right.
This can prevent serious and deadly future illnesses.
The child's life can be saved and people always try to find
Ways to improve themselves anyway, through education, diet and so on.
So why would this be different?
You think it's wrong.
You change the course of nature.
After all, the child is different from what was initially intended.
This will only lead to a further split in society
between those who are genetically improved and those who are not.
Number five the price of love.
You and your best friend have known each other since childhood.
In addition to spending a lot of time with your best friend, you even hang out
with other people and have recently discovered that you have developed
very strong feelings for a specific person.
You introduce this person to your best friend and over time
Do you notice that the two seem to have an incredibly strong connection.
After a few months this person tells you
That it feels a deeper connection with your best friend than with you.
What are you doing?
Would you step aside and let your best friend
And the person you enjoy continuing to socialize?
Although it is incredibly painful for you?
Or would you fight for your love and try to prevent them from meeting
and risk losing your lifelong friendship?
What weighs heavier than your own happiness and jealousy
Or their potential happiness together?
Write in the comments what you
answers and if you can justify why.
If you have missed part, I put it as a link in the description.
And as always, thank you for watching!