The time was
06:30 in the morning December 20, 1987
When the Doña Paz ship left the port of Tacloban
located on the island of Leyte in the Philippines.
Ship Doña Paz was a passenger ferry built by the Japanese company
Onomichi Zosen of Hiroshima in Japan and was about 93 meters long,
13.6 meters wide and could take on board 1518
Passengers and 66 crew members.
The ship operated the distance between the city of Tacloban
and the capital of Manilla in the Philippines, located on the island of Luzon
With an intermediate stop in the city of Catbalogan on the island of Samar.
This route did Doña Paz twice a week.
When the ship left the harbor it was scheduled to arrive at Manilla the clock
Four in the morning the day after.
Philippines is a country consisting of
over 7000 islands and is completely dependent on vessels or boats as a means of transport between the islands,
Which makes passenger ferries the most economical mode of transport for many locals.
According to reports it is apparently very common
that the ferries are overloaded in the Philippines.
So even if a ship such as Doña Paz can only
Receive 1518 passengers and people are still crowded to come along.
And it is especially common before festivals as at this time,
Only a few days before Christmas.
When Doña Paz left the harbor after her stop in the Catbalog
It was clearly noticed that it tilted heavily to one side,
Which showed that it was overflowing with people.
According to reports and testimonies, over 4400 people were aboard the ship
And many of these were children under four years.
None of them knew they would soon be involved in the worst ship disaster ever
in peacetime.
A day before,
December 19 at.
20:00 in the evening, left the oil ship MT
Vector the port of Limay in the province of Batan in the Philippines
to get to destination even a masbate.
The ship Mt Vector had 13 people in the herd
and was loaded with 8800 oil barrels
which included gasoline, kerosene and diesel.
December 20 at.
22:29 - The ship Doña Paz was now out in the strait,
Table between the two islands of Marinduque and Mindoro.
It was a dark and silent night
but the waves were high and hit the ship
And somewhere out there in the dark, the ship MT Vector was also.
Right now we're just seconds from that disaster
that will soon occur.
Some things that are important to know at this time are the following.
Inside the vessel Doña Paz it was extremely crowded and most of the passengers tried to sleep.
People slept in the corridors on top of the deck and almost all the cabins were overcrowded there.
3 to 4 people could split on a single bed.
The ship's communication system was broken so they could not call for help if needed.
The Life Rights on board were locked up in a separate room
And if that wasn't enough, the ship was also ruled at this time
An apprentice without sufficient experience.
The captain and the rest of the officers were either at the bar or watched TV in their staff room
And on board MT Vector it wasn't much better.
They were heavily understaffed with only 13 men.
They had no training in dealing with crisis situations, inadequate navigation equipment and that
In its most recent inspection of the Philippine Coast Guard was discovered
That an MT Vector had an error on the steering.
The radio license had expired 1.5 years ago and they missed
also an inspection certificate.
When the clock strikes 22:30 Mt Vector shows up
and collide with the port side of Doña Paz
Which knocked out the engines and all electricity on board.
In connection with the collision they ignited
8800 oil barrels aboard My Vector
which led to an immediate and powerful explosion.
The explosion was so violent that
It immediately settled both vessels on fire.
The passengers had nowhere to go.
The oil had leaked into the sea, as well as the water around.
Both vessels were in flames.
No lifeboats could be hoisted down because of it.
The fire spread rapidly on deck and looked into cabins
And the social spaces that packed with people.
The life jackets were locked up.
The desperation caused many to jump out of the side of the ship
Just to land into the burning inferno below them.
The crew of a ship named Don Claudio,
who found themselves some nautical miles from the collision, the explosion heard
and saw a fire bullet that towed up several hundred meters
in the air.
They arrived at the site
A few hours later and managed to save 26 people.
24 of them were from Doña Paz and two were from MT Vector.
They were taken ashore where they received medical care.
Doña Paz sank 2 hours after the collision
And Mt Vector sank 2 hours after that.
As I mentioned earlier it was
Over 4400 people aboard the Japans and 13 on 50 Vector.
And since only 26 people survived, this is
the worst ship disaster ever in peacetime.
Because most of the passengers are encapsulated
Inside that Japan, the total death number is unknown.
But estimates show a figure that about 4385 people died in the accident.
Since no SOS signal was sent
Out it took about 8 hours before the Philippine Coast Guard learned about the accident
and another 8 hours before the rescue service was sent out.
But once they arrived at the scene, both vessels had dropped
a long time ago.
The tragic collision between Doña Paz and Mt Vector
Became an alarm clock for the whole world about the importance of security aboard passenger ships.
This event created a national grief over the entire Philippines and raised urgent questions
about how ships are maintained, about how many people they are allowed to wear really
And how well equipped they are for emergency situations.
We can only speculate what went through the head
on the passengers aboard Doña Paz who was stuck in their cabins
When the ship was standing in flames and sank.
How many were alive when the ship was on the way down underwater?
And what to do in such a situation?
You run out of the cab and risk being suffocated by the toxic smoke
or you throw yourself down into the burning sea
Or just wait until the sea encloses one?
What do you say to their child
When you know there is no way out?