Then we are
Back with ten old execution as methods from the past.
Part two.
Don't forget to look at part one afterwards.
Link can be found in the description.
But now we jump in right away.
Number 1: Brass bull
The brass bulls were manufactured during ancient Greece
and used as a torture and execution tool.
It was a device shaped like a hollow bull,
Made of bronze or by brass.
The punished person was locked inside the bull through a gap in the side.
Then you lit a fire under the bull.
When the metal got hot, the person would
Inside slowly roasted alive.
The bull was designed in a way where one had made holes in the bull's mouth
or in the nostrils and when the punished screamed in there the sound came
out of there and distorted it to a sound similar to a bull
Beeing ..
Number 2: Gillotin.
Guillotine was a device
that consisted of two large vertical rails and a large heavy
Blade placed at the top, also called car.
The penalty's head was placed in a bracket and then
If you dropped down the blade which then cut off the head from the body.
It was important that the blade was angled so that it created a
Cutting movement over the neck.
If the blade was straight then it could happen that it punished
The person only broke his neck and was still alive.
Number 3: Poena Cullei
Pena Cullei was
a punishment used in ancient rum.
The punished person would be placed inside a sack along with different animals,
For example, a snake, a dog and a monkey.
Then they tied the bag together
and threw it in a lake or in the sea.
The person fought for his life inside the sack at the same time as it
Got to fight panicked animals that also tried to save themselves.
It ended with everyone inside the bag drowning.
Number 4
Leather.
The skin of someone means removing a person's skin.
Usually while the person was still alive.
It was an extremely painful and horrific execution
method that often led to shock,
blood loss and finally death.
Number 5: Ratbrene
The rat cage
was a horrible execution method used during the Middle Ages.
The punished person was tied on to a platform
Or in a chair with a cage placed over the stomach.
Then they placed starved rats in the cage
and by heat it up from the outside, the rats were forced to gnaw
And scratch through the person's body in a desperate attempt to escape.
The rats bit and tore through the body on the punished person
Until it finally died.
Number six walled.
The punished person was walled in live stone for stone
and then left there to die by either thirst or by hunger,
Which could take several days and sometimes weeks.
Number 7: Honey boat
The honey boat, or a shame as they also
was called, was an antique Persian execution method.
The punished person was stuck between
two boats, usually completely naked, where the head,
The arms and legs stuck out from the sides of the boat.
One then placed the boat in a lake and then forcibly fed
Man the punished person with a mixture of milk and honey.
Over time, this made the person got massive diarrhea,
Which would attract insects.
One could also pour honey on it
punished the person's body to attract more insects.
The insects and the little animals or fish that entered
Between the boats began to eat the punished.
This created smelly infections as they ate up their flesh,
Which led to a slow and painful death.
Number 8: Crushing
Crushing, is much like it sounds.
You are executed by being crushed.
It usually meant that a heavy object, such as a large stone,
was placed on the chest or on the stomach of the punished person.
Then they put on another stone and then one to
And maybe another one.
In the end, the weight became so great that the body of the punished person
was crushed.
Number 9: Death by melted metal.
This method of execution meant that one poured melted
metal such as lead or bronze,
down the throat of the punished.
The extreme heat caused severe burns,
resulting in enormous pain
And finally death.
Talk about heartburn.
Number 10: Death through a thousand incisions.
This method, also known as Lingchi,
was a method of execution from China abolished in 1905.
The punished person was tied to a wooden pile in a public place.
Then you put small cuts on the body a little here and there.
The cuts were random with different depths and different lengths.
Sometimes you could start putting the cuts on one arm
Cross and right and right and left until it finally fell off.
Then they continued over the rest of the body.
A very slow and painful death
If you were merciful.
Did you put the first incision in the throat
so that the punished person died faster.
There were 10 old execution methods.
Part 2 Which method did you think was the worst?
Feel free to submit a reply in the comments field.
And as always thanks for looking.