What is psychosis?
We will find out today.
When someone experiences a psychosis one has
hard to distinguish between between imagination and reality
And it can manifest in different ways,
As for example through a sense of paranoia where the person
may feel persecuted or in danger without a concrete reason.
Or by hearing voices, which is a type of hallucination
where people hear sounds or conversations that others cannot hear.
Psychosis Diseases are a collective name for illnesses
Where reality is experienced differently.
The most common psychotic disease is schizophrenia
Which I have also made a separate video about.
But there are also others such as
reactive psychosis that is a temporary psychosis
triggered by stressful events,
Schizoa -efficient syndrome
that combines schizophrenia symptoms with mood swings,
delusions syndrome, giving prolonged
delusions without other psychotic symptoms.
And then there is something called birth psychosis.
It is a rare type of psychosis that can occur shortly after childbirth.
Psychosis is not
a disease in itself without rather a group of symptoms that may
be part of several different mental health conditions.
It is important to understand that a psychosis is something that can hit
Anyone and there is nothing the person himself has chosen.
Symptoms may occur as a result of frightening or severe events,
other diseases or use of certain types of drugs.
There is help to get and with the right support and treatment, many can live
A good life despite periods of psychosis.
But what exactly does it mean to have a
Psychosis and what is it causing?
A psychosis can develop in different ways.
It can occur suddenly or gradually over a longer period.
How long a psychosis can last can also vary
From just a few weeks to several years,
and it can either occur a single time
or return on several occasions.
During an ongoing psychosis, the individual is usually strongly engaged in their own
Thoughts and experiences that can be very intense and overwhelming.
If you experience the following symptoms, it may be a sign of psychosis.
Delusions, hallucinations and thought disorders.
Delusions mean
that your perception of reality is changed
And often in a way that is difficult for others to understand or to believe.
For example, you may experience a strong feeling that you are persecuted,
Although there is no evidence of this, which is a form of paranoia.
You may also be convinced that you possess special
supernatural abilities and has a great important fate
Like you are selected to do any special assignment for the good of humanity.
You may experience that you are in danger, perhaps exposed to radiation from space
Or other threats, even if there is no concrete evidence of this.
In addition, you may feel that the surroundings are communicating with you
By sending secret personal messages,
Maybe via radio, TV or on the internet.
Messages that only you can understand.
These experiences are often very intense and experienced
As completely real, even though no one else around you experiences them.
Hallucinations mean that
You experience and see things that are not in the real world.
You can hear voices that no one else hears.
You can see things that are not there,
feel things on your skin that are not there or even feel
Smells and flavors of things that are not there.
Thought disorders means that your thinking can
be confusing and difficult to follow and understand to others around you.
You can jump between different subjects and ideas without a clear connection between them.
Your thoughts may feel spinning and overwhelming and that
Can be difficult to focus on one thing at a time.
This makes it difficult for you to make decisions and to solve problems,
Which can make everyday tasks very challenging.
What causes a psychosis?
Psychosis may have different causes and there are
Several factors that can increase the risk of developing the condition.
Here are some of the most common causes and risk factors.
Heredity.
If there are psychotic diseases in the family, the risk of developing a psychosis may be higher.
Trauma and experiences of trauma, especially
During childhood, can increase the risk of psychosis later in life.
High stress levels or significant life changes
may trigger psychotic episodes in some individuals.
Prolonged sleep deprivation and even psychiatric
condition such as bipolar disorder and schizophrenia.
It is important to note that psychosis is not always linked to another illness
and can be triggered by an isolated event.
In addition, a combination of different factors can contribute to the development of psychosis
And different individuals can have different risk factors.
But as I said, psychosis can hit anyone,
regardless of age, gender or life situation.
Although certain risk factors may increase the likelihood of some individuals
is there help to get when someone is undergoing a
Psychosis becomes the changes in behavior often noticeable to those around them.
Especially if you know the person before.
For example, a person may begin to tell about their delusions madmen
Like feeling persecuted or being exposed to threats.
It may also be obvious by the person not answering when
one is trying to get in touch or that they talk to themselves or
Maybe even breaks out in laughter for no apparent reason.
People who experience a psychosis can sometimes feel an excessive
rising despair or hopelessness, which can lead them
to consider very serious and harmful actions against themselves.
It is of utmost importance to seek professional help and support immediately.
If you or someone you know, these tanks or emotions are experiencing.
You can contact a psychiatric reception, a regular emergency room
Or if there is an acute risk of self -harm behavior.
Call 112
I hope you have
Learned a little more about what a psychosis is for something.
Feel free to subscribe to the channel.
And as always thanks for looking!