I was going to start by asking you to tell you how you got into the thought
That you would plug in at all.
Do Ellika want to start?
My career change has been based on the fact that I want to be involved and influence more
And work on development issues, leadership issues, knowledge issues - -
And it was so important for me to do it with a high quality -
that I quickly landed in that I really want to have my feet -
If I am going to work on these types of questions.
When I with the help of coaches began to look at which courses existed
And quickly found this one, I saw that it was so wide -
And had so much of the pieces that I wanted to supplement with ...
So yeah, it was pretty obvious even though it wasn't the first thing i thought
When I thought about retraining or changing course.
But it feels like a solid foundation, and quite necessary to get a job.
Because I got these thoughts when there was time left before you got to start ...
For singers it is an age limit of 45 years
And these thoughts came to me around 43-44.
Then I asked if it was possible to talk to an adviser in advance
And it went really well.
I can recommend that -
Because it's a pretty long process.
Also to realize what one needs to do -
To enter the education with e.g.
The college exam.
Karin, how did your thoughts go before choosing a line
And start plugging at all?
I have taken quite a lot of independent courses at the university
And also through my second job as a teacher at the School of Music -
come into contact with constantly developing me skills.
It began as a reaction to me getting a mission
As course leader at the School of Music where I got more to bite in -
Even I was used to in the orchestra ditch as a fluteist.
It attracted my desire
To learn more about organization and development work.
When I then saw the opportunity with the Sok Foundation -
set it off quite a lot of thoughts, and soon I landed in -
That the staff and work life program would be exciting and fun.
An exciting education
With all different orientations.
The interdisciplinary in it.
Since then I have always been curious about what is happening
On the second floor of the opera where the HR persons sit-
And pondered a lot around ...
... how to work in an organization by raising the level, to develop
And what skills are available to take advantage of.
So precisely the HR perspective has been with me for many years.
So when the chance came, it was very easy to want to go there.
There is an old prejudice or thought that one cannot plug
And learn new after 20 years of age.
In order to learn a language -
Should you start at three and be finished at eighteen-
Then you cannot acquire new knowledge.
Do you feel that it is a correct analysis, do you want to start, Karin?
Yes, that analysis feels old -fashioned in our society where learning is needed everywhere.
The entire digital revolution in society requires learning
And a constant flexibility and openness to change.
Plugging at 20 is perhaps still the most common
But far from the only thing.
I think a lot has happened in recent years
when it comes to who is plugging in the university.
You can read 1,000 pages course literature in English
Yes, the psychology book was 1 & nbsp; 001 pages in English.
It is clear that there is a certain difference
But both age categories have their advantages and disadvantages.
I bump the question to you, Ellika, with with the addition
That as an opera singer is regularly studied new works.
It is also a form of learning.
Yes, you have with you that you have been in a profession where you constantly learn new
So I wasn't so worried about it.
What I want to add is ...
There is a quote by David Bowie that I now don't remember
But it is about aging about - about -
That you become more and more the one you are intended to be.
It's so nice, because it's about why you plug.
The older you get, the more your choice is about who you are
And what abilities you have.
Many people start their song and music career very young ...
I started playing violin when I was five and from eighteen it was singing.
I bought all the concepts with holes and hair.
My choice when I was over 40 was much more based on who I have become
And I didn't buy any finished concept.
I think it is a very favorable breeding ground for learning
Learning from one's own desire and curiosity to develop.
What else should life be about when we live for so long
Should we just stagnate the older we become it is an old thinking -
From when you died at 55-60 and worn out from 40.
So it doesn't look today.
We actually have to fill our lives with something meaningful.
Learning new makes you feel more vital, and it opens new worlds.
It may happen that it takes a half hour extra to plug in certain things
But you have completely different experiences to hang it up and do it out of desire.
You should not underestimate that.
Now you are both a bit into the program.
You should plug 3.54 years -
And have done about half now.
- Lite just over.
We are in the last year.
If you were to try to do a kind before and asking ...
We start with you, Karin.
Can you describe the difference
Between what you thought and what you actually are with?
Interdisciplinary as I mentioned before
Don't be so ready for me when I applied for the program.
It has been a great opportunity to broaden one's own perspective
In a helicopter perspective over the community -
And one's role in the importance of that work.
The training has been amazing
and the opportunity to delve into the different pieces at all -
which is pedagogy, sociology, psychology and even
Finance and labor law.
It has been a lot of fun.
Did you have fears about you would not be able to do with pace
Or have enough data competence, or was there any resistance in you before?
The digital competence became alert that one must switch up
In relation to what you do when working as a musician -
And it is an important part to absorb if you are going to do a career change -
or broaden their knowledge.
There you will not get away!
It really is a necessary evil and also very fun!
I almost look like learning a new instrument
to dive into the new programs and what is required.
But otherwise also a lot of literature
And scientific articles, many times in English.
Of course it is a challenge but also very fun -
to get that challenge.
Ellika, how do you feel for what you had thought you would be able to be with
And what it looks like now?
It was a change to enter the academic world
focused on academic thinking, and to think more in terms of research.
There I had a resistance, that it wasn't just "you should learn this"
Without you to do things in a certain form, and there are rules.
It took time to get in, and I've struggled with some resistance with it.
But now I can see that the scientific structure to present things
or put forward arguments is incredibly good to have with -
Whatever you do later.
For a while I thought:
"I should not become a researcher, why do I have to be able to all these methods"
But now I can see that it is a tool for acquiring knowledge
And present materials in a credible way.
So it has been a journey for me to buy the academic approach.
I was not aware that I gave in to that angle on it.
But now I can see that it is a tool for acquiring knowledge in general.
It is easy to think that one is going to an education
To learn something, and then you are done with it.
This is rather like getting tools to learn all your life.
You have a confidence in that you are able to learn this.
I just started my first job and notice that
I have self -confidence that although there are a thousand new things at one time -
Will I be able to do it because I have managed so much these two years.
It becomes like a warm -up in being able to acquire new knowledge.
I probably had a naive idea that this would be pretty quiet.
I would take long walks in the botanical garden
And have time to write.
I had no idea how much work it was -
And how much text masses to absorb.
That being said, it is a completely different life.
One has an eight-five-five-life-
And vacant weekends.
I have not had that in my entire working life.
Getting into that rhythm is comparatively restful
But it took some time to get into how to attack so much text -
And impressions at once.
It has not been quiet!
You both come from a professional life with a high tempo
and high demands to deliver at the moment-
And you probably have a lot of expertise and knowledge in your spine.
Is there any of the work you delivered on stage
and in the orchestra ditch-
As you have use and benefit when you plug?
As a musician you have a huge discipline, otherwise you will not.
You are used to practicing independently, working together in team ...
An opera performance is based on having a goal
to reach the premiere, and to gather around that goal.
There are many pieces that I think ...
As a musician or singer, you are not really aware of everything you can.
When to gather and decide on what one wants to do
Thanks to the possibility of the SOK Foundation-
You sometimes forget that you have a lot that is positive with you.
This bit with group work in a team
Have we really worked with for so many years -
Maybe without thinking so much consciously about it.
But precisely the discipline and ability to focus
Think I'm the biggest pieces that are a big plus.
But you have to see it too, maybe get help from a counselor or coach ...
"Think of all this that you can" "Yes, just that!"
... to strengthen their self -confidence and be able to have the courage to take the step.
Did it feel scary when you took the step?
-Yes actually!
To voluntarily resign and do this instead was very big.
And many were surprised: "are you really going to do this"
"You have a great job at the opera."
But with me it would have been a longer process than you might think.
So the longing for the new was stronger than the fear of losing what I had.
How long was it scary then did it go over quickly?
Yes, but the help you get through the advisers is fantastic.
Because it needs to take its time.
One needs to live in the ambivalence
and be able to stay in the old one and feel that you might try it -
So that you do not make too quick a decision.
For me, it was important to be able to bounce the pros and cons with myself.
Because it should be sustainable too.
You should not think after three years: "What did I do"
... and longing back.
Without it, it must be a well -considered decision.
And the advisers and even a coach that helped me at the beginning
by structuring the thoughts ...
It is an invaluable help that you should not hesitate to take.
Even if one does not take the step fully
Without just wanting to nose on what help there is to get -
Is it good to contact the SOK Foundation and talk about it.
Air their thoughts.
How was it for you when you ... made the decision
It's almost that you don't remember it now.
I knew I wanted to do something else, that I needed to do something else.
I had been working for so long and was ready
That I did not want to do the same for 20 more years.
I enjoy contrasts and changes in my life
But also thinks it's hard.
It is both "A Blessing and a Curse".
Part of it is to meet the both admiration of their colleagues
And disappointment that you leave.
Admiration for daring to take the step -
and disappointment and even
a feeling of leaving -
Because you look down on it or don't think it's good enough.
That is very individual.
It's a fantastic job
But it sets certain requirements and has some restrictions.
One begins to feel that the requirements do not fit a
And that the restrictions inhibit one, and this opportunity exists ...
But it was a challenge to meet ...
Both admiration and disappointment should be respected, while at the same time being full
With his own process that I have experienced has come and gone in waves.
After all, change processes may catch up on one year later:
"Just that, I will never have a premiere or go to a staff party at the opera anymore."
Or whatever it may be.
It's a little fragile ice sometimes, and you have to allow that, I think.
Part of going through change is that it may feel uncomfortable sometimes
But it is okay.
It is a change you have chosen yourself
And there is great value in it.
But I thought about what you said about what you have with you from your professional life ...
One should not underestimate one's habit of entering a professional role
that there are very high demands on professionalism within opera.
It requires everyone to know their thing and does it in the right place at the right time.
It requires discipline and entering the professional role required right here.
You have tremendous training on that.
You can flame one second and then focus!
One should not underestimate
that it is a huge quality to have with you whatever one does -
That you are used to delivering, focusing and doing everything with quality.
Working life today also looks so different than 2025 years ago.
Then they stayed longer in the same profession.
Today it may also be about moving, making new contacts
and change employers in a completely different way - even
to change career.
It is also a big bit of what it will look like
And that it is not so strange to learn new things and plug.
I have to connect how natural it feels to change in the middle of life.
Once you do it you think: "Don't everyone want to do this"
Then you are different as people.
It is suitable for changing tracks in the middle of life.
It may not suit everyone, but I have met many who say:
"Oh, I would have liked to do. I want to get something new now"
At 4555 you have quite many years left to work, actually.
Many also have the notion that they could not plug
That it was so long since last time, and so on.
And that you often limit yourself.
But it is very much about having role models and hearing about
That you have dared to take the step.
- There are many courses ...
We are suitable for the university.
It might not fit everyone
But then there is certainly something with another type of education they want to work with.
Today there are fantastic opportunities.
Mooc massive open online courses -
Available all over the world.
Many people do not know it.
You can follow courses in New York and at various fine universities.
There is so much as one does not know
And it can be an input to expose yourself to learning new.
You can sneak tests!
-Just!
I started my career switching by plugging at half -time
And it suited me pretty well.
I got soft -start into how it was -
And feel that it actually went well.
So you can test that!
Many of one's fellow students are perhaps younger, 2025 years.
Is it a lead or disadvantage?
- We have had each other.
It has been very worthwhile I can't imagine -
How it would have been the only one over 30 among 80 people.
But you get into it in some way.
Finally, you stop thinking age.
It's like most things.
When new is so aware of it
And think about it.
But now I don't think much about it anymore.
And you find ...
It is about finding them that one cooperates well with
And it's about something other than age.
When you find them, their social security number does not matter.
Do you think the same?
- Absolutely, I recognize it.
Something that can help one when you have different age categories ...
We who have a professional career behind us, or are in the middle of it
Need to feel respect for the younger ones.
Not: "I'm my mind or so."
Having the humble attitude helps a lot, and they feel that.
The teachers also talked a lot about having a mixed class
With different ages and life experiences.
It is very rewarding.
I get such respect for the knowledge of these young people
And their point of view.
You get many perspectives with them -
that are valuable.
To get them so close.
You sit next to each other in the benches and discuss.
You get a task from the teacher and have a snack.
It depends more on who you are as a person and what attitude you have.
We define so much by age and profession in many contexts.
You do not ask "who are you" but "what do you" or even
"She's si and so old".
So if you let go of it yourself, I think you radiate something else
than that you are very fixed to it.
With a slightly higher age you can actually contribute with a calm.
I can remember myself from the age that one became very stressed out
over exams and things to be delivered.
I should not say that I have not been nervous
But you have a different experience and can't cope with everything -
And life is so complex.
So I feel that we can contribute:
"Now we do this, it will be fine. Think about this ..."
Then you can both give and take, when you contribute your experience.
Yes, that last ...
It's also so fun in this education ...
We talk so much about sociological and educational theories in the subjects
and we sit with a full working life in the back -
And can directly orient us in a theory.
Out of memory you pick up situations: "ah"
And so you look at your model and understand: "It happened there."
As a younger one, you may not have as easy to color the models as we do.
No, it becomes more abstract.
It is fantastic to have experience to hang up the new knowledge.
And when you, like us, read about working life, it's very worthwhile
Both for yourself and the surroundings that you have worked for a long time.
Actually, I think they should have requirements for work experience
on the program.
It doesn't have to be a requirement but a recommendation -
Because then you get much more out of it.
But many young people have worked.
Almost all our courses have worked a little neighbor.
It is noticeable that it makes a difference.
You who both will work with staff groups in the future ...
I know that you both have thoughts about lifelong learning and weight
because even as an employee who should not do a career exchange -
Learn in his profession.
Are there any thoughts about lifelong learning that you want to share
Karin
We have pedagogy as our depth, and it may be more about the aspect
to encourage staff in an organization -
To constantly work on their skills development.
It is clearly noticed, not least after the pandemic
How important it will be to quickly absorb new digital tools -
And adapt.
It is almost a requirement in most organizations today.
Being quick, being able to learn new and having that humility too.
Even as high in an organization you have to work
with taking up new ones.
You can't rest on your stocks.
And that one can see it as an opportunity instead of a compulsion
Yes absolutely.
Learning new is so much about changing the perspective
Or see several perspectives.
It may have been the clearest lesson -
Even in this education with many perspectives with different subject areas.
And it's fun to have the opportunity to widen the world in some way.
And also understand the context: what does the opera mean in society
And what does culture in society mean, etc.
When working at an institution you easily become like a large family
But don't really have all the perspectives you could have.
And I feel that is a lovely, fun and exciting insight.
What do you think about lifelong learning
Would you jump on a new education in 15 years
I think learning is very much about confidence
That we are happy to be a little afraid of something that we have not tried before -
And it feels uncomfortable.
Then when one bit by bit conquers something -
If you get self -confidence and dare to try new things more and more.
But sometimes you have to expose yourself, and there you have a huge experience
As a professional singer or musician, because sometimes one gets a piece -
Which is the most difficult thing done.
You don't get into it ...
And then you should over the threshold, and suddenly you can
And suddenly it's fun.
As a professional singer or musician should not be underestimated
That you have the tool to get through and cope with the resistance -
And build up self -confidence.
It's a staircase one walks uph's
All the time in life, I think.
You face new challenges -
With everything possible, and ...
We should not forget that life is constantly changing.
We have to learn what it is like to live with toddlers, teens, outdoor children
Aging parents ...
We are constantly facing such challenges in our privacy.
I don't buy that we learn best when we are young
Without I think we are made to learn and develop all the time.
We are made to meet challenges
But it is so easy to listen to the voice that says:
"I can't, it feels uncomfortable."
I don't know about how many things I thought "that's nothing to me"
And then I end up there and it was as good as any.
The resistors we have ...
It is probably a shelter in order not to expose us to whatever
But that is not always true.
If you were to be invited to a staff party at Malmö Opera
and meet colleagues who wonder:
"To plug when you have a career behind it is worth it"
"Should I do that what do you think?"
If someone asks, I think about being curious: "Dare"
Another important thing is to work with the idea of widening their network.
Not only to spend time with like -minded
And in this way also challenge itself.
To have a circle of friends with many different people and occupational categories
Have probably aroused the desire to learn and dare to take the step for me.
But ... just the courage to dare to take the step.
Many may not even think about
able to do anything other than play or sing.
Then that's one thing.
But it is also important
To see if you really want to stay for the pension in your role.
Will you be able to do it and how will it be at the end?
Many people probably think the thought that it can be pretty tough
But it does not think fully.
From that point of view you can also have a discussion.
I think it's just so taboo too.
If you raise the question, many people think: "Is there anything wrong with my game or"
It is so closely associated with the person and what you performed as a musician.
It is a fairly complex and sensitive situation.
Giving a tip where I don't know ...
But to reason and open your eyes a little.
I can imagine that many
Still, would be curious and want to ask how you feel it is.
But I think it must also come from desire or curiosity.
Working as we do means that you have to choose a lot in your life.
You have to focus.
If there is anything else as you thought:
"Wondering what it's like to work with it ..."
"I would have liked to use this side of myself more ..."
"I'm a little worn out just working on this part of my abilities ..."
... then there is something to pick up there.
Then one can start widening their picture of what this something is
By taking a lunch with someone working on it.
Like traveling to another continent: you know you want to go there but no more.
Then you start reading books, watch some movie and ask someone who has been there
And suddenly you have booked the ticket and are there.
It is such a type of process.
There is some seed in one because you do this.
You do this because you want something.
But it's all about widening, and it may take some time
Because you have been here: "How do I perform best tonight?"
It is perhaps what life has been a lot about
To make a really good performance tomorrow.
But if someone would ask: "Do you think I would be able to plug"
Yes, but God.
Yes
But you should plug something you want.
That's the thing that is the thing
And there will be doubt on the road, it does so with all the changes.
My God, however in love you are when moving together
Will you wonder what you have done.
Then you conclude that it was pretty good anyway.
It is so cool with new knowledge, it is such a kick
And you get such respect for people.
The opera world is a bit navel -gazing, you just think about what is moving in it.
For me, it has been so anyway.
But now I have seen:
"Oh, what many professions there are what a lot of knowledge people have!"
It is a kick and a humility for what the rest of the world has to offer.
Do you have something you want to add
Working in a large organization ...
After all, we have had a large organization that you have not had full insight into.
It has been fun to almost retrospectively gain understanding
for what you have been in. And so has ...
... in a way broadened views, that one sees another aspect
for example
The employer side in another way in such an education.
We had a task where we looked at the Opera's annual report.
It hit me:
"Why have I never done this I have worked here for so many years!"
It is to come in from another direction.
-Really!
You also get a different understanding of what it is like to be a manager.
It is easily happened as an employee that you do not have the full picture.
If you work within HR I really think it's important to bring
That many employees do not have the full picture.
Then it is so easy to criticize, not understand the extent and their own role.
It has been very exciting from the organizational point of view.
I agree with.
And that from a social perspective
gain more understanding of the complexity of community and organizational issues-
Which means that you no longer become as categorical.
Further perspectives are carried with you for the rest of your life.
It's a gift to have.
-Very good!
We round off the conversation with the wise words.
We thank you for joining today!
-It was fun.
Thanks!
... and wish you the best of luck in your next or current - career.
If you have changed, you still say that you are an opera singer and musician -
Or do you say that you are students or HR ...
It all depends on how the question is asked.
I'm probably a career exchanger right now.
It was a good question.
However, it is not so easy to answer.
I am still teaching at the School of Music
And last year I had a job as a HR consultant.
Then you had to enter on LinkedIn that you are a HR consultant.
Of course, it is now a period when finding your new role.
So simply it is not.
Because in soul and heart you are still musicians.
The music and culture are so close.
But it is also an opportunity to broaden it.
To be left in that too
in one way or another.
I don't know where I will eventually end up.
But hopefully you can take advantage of everything you have done
And the insights one has from the cultural world.
... with all the new.
Able to contribute in some way.
It's like being born in another country.
It is such a deep part of one's identity.
There will always be that I have been an opera singer.
There is so much who I am and have with me.
It's my "tribe" in some way.
It will be exciting we will have a follow -up call in five years.
Right.
Good idea
Thanks so much!
-Thanks!