Today I will teach you how to build your own fund portfolio super simple.
So you have something to brag about on your tinderdate.
*Slurp*
What you will learn today, it's not Rocket Science.
You don't have to be a brain surgeon or hot Einstein by surname to understand these stuff.
Saving in funds is very basic, it is something I learned when I was 19 years old.
So don't be afraid to learn to save in funds.
It is not that difficult!
Don't make it harder than it is.
So, fix yourself a cup of coffee and then we run!
For those of you who are new here, I am called Marcus, and I run the site SPARCASH.se
Savecash is for you who are a beginner and want to learn how to invest and save money in shares, funds and much more.
Is it that you want to learn more then I have lots of simple guides for beginners
So go in there and see if there is something that suits you in taste
If you want to learn something more that I have not talked or written about, feel free to tell about it!
What is a fund?
A fund is like a bag
A bag of securities simply.
It could be shares, interest rates, bonds and other things.
The reason you invest in a fund
Is in order for you to avoid having to pack up your own equity portfolio
There is a manager who controls the fund.
The fund manager decides what should be in the fund and packages it a bit like a good and mixed bag.
It's a bit so it works when you invest in funds.
There is another person who picks up a bag for you and you buy a little bit out of the bag.
Then you get to harvest the good inside the bag.
What is so good about funds is that you can save monthly in them
You can save monthly in funds with a very small sum
Some funds require as little as 1 kroner for you to invest in them
But with shares you need to have the sum that the share costs
Most funds usually require 100 to 200 SEK in the smallest purchase amount
If you automatically save monthly in the fund, it is usually a lower amount than that.
Some funds, as I said, require as little as SEK 1 even.
It is not required so much for you to invest in funds
So every month you receive pay, then you deposit a small amount of money right into your various funds
For example, I save in 8 different funds right now.
I replace my funds once in the quarter to once in the half year
I see that one fund is going a little bad and another fund is going a little better
Then I replace it worse with the better fund!
It is not more difficult than that;)
Funds, have a risk level
At the level of risk you can see how much money you can expect to earn
The higher the risk, the higher the chance of making more money investing in the fund
Very many out there have low -risk funds
These low -risk funds are usually fixed income funds.
You may know that we have a fairly low interest rate today in Sweden?
So, it's not so good to have these short -term funds and fixed income funds overall.
Because you don't get much return on them.
And if there is also a fee on the fund, it may be that you go back on your investment in the fixed income fund.
This is Swedbank's most popular fixed income fund in February 2020.
As you see in 3 years, it has given you -0.54%
And in 5 years it has given you -0.77%
I really don't understand how people can have stuff like this in their portfolios
Is it that you have fixed income funds or know someone who has it
Then think about replacing them to a savings account with higher interest rates or similar
When I choose funds, I personally am not a big fan of low -fee funds.
I like active funds.
It's because I'm an active investor, I like to replace my funds on and off.
If you are a passive investor then index funds may be better suited for you.
Index funds have become a bit like a sect, to chase low fees.
The truth is not quite as people say
If you pull out the savings horizon of 30-40-50 years then the fees play a role, it does.
But in the short term, 3-5 years, you see that active funds beating passive index funds.
I like them, I would rather have a little more return and pay for it with a fee.
Then of course one must have common sense
A fund that costs over 2% may not be reasonable
When you look at the tax return in these graphs, the fee is deducted
So think about it when you look at history through historical returns in funds, that the fees are always deducted.
What funds are good for a beginner?
The absolute best for you if you don't have a savings already
The easiest gateway to begin and learn more about funds and shares
It is to buy the free funds available
Avanza Zero, and Nordnet Index Fund Sweden.
The good thing about these funds is that they are completely free, it costs nothing for you.
It doesn't cost to buy and it costs nothing running either.
So these two funds are perfect for those who want to get started
My tip to you who are a beginner for those who want to get started and save in one of these free funds
Put in SEK 100 into each of these two free funds
Then you test and see if anything happens to your hundreds
Then you can follow them here two funds and then you can compare them to each other
What is the difference between these two funds and what makes them go up and what makes them go down?
These two funds are Swedish funds so they follow Swedish shares
so you don't have to select your own shares to invest in
So it is perfect for you who are beginners to get started with
These funds follow an index and so -called passive index funds
Passive index funds are something that very many people like as they have very low fees
The fees give you more money in your pocket in the long run
So over time the money will go to you and not to the bank
That's what is the great thing about these free funds.
What funds shouldn't you buy if you are a beginner?
You should not buy any high -risk funds that you have no control over.
Do an analysis first.
Do not go into, for example, emerging land funds
As for example, when I was little
so my mother bought Russia funds for me without even knowing
without knowing the effect with it
and to invest in Russia can be good, but
you need to know what effect it has
And in this case there was very high risk
and that was when Russia stood on a top
Then the Russian Fund went down
Then someone chose to sell my Russia funds ...
It's a tip for you, choose a slightly wider fund from the beginning if you are new
Then when you start to get a little more comfortable with saving in funds
Then maybe you can pick out the slightly gullier funds
When you know a little more and have a little more meat on the legs simply
- So choose a wider fund first.
So now I have gone through a lot of basic stuff for you who are a beginner.
Is it that you like this video
And want to learn more and get to know others who are beginners
So I want to tell you to join our Facebook group
Which is just about saving in shares and funds for beginners
Link is below
Is it that you like this type of videos and want to see more of it?
Then give me a thumbs up!
And you get a great subscribe to the channel
So I hope to see you in the next video and thank you so much for watching this one.
So have a good time and we'll see you, hello!