In this video I will teach you to buy shares. Perfect for beginners!
Hi my name is Marcus and I'm the one running SparaCash!
SparaCash is a site for those who want to learn more about investing in stocks, mutual funds and much more.
Perfect for you who are beginners and for those who are new to investing your money
So subscribe to this channel and go to SparaCash.se if you want to learn more
Now let's get going with this video
Buying shares is pretty easy
I would almost say it is easier today to buy shares than to go to Ica and buy snickers.
So why do you want to own shares?
Well, that's partly to make money.
When you buy shares you buy part of a company.
What this means is that you actually have the right to influence this company.
You thus own a small part of the company and thus become a shareholder.
When you are a shareholder you have the right to receive a portion of the profits that this company makes.
Not all companies distribute their profits
But many of them do, especially the larger, more stable companies.
So every year or every quarter you can see their profits
That may increase over time
That will make you more money over time as the company makes more profit
So over time you can make quite a lot of money investing in stocks
Another benefit is that over time as the company makes more money
So hopefully the price of the shares will increase
So when it's time to sell, you sell with a pretty big profit, and there you can make money, too.
Smart eh? (͡ ° ͜ʖ ͡ °)
This is one of the advantages of buying shares.
There are also disadvantages to buying shares
Keep in mind that it is a pretty high risk
So there is a chance that you will lose money as well
If so, you do not really know what type of stock you are buying
Among other things, the company can go bankrupt, and then you can lose your entire investment
It may not be likely that the company will go bankrupt, but there is still a chance, think about it!
When you invest in shares, it goes up pretty quickly, and down pretty quickly.
It is high risk as I said, so keep in mind that you can lose money pretty quickly.
It was a little short on stocks, so I think we will jump into the next topic to take us one step closer to how to buy stocks
And the next step to buy shares is to have an account.
You must therefore have a bank account on which you can buy shares.
And what I recommend is that you have an account at Avanza Bank, or Nordnet Bank.
There are two stock brokers that are focused on buying and selling shares
And makes it pretty easy for you to trade shares through
These two brokers make it free for you to buy shares on the Stockholm Stock Exchange.
So if you are a new customer you can trade shares without a commission up to SEK 50,000 versus SEK 80,000.
When you are a new customer, completely free of charge.
However, be aware that this is about shares on the Stockholm Stock Exchange
Check which list the stock is listed on
Before you buy your shares for the first time.
So it really is free of charge without this commission fee.
Once you have registered an account to buy and sell shares at such a bank
Yes, then you are ready for the next step!
Now that you have an account registered with an online broker
it's time for the next step - and it's opening a tax scale.
Thus, a small box in which to store your shares or funds.
When you register with Avanza or Nordnet, it is almost always the case that a Share &amp; Fund account is opened
And it is the usual traditional type where you estimate 30% on the profit.
You will also be asked if you want to open an investment savings account or capital insurance.
The most common thing today when trading Swedish shares is that you have them in an investment savings account.
Is it that you want to know more about how these different account types work,
So I link to an article below on SparaCash that easily explains the difference between these three.
But in this guide I recommend that you use an ISK. Now we move on to the next step.
Find Shares - Which stock should you buy?
After all, you have to make an active choice for the type of stock you are interested in buying.
And then you might be thinking
Should I have Swedish shares?
US stocks?
Dividend Stocks?
Investment company shares?
And it's pretty hard to know
There are a bunch of different stocks.
It is quite difficult to choose which type of shares to hold.
Avanza and Nordnet have different stock lists
So you can filter out and check
And think about which stock suits you well
For example, you can filter by how many people own this stock
Or, how good the share has been for 3 months, 3 years or other.
And there you can then make a choice yourself.
Based on which stock you are interested in.
What I usually advise beginners about is to buy investment companies.
It is a company that in turn invests in other companies.
Examples of two common investment companies are Investor and Industrivärden.
Is it that you do not feel ready to buy shares? It's totally calm!
Then you might be able to read a book about stocks instead, and start by buying a fund instead.
Once you decide which stock to buy
Then also think about, how long should you own the share?
When should you choose to sell this stock?
Or should you own the stock all the time, ie for life?
It's up to you to decide!
Now it's time for us to buy shares!
So I was going to show you how it goes ;-)
If you are not already a customer at Avanza, there is a link below
you can click on Avanza and register.
Then you just have to honk and drive.
So now we jump into how to buy shares on Avanza
So I'll start by logging in and clicking here on the search box
Then I search for a share that I have which is Plejd.
Then we click on Plejd, so
Then we press Buy.
Now I show the simplified purchase box on the computer of a share.
So if you click on settings here
Then you see that you can choose a simplified view or a standard view.
But now I think we will start with the simpler stock view of how to buy and we will go through it
First you have an account
It is therefore which (share) account you want to buy shares on.
Here you get up, for example your regular AF account which we see here at the bottom.
Or your investment savings account, if you don't have one then open one.
Or a capital insurance.
I choose to buy shares in my long-term investment savings account
Here I already see how many shares I have in this account
And then you see your average price, ie your purchase price.
If you do not already have the share, it will only say Number in the account: 0
In amount, you enter how much you want to buy shares for.
In my case we say SEK 100.
What Avanza does then is that in Number it automatically fills in
How many shares you can afford to buy, for the amount you have entered.
In the former field.
And it also pre-fills what it costs to buy the shares
Yes, a share is currently priced at Pledge 72.20.
As it has pre-filled here
From SEK 100 for which I wanted to buy shares, it has automatically counted down to SEK 72.
Now I see here that I had order terms opened
and it's something we can remove
To buy these shares, I just press buy.
I find it rather ironic that I make the same mistake that I myself have talked about NOT doing.
If you know what a mistake it is I make a comment below 🤦
There they went through and I have now bought 1 share in Plejd.
If we scroll down, we see here during the End of the Day
That we have bought shares in Plejd.
It was no more difficult than that
Awesome, now I've shown you how to buy shares
So now it's up to you to have patience
Keep in mind that stocks have a high risk
So think about how long you will own them
And it is recommended that you have shares for at least 3-5 years
Or that you see it as a savings horizon to
Money you invest in shares is money you should manage to be without for 3-5 years at least.
Think about it, keep in mind that it will swing a lot. It goes up a lot and it goes down a lot.
So be patient now that you have these shares.
So I hope you learned something about this video
And if you did, feel free to give me a thumbs up
And please subscribe to the channel in case you want to see more of these types of videos
And is there anything more you wonder about?
As I may not have answered in this video, please leave a comment below
So I can answer it
Have a look at SparaCash.se, there are certainly more guides you can learn from
if so, you want to learn more about investing
So thank you for watching this video I hope we see you next, ciao!