Something I come across are many beginners who are unsure when to buy and sell stocks.
Before you buy your first shares, it can be good that you know common mistakes
as many others do, including me!
These are 5 common mistakes that beginners make when buying stocks for the first time.
Hi, my name is Marcus Lindblad and I run SparaCash.se
You are probably a beginner and want to get started and buy and sell stocks.
I do not want you to make the same leap as many others actually do.
I'm listening to a podcast called AvanzaPodden (very good podcast)
AvanzaPodden has a facebook group where I asked the question
what are the common mistakes when buying stocks
If you want to read more tips about mistakes, I link to the thread below
I have also made a post about it on SparaCash.se which you can also read
so the question I asked was: What are the biggest mistakes you made when you started investing?
1. To have the wrong brokerage class (courtageklass) and to get a loss immediately when buying the stock
When you buy shares, there is something called brokerage
Brokerage is the fee for when you buy a share
You also pay brokerage when you sell a share, ie a sales fee.
When you register on, for example, Avanza or Nordnet
Then you get to choose which brokerage class you want to be in
The first common mistake beginners make is to choose the wrong brokerage class
When they buy shares for the first time, they do not think that it costs a fee to buy shares
and this purchase fee can be so large that it eats up a large part of your investment
So let's say you invest SEK 1,000, then it's stupid to pay SEK 30 in brokerage (purchase fee)
When you become a new customer at Avanza, you get SEK 50,000
and up to SEK 80,000 on Nordnet to buy shares for no brokerage at all
The brokerage class is important, make sure you have the right brokerage class before you buy and sell shares.
Mistake number 2 is to buy a company of hope.
For example, pharmaceutical companies, cancer research, and similar stocks that make new issues after new issues.
This simply means that many of these companies can be found out through share groups on Facebook and the like
There are often quite hyped companies that may not even make a profit
suit yourself for them, it is quite easy to burn yourself on such stocks
It is simply believed that they should make one completely magically rich or the like
Beware of them, wait a bit until you get more meat on your bones by buying shares before you go into them.
If it is the case that you choose to buy a research company or something else
go in with a very small amount that you can afford to lose because you can very easily burn yourself on them
k3. Trade with leverage too early before you understand how it works.
I have done this and this is how I lost two months' salary at a very young age.
When I was 19 years old, I did this, and that was right after taking the student
Then it hurts quite hard to lose two months' salary on trying to trade and play some kind of guru
Trading with leverage means that you trade with borrowed money
Let's say you buy a leverage product such as Bull OMX x15
Bull means that you believe in rise and bear means that you believe in decline
Let's say then that you buy a Bull OMX x15
Then you think OMX will go up
and is it the case that OMX goes up 1% then you earn 15% (in x15)
BUT! if it is the case that what you invest in goes down -1%
then your position will instead go down -15%!
so it is a lever, so there will be a greater effect upwards or downwards
so I want to give you a big warning finger for that
another mistake that Andreas Hansson has suggested
and that is not having the patience to keep the good companies you have actually managed to buy
this is something that I personally recognize myself in very much
when you have bought a share and it is going well, dare to keep it then
Many people want to sell a stock straight away if it goes down a little bit.
Think long term. How long do you want to own this stock? How long do you want to invest this money?
This is a lesson that many beginners will learn that they take home the profits crazy too soon.
Not having the patience to ride the train.
Do you feel that you want to sell and take home some profit in a share?
Then instead think about whether you should sell half of your investment
or if you are just going to sell your investment and keep the return you received on the shares.
5. Play with money you need or plan to use soon.
that one does not think long-term.
Let's say that it's money you need in a short time and you just want to quickly make it increase in value
let's say you need to buy a car within a month or so.
you may then think that you can make the money increase in value by investing it in stocks or something similar.
But you have to take care of it because it's easy to get burned and lose that money
when dealing with this type of trade
Do not try to make your money grow incredibly fast in order to
because it goes incredibly fast in stocks and that is the danger, that you can lose money in a very short time.
by believing that you can speculate in the right direction
so stay away from it :)
So many of these mistakes I also recognize myself in
I want you to read through the mistakes carefully if you are a beginner in stocks
Take it a little careful. Do not be afraid to dare to invest but be a little careful about -how much- you invest.
It is important that you do not postpone your investments either
Take a small amount that you invest each month
If you do not feel that you are a typical active investor, then choose funds instead of investing in shares.
These were a couple of common beginner mistakes that most people have made
Thank you so much for watching this video, I'm glad you've come this far.
Feel free to give a thumbs up if you like this type of video.
Feel free to give a thumbs down if you do NOT like it. And feel free to give criticism because I welcome it.
I want to learn and get better at this.
Good luck with your investments and I hope to see you in the next video!