Tjena My name is Marcus & I Driver SpareCash.se
VoiceOver: In today's video I thought about telling us why I started SpareCash
And how I started with stocks
I think you will find it interesting if it is so that you recognize it in what it is like to be
Beginner
And how to feel paralyzed and unaware of why one should invest
Money and how shares and funds work simply
The point of this video it to show you
Exactly how much more you will be able to learn after you have taken hold of learning how it works with
Investment.
Investments that I always complain about involves risk.
But the risk is
Other thing when talking about life not to invest your money in shares funds
Without risk generally in life
And when we talk about risk
Then I want to back the tape
To the year 2013
The year is
null
The same year Jimmie Åkesson gets
Cake in the face
Usain Bolt
Continues to run home gold
And I take the student.
During this summer I get a summer job at the post 'Okay what the hell it's a horse here'
Tjenare * laughs * what the hell
This money I saved
What would I do with them
Yes
I knew one could invest the money in any way
In shares or funds
But how does it really work?
I had no idea how it
In fact, works
I had no one in my family
That could teach me about shares and funds
I was told
One could save the money in shares
But I had no one who could learn how it actually
Works
So
What do you have to do then
Grab yourself of course
And if you google funds and shares where you end up
Well, of course
Flashback
And that's why I then chose to invest in Avanza Zero
A free fund at Avanza
I create an account at Avanza and I have
No clue
What the hell
I was doing
And my point is to say that
It is not so important to
Know how it
Works without the important thing here
It is to actually put
Running
And that's what I'm
So happy about
Look back that I
Actually did it
That I actually dared to take that risk
To dare to invest my money
One does not have to be a brain surgeon to invest or save their money
So if it is so that you are
Just as I was
7 years ago
You may be alone and you have no one in your family or family who can teach you how
it actually works with stocks o funds
Internet is yours
Best friend
And that is why I started saving cash
Because I want to
That one as a beginner
Be able to find easy to read
and easy to understand information
And that's why I started with this one
the youtube channel so we do this in video format
So that you can easier
Able to understand how it goes when one
investing their money
And why it is so incredibly important
I know this may be a bit strange video and maybe not usually do but
I just need to say then I need some background about how I actually started
To
Not everyone is born with the knowledge of investing their money but also if you are a beginner so
Will you learn it only takes some time
But dare to get started
Because otherwise you will never learn.
Thank you so much for watching this video I hope to see you in the next