Earn Now I'm back again with a video about my investments
There are quite a few of you who are interested
As many as 3,500 of us are subscribers to the channel
It's totally sick
And that many of you are curious about how I invest and how I think with my portfolio
So in this video, I thought I'm going through mine
Finance type or how I.
Structures up
My portfolio
And for those of you who are new here, my name is
Marcus Lindblad
I run SparaCash
and SparaCash.se is
a website I started four years ago
And with goals and to teach beginners how to invest in stocks, mutual funds,
And much more
And that is exactly what we are going to go into
In this video
I think a little short so I will give an overview
To you about what it looks like how I think
Every month
Around my money simply
So
Every month
I kind of have not
Keep an eye on my finances if I am to be honest
So money is not that fun!
So it's fun to have money
But it's not so fun to sit and measure every number
and count on every single sausage but what I do
It is that I have a document, a so-called "spreadsheet" as it is called.
And in this spreadsheet or yes
Exceldocument
So I enter exactly how much each month
my money is worth it
This takes just over a quarter of an hour
Much like me
do every month
Then I enter
How much money do I have on Avanza
How much money do I have on Savelend
How much money do I have in my savings account at the bank
How much money do I have in Bitcoin
All these different parts I enter and update
To keep track of what it's worth right now.
So that I get an overview of approximately how much money I have in different places
But also what it is that increases and what it is that decreases in value.
Because then I know if I should put in a little more money somewhere else
And yes then we come in
My portfolio and my rules
And I usually have as a small rule of thumb like that
Just over
80%
Out of all
Money I have
80% of all my money I try to have invested
So that they increase in value or them
May work in any case
And that is my long-term investment
In for example
Stocks, mutual funds and cryptocurrencies and such
That's about 80% of my total personal finances
20%
The remaining part (20%) is for more short-term savings.
Short-term This means that they do not have to lie Cash or in cash in the mattress
It could be that I have them in a savings account with a little interest or I invest them in
P2P loan on Savelend or Mintos or something else
And it's simply money
Who is a little safer who may not have such a high risk if it is the case that I want
Put them in
Shares in case the stock market goes down a lot or I vettifan ...
The refrigerator may break and then you can have some money there to use
In case, yes, unforeseen events simply happen!
So if we start from the bottom
And then we start with the most boring, that is, the short-term
Then I drive on one
Savings account with interest
And then the complete bank has a savings account
with 0.85% interest (right now)
per year
It's not that much but it's still more than you
get in a regular savings account
In other words
At the bank, you usually get 0% interest today, so it is good that you use it, perhaps completely, for example
or Avanza bank which also has (savings account with interest)
And there you can also unlock the money
on complete, there is no binding time
without
No, as you can get the money
Anytime but on Avanza
so you can also unlock the money but I do not like to unlock mine
Savings without
They want me to lie there moving if I need to take them off
Then I also have a little bit in it
Peer to peer loans
At Savelend
and on Mintos
And yes it is so that you invest in credit
And myself
Personally consider
Investing in private loans and credits has a slightly lower risk than the stock market
I think that
Where I invest in those, it is reliable
And it's not as shaky as having the money on the stock market, for example
So I consider it my little one
Short-term buffer savings
where I may not need to take off right now
But in case I urgently need money
So I would rather take from there than my shares
And then we have
the meaty part of my portfolio
And that is then my investments in
Shares, mutual funds and cryptocurrencies, &amp; other goodies
So I'm gonna jump into my little portfolio here now
And then we'll look
What I have for good
in good
So in my long-term portfolio
It exists right now
out of four shares
It's Castellum, Mycronic,
It's Plejd
and that's Sinch
Then I have some funds
And then I have Avanza World Tech by TIN, BGF World Technology
DNB
Technology
Jpm China
Spiltan equity fund investment company
Spiltan Small Company Fund
Swedbank Robur new technology and TIN New Technology
So right now what will be the eight funds This is my long-term portfolio
I try to hold the shares a little longer
So I do not go in and poke so much
Without being allowed to lie there and indulge if I think so
that they are in a positive trend or whatever you say
So they go up
Then they can lie there
I trick the funds a little more often
I always have a monthly saving of SEK 1,000 a month that goes directly into the funds
And sometimes if I feel that yes but now the funds have gone well
And I need to buy some more shares
or I WANT to buy a little more shares
Then maybe I will sell some fund that I think has not gone as well as I expected
And then I buy more shares
And then during the year I deposit
a slightly larger amount to when I buy shares
Yes, but then I want to buy
for a slightly larger amount than I do in mutual funds
Funds, there are hundreds of notes that go into each fund
these are not such large sums, but in the shares I may trade for SEK 1,000 up to SEK 5,000
More than So if it is that I feel
that I want as well
Then I have an experiment account that I started with
And that's my endowment insurance
Foreign endowment insurance
And here I have then
thought
That I will invest in dividend shares and that has probably been the case
I have three shares there right now and that is Cibus
Innovative Industrial Properties
And Realty Income Corp
These are the 3 shares I have in there
So now we come to the part where we talk about the middle ground
What I have done through the ages so I have only bought cryptocurrencies for fun
Because I think it's interesting to keep track of
So I have a little bit of a slur in cryptocurrencies just because it's fun
And exciting if it goes up or down
And then I used two brokers called Binance
and Coinbase
Coinbase to buy Bitcoin on
and Binance to buy shitcoins as we call them
Generally speaking, with my investments I do it mostly to
I think it's funny
And money that you do not need they think I should grow
And is it the case that you have money
on their savings account (with 0% interest) they lose in value because we have inflation and we get no interest on the money
So prices are rising
And the value of yours
Decreases when you have them in a savings account
Precisely in kronor, they may not
Goes down
but because prices are rising
and you do not get any interest on your money
So in the long run
Then it will be like that
Your money loses value
In times like these when the stock market has gone up quite a lot even though we have a pretty
Shaky year (2020)
Well then maybe I'm a little more passive or right now I'm a little more passive
I stock up on a little more savings
If it is so that it shakes a little, so that you can jump in and fish a little at the bottom
It is very rare to hit the bottom, but it is still good to dare to buy when others are worried
and sells
when it is at its reddest on the stock market that is when you should actually buy
for that is when you make real bargains as well
And that's how I think
Quite a few complicate this so much
and make it so cumbersome for themselves
it is not that difficult to invest your money and you do not have to understand everything
But it's enough to have a sense of what
Type you invest in
you do not have to think so much more than that
Without having a savings
Which you always activate every month
Make money all the time
And that's what I do
late
Do not bother about it so much but it is more important to
you are actually saving money
than that you try as well as that yes
Bargain and find something
Super good company
Like here and there
which will give you triple the money in one month is very rarely done
Without it in the long run you will make the big bucks
This is something I're nagging about all the time.
I know it's very boring though
It is more important that you save
than that you do not save
so it is that you do not have
Started investing so Yes but I add links to everything I invest in below
Follow them and like
There are no buy recommendations what I have invested in though
Many of you are nagging and want to know what I have so
That's why I'm making this video
Is it that you want to know more about
For example, how I think about the stock market
Feel free to follow me on Instagram
(SparaCash)
And
Would love to join the group 'Shares and funds for beginners' if it is the case that you
have any questions
There we can gather and gather
together a community where We learn from each other
So there we can ask questions completely free none
Questions are stupid
What are you investing in? I would very much like to know. Feel free to write a comment below
what shares and funds you have!
and who you believe in
And I just want to thank you for now we are
3500 subscribers to this channel is completely sick
So it has gone so fast
I really want to thank you who subscribe to this channel
So it's a lot of fun
And
In the long run, I have little plan for how we can make this channel even better
What kind of material we can publish in the future
Do you have any suggestions
So feel free to write a comment below because I write it down and I plan quite far
Ahead
But thank you so much for watching I hope you learned something with this video
Hope to see you in the next video
Have a good one
Hello