Hello you!
today, we're going to talk about mutual funds.
We thought we'd address this
battle between active funds
and passive funds.
Which fund should you choose for
your savings?
I have taken help from a
guest who knows this
funds and we will clarify the
issue for you to find out
what to choose for your savings
and if you didn't know
, my name is.
Marcus Lindblad and I
run save cash and save
cash is for you who want to
learn how to save in shares
funds and much more so
we will go through it
What is an active fund?
What is a passive index fund?
Which ones have gone the best and which ones
should you save?
Then we have Johanna with us here
who is a guest and we are going
talk about active and passive index funds.
But can't you introduce
yourself a bit like that
viewers get to know who you are?
Great, thanks for letting me be
here on your channel and talking about mutual funds.
After all, I then work as a saver
for them at the fund companies
association and it is a
trade organization as a whole
simple seems too.
Healthy fund industry in the
interest of savers and my role as
thrift economist is that
inform and educate
consumers about funds and fund savings.
And I do that by blogging,
lecturing and so I try
to present
interesting facts about
savings and funds in particular
many different channels that as
I can.
But Johanna,
if you explain just a little
Briefly,
what is an active equity fund?
An active equity fund is a fund
where managers,
administrator or the administrator
is active in.
The selection of which shares
should be included in the fund,
so it is simply that
the trustees they do their
analysis and they examine which
companies that they believe in the most and
that they believe have the best
potential for a high
return in the future.
And they are the ones they choose
to include in the fund.
If we take just one example
, we can say that it is a technology fund
which is actively managed.
Then the manager will try to
find the technology companies like them
most believe in and include them in the portfolio.
Sometimes maybe even
go and meet the companies too
to understand the business.
They talk to management.
Yes, they are simply active in the
selection of these funds
and an active fund usually,
but not always , costs
more than an index fund because
the managers and they have to
get paid for this
work that they do.
But it is also the active
funds that can provide that
is called excess return and
it means that the fund
develops better than the
comparison index that the fund here.
This means that active funds.
They can be worth a higher
price if you find a good one
managers who deliver
this excess return
and the other fund types
index fund that instead follows
an index
and then you can wonder,
say, what is an index?
Well,
that shows something
value development time for
a composite number of shares
over a specific period of time.
And one
thing that I really want to point out.
Mediu's index management
an index fund does not
automatically mean that you have one
lower risk, without
there are indexes that have a
high risk and then there are
index that has a
lower risk.
Everything depends
which index the fund
chooses to follow for it exists
any number of different indexes
and because then that this fund
chooses to follow an index
and does not make any active choices
then so can this
administration fee
much lower,
but that also means that
man as saver
should expect a
return that is
in line with the index.
And I also want to point out
that this return
as reported
it is always reported after
fees so that
you, as a saver, should not hold
on and count anyone out
fee without
it being shown after fee.
So it is that it is
very easy to actually
compare how different funds have performed.
But if you are now saved and
thinking because you are talking
after all, quite a lot about
passive index funds being suitable
most of them and
some others say that active
equity funds are much better
and give better returns.
What should you really choose?
I don't think there is
a certain one
type that is best for all
savers in all types of
situations, but I think both
active management and
index management fulfill their purpose
function and
when you choose which
form of savings you want to have
should you include several different
factors in your decision-making process,
so it cannot be said that.
This particular type suits
all types of savers
then there are certain
shapes that fit a lot of savers,
but I think that man
you must include several different
criteria when choosing
which fund
you should have in your savings.
So if you look at the statistics
and data on these different funds,
which ones have gone the best?
If you check whether you should
say this,
we are on the form association
for no statistics like this ourselves.
But morningstar has a
statistics bank with mass
various statistics where I
found these numbers
and for the category Sweden shares
so painting shows that 42%
of active funds beat
its comparison index during
a year
and over 10 years the same
figure was 28% so that
it is clear that there are
active funds that manage to beat
its comparative index over time.
But not everyone
beats the benchmark.
So who is an active equity fund suitable for?
Yes, I think that active
equity funds can suit anyone
which is
a little more interested in his
fund saving and can think
themselves to be
somewhat more active than those who want to
maybe start a
monthly savings and then
forget about it completely
ii maybe twenty thirty years too
if you choose an actively managed
fund, I think that
might be good to log in
sometime sometimes and and
check how this fund has
developed don't you think
still with the trustee
regarding the management
philosophy or have you changed
you and has the fund performed
as you thought it would
would do.
Ok but
passive index funds then who
would save in such.
A passive index fund it is
really a very simple one
savings form that suits
most people and if you choose one
index fund, you can usually
be sure that you will not pay
unnecessarily high fees.
But you also won't get
a return that is better than
the particular index that you have
chosen to follow.
But here it is also important to
remember that
not all indexes are the same and
your fund will evolve
as the index you have chosen
to follow.
But then I also do
n't think that but one
management group necessarily has to fit
just a certain type of
investors but
I think you can choose both
active funds and passive
funds in their portfolio.
Because I myself save in both
active and passive funds
perhaps it is that you think
a passive fund is suitable for
a certain market
meanwhile. You want an actively
managed fund to come
for a different type of industry.
Then I
actually got a few viewer questions.
First question is from Jimmy,
what is the purpose of having one
passively managed index fund?
except cheaper fee.
Yes, but the purpose is to be able
to follow a specific index
as that is how you want the exposure
against this particular index so that
you don't want any others
deviations from this index
, so perhaps you as a saver
think it is unnecessary
to have an actively managed fund
who make a little more active
decisions if you are still alone
interested in getting that particular
exposure as the index
gives it.
Karlsson asks,
what should a fund portfolio look like?
Yes, that is a very difficult
question actually because
fund portfolios can look
very, very different and
There is no right or
wrong here.
You can have
bond funds, you can have hedge funds,
you can have
lot of different
kind of fund types and if you
as a saver should see which one
fund portfolio you should have yourself
that's how I think when you're
new
which savers should start by
looking at.
What type of risk you are looking
for and from there check
which fund types to choose
and try to think about bringing
in some diversification and
maybe start with them
a little wider the funds that
usually invest in many
thousands of companies.
Machine investment asks is
it good to have only active
funds with high risk if you
save for the long term?
Yes, it's a bit of a clever question
because I don't think so
As I said, there are some right and
wrong when it comes to saving.
So If you are comfortable that you
have taken
high risk and that you have chosen active
funds, I don't think
there is any problem with that.
If you feel safe in it
and you believe in your trustees
I don't see any problem
with that
later and if it is in the long
term as you say, it can
after all, also have time to make
changes in this saving.
Out, because time goes by and
the conditions maybe
change and and you change
your philosophy,
philosophy and your savings.
Then we have a question from Adam Glimsell,
which fund should one invest in
for decent short-term savings?
Yes, that is a bit difficult with what
you mean by decent
short-term savings.
After all, there are fund types that
have lower risk.
That's where the bond funds end up
and mixed funds end up
just below pure equity funds.
And that is usually
seen as guidelines
a couple of years
when talking about bond funds.
But there is a risk with
bond funds too,
so it is not risk-free to
save in bond funds
so it depends entirely on what you
feel saves that you are
prepared to lose and
what this money is meant for
so if you talk about a
year from now, you would probably say that you
don't need to save in funds
, but then it can be good to
deposit it into a savings account.
But otherwise about which
fixed income funds exist and about
you think you can get some
return in this
the interest rate meeting that we have.
And then it is the Financial Council children
who have asked a question
so and they ask how
likely it is that a
actively managed fund beats
index over the long term?
Yes, that's it, there are
studies like morningstar
have done
over how
actively managed funds have gone
over time and what they have
found is that it depends
pretty much
what category they've looked at,
so there seems to be some
kind of categories there
actively managed funds
is slightly more likely to
beat its benchmark.
But I don't have pure
concrete figures as to why
probability exists, without
there I think that as a
saver you have to bring your own
own thoughts about the future and
which sectors you believe in
or which themes you
believe in instead of
jumping on something that is
trendy right now.
Thank you so much Johanna for
wanting to join in and answer
on our questions about funds.
Big, thanks for letting me be
here with you and talk about mutual funds.
Thank you so much, Johanna,
for wanting to join in
answer questions about funds
and I hope that you as
looking has received answers to your
questions and so I hope that
see you in the next video have a good time.