Hey!
Hello!
There you should look, not there.
Okay sorry.
Now we will run a review of our share portfolios from the month of September.
And as you can see, we are in a different place.
A year ago we were in Spain and where are we now?
Now we are on the island of Paros in Greece.
Jajamän.
So we jump into the Avanza overview.
Like that then.
How was your September show my month?
Who should we start with?
We'll start with mine, I think.
We'll start with yours, okay.
Your total value decreased by?
SEK 22,356.
But I have also deposited 5,000.
So it actually decreased by SEK 27,735.
Wow!
That is a lot of money.
Yes it is.
So we'll check mine then.
View my month.
Your total value decreased by SEK 28,976 in September.
But I have deposited 21,000 kroner.
So really, I'm down 50,000 kroner in September.
Yes, there will be almost 80,000 of us back together.
Ah shit then.
That is a lot of money.
And.
It was an expensive vacation.
The month before then.
For you, it was yes.
SEK 4431 back.
So September was worse then August.
Yes, of course.
And mine was 37,000 in development.
Or yes, SEK 33,000 in value change then.
Because I made a deposit there.
But we look ahead.
Exactly.
So we'll see what we come up with now.
This is how your development looked like.
Minus.
Minus 3.10 percent.
We'll see what yours is up to then.
Yes, a little down there at the end.
Yes, my curve looks worse.
Minus 4.6 percent.
But then we will also point that out as well.
That the savings offices are included in this.
Exactly.
And I have quite a lot.
Or a large part of my portfolio is in a savings account.
So it probably also affects my numbers.
Yes exactly.
I have a little splash on my buffer there.
But yes.
The month before.
1.07 percent.
And for me minus 3.36.
Damn, you should take other of my money instead.
I know, I can take over and save cash.
Yes, may I do that.
Okay, next one then.
Okay, then we'll see.
I'm behind 1.07 and Avanza average is behind 2.9 percent.
So it is still better then the average.
Yes, much better than the stock market now.
And we'll see my portfolio.
Minus 3.36 and.
Minus 2.9 so worse than the average.
And worse than the stock market.
No, now it's the month before.
No.
And and.
We want September.
Yes exactly.
Yes, then we check September.
Yes, but there I was 3.10 percent behind.
And the average for Avanza was 3.18.
So something better then.
Yes, but exactly.
And I'm slightly worse again.
Okay, let's check the next slide.
Yes.
Then it was Volvo that worked best for me.
Played.
Yes, and then the rest was Bakta.
Right.
And here there are quite large numbers in the difference there.
It looks like you have a little more money in the funds maybe.
I have much more in mutual funds than in shares.
Right.
So that says something about perhaps having a little more funds.
It might go a little better then.
And.
This is how it looked to me.
Lundberg best, Adtraction and Mag Interactive.
And then we have the big positions in Evolution, Castellum and Savelend
which retreated properly, 8,000 down to 6,500.
Yes, tough.
That's it.
Yes, we skip ahead to the next day.
My best day was September 14th.
Almost 9,000 plus.
Worst day, September 26 and then I walked almost 10,000 back.
Right.
So juicy.
Yes, for me then.
September 14 here with, same.
Plus 18,000 almost.
But worst there, September 26 for me too.
Minus 17,000 kroner.
Yes, you have slightly higher numbers than I do.
Yes exactly.
It swings more in both directions.
But I'm not as risk-taking as you.
No, exactly.
I have a little more shares than you do, perhaps.
And.
Okay.
Yes it was.
So we come to Felicia's little overview.
What do they write then?
Interest rate peak in sight or?
Much about the crown then.
And I have talked before in my overviews about people moving into global funds.
And you have a lot of that.
Yes, I have noticed that they are the ones that work best.
Really.
They are very much a plus right now.
And it feels fun anyway.
And.
But in recent weeks it has been a little tougher on global funds, then?
Yes maybe.
Maybe not so good at it.
No.
No, exactly.
Yes, but I usually scroll down to these now.
Now we see in double screen then.
But mostly the funds bought.
Do you recognize any of these funds?
Yes, I recognize them all.
But as I said, I don't own them all.
No.
But I do own, I think I own county insurance.
Right.
And also the split.
And it has been the case that the dollar fell a bit against the krona here a week or so ago.
Then there was probably a bit of panic among some that the American stock market fell and the dollar fell against the krone.
And then it will be a double whammy.
So little that I have been aware that perhaps one should be a little careful about buying too many global funds.
Yes, what does it look like otherwise?
The most bought shares nibe, Novonordisk, Investor, Sinch and Starbreeze.
Do you recognize any of those stocks?
Yes, I recognize Investor and I own it too.
And Sinch I recognize and unfortunately I also own that.
Unfortunately still.
Yes, then it was minus 85 percent back so far.
Yes, it stings.
It is a bit interesting that the most sold funds are spilled equity funds and investment companies.
Yes, but it has gone a bit weaker now, right?
Or I compare it to their global funds.
Yes exactly. It could be that the global fund has done a little better than the Swedish fund has done then.
So I can imagine that there are some who might sell off the Swedish fund and replace it with the global fund, perhaps.
Is it good or is it bad?
So, I would say that both funds are good.
But that I think that many people might make this switch because they think that this fund is better than the global fund.
But personally, I would say that I think there is perhaps more potential in the Swedish fund right now than there is in the global fund.
Precisely because the dollar has become so expensive and that the investor who is the largest holding in the Swedish fund is traded at a very high discount.
And the investment companies in general in Sweden have come down quite a lot in valuation then.
So I'd say no, there I'm sticking with this fuck the sell button.
Yes, that's what it looked like.
Among our, now I happened to close down your tab but the overview we already went through there at both back properly this month or the month of September.
But generally then, what do we feel?
Yes, what do we feel?
I just feel like you've gotten used to it now.
Because if you look at this year and also a bit last year, it went back quite a lot.
And you're kind of used to it.
And like I told you, it feels like you deposit money every month and then you watch it disappear.
And then I deposit new money and then it disappears.
So no, it doesn't feel fun.
But I still think in the long term that I will be happy that I continue to invest every month.
And today, when we record this, it is Tuesday, October 10, when the stock market is up 2.5 percent.
And so when we were lying on the beach today and logged into Avanza, we saw some pretty funny numbers in the end.
And it is then that you feel that you are happy because you actually continue to invest.
I think I was up last time I checked 15,000 kroner today or something like that.
So it is the case that it is tough in certain periods and then all of a sudden it goes the other way.
And then you're quite happy that you haven't sold off but that you've perhaps invested a little more money.
Exactly. I guess that's how you think. Be long-term.
And when it goes down, you have to buy more because then you get more shares.
And when it turns up, it goes up faster.
Exactly.
If you choose the right stuff.
Hopefully it will be fun in a few years when the stock market is up again.
Yes exactly.
So hopefully we can go on a trip like this again next year.
And.
Without having to panic.
I'm on your channel once a year.
Once a year yes. It was actually a question.
I'll see if I can find it so I can post graphics here.
Someone asked when you would be back next time.
And.
How do you feel? Is it fun to join?
Well, of course it's fun, but I don't know much about stocks and funds.
So yes to you I feel very ignorant.
But it might be fun for you to see too.
What should I say. You may not need to be super knowledgeable and such to be able to invest money.
No exactly.
Although it is good of course then it was.
Yes, and you don't have to be a brain surgeon to be able to save.
In principle, anyone can start a fund saving.
So it's not difficult.
No, it is not.
It was quite simply our month of September.
Yes, and if you thought it was fun to watch videos like this, please give it a thumbs up and write a comment.
And if you want to see some of Ida's content, you can go to her channel.
Exactly then, if you search Made by Run, you will come to my channel where you can find some fun about crocheting and making your own candles and such.
Lovely.
Yes.
Shall we go have dinner now?
Now we're going to have dinner.
Thank you so much for watching.
Have fun.
HI.