In this video, we came through five ways
Which I use to make more money
My name is Marcus and I run SparaCash
SparaCash is for you who want to learn how to invest your money in equity funds and much more!
Now we jump into way number 1
It is that I invest in dividend shares
Dividend shares are a company
Who gives out part of their profit
This means that the company in which I own shares in them shares
of the profit to me
Because I invest in them
In other words
The more money I invest in the company
The more money I get back
For example, I own 569 shares in Castellum because Castellum pays approximately SEK 6.50 per share
That's how I get out roughly
SEK 3,700 just this year just by owning castellum's shares
With this dividend
So I can buy more shares
And next year Yes, but then I get a higher dividend
Because I own more dividend shares like this
It is called interest on interest
And it's very
Powerful in the long run to earn even more
Since 2014 so I earned about SEK 32,000
On this kind of profit sharing
By owning different shares
Put number 2
It's that I use credit cards when I shop
I use the complete card when I shop And then I get up to 4% in bonus back
When I shop for different things
For example, I ordered a new camera
And then I got
SEK 100 back straight in my pocket
As Thank you for using the complete card
In total, the last twelve months have received just over SEK 1,100 back
Because I used the complete card
This is money that you can set off on the next invoice, so it is pure money
This means that you do not need to use them on for example
Airlines or specific store or other that many other cards require
But it's money you can set off
and use. So pure tax-free money.
And now there will be someone who comes and whines
"Do not deceive people and take credit cards and get into debt"
I'm not trying to do that
If it's not you
can handle having a credit card
Then you should not have a credit card either
another credit card for you
Who knows how it works
read on before applying for a credit card
But
There is a lot of money to be made if you use a credit card correctly
I forgot to pay the invoice last month and I had to pay SEK 130 in fees
Or in interest
And it sucks
So
Make sure you keep track
How credit cards work but do you use it right
That way you can make a lot of money
I like the complete card because there is no annual fee on the card either
And that's a great bonus
Way number 3 is that I invest peer to peer loans (P2P loans)
And then you might be wondering
Yes but what is
P2P Loan for something?
Well P2P loans are quite simple
So that you lend your money
To a company or private individuals or what for a small interest rate
And I
I use Savelend and Mintos
When I invest in P2P loans
These two actors are two that I have done some analysis on that I trust
In addition, I am a shareholder in Savelend
So there I have a little extra control
There are more players out there such as
Brocc, Lendify
And they can also be used
But I am not investing anything there right now but there are links below to the various players
Keep in mind that there are some p2p players out there who have
went bankrupt that has escaped with investors' money
so it is a risk, it is not a risk-free return
There is no risk-free return
I have invested just over SEK 6,500 in mintos for about 2 years now
And they are now worth about eight thousand
My annual return has gone up to about 10% on Mintos
And this is before tax
At Savelend, I have invested SEK 14,000
And now the money is worth just over SEK 15,500
And this is after tax
Way number 4 is that I have my savings in a savings account with interest
Many people have their buffer in their regular bank
A salary account with zero interest but it actually exists
savings accounts out there with up to 1.2% in interest
Avanza has a restricted savings account
with 1.2 percent interest
and Komplett bank has a savings account up to 1% in interest
Very many people forget that it exists
Savings accounts with interest today
But quite a few Dom all have their money
In a savings account that has no interest at all
so you are losing money on having savings there
Because inflation eats up the value of your money
Make sure you always try to get interest on your money
It's not that much but it gives an extra hundred bucks in your pocket
per year
Put number 5 and it's pretty fun it is
that I'm talking about making money
So of course there is
opportunities for me to make money
On learning just how to make money
And secondly, it is if you use any of these links
To these different companies
Which I'm talking about in this video and my other videos of course
On my website SparaCash.se
That's how I make money helping people
Find different services
Through affiliate links
And this is something I'm trying to do
in as neat a way as possible
Because I test the different services and then I see what works and what is good
And there I use a link
So I can help you make more money
As a thank you, you use my links if that is what you want.
And if you do not want to do it then it is absolutely fine!
You absolutely do not have to do it, it's completely calm
But I would very much appreciate it if you did
And this is called affiliate marketing
And is it that you want to know more about how to start with that or something
Feel free to write a comment below then
I want to know if YOU have any more tips
How to make money
Write a comment Below
So I can get to know you and so I can see what you can!
And links to these tips they are of course Here below in the description
and is it so that you like this video and these types of videos then give me a thumbs up
and so I hope that
you get a sick good day
Hope to see you in the next video
Thank you so much for watching
Hello
But as I said
feel free to tip if you have any tips
Ja ... Pengatjäningstips
way
Blue