I run a Youtube channel and website called SpareCash.se and I started it in 2016.
I became a millionaire as a 27-year-old, it's such a title that newspapers and everything else love to flag with.
Then it goes up and down as you understand, the stock market turns a lot.
But my channel anyway, it has 43,500 subscribers, a thousand views about every day.
Overall, over 3.3 million views on the channel.
And I have about 500-1000 views on my website at sparecash.se every day.
So it is so that you want to learn more about the basics because today we will run about an hour and a half.
So this channel is great, I think.
But I'm a little biased in this then.
But there are a lot of people who appreciate it anyway, as you can see, I'm the biggest in finance on Youtube,
As privately owned then, which is not run by Handelsbanken or something like that.
And a little story, a background then, to how everything started.
So I actually started as a lecturer on young stock savers a few years ago.
As you can see here I was in Strängnäs and lectured to a bunch of high school students.
And it is a project called Young Private Economics.
And then you go through these grounds, shares, funds, savings, pensions and stuff in a short time.
Meanwhile, I traded and played Allan Ballan on the stock exchange as a 19-year-old.
And lost quite a lot of money.
20,000 on turbocharges, which I heard here, in just over two hours.
And then I got a mindset and thought it is better to do something with the money
Instead of just sitting and playing with them to make them try to grow.
So I booked a trip to Thailand, to Bangkok.
And then I was away, there I was a little more fit.
Snorkeled with whale sharks in the Philippines and got some other thoughts of life.
I was in Australia too and saw these cute Wallabies.
But while I was in Australia, I got a mindset
And I wrote in my notepad on the computer.
Start Your Own Shit.
And it was there that, like the foundation for Sparecash, started.
So I came home and started knocking code, programming and building sparecash.se.
And that was the foundation.
And it is 2016 and today I live on this.
So it's a little short info about me and what I do.
So this is my full -time job in principle.
The goal then was with Sparecash to get beginners to dare to invest.
Because I know how complicated it is.
Mathias, you and I are, after all, childhood friends.
Got some questions from you on Facebook about shares and stuff.
And then I felt that why not just build a blog or something
So that people can get this simple info in an easy -to -understand way.
And now I have a shirt on me.
Usually I don't have a shirt on me.
Because I don't want to appear as a banker or anything.
Because I have a little anger against them.
Because you often formulate info quite advanced.
But at least it succeeded well.
As I mentioned 500-1000 visitors per day.
The great thing about spacash is that we also have a discord server
Which is open and free that you can join.
And we have a Facebook group with 22,000 members
Where you can ask questions and stuff as well.
So yes, there you can go in.
On the website we have more than 150 articles, guides and the same on Youtube.
Great Success, so far anyway.
But we haven't stopped there.
But now I think we should go into what I guess you are all here for.
Right?
Learning about shares and funds.
Yes, awesome!
Is that as I said so you have any questions
So just pause me and get up a hand and set it.
I don't want me to just stand here and talk without
I really want you to also be involved.
So I want you to reach out a hand if you know what a share is.
Raise them out loud now so I see it.
Does anyone know what a stock is?
Great!
Raise up one hand if you know what a fund is.
Super good!
Does anyone know what a fund is?
Great, lovely!
We have a little mixed level here today.
And then I want you who have bought funds entirely yourself to reach a hand high.
Yes, a couple.
And if you have bought shares all by yourself, I want you to reached a hand.
Great!
A little 50-50.
I actually had a mentimeter here before
But it takes too long so we drive hand raising.
But type 50-50.
And then I think like this now that we should go through.
It is not in order but we have written some points.
Common mistakes that I have made on my ten years on the stock exchange.
And then common mistakes that you will make if you start investing.
When you start investing.
We will also go through some basic theory of how shares and funds work.
How to buy them.
And also which shares and funds I do not recommend
But still suggest that you may want to choose if you are a beginner.
So, if we start with my mistakes I have done.
Number one I mentioned.
Tried to play Daytrades.
And if there is any word here now that people do not understand then stay me and ask "Marcus, can you explain it?"
What is a Daytrader?
Great question.
A Daytrades is short for daytrading.
This means buying a share or an investment today.
Maybe in the morning.
And then you sell it in the evening to make money during one day.
Then there is also something called swingtrading.
Or swing trader.
It has nothing to do with the swingers here.
It's about owning a share for a little longer.
But also in the short term.
So maybe a week, maybe a month and try to make money in the short term.
And then we have those like me who are long -term investors instead.
So daytrading is that you try to make quick money.
And one more mistake is that I have not been long -term enough.
And that is, for example, here you see a graph at Fortnox.
Which is an accounting company.
And then you see that this is a five -year graph.
So when the green line goes up, you make money.
When it goes down you lose money.
Or it increases or drops in value then.
And I owned it for maybe two, three months.
If I had kept it for five years instead, maybe I had doubled my money instead.
To earn maybe 10 percent on it, I could have made 600 percent.
An example of not being long -term.
Missed to take home profits and ignored for high values.
And there is a picture of it.
Which is sinch!
Have you seen my Youtube channel.
Then you have seen some videos about the company Sinch.
Where the blue pups are when I buy and the red pups when I sell.
Can anyone explain what the error is with this picture?
Or what I've done wrong?
You buy when it's expensive.
Exactly.
I actually bought pretty well in the beginning.
But the problem is that I continued to buy when it was fell.
But it is impossible to know.
If I were to cross this picture until we're on top.
Then everyone had said ooh what a nice stock.
But no one knows how it will go in the future.
What I didn't think about was the valuation of this company.
It was quite expensive and highly valued.
This is almost a whole lecture.
about how to know it is high or low valued.
I can try to make it a bit in the end.
But that was the problem.
Then when it fell, I sold the shares.
And mistakes you will make.
If you are now starting to invest.
When you start investing.
You will make mistakes.
That you try to chase quick money.
As I said.
You go in.
It increases by 5% - good then I take home the profit.
Sell off in panic when something falls.
It is also common.
When it dives 5-10 percent.
So it is not certain that it is justified for it to do so.
Without it, maybe it is that.
Yes there was a war somewhere in Europe.
And that does not mean that the company is going worse for it.
So sometimes it can be good to have some ice in the stomach.
This point.
Buy shares that you don't understand.
Does anyone can answer what I mean?
No you drive.
That one does not understand the product
Great.
Hard to value.
Hard to understand the whole and the future about the company.
Exactly.
That you do not understand the product.
We will get into what shares are for something.
In short, shares are a company.
And when you buy shares.
So it is good to know what the company does for something.
If I buy shares in Holmen.
Because I have seen this in town.
I even know what they actually do.
There is something about paper and so on.
Forest and a little so.
Yes sometimes it is enough.
But sometimes you may have to cave in and understand what they are making money from.
So it is important to buy shares that you understand.
A common mistake to.
Is that you get greedy when something goes up.
Although you do not understand why.
As you saw in my case with the share Sinch.
I bought more as soon as it went down.
Bought more and thought this is just a dip.
It will turn up soon.
It didn't.
So it's pretty common if you get greedy then.
And the last point I wrote in little text.
Because I barely got a seat.
But which is very important.
You will make mistakes.
But learn from them.
Many people completely leave the stock exchange.
We talked a little about it on the phone.
That many who may go into the stock exchange.
Investing a bit.
Losing a lot of money.
They think.
"It's a casino shitty."
"I will never be on the stock exchange again"
And then they will lose all potential rises in the future.
And then maybe you save.
In a savings ponto for his child for 40 years.
And misses 500 % rise on the stock exchange.
So it is very common.
Some thoughts spontaneously there.
Someone who has something about adding.
As they have been through.
As a mistake maybe.
I have been with 2 things you are talking about.
Before Corona broke out.
So I had.
Quite a lot of money on the stock exchange.
And it.
After all, it dropped.
It was many years.
Incorrected crowns that fell.
But then it went up again.
And then I chose to sell the shit.
And never ever.
Put my foot on the stock exchange again.
I did it.
Now.
I put them on.
Long -term.
Long -term funds instead.
But.
I laid.
My private pension.
On something I might not have done.
And.
I am not a one who goes to Avanza and looks every day.
But maybe I look once every six months.
But I had a discussion with a friend.
And I prayed.
"I save in this"
But I can go in and show how it goes.
And then they had gone bankrupt.
And that was my pension.
Yes it sucks ...
But.
Was the private pension couple?
So I had put in.
SEK 500-1000 each month.
As well as.
500-1000 not 500000. *giggle *
You don't know!
- No you don't!
;)
It was a little.
Typical.
It's not something I hang lip for.
It's a bit that you've gone into.
I knew what the company was doing.
And I saw.
That they wanted to.
But it was like.
How do they earn money.
And it was there.
I might not have been aware.
Exactly.
But that has been learned from their mistakes.
Great.
Spread the risks.
Just.
Great thing.
Unfortunately, it is so.
Companies go bankrupt sometimes.
Therefore, it is important when choosing shares.
That you look at them.
And we will come in on a few different pieces.
How to avoid them.
To filter out such companies.
Which can potentially go bankrupt.
It is by far the worst outcome.
When we invest.
If a company goes bankrupt.
Then we lose all our money.
There is no value left then.
Most often.
And now we will go into some theory.
And as I said.
Don't be afraid to cancel.
And ask questions.
And often.
So it usually looks like this.
When talking to someone.
About shares and funds.
It is said that shares are high risk.
And it is said that funds are low risk.
What do you think about that?
You shake your head!
Incorrect.
Why?
The funds also own shares.
Exactly.
It's wrong.
Just as you say.
But if we say this.
That shares are higher risk.
And funds are high risk.
Do you think it sounds better?
Yes it can be.
It can be.
It can be so.
Depends on which company you are investing in.
Yes.
I did that.
I wrote that this is right anyway.
But that is a subjective issue.
But I would still say that.
To stock.
Many people are looking for stable shares.
Safe shares.
There are safe companies.
But you still have to keep in mind that as an investment.
So shares are always high risk.
And almost always higher risk than funds are.
But both are still high risk.
Because you stop your money.
And they will swing in value.
So.
Then it depends on how you define risk.
Easily explained.
Higher risk in shares.
High risk in funds.
And what is the difference between equities and funds?
Now let's see if.
I thought about showing here.
Because everyone has not seen me before.
So I'll see if I can outsource this to myself.
And yes the biggest.
The difference between shares and funds.
It is that when you buy shares.
So you indirectly own part of a company.
And if you buy a fund instead.
Then you get some of a bunch of different shares.
Up to 20-50 different companies.
Maybe you get if you invest in a fund.
So.
So there it may look.
It's a pretty old video you see.
I had no glasses on me.
But.
Now this is also the example.
Pretty fun.
I don't know if anyone sees an error here on the left side.
Ica I heard!
They no longer exist - exactly.
It is a limited company.
But you can't buy them over the stock exchange anymore.
Because they were bought.
Or purchased from the stock exchange.
But the practice is like this.
If you buy shares, you buy a share.
Or a business.
When you buy a fund.
So.
With the traditional rules in Sweden.
So you get at least 16 companies.
On a fund.
And that's why I say it.
Funds are high risk.
But it is not as high risk as buying a stock.
I think it was you who said it.
To spread the risk then.
And that's what is so nice with funds.
If you are a beginner, maybe start by buying a fund.
To then spread the risk among several companies.
So it's good to start with a fund so you don't have to think about it.
That one must buy 10-20 shares yourself
And when choosing between them here.
So I usually say this.
Do you want to spend time on your savings?
Yes or no?
What do you say?
Do you want to spend time on your savings?
No?
You shake your head a little.
You?
And you?
No?
Yes.
So yes then I would say that you can buy shares.
But if you don't feel like it.
Then choose funds.
And are you interested in specific companies?
Yes but then choose shares.
If you think
Spotify they will go well.
Yes but maybe buy some shares in them then
But if you are not interested - buy funds.
Are you okay with your money swinging up and down very much?
If you say yes here.
Then maybe you can lean on buying shares.
But if you are not comfortable with it.
Then you should stick to funds.
Because I think most people will understand it when I show this picture.
It is taken today.
And this is a company called Hexatronic.
Does anyone recognize this company?
Yes.
Does anyone own shares in Hexatronic?
No longer.
Did you sell today?
No a few months ago.
Yes the same here.
Yes I suffer with you who own shares in Hexatronic.
Today, the share fell 32 or more percent.
And it is like this that can happen when you own individual shares!
Because I have also owned Hexatronic.
And went from having made a mega win
To leave.
I think I made a thousand dollars in profit.
But from having been in 200,000 plus in Hexatronic.
Down to maybe 20,000 plus.
Or less.
I do not remember.
I've suppressed it.
So it's like this.
This is how you buy shares.
It can be so.
So now we come up with a little how to start.
If you are going to start investing then.
And here from my website.
Sparecash.se
Then I have a list of slightly different shares and fund brokers.
And now I thought it was just a little quick going through them.
So you have a phone with QR code scanner.
So you can scan and get there directly.
So you have them lying on their phone.
Because you who are here.
I want everyone in here to start investing.
So be sure to scan them here and put them in the browser.
So you have them there.
And then after this lecture we sit down and chat a little out there.
And then you open accounts so you get started.
So you don't go from here and just think "what should I do for something"
It is today we start.
The best day to invest was yesterday.
The second best day to invest is today.
Avanza is what I use most.
Then you scan that code and you will get there right there!
It is free to save in shares and funds up to 50,000 in total savings
Then you get the fees back
Once you have reached 50,000
Then it starts to cost fees.
They have the largest range of funds and shares in Sweden by the niche brokers.
The easiest way to use I think.
I mostly use it.
And you get interest on ISK.
Interest rates on savings account get up to 3.7%
Does anyone recognize Avanza?
Yes, most.
I will go through five different ones here.
I see that we have one that records physically, which I like.
Am I too fast here, so tell me and stay.
Next we have Nordnet, which is a major player in Scandinavia.
Here, too, they have up to 50,000 in total savings without fees.
This means that you can start at Avanza.
Once you have reached 50,000, you can switch to Nordnet.
So you can save 100,000 without fees.
Fantastic.
They also have English language in the app.
If you are not so good in Swedish, then this is better than Avanza's app.
If you prefer English.
Interest rate on savings account is 3.6% so Avanza is a little better.
Then we have a newcomer.
I forgot to ask how many recognize Nordnet?
Not as many.
It proves that Avanza has a strong brand.
And my shares there are doing well.
But Nordnet also has good potential.
Levler, how many recognize it?
One.
No other.
Today I heard about them.
Levler is a bit like a Avanza/Nordnet, though even less.
Owned by Söderberg Partners.
They offer that you can buy shares free of charge.
So you can buy shares completely free of charge.
Until the billion, until 2025.
It's great.
Easy to use.
25 % discount on fund fees compared to Avanza Nordnet.
The fund fee you receive at the big bank and Avanza Nordnet.
Discounts by 25 %!
I think so.
And they have a slightly higher interest rate on ISK.
This one is for those who like to buy clothes.
So you should use without Levler.
For Levler looks like you are at Zalando.
So they have simpler user interfaces.
Is it easy to change the bank?
Great question.
I would say both yes and no.
If you are running in an investment savings account.
Then you can move the entire investment savings account to the bank.
But if you have a capital insurance, you cannot move from bank to bank.
So if you want to be able to move from bank to bank, it runs an investment savings account.
But I think it sucks a little.
Too often it can take a month to move the entire account.
And unless the investments are there.
For example, if Levler has a little limited supply of shares.
They do not have foreign shares yet.
Then you have to sell them.
Then you will not bring them to the other bank.
Could it also be purchasing information that you lose?
Yes exactly.
You lose what you have bought in for price.
So you have to enter it manually.
If you have purchased your shares in Telia or Holmen to SEK 100.
And now they stand in SEK 300 so maybe it will not come along.
But at Avanza and Nordnet you can change it.
So then you can put it in.
I think there are several apps.
Can you move other shares and funds on all different shares?
Great question.
If they have the same range then?
This one is a bit limited at present.
It is quite newly started.
But if you want to get hold of all shares, it's Avanza and Nordnet.
But there is then if you may want to buy shares in Poland.
Or maybe in the UK or so.
So it can be a little limited.
But often you have American, Swedish, Norwegian, Danish, German and Avanza and Nordnet.
Then it is the others who are a little limited then.
Savr we went on.
SAVR is a platform just for funds at present.
They offer a discount on the fund fees like Levler then.
Although they do not have this fixed 25 percent.
It's easy to use and also ...
Are you in the share savers and not using SAVR
So you have SEK 300 to start investing for.
If you choose to join SAVR and are a member.
If you are not members then you can become members
And then you automatically get SEK 300 to save for in SAVR.
More information on the membership page, the share savers.
Yes, they can talk to you then after.
SAVR is good and there you get 300 bucks with the share savers and membership.
When you invite friends you get 100 bucks.
Because I have Instagram account.
Unfortunately, now they have limited it.
Back in the days then, I think I got 5,000.
You can invite friends and get 100 SEK.
And so it goes straight into the investment savings account.
Shit smart.
They will launch stock trading in the future as well.
I think they also pay.
Do you know the programmers who are good?
So email them.
I think they pay type 20,000 if they find a programmer.
Shit smart, free cash!
It is a little cheaper to save in the fund at SAVR.
Because they take a platform fee.
Instead of that fee Avanza and Nordnet takes.
Levler, for example, has a fixed 25% discount
While SAVR you get 5 % and you get 25 %.
But you can always compare where it is the cheapest if you want to buy a fund.
Check out what it costs at Avanza and SAVR and then make a decision.
Aktieinvest!
This one is a little fun because it was owned by the share savers a while ago.
Even there, it is free to buy stock but up to 60,000 instead of 50,000.
This I have not really agreed as well as Avanza Nordnet.
But it works.
The best thing about Aktieinvest is the second part there.
Which is the purchase of parts of shares.
If you want to buy a share in Apple or Google.
So maybe you must have 1000 SEK.
But here you can buy part of a share.
So you don't have to have 1000 SEK.
Without it, maybe SEK 100 is enough.
So that's the best.
There is also another platform that I just started testing.
Called Kiwi Trader.
Which is similar.
I can add there.
The good thing about Aktieinvest is also that you can save monthly in shares.
So you can say that 1000 SEK you want to invest per month.
Then you can choose which shares to invest in.
And it does not offer many others.
It is often that you saving monthly in funds.
But here you can save monthly in the shares you want.
Found in Aktieinvest.
If you want to spend time and check it out.
And it was owned by the share savers that you mentioned.
Exactly.
Those kiwi trader as i said too
I have started testing them.
It is the same.
So it's great.
You can build a whole portfolio with 50 different American shares.
It is a very low cost to save monthly.
And they also have savings boxes.
It's kind of a bit like funds ..
But read the price lists.
Because I know it was part of these cooperative shares.
There may be some hidden fees that you do not understand.
So it is important to read them too.
Okay.
Now you have found out where to start investing.
You have these banks on the phone.
And now there is some outsourcing of Marcus again.
And when you have opened an account at a bank.
Then you need an account to have your shares or funds on.
And there are three such types of account.
There is a equity fund account.
There is an investment savings account.
And there is a capital insurance.
When you buy Swedish shares.
So I recommend that you have an investment savings account.
Because it has a low tax.
And you don't have to declare your business to the Swedish Tax Agency.
Do you have a equity fund account.
So you have to pay 30% tax on profits.
And besides, you have to declare this.
So in your tax return after you have sold your shares.
Then you have to report it to the Swedish Tax Agency.
And it can be a little complicated.
So, as I said, open an account at a bank.
Open an investment savings account.
And then you're up and running.
Like, briefly explained.
Choose one of these brokers that I have shown.
Or all.
It does not matter.
Test everyone.
Open an account on a bank and then open an ISK account.
It's kind of the easiest.
Low tax, you don't have to think so much about it.
The tax comes in pre -printed in the declaration.
It is important to point out that it does not cost to open several accounts either.
You can have an account for different purposes.
For that I also get questions about.
Does it cost anything to open an account?
No, you can open.
Open as many accounts as you like.
Exactly, great Byron.
It is therefore completely free of charge to open accounts at these banks.
And it is free of charge to open an investment savings account.
At my Avanza I have two investment savings accounts.
A capital insurance.
Some have 20 investment savings accounts.
Just to test different strategies and such.
Or different purposes.
This is an account for children, for the trip, to the car.
It depends on what one is for a person.
Exactly.
Have order and find out.
Okay.
Investment savings account, low tax.
Don't have to declare.
Equity fund account, maybe I should say so before.
When you open the account first.
Do not throw 100,000 into an investment savings account.
And then it doesn't matter.
Because then you have to pay tax on them.
For every penny you deposit into the investment savings account.
Raises the tax that comes then in the declaration.
First put money into such a common thing.
Equity fund account.
It gets a little complicated maybe.
And then from there when you know.
I will buy these funds for SEK 1000.
Then you can transfer the money to the investment savings account.
And buy them there.
If you do not have a monthly rolling fund pair.
Which is drawn in ISK.
Automatically
Yes exactly.
Difficult?
- Yes
Take it again then.
Okay.
Let's say we have Avanza up here.
You see my mouse pointer.
So you deposit money.
And then you do it in the equity fund account.
Then you also have an ISK account.
And you can have a capital insurance.
But as soon as you put money away.
In here.
Then the tax will be increased for you.
Then you will have to pay tax on it.
So money that is in an investment savings account.
You would like to have invested.
Otherwise, you pay tax unnecessarily.
Comment?
Good.
So...
Do not have uninvested money in investment savings account!
Exactly.
And then when you deposit money here too.
So the tax is based on one year.
Without making it too complicated.
So don't put money in and then withdraw them.
And then put in money and withdraw them as a payroll account.
Money you put on the investment savings account.
Let them stay there and be invested.
But for us to catch up with everything.
So I think we will move on to the investments.
That's what you are here for.
For making money or how ...
So...
And now it's time to choose which shares to buy or invest in.
And this can be a little difficult.
I have made many different videos where I talk about finding shares.
But a type of share that I think is worth mentioning if you are a beginner.
These are investment companies.
Investment companies shares, yes they invest in other companies.
So it's almost like buying a fund.
And this I think is a good type of shares to start with.
Because you then spread the risk.
Even if you only buy one share.
So your risk is spread to the companies in which they in turn own shares.
And examples of investment companies are Investor.
Industrivärden.
Lundbergs.
Crees.
Svolder.
Yes, there are many different investment companies that are ...
Which is good, I would say.
But I'm pausing this one.
So this is what I usually tell beginners about.
When you do not know which shares to buy.
Start with the investment companies.
And what I'm showing here.
This is the investment company.
To be a little clear.
Investor is a company.
Which owns shares in Atlas Copco.
ABB.
AstraZeneca.
Seb.
Do you keep up with how it works?
Good.
So that's why I said it is a bit like buying a fund.
Because they in turn own more shares.
So you don't have to do it yourself.
Industrivärden.
Volvo.
Sandvik.
Handelsbanken.
Do you recognize some of these companies?
Lundbergs.
Does anyone recognize Lundbergs from here town?
Indutrade, Holmen, Lundberg's properties.
And lots of others.
Hufvudstaden and so on.
We have a little more technology focused.
They are the founder of Avanza.
Sticker app.
If you order stickers online.
Google.
Buy stickers.
So you will definitely see this website.
Apotea.
Most people in here I recognize.
Instabox.
Or called Instabee Group Now I think huh.
Svolder, Beijer Group, Troax, New Wave Group.
If you are doing.
Is it Bajen.
So you have probably seen that there is a craft on their sweaters.
So Hammarby.
And they are owned by New Wave.
Or it's a brand.
As you can see, there are still a lot of brands.
As you may have seen sometime.
And why should you chance to buy something like this cancer company.
As any old guy on Facebook tips on.
Where you can instead trust these big companies.
Who has made very good historical returns.
Instead.
As a beginner.
Good tips I think.
Can I add?
Also when looking at investment companies.
So you can take part in companies.
Which you can't buy on the stock exchange yourself.
On the stock market.
So -called unlisted companies.
So it is also a huge advantage.
Yes.
Exactly.
What do we have there then?
Spiltan?
Apotea can be purchased now.
No.
Exactly.
Apotea and Creades.
Just.
So.
You are.
With an investment company.
As you can see here.
Atlas Copco, ABB.
Seb, AstraZeneca.
All of them can be purchased on the stock exchange.
That is, when you go into Avanza.
And looking for companies.
Then you can find them.
But instead of buying them.
So you can buy Investor.
So you get all them in one package.
But for example.
Apotea, Instabox.
Or instabee.
You cannot buy shares in them.
Or type Savecash AB.
They are not on the stock exchange.
Because I'm a private company.
Small crap company.
But these.
Fine.
You can get them by buying.
For example, Crees.
Then you can ride on the scale that it is going well for them.
And so.
Were you about to say Spiltans?
Yes.
You can buy several of these.
Investment companies.
If you buy Spiltans.
Shares.
Fund.
Equity fund.
Then you get part of.
Then you buy several of these.
Great fund.
I will show it later.
But also.
The investment companies have a lower fee.
Than the funds have.
Great.
Exactly.
You can buy a fund.
Called Spiltan's investment company.
And get all of them here.
But then it costs a fee every year.
To own that fund.
So it is cheaper instead to buy these investment companies
and make "your own fund".
Okay, one last then.
So the investment companies are so good.
It is that there is skills there.
So they go into the board of the companies.
And helps them with their skills.
So that if you have someone from Investor.
So they can come and control and help.
So that the companies are moving forward.
While funds can be more passive.
And just own the companies.
So that's why.
As you said they have succeeded historically.
Thanks to his skills.
Therefore, maybe you can expect them to continue to do so.
Yes exactly.
They go in and actively help companies.
So okay, when you have to choose shares then.
As I said first.
Start with investment companies.
Or you don't even have to choose shares first.
You can start with funds.
But then.
I think it is more important to focus on which companies should avoid.
Rather than which one should I choose.
If you focus on which to choose.
Then you often choose the companies that go best right now.
But that may not be the best in the long term.
Basically everything that contains.
Biotech, Pharma and so on.
Does anyone have something like that?
Bone support
Bone support!
It has gone well.
But it is also such an example.
Where you might buy it.
Although you do not really know exactly what they are doing.
That's why I usually say it.
Avoid such companies.
Who will research and save the world.
Through cancer and innovation.
They often need to raise a lot of money.
And they burn money very fast.
Which means that the value of your shares goes down here.
And then it will be concerning.
Bankruptcy.
Sometimes.
But often it is.
Make sure the companies make a profit.
Very important.
That's probably the most important thing I would say.
Important to check it out.
And you can do that by going to allabolag.se.
And so you can see that the bars are green and not red.
A simple notch.
I will also show it at Avanza.
Once we have finished this presentation.
We are soon ready.
And the last thing.
Do not buy things that are recommended in Facebook groups.
It's so common.
There are so many who go into the Facebook group and write.
What shall I buy?
But how can we compare it then?
It's kind of like ...
I do not know.
Do we have any good comparison?
No I don't come up with anything.
Tris lots
Trislott, exactly.
I just think that those who print things are looking to make money.
Yes exactly.
Those on Facebook groups that say buy this share.
It is because they own it.
They want...
Most often it is because they have gone down so much after them.
That they have to get people to buy it so that the price will go up again.
So that they can get out of it a little easier.
And not lose so much money.
It is usually so.
Or that they write, now comes the rocket.
Or, now it will fly.
It's bullshit.
It is almost always such companies that have gone down 99 percent.
Which people write about this.
I can also add that if you are on such a forum.
So there is probably some starting company that everyone is talking about.
And these are probably high risk.
So I can fly or it can fall.
It's not like this, what should I buy?
Then pull something with something boring and stable here.
Investor.
That's probably what to buy.
But it may not be so fun to hear it.
You want a clip.
People want back dumpings.
Hope this is the next clip that I will become a millionaire on.
Next gamestop.
Yes, the next gamestop.
And we saw how it went ... It didn't go well.
So...
Should we see if it will continue.
Do not buy this if 99 percent have fallen.
There is a reason why the share has dropped 99 percent.
And it's not because it's cheap.
If you check SAS for example.
Does anyone own SAS shares in here?
Thanks, good God, for that.
SAS CEO himself has said in the reports.
I don't even think he owns shares in SAS.
There will be no shareholder value left.
So don't buy it.
They need to raise more money and the share is diluted.
It's the same thing, you shovel money into a burning fire.
Buying shares in SAS right now.
And they will be delisted and the money will disappear.
So there are still ten thousands who have shares in SAS.
So you know a friend who owns SAS, ask them and sell them.
For that money will disappear.
So that's an example.
Okay, but some tips now.
Some tips when buying shares.
And this is a picture from Lundbergs.
It is an investment company.
So it is a graph of how I have traded in Lundbergs.
And the green line, so it is the share price.
How that price of it goes up and down.
The yellow line is the average of all companies on the stock exchange.
So you understand the difference there.
Divide your purchases.
So it means, if you have ten thousand SEK that you want to invest.
But don't throw everyone in at once.
Without here, as you can see.
Here I have divided ten thousand SEK and buy a thousand SEK now.
A thousand SEK tomorrow.
Next week.
But as you can see, things go up and down.
I have no idea.
You see, I bought at the top there.
But over there.
There I made a really good purchase.
But I have no idea.
I don't know when it's on top or on the bottom.
So divide them instead.
So that you do not go all in with a hundred thousand at once.
When you have been inherited.
Or a thousand.
So I think that's good.
And then when you see it, it is very low to watch three years to Marka.
Just.
Do you dare to invest so much money then?
That's what is a good question.
It is never easy to answer it.
You can never know what is right and wrong with.
There are some who look at graphs like this.
Then when I have probably seen such ads on Instagram.
Buy my course.
I know.
This share should go up.
Become rich.
Earn a thousand kronor in one day.
I earned a million yesterday.
Why are you selling a course then?
If you are so good at knowing which shares to buy.
I usually say.
Take it easy.
Instead.
Do not try to look at graphs.
When will it go up?
You don't know that.
The important thing is not to look at the graph.
Without looking at the company.
I know this is a bit subjective.
Now I only show a graph.
But we see, for example, these figures down here.
This is something that makes people not go into shares.
You rarely look at these p & e ratio and stuff.
Stock market value.
Profit per share.
Unfortunately, we have not unlimited time today.
So we can't go through exactly what it means.
But the P & E century is a pretty good measure of companies.
To know if they are expensive or cheap.
But avoid keeping in mind that this is an exception.
Lundbergs.
At an investment company you cannot check out a P & E figure in the same way.
But if we were to take Nibe selling heat pumps.
This stands for years ...
How do you say now?
Help me Markus.
Award.
So how many years it takes until you get your investment back?
Exactly how many annual gains it is valued at.
If you were to say that this is a regular company now.
So you say that there are 11 annual profits that it costs to buy this stock.
And if the P & E century is negative, it means that they are at a loss.
So if you see p & e ratios, you who record write this down.
Because this is the most important thing you need to know.
If the P & E figure is negative, the company is at a loss.
And avoid them when you are a beginner.
I'm not saying buy them, not.
But please avoid them until you understand.
So p & e figure, then you often say on the Swedish stock exchange P/E 10-20.
It's a good valuation.
Or a reasonable valuation.
During p/e 10, then you can say that the company can be cheap.
And you want to buy cheaply valued shares.
So now it gets a little complicated here.
But cheaply valued has nothing to do with what the price of the share costs.
A share can cost a penny or a thousand SEK.
It does not matter.
You have to look at the valuation and you usually see this easily via the P/E figure.
And a measure to know how big the company is by looking at the market capitalization.
If I start a company today and cost SEK 25,000 in share capital.
Then I have a market capitalization of SEK 25,000.
Here you see Lundbergs, they have a market capitalization of SEK 119 billion.
So it's a little bigger.
Pretty big.
And then you get a hum if it is a small company or a large company.
If there is a million there in market capitalization, then it is a very small company.
And small companies have much higher risk than the larger established ones then.
Can have.
Will you mention interest on the interest effect?
No, I actually haven't included that.
But we can show it later.
Is it going well?
Great.
We can pick it up later.
Okay, more tips then!
Now we have come in on valuation.
Don't panic when something crashes.
Read on before acting.
That is, when Hexatronic falls by 33 percent as it did today.
First, think why do it and then think about.
Should I sell or not?
And then the long -term perspective was the most important thing.
Just as you said, interest on the interest effect.
When you buy shares, do so for at least three to five years ahead.
So when you invest, think so far ahead.
So that you do not think that after a week I should sell.
For the longer you wait the greater the likelihood that you actually make money.
We do not have many slides left.
And now we come up to funds.
A little quick ice cream, it's the last here now.
And then I show this particular fund that you talked about.
Spiltan equity fund investment company.
So we talked about investment companies before.
And not to make it too confusing with the game, this is a fund then.
The game itself is also an investment company.
But this fund invests in investment companies.
So, for example, here you see that for five years each month and even more often I have bought in it.
And I think that is great.
It is the small saver's best friend for everyone in here who has not invested.
Start in funds.
Then you can save, for example, Avanza a penny.
Maybe a hundred kronor per month.
And then you spread the risk in several other companies.
But it's not just the best friend of the small saver.
It is also the bank's cashier.
Just as you mentioned.
After all, there are funds that banks make a lot of money from.
And that is through fees then.
And we get that right away.
But when you save in funds, set up an automatic monthly savings.
So that you go in and choose monthly.
And then it is every month that is drawn with direct debit.
Directly when the salary comes, you buy for a hundred SEK a month.
Two hundred kronor, five hundred kronor.
As much as you can afford.
Because as you said with interest on the interest effect.
Over time, there will be a lot of money.
My monthly savings looks like this.
Two thousand SEK a month.
In Swedish funds, global funds and small company funds.
I would have liked to go through more about funds.
But unfortunately I don't have time for that.
There is more to read.
But there is a lot of info.
Everything is available on my website sparecash.se
So when you want, if you are going to set up a monthly saving.
Don't make it harder than it is.
And choose a Swedish fund.
And choose a global fund.
It is enough.
It is not needed more than that.
And then please choose a cheap fund.
And then I have written avoid these funds.
Then I do not mean specifically this fund
Without some benchmarks.
I have funds that cost more than one percent per year.
But try when you are new to avoid them.
Until you know if they are worth that fee.
So benchmarks, avoid funds with one percent in fee and up.
Fund in fund solutions.
This means that the fund has funds in itself.
If you are on the Avanza app or on your computer.
So you can scroll down a bit.
Under the fund and then you see the holdings
And there are a lot of funds in there.
I hope no one works at Maxmathiessen or Söderberg Partners.
But they have a tendency to do.
They have a tendency to buy funds in their funds.
Which means you receive a fee on the fee.
So you pay a double fee.
And also in the pension for example.
So it may be that you have a fee for the entire pension savings.
So you who have an occupational pension.
Check out your occupational pensions.
There may be very hidden fees.
Which you don't think about.
If you don't know what you are doing.
Avoid funds that have been best in 2023.
It's pretty common.
I know there is a lot of traffic on my article.
Called the best funds 2023.
There is a reason why I baptized it.
Because people like to click on it.
But funds that have gone best this year.
Has no guarantee that they will be the best next year.
Without this is an example of such a fund.
Which did not go best this year.
But previous years.
As you can see in five years, it has gone 101 percent.
But this year it has backed 20 percent.
Hedge funds I also say that you should avoid.
It's a bit complicated.
And fixed income funds if you are long -term, I think you should avoid.
If you save in 10-20 years term.
So you won't get that much return with fixed income funds.
But it also depends on.
I'm not saying don't use fixed income funds.
But myself for my long -term savings avoids it.
Because I want to get as much return as possible.
And what I meant by this fund.
Now I have a picture.
Why I mean to avoid them.
One should avoid those who have gone best.
If you see the difference between these two.
So you see here now that I've taken from the top.
2022-08-10.
Until today.
So it has backed 30-31 percent.
But the stock market that is yellow.
Located basically plus minus zero.
So if you had gone for 2021.
Or what it was when this one went really well.
And pushed in 100,000.
Because this fund went so well.
So you had been back 30 percent today.
It is very common for people to do so.
You buy the fund that has gone best.
And then you think it will continue to go well.
And then it just gets pancake
Like when buying Tesla.
Yes Tesla is a classic.
Yes.
That's all I had.
Super good.
Now I can switch to questions.
So I say thank you for your time.
And then I go over to questions.
And if you want to check out my youtube.
So just scan this code.
And we have time.
So I can also go in and check out my corporate portfolio at Avanza
Thanks.