Yes but hey or is it okay with you or
Today we will talk about stocks or mutual funds What should you choose
And how should you think when choosing between stocks and mutual funds
Is it so that before you watch this video, it may well be that
Bring out a cup of coffee and since we are more than a thousand subscribers Now we will celebrate with a little bun
I did not pay for it so #sparadkrona
Before I eat my bun, I will also present the winners and the winners I have drawn are
Philip Rydin
Emil Hanna uppström Siberia's soup kitchen
Åsa Lundgren just over nurses Karam Julia and Ardalan
Congratulations you have each won a share book you can contact me on Instagram or Facebook
With your address, I will send out the books to you
In today's video we will talk about
Equities or mutual funds, that is
What to choose
When you save
Should you buy
Shares or should you save in a fund?
And yes the biggest difference between stocks and mutual funds
When you buy shares, you own indirectly
Part of a company
And if you buy a fund instead
Yes, but it is so that you get some of it
A bunch of different shares
Up to 20-50 different companies Maybe you get if it is the case that you invest in a fund
But if you buy a share, it is only the company that you invest in
If we think about just that statement
So maybe you understand that
There is a slightly higher risk that
invest in stocks
than it is to invest in mutual funds
When you invest and save your money
then you need to think about how much risk you are willing to take
By investing in shares, you take a very high risk
And when you invest in equity funds, there is also a high risk but not as high as if you had only bought 1 share
That is, if that company is doing badly (in which you bought shares)
then your entire investment goes to the pipe turn
But if you buy a fund instead
then you spread the risk
Among different companies
You will receive at least 16 shares if you buy a fund
I usually say that
Equity suits you who are looking to take a little more risk who may want to
it should go up and down a little faster
Also you who want to spend some time analyzing different companies and see which ones are doing well and
You might be thinking that "this company will do well"
You like to speculate
And you want to spend some extra time on your investments
You may find it fun to invest in stocks
You might find it fun to follow different companies
And like economics and everything in general
Yes, but then maybe shares are something for you!
The catch of buying a fund instead of shares instead
You do not have as great a chance to make as much money
if you then buy a fund instead of shares
But a fund is perfect for you who do not have the strength to
think about spreading the risk without
Want someone else to take care of it for you instead
If you want to invest in stocks
Yes, but then maybe it's because you wanted a slightly higher return
For example, I buy shares because I think it's fun.
Not because I think I'm a professional or that I'm good at analyzing different companies but it's a bit like a hobby for me
I think it's quite fun to follow different companies, how it goes for them
And yes, then mine grows
Savings also over time if the company is doing well
If I find something that I think will go well.
It's simply about speculation!
Instead, when buying a fund
This is how you hand over that responsibility
To the managers who manage the fund
Because you think they're better at finding good stocks than you are.
If you choose shares - Then you get the following benefits
You have the chance to make more money than mutual funds
It costs no annual fees or ongoing fees when you own shares
3. You completely decide which shares you want to invest in
When you buy funds, it may be a little difficult to think about
What shares are actually in this fund?
Because it's not something you can control
So if you want to invest morally or ethically or environmentally friendly or something else
Then you can not choose it in a fund
There are various funds that have such classifications
But
It is actually the fund manager who chooses
what should be in the fund and not you
But when you buy shares then you can control this all by yourself!
Disadvantages of shares
Yes, but it is that you have a higher risk than funds
Also swings quite a bit up and down
So it's you are not. comfortable with
It might go down 10% in one day
Yes, but then maybe you should have a fund instead.
When you buy a fund, then
you hand over the responsibility to the fund manager.
To control and set and decide which shares are to be in this fund.
Funds may be for you
who want to spend a little less time on your savings
And only have an automatic saving where someone else takes care of you
You may not feel like sitting down and choosing different stocks
And then maybe funds are better suited for you
A typical stock investor
Yes, it usually sits on needles and often checks how the savings go every day
Myself, I'm one who invests in stocks
But I think it's fun!
I like to follow the stock market and keep track of how investments go up and down
I have no problem if it goes down quite a lot in one day.
I think it's quite fun to follow
how my shares are doing
But you absolutely do not have to choose either or
Without you can have both shares and funds in your savings.
I myself have both
I have about 80% shares and I have 20% equity funds
There is no fixed rule with the 80/20 principle
I just think it's nice to keep it at a roughly
If it is the case that my shares are doing badly, then hopefully my funds will do better.
The vast majority of them probably make more money
on investing only in funds other than equities
It is very rare that you see that
People beat the index (the stock market)
You need to be good at picking good stocks
If you want to be able to beat the index
It takes quite a lot of luck at least over the long term
In the short term in a year
So there Yes but then maybe it is the case that you beat the index, but in the long run it is very rare to do so
In fact, the vast majority benefit from choosing a free fund
In other words, an index fund with a very low fee
They show over time that they give quite well
But if you're like that
Do you like to keep on tinkering and investing yourself and find different stocks and companies
Yes, but then maybe it's so
You should invest in shares with
You absolutely do not have to choose
Without it, it is possible to actually invest in both shares and funds.
If it is the case that you are new to investing and you have neither invested in equities nor mutual funds.
Yes, but then I think you should start with a fund at least
Funds do not fluctuate as much as equities do
And it's pretty easy to get started and
Just put a hundred bucks in a fund at no cost.
So there is no purchase fee and no sales fee on funds.
On shares, on the other hand, you must pay a fixed fee.
A purchase fee and a sales fee
which is called brokerage while on funds it is an ongoing fee
an annual management fee that is deducted from your investments
But there are free funds out there that you can use that you can start with if you are a beginner and want to start saving.
But then maybe it fits well with a free fund
To sum it all up
Choose what you think is most convenient to invest in
If you like a little higher risks but then maybe you should invest in stocks
But if it is the case that you want to spend as little time as possible
Then it might be better to invest in mutual funds.
If you want as low fees as
Choose some free index funds
If you want a little better control and
Want to invest in funds that
fluctuates a lot and has a higher risk and higher chance of making money
Look at active equity funds then instead
Maybe it suits you better
And then when you have learned
Yes, but then maybe you can go in and test and buy some shares
It's entirely up to you - feel for yourself
But dare to invest - That is the main factor!
Dare to open a savings and just start investing for
With time, you will learn more.
I hope you have gotten a little more meat on your bones and regarding the issue of stocks or mutual funds.
Thank you so much for watching, if you give me a thumbs up I understand that you like this video and I hope to see you in the next video!
Hello!