Hexatronic has a report today and I thought I would make a quick comment on the report after a lot of requests namely.
So we check and then we see here that the share is currently trading down to minus 10 percent.
Absolutely crazy and it was one of my biggest holdings, or has been anyway.
Now it is no longer that after this year's decline of just over 40 percent.
And we actually had a bang report.
Because if we look here, we will see that yes, but it is a record quarter.
The first quarter was a record quarter both in terms of sales and profitability.
Mainly North America then, the USA and Europe very strong except for Sweden then which has taken a bit of a break if you say so.
But despite this, the stock is down a lot.
Because if we take a look at this graph that we see here, we can see that the turnover is crazy.
They are growing nicely and the margin is also up so that you increase both profit and turnover.
But there were few words that were reviewed in the report, where some might have interpreted this organic growth, which has come down quite a bit.
For example, DI who shared this graph back then of the organic growth which has dropped quite a bit.
Which could be a reason why the stock is traded down so much.
Since the order book, we also see that it has come down quite a bit.
But CEO Henrik Larsson-Lyon says himself that they are not worried.
In the past, during, for example, covid, there have been very long delivery times.
This means that you may have ordered or placed an order 4-5 months in advance.
Because it takes so long then to get material in to be able to implement the words.
While it will then go back a little more normal 2-3 months maybe so.
And this could be one reason why the market trades the share down so much.
It has also been very highly polished.
And I scraped together some numbers, namely on turnover which has been historical as you can see above me.
And then we look at turnover, then the biggest legs where we see the most likely growth going forward.
It's probably North America and the rest of Europe.
For this we have the USA, we have Germany and we have the UK.
Those are the three biggest parts if you say.
And we look at historical growth.
Here, I have not included Sweden because as you can see here, Sweden is a bit sluggish and not so extremely high growth potential.
But if you look at these legs, it looks very nice in the long run.
If you think that the US will continue to grow at the same rate as it did before.
After all, there was decent growth if you look from the first quarter of 2022 to the first quarter of 2023.
And then we add the quarters together and we see that it looks quite nice geographically.
Both in Europe and in North America then.
And if you look at the estimates that I have entered here, where it is assumed that you follow these financial goals.
If you reach 20% growth in 2023 2024 2025.
Yes, but then we get a P/E of 17 in 2024.
And falls down to P/E 14 in 2025 if they then succeed in this.
One thing that I find interesting is the Biden package itself.
As it has been presented in the USA.
Which Henrik has actually talked about himself.
And next to this, I wrote a little about this Biden package in brief
from what Henrik said during a previous interview in DI in March this year.
And this is broadband if you are to say Biden's contribution then to the United States.
It is to develop the infrastructure.
It's called the Infrastructure Investments and Jobs Act.
And for broadband, they budget 65 billion dollars.
And Henrik and Hexatronic estimate that this money will flow out
Or start rolling out in 2023 or the end of 2023.
And there Henrik himself has said that they have a market share of 5-6%.
And there is a major player in the US that has 70-75%.
And this growth hasn't shown up in the numbers yet.
And since we see such explosive growth in the US, it's like the good times are ahead of us.
So it will be better in the US.
This way, I don't think you should worry that it will sort of stop in the US right away.
But here you still gas up.
So I actually don't understand why the market is trading the stock down 10% on a record report.
I think the market is a bit too worried actually.
For interest rates and inflation here for Hexatronic.
So I will stay with my shares.
It's not often that I post comments like this.
But I will stay. I will not buy more because the holding is a bit too heavy in my portfolio right now.
So we'll see how it goes.
We are keeping our fingers crossed that it may be the case that the market reevaluates its view of the share a little further on.
But it was a small short report comment on Hexatronic.
Hope you appreciated it. In such cases, feel free to put a thumbs up and so on.
And if you want to know what I buy and sell for anything in real time, you can become a member of the channel.
Thanks to all members and you who watch and subscribe.
Have a great time! Ciao!