Are we recording now?
I am good looking?
Hello, hello. Today we are going to run a
Q&A video and now it is so that this intro-
-or the previous intro sucked, so now I record this on
the other camera because I have a little lack of time.
So, now we jump to the other camera
and then I start some videos.
Hello!
Today we will run a Q&amp;A, a question video.
I think we'm jumping right in.
That's fun.
Tjena Marcus. I wonder what is the difference between the
A, B and C shares for the same company?
Tjena Emil. Well, the difference between
A and B shares is that-
-it is usually the case that when you own an A share,
you have the right to vote.
You have the right to influence the company.
At a general meeting, for example, you get to
vote on what you think and feel.
If you think a company should do this or that.
If you instead have a B share
, you do not have as strong a voting right.
An A share is usually worth 10 times more
than a B share in the form of voting rights.
Otherwise, the shares are exactly the same.
The more shares you have, the greater the
impact you can make on the company.
If you are the main owner, you usually have A-shares,
but if you are a small saver like you and me-
-then it is usually the case that you drive on the B shares instead.
These shares with less voting rights
usually have greater turnover on the stock exchange.
So it's easier to buy and sell them.
A short answer to your question is that an A share is
worth more than a B share in the form of voting rights.
If you are not the main owner of the share, then
it is unnecessary to even think about it-
-and only buy the share that is cheapest
and has the highest turnover.
Should it be a high or low P / E ratio?
Tjena Elin!
The P / E ratio is an abbreviation of price divided by earnings.
Thus, the share price divided by the earnings per share.
These two key figures. How much does the share cost
and how much does the company earn in earnings per share?
Then you get the P / E ratio.
If a share costs SEK 5 and the earnings per share are SEK 1-
-then it takes 5 years for the company to earn the profit
that the company or share is valued at.
Some people think that a low P / E ratio is better than a high one,
but quite frankly you can say that a low P / E ratio
-means that the company is undervalued
compared to a high P / E ratio.
It can be said that the higher the P / E ratio of a company,
the higher their expectations are.
For example, we have Amazon which has
had a P / E ratio of 70 up to 130-
-if you look back since 2011.
But Amazon has also done very well,
increasing sales quite significantly.
And the stock has actually more than
tenfold in value since 2011.
So in that case, a high
P / E ratio has actually not been so bad.
Personally, I do not care so much
about P / E ratios when I choose shares.
Tjena Marcus.
I was just going to draw a quick question
how do you think about your own investing?
What is the goal of your savings?
How did you set it up in the form of monthly savings?
And you can even add how you started.
Did you have any start-up capital or did
you save monthly with a lower amount and then increase?
Yes, your strategy quite simply.
Tjena Daniel!
I always save at least SEK 1,000 per month
and today I do it in 7 different equity funds.
Gradually, I sometimes sell off some of the funds
if I am dissatisfied with the return.
And then I buy more of my shares instead.
I often want an 80/20 distribution
between my shares and funds.
I remember when I was little
and then we had cash-
-and I saved them in my piggy bank and sometimes
I took out my money and put them on the floor.
Then I wrote on a piece of paper how much I had saved.
My first goal was to save to
a Sony Ericsson mobile phone.
I really wanted it,
so I saved as much as I could-
-to afford to buy this cell phone.
And it's always with me.
This to save for something-
-or just that it's fun
to feel that you have money.
I started investing by reading a lot, I googled a lot and then I opened an account on Avanza.
I was 19 then, so it's just over 7 years ago.
So 7 years ago, in 2013 I think,
then I bought Avanza Zero for SEK 2,500.
It was savings that I did not
know what to do with.
And I have always wanted to learn
how stocks and mutual funds work.
So I put this money on Avanza
and started buying Avanza Zero.
I bought Avanza Zero afterwards, a bit like that.
And then I bought my first shares after that too.
Then I took some courses and have learned over time.
You never get full, even though
I've been doing this for 7 years-
-you never get full, you learn
all the time and that's what's fun.
Erik Martinger.
Many monthly savings in funds,
but what about stocks?
How do you do?
As I mentioned in the question before,
I buy funds every month.
Sometimes more often than not, if it is the case that it fluctuates a lot,
like now in corona times, I bought a little more.
As I said, my funds
account for more than 20% of my total portfolio.
-then I usually reallocate a little
or sell a little of my funds.
And buy more shares instead.
Because I think it's
more fun to deal with stocks.
Mattias Sandelius.
What does your portfolio look like?
Tjena Mattias!
Yes, I have 4 companies in my equity portfolio today.
Some may think it is a little higher risk,
but I like that it is high risk.
And I like when it swings a lot.
I think it's fun.
Today it is Castellum, Mycronic, Sinch and Plejd.
Then I also have 7 funds
and you can see them here.
Gabbe Lönn Erlandsson.
Do you have any examples of places where you can invest in the
interest-on-interest effect to secure your future savings?
Tjena Gabbe
I do not really know what you mean, but the interest on the interest rate effect
you achieve if it is the case that you invest in something-
-and then you get a return or interest
and then you reinvest it.
So that the year after or a time after that,
you get a bigger return or a bigger interest rate.
I advise you to watch my interest on interest rate video
where I explain more about interest on the interest rate effect.
Dividend shares are a perfect example of
how to apply interest to the interest rate effect.
How do you go about finding out
why a stock is going high or low?
Usually check news about the company, reports and more.
Through rumors, I search for news on Google.
If you search for the company, you usually
find it on Google on news or on Twitter.
Rafi Newton Andreasyan.
I do not know if I said that name correctly, but ... Sorry.
What strategy do you use to decide if you want to buy
a particular stock or not buy it right now?
I actually have no direct strategy, but if
I feel like buying a share, I buy the share.
I have a little gut feeling, you could say.
If I think the company has potential and I want to buy shares,
then I usually buy a small watch item
-which I hold and then I read about the company.
And is it so that I get a greater faith
in the company, then I buy more.
What did your portfolio look like when you started with
equities and mutual funds? And what does it look like today?
I am therefore interested in how the development has gone.
The development has probably not gone so well. I made quite
a lot of beginner mistakes that everyone makes the first 2, 3, 4, 5 years.
I'm still a beginner in my eyes.
I bought a lot of Avanza Zero in the beginning and a bit naughty ...
yes, cancer companies and stuff.
I do not think it went very well, but I can
throw up a print screen here so you can see.
Wilmer Lehtonen.
Hi, here is a question from a real beginner.
I am trying to build a portfolio
and study a few different funds, but also equity
-it feels like the stock market has been doing very well lately
and many funds and equities are at the top.
How to think then? Should you wait or
look for others who have not done as well?
Or buy into those who are high and wait for
Q3 in the hope that they will go up further?
Thanks.
Yes, you Wilmer.
I think you should not think too much.
But should I think about how long I invest?
Am I investing in one or two years?
Is it that you invest quarterly or why are you worried?
Of course, in the short span of time, it's hard
if it fluctuates a lot.
-as an example with corona when the stock market went down 10% in one day.
It was a lot of work for a lot of people and many sold out
and you might lose some money on it.
The absolute best tip I can give and
that I usually give, is to be long term.
To think that this is money that
I invest in maybe 10 years.
Then when you invest, you know that I should
not be affected by such short-term events.
So should one wait?
Yes, if you find it difficult because there is a risk that
it can go down a lot, then maybe you should wait.
Instead, I usually think like this that I might invest a little
less, if I'm worried it's a pretty high peak.
And keep investing over time just all the time.
You do not have to go all in at once, because that's
what a lot of beginners do in the beginning.
That you buy insanely large sums,
so if you earn 20,000 a month-
- do not go in with 20,000, but go in
with maybe 10% of what you earn.
If you might deposit SEK 5,000 for savings,
then you do not need to go in with 5,000 at once.
SEK 500 is enough, so that if it
goes down, you can buy for another SEK 500.
Then you have come in both when
it is high and when it is low.
Filip Thunstedt aka the boss and the legend.
Do you run mortgages?
Yes I do. I run with securities lending.
The super loan on Avanza. I run a maximum of 5% loan.
That's my personal rule.
Magnus Sturedahl.
How to lie down long or short? And how
do you calculate a possible loss?
Going to bed long means
that you believe in your investment in ...
It is believed that it will simply go up.
Going to bed short on time means
believing in decline.
It is therefore believed that investment will decline.
This can be done with leverage products
such as bull, bear, turbo variants, CFDS.
There are a variety of such products.
I actually do not know all these products in my head, but
leverage products are not recommended for beginners.
It's pretty easy to burn yourself there.
If you want to calculate the risks with a lever, then you have to look at how
much leverage is in the product that you buy.
Then you get to look at the potential downside,
if it is the case that it would go down 5% -
-multiply it with the lever, type.
There you have your risk.
Plus any fees and interest for that product.
This is a very complicated issue
that is very difficult to get into right now.
The risk is great when you trade with leverage,
so read on carefully and make sure you learn first.
Tore Landin Larsson. My real brother, the star.
Strategies for buying, selling, reallocating. It would
be interesting how you reason about it.
So, when you take home profits, sell off bad holdings, if you are long
on minus investments or if you sell off those with the highest development?
Well, it's a little hard to say something red.
If it is the case that I see that a company is
not developing as well as I hope
-if it just keeps going down and down, then maybe I'm selling off.
For example, I invested in Catena Media
a while ago and they did not go so well.
-then I sold at a loss, because
it's better that you sell at a small loss-
-than you sit for as long as you like
and hope for a turnaround.
Many say, "Yes, be long-term." Which I also say
that you should be for 5, 10 years and blah, blah blah.
But if there is news that comes up
during the time you invested in a stock-
-which shows that this company is not performing well
and their profits are falling, they are losing money.
Why should you join a sinking ship for?
Then it's better for you to get rid of that sourdough.
That's usually how I think.
Then I prefer to hop on a boat or a train
that goes and where the chance to make money is greater.
I also invest my money in something that I
feel can give me more value for my investment.
Than I should have them in some sourdough
that does not give me a return simply.
Tony Godlike Lindh.
Is it better to allocate an equal amount to funds
or a large amount to a single fund?
Yes, you Tony. This is a good question. I myself prefer
to do so so that I spread the amount among different funds.
Some funds that I think will
go better, I have slightly larger amounts in.
And some others have slightly smaller amounts in
which I might think is high risk and other things.
So it's different and it's from person to person.
You get to feel yourself, quite simply.
Erik Martinger.
When will the video come up?
Now.
Ida Runn. I subscribe to Youtube, but still
have not received a vacuum cleaner as you promised.
I wonder where it is?
Vacuum cleaner?
So now I have answered most of the questions
and forgive me if I have not answered your particular question.
I've been getting a lot of crazy questions lately
and I try to answer as much as possible.
I have an idea that we should run maybe this week's question
or that I bring some of your viewer questions-
-and have them at the end of each video perhaps.
I think it might be a good idea.
Feel free to thumbs up if you like the idea
or write a comment below.
Dare to introduce yourself in the
comments field here on Youtube-
-or in our Facebook group.
It's incredibly fun when we build this small community,
so we can learn from each other.
It's a lot of fun.
I get an awful lot of questions every day and it just grows
every day and I get more and more messages-
-and I actually do not have time to answer everything.
Sometimes it can be that I answer and it is because I am kind,
but preferably I wish that if you have private questions-
-either you can book a meeting with me
for a fee for my time costs.
I have to pay my bills.
But otherwise it is so that I recommend
instead to ask the question completely free in our Facebook group-
-so that others can take part of the knowledge.
But it can also be the case that others in the group
can help you with just the answer to your question.
And I really appreciate when you others
answer questions in our Facebook group.
So that I do not have to go in and answer everyone myself,
because it takes an incredible amount of time from me.
We have more many good videos that will come and
if you have tips on good videos, comment as well.
I hope you enjoyed this video too.
See you in the next. Have a nice day! Thanks.
Bye.