Avanza and Nordnet, they've got competition.
In this video I'm going to go through Levler, which is a new stock platform where you can trade stocks and funds.
And now they offer fee-free trading of shares until March 2025.
So I will go through my thoughts about the platform, how it has gone, I have deposited SEK 1000 for which I bought some shares.
Will show how it works, what I don't like and what I like about the platform.
Now we run, roll intro!
Hi mate, nice to see you again!
That's right, Levler is a new savings platform that offers stock trading, they just launched it.
They have been around for a while, I don't know how long, but I have about a year or a little more.
They previously only offered mutual fund trading, but now they have launched stock trading as well.
They then offer a 25% discount on all funds and also interest on ISK.
So I usually say, if you want to start saving, start with Avanza, up to 50,000.
If you want to buy more shares after that, go to Nordnet, then you have up to 80,000 but only within 6 months.
So there you have a time limit.
At Levler, there is no time limit, or I mean there is no amount limit, but the time limit is until March and then 2025.
Then it will start to cost brokerage.
But the brokerage at Levler will be cheaper than at Avanza.
I put graphics here, compare, here you can see the price of Levler, here you can see the price of Avanza and Nordnet.
First of all then, what can you buy on Levler?
Yes, you can trade shares on the Swedish stock exchange, i.e. the Stockholm Stock Exchange, not, for example, Spotlight.
For example, you can't buy, for example, Plejd, but you can buy, for example, Evolution.
You can buy Hennes and Maurits, H&M that is, but you can't buy, for example, Spiltan shares.
So that's the downside then.
It is only Nasdaq Stockholm as it currently is, but they have plans to launch it in the future.
You can't buy foreign stocks either, and I've had questions in the group about whether you can buy Bull & Bear and such leveraged products.
No, but this is purely shares or funds on the Swedish stock exchange then.
And what's really nice is that they offer free brokerage until March 2025.
So I got into the app and put in a coin to try this out.
I have bought some shares.
Brokerage-free stock trading simply means that when you buy and sell stocks, you have to pay a fee.
And they skip this fee, so for example on Avanza and Nordnet you have free brokerage up to certain levels.
50,000 is Avanza, 80,000 is Nordnet.
So this is good, there is no upper limit as far as I can see anyway.
And this is really fun for us who like to save money and not pay so many expenses.
So I caved in and tested this app and let you know what I think, give some feedback to the app simply.
If you want to try Leveller, there is a link in the description and the comment field.
So go, try it in case you're a bit keen on saving money.
So if we start with first of all my experience, I deposited a 1000 note with Swish and bought some shares.
I bought some Investor, I bought some Lundbergs and I bought some Betsson.
The app works well, but the first thing I encounter is that it feels a bit like an online shop or a clothing store.
A bit strange, but it's probably because they have chosen to target people who may not be familiar with shares simply.
You press add to basket when you want to buy a share or a fund and then it's like a checkout.
So that you can click on what you are interested in and then in the shopping cart you can pay.
And it works, but I prefer the traditional way of saying buy or sell, that you press that instead.
So it works to buy shares, a disadvantage here is that you don't get the same functionality as with Avanza & Nordnet.
For example, you have no buy points in the graph, you have no technical analysis, somewhat limited overview when it comes to your total portfolio return.
So far from what I can see, but I have just opened an account in and of itself, the P/E ratio shows a little error.
Evolution showed a PE number of 339, so that might be a bit misleading.
The fund discounts are also good, which we will get into now, and it is the case that Leveller offers a 25% discount on the fund fees.
I haven't compared against SAVR and Fondo, but the two platforms also exist that offer quite heavy discounts on the funds.
This is how it is good if you save in funds, so you can check if you have active funds, you can save quite a lot on fees on these platforms.
Now I thought I would take some questions that came from the Facebook group then.
Rasoul asks what happens after 2025 with the fee, well then it goes to brokerage, 0.185% in variable and minimum brokerage is one kroner.
About a 25% discount compared to Avanza and Nordnet, so it's cheaper than Avanza and Nordnet.
Jessica asks if the funds are only discounted until March 2025 as well, or if they continue after that.
The discount should be the same as I understand it, 25% discount is sort of permanent and it's not a temporary thing.
Alaa asks if they have bull and bear certificates, if there is a free charge on them as well, but no, they don't have that at the moment and I don't know if they will launch that.
Isak asks if it is free of charge on American shares, and no, they only offer trading on Swedish shares at the moment.
But it is something they plan to launch in the future then.
So my honest opinion about Levler, I think it works well to trade on Levler, I have bought shares, I encountered some bug though when I bought shares.
But first of all, what I like about it is that the app itself or the website looks a bit like a clothing store, it feels like a web shop.
So it's like nothing that, what can I say, the design doesn't appeal to me right away, but the idea is more to appeal perhaps to a beginner who has never saved before.
Who might recognize themselves at a clothing store or an online webshop or something.
I know someone on Discord said, shit it looks just like a store, I'll put a picture over here so you can see and compare, it looks kind of funny.
I would like to see that when you have placed an order, because you can enter the price you want to buy a share for and place an order, then I think it is a bit unclear that you cannot find it so easily.
You have to go into account events to find this, I would have liked it to be on the overview or something so you can get to it faster.
And one thing that also bothers me is that you are logged out fairly quickly, I don't know if it has to do with the bank ID or something like that, but on Avanza Nordnet it feels like you can be logged in longer.
At Avanza, I know that you can decide that time, how long you should be logged in and so on.
Another thing that bothers me a bit is when you press search, at least on the computer, it first of all selects funds, not shares.
Here, I would instead like that when you press search, you get a sorting of both stocks and funds.
So it's a bit frustrating, and I got a bug then when I bought or was going to buy shares in Betsson, then it said something like, the order didn't go through and then I couldn't place a new order because the previous order didn't have gone through.
But it was all of a sudden gone, so I couldn't go in and remove it or anything. There must have been some bug or some temporary error.
So it works to buy shares, it works great. I haven't tested funds per se, but it could be a bit like that, a few small bugs here and there.
But it's great that you get free fees, at least until 2025. It's worth its weight in gold.
The future plans for Levler. After all, they have said that they are going to launch more markets, that is, more exchanges and also foreign stocks and have said on Twitter that they are going to be competitive here.
So it's fun to see what will happen. They also offer an interest rate, I forgot to say, on ISK of 1.25% or something like that. I put graphics here with how much interest there is.
Here you can see my portfolio, how it looks today, with the three shares that I bought. I chose to invest my 1000 note in Investor, Lundbergs, which is a small base in my private portfolio with.
So I just experimented with them. And then I bought Betsson too, just for fun. It came up and I thought we'd run one. So that's how it looks at the moment.
So overall, I think the app works just fine, absolutely. I think it's great that Avanza and Nordnet have competition. I have gone on Twitter and said that I am bothered by the brokerage classes where Avanza is good so you can change the brokerage class once every day.
There we do not know how it will be at Levler in the future. Nordnet gets a leg up there, because there you can only change the brokerage class once a month.
So it's really lousy Nordnet, you have to fix that. It has to get better.
But generally speaking, I hate it. I hate brokerage classes. I HATE brokerage classes.
Stop it, everyone. Even Levler. Try to fix an automatic brokerage class. So you always get the cheapest fees when you buy and sell shares.
And if you appreciate this video and are considering opening an account there, you are very welcome to use my affiliate link down here in the description or comment field for Levler.
As I said, free of charge until 2025. Go crazy, shop. There are no fees, so just drive.
So you can test yourself, buy and sell a little and so on.
And thanks to all the members who join and support the channel, it's much appreciated. If you want to know what I buy and sell in real time, you can do it via the membership.
And you can become a member either here under the video on Youtube, it's the cheapest, or on Patreon.
If you can't access this button, I'm on Patreon too and it's exactly the same content there.
Then you also get access to group coaching and other things and you get a nice little star or something like that, a bubble on your username in the comment field.
Thank you very much for watching and if you want to see more about Levler and other platforms, maybe suggest some other platform in the comments section.
So I hope to see you in the next video.
Have a great time, ciao!