Do you want SEK 20,000 today
Or do you want SEK 1.3 million in 30 years? You decide
You may be dreaming of making a lot of money
And the truth is that most of them want to get rich today
But if you knock it out, if you look
in the long run and how the other millionaires and billionaires how the very richest in the world
have become rich
So it is with the help of the compound interest
Everyone wants a quick fix
You want abs now
But you do not want to go to the gym
You want to buy a car today but you have no money
Do you have patience
Then you will get rich
Believe me
After this video you will have
The formula
To how to do
We will go through three points
And then you will understand what the interest rate on interest rate effect is
And how to apply it
On your
investments so you can easily start investing
And in the long run build a large fortune
So we start with point No. 1 And that is perhaps the most boring point But what is interest on interest
And simply put, it's about you
Invest your money
And after a year
So they increase
Let me take an example, let's say I have SEK 100, your SEK 100 will receive 10% interest
Return every year
After one year, your SEK 100 has become worth SEK 110
After a year
This is how you got an interest on your money and it is now that this interest-on-interest effect strikes
Year 2
When you have already received
Interest on your already interest-bearing money then
Earlier then
Then you will receive interest on your already interest-bearing money
Year 2
Yes, then you get ten percent
On your SEK 110
As they are now worth
And when you pull it out in the long run it's then
You can see the great effects of the interest-on-interest effect
Overtime
So these will increase in value because you always get
interest on your already interest-bearing money
It is an interest-on-interest effect
very briefly explained
And now you come
surely ask "But how do I get interest, where do I get interest from"
And it can be a savings account, it can be funds it can be shares,
Cryptocurrencies it can be anything for investments that you get a return on.
The most common and what
I usually talk about investing in stocks
on shares
This is how you get a profit sharing from these companies that you have invested in
And if you do not know what a stock is, check out my video about stocks for beginners
But with stocks
Yes, then you get a dividend from the company's profit
Which allows you to reinvest the money
And normally you might get two to four percent
In different shares
Which gives out this kind of profit sharing
And that is exactly what is magical in the long run
When you reinvest this dividend year after year
That's when you can see really cool effects
With how your money grows
I want to take the example
Castellum a real estate company
Those who bought shares
For SEK 100,000 in Castellum in 1997
and has retained them
Today has shares for a value of
SEK 4 million
Those shares currently yield
Dividend
At approximately SEK 110,000 per year
That is more than the original investment amount
How sick!
So more than what they invested
Get them back every year
In dividend
Crazy!
The key to why the interest rate effect is so crazy
It's because you use the time
The longer you invest
The greater this interest rate on the interest rate effect
Therefore, it is extremely important that you who are young
That you invest
As early as possible
The greater the interest rate on the interest rate effect.
This is what gives some an edge over others
For example, many parents invest their money in their children before they are even born
Which means that this interest-on-interest effect can only work for the money, just over time
How should you think when investing your money if you want to get an interest rate effect?
Yes, I'm thinking like this
Money I do not need
Money that I pile up, I invest it!
I have no direct plan with them.
But I just want to invest them and let the money work for me.
And so you should think.
You do not have to worry about saving a latte a month or whatever
Live your life, enjoy! But money that you get over that you can afford to invest does it!
And let this money be invested over a longer period of time.
The longer you invest
The greater this interest rate on the interest rate effect
And that's what I want you to understand
This is how it looks
If you, for example
Deposits SEK 20,000 that you invest
After one year, they have increased by 15% to SEK 23,000
Year 2
Yes, then they have increased to SEK 26,450
Now keep an eye on this green bar here
So that's how much It increases For each year
After 3 years DKK 30,000
After 4 years DKK 34,000
5 years
Six years
7 years
Look at the green how much bigger it will be than the blue bar
And this then proves how much your money increases over time
And now we max out on this really properly
So that you can see what a difference it makes
After 30 years
so have your 20,000
become worthwhile
1.3 million
And this is an example of what the interest-on-interest effect can do to your invested money if you just have patience
And let them work year after year
Einstein called this the eighth wonder of the world
And there's something in that
This when you pull it out in the long run
That's when they get these magical effects
So it
So-called interest-on-interest effect
"snowball effect"
This is what allows you to get filthy rich
In a really long time
And what the interest-on-interest effect is really about
It is that you have to be patient
Just like you do not get stomach cramps
After a gym workout
And you will not get rich
of scratching a bouncy castle, if you do not have a damn lucky
It's simply about investing your money
And then you have to be patient
You should let the money grow over time
Year after year, they grow and grow
And the longer you wait, the longer
The bigger the snowball and the more money you make.
This is not revolutionary
You will not get rich today
And that's not the point either
The very purpose of telling this is just to be long-term when investing in stocks
It is in the long run that you make the big money
Now these people are talking about the fact that a friend or uncle or something else has become a millionaire
In one day through stocks
That may be true, but there is a very low chance that you will succeed as well.
That's why I want to
Clarify over how important it is to you
Is long-term and that you have a long time horizon when you invest in shares
It's incredibly important
Have patience
Because that's when you make the big bucks
If you do not already know what stocks are or how they work If you have not already opened
A share account, I think
that you should do it
And in my video shares for beginners, I go through how easy it is to actually buy shares
And how it works and how you make money on them
I think you should watch that video
And if you already have a stock account and know how it works, I think you should check out my second video about beginner mistakes
as different beginners do when buying stocks
Thank you so much for watching this video and if you like it, feel free to press thumbs up
Have a good time See you next time
Hello