In this video, we will go through five simple steps
to how you can start investing your money
My name is Marcus and I run SparaCash
SparaCash is for you who are a beginner who wants to learn
Start investing your money in stocks, mutual funds and more.
Now we start with step number 1!
Step number 1.
Start by opening an account at a bank
And I usually say to open an account at Avanza bank or at Nordnet Bank
They make it easy for you to invest your money
In both equities and mutual funds
Traditional big banks they like to make it difficult for you
They do not want to make it easy for you because they want you to go to the bank
&amp; you should get help from those There Because then they can
Lock yourself in
In their own
Products
They do so to
they should be able to make more money on you as a customer
but Avanza and Nordnet want to make it easy for you so that you can understand that you can trade shares and mutual funds yourself
Because that's how they make more money
In short, good
Open an account on Avanza or Nordnet there is the link below
They make it easy for you to start investing
It takes about 3 minutes to open an account at one of the 2 banks.
I recommend you open an account at both banks
Because then you can take advantage of both their new customer offers
Step number 2 is that you should open
an ISK account
A so-called Investment Savings Account
An investment savings account makes it easy for you to invest
I have a video on how an investment savings account works
Both advantages and disadvantages.
If you want to know more about an investment savings account, you can watch that video
An investment savings account is perfect
For you who want to start investing your money and can not keep track of what you have bought and what you have sold
How much are you going to pay in taxes and declare and stuff like that cumbersome fuss
Without opening an investment savings account, you deposit money you start investing, and then redeem yourself
And you get a very low tax
The only thing to keep in mind when investing money
An investment savings account is that money you invest
should stay in the investment savings account.
You should not use your ISK as
a salary account when you lock in and out money without money that you deposit in an investment savings account
stay there, this for tax reasons
Step number 3 I usually say but start by buying a fund
Buy a free Sweden fund, for example
Advance. Zero or Nordnet Indexfond Sweden
These two free funds
They spread your money among a variety of stocks
On the Swedish stock exchanges
And completely without a fee
It is perfect to start with these two types of funds
Just to get started - because it is getting started that is the most important thing
So you can try by depositing maybe SEK 100 in one fund and deposit SEK 100 in the other
And then compare these two
How your hundred bucks differ how they go up and how they go down
Quite a few want to start by buying shares
I usually say start with a fund so you can learn how the process works
Is that how you feel you want to start buying shares instead
But do not really know what it is, of course I have a video about shares for beginners that you can watch
Step number 4
You have to decide how much
money you can save every month
The best thing is that you set up a monthly savings account
these funds
So that you every month
Invest the same amount all the time so you buy both when it is high
And when it's low
let's say you invest SEK 100 every month for 20 years with a 10% annual return
It will be approximately SEK 72,000 in the end
If you instead invest SEK 500 every month for 20 years
To 10% annual return
In the end, it will be approximately SEK 361,000 with interest on the interest effect.
Do you not know what the interest rate on interest rate effect is?
And
I have a video for it;)
The last step, yes it is step number 5
and that is that you should: Put yourself on your hands!
And what do I mean by that?
You have to be patient
In other words
The more patience you have
The more money you will earn
It is in the long run that you make the big money
And as I always say
It is a high risk to invest your money.
One last tip and that is that
The earlier you start
The better with the interest rate on the interest rate effect
then the money will work for you
the more wealthy you will become
Money As you invest it is money
which you should be able to afford to lose
money that you can afford to spare
thus to be without
for maybe three to five years at least
Keep in mind that historical returns are
no guarantee of future returns
It therefore means that
Equity funds that have performed well in the past
So there is no guarantee that
They will do well in the future
But if you look at the history, we see that the stock markets have given 6-10% return approximately per year
if you pull it out in the long run
So here are five simple steps you can take to begin the process of preparation for mediation
Links are below
How to open an account and more. If you have any questions, comment below
Thank you so much for watching this video
See you next time!
Hi!