Hey
In this video, I thought I would go through
My 2020
This is because Avanza has a summary of it
How mine and your
stock and fund portfolio at Avanza have fared in 2020.
And you can easily go into it
If you check the address here
So you can get an overview similar to the one I will show
how your investment has gone simply!
Like Thank you for becoming so many subscribers here on the channel so I think I should be a little nice
Show me exactly how it went for me
To show that I'm not a lying ugly fish like
And
Some other social media has
If you have been following the stock market over the past year, you may have a clue that
The stock market got a small crash there in March 2020
when the pandemic occurred
And then, as luck would have it, the stock market recovered
And the vast majority of us
Which was included throughout 2020
Who sat still
has probably made quite a lot of money
the cut has actually made quite good money and we will see that now in this overview
But I think we jump into the first, that is, my total value
How much it increased by
My total value increased by SEK 213,721
And from that we then have deposits of
SEK 41,500
We have a development of SEK 165,000
And dividends of SEK 6,700
And my strategy in 2020 it has simply been to just
be still and do not do much.
In the past, people may have gone in and bought and sold
one has been satisfied perhaps after 10-20% return
But this year I have let the shares rush
and most people have actually done that, they have gone up quite a lot quite a lot of shares
Going on to the next picture, we'll see
Yes, but it went better for me than the average at Avanza
I think quite a few of us might have
had the good fortune to be above average
Both more than the index and more than the Avanza average
If we have been sitting on these technology stocks
The sustainability shares or similar.
So my development ended at + 38.06%
Percent
But my main portfolio, the long-term portfolio, did a little better
Around 39-40% so it is probably the one that makes up a larger part of my total investment portfolio at Avanza
And you have to be happy with that
I'm definitely happy with that
But it is in the long run that is the most important thing.
Hope it holds up too
This was a very magnificent year
So I must be very happy that I managed to beat both the stock market and the average at Avanza
If we go on to my best stock friends as they call it, we'll see
The best stock I have to thank is Sinch
which went plus SEK 104,000
Mycronic at + DKK 38,000
And Plaid at + SEK 35,000
Have you seen my video about stocks for beginners, it's quite funny
Because we have a sticky comment there
I have promised to keep Plejd as long as I have patience so we can see
But the losers then that I talked about in my loss video so among other things we have besqab
which is the loser I chose to sell off
There I went minus - SEK 30,000 on
Castellum actually went down - SEK 2,500
And then we have Realty Income Corp.
We're moving on
In this monthly overview, we see that November went best at plus SEK 93,000
And in March I sat down. on the hands and it was very difficult psychologically but there you have learned something
Minus SEK 57,000 I went there
And then we have these days which I think are quite interesting
And then you see March 12th
Then I was minus - SEK 34,000
In one day then!
It hurts quite a lot when you look at it
Then you have days like
April 23 plus + 25000 kr
And in November we have two days, one of + SEK 17,000 and one plus + SEK 19,000
If you look at the overview shown here, you will see that it is Sweden that my majority of shares are in
And then it's in the funds that I get a little more spread across the US and China
But I prefer to stay on the Swedish market, because I have the best control there now.
But I'm thinking of broadening a little more globally in the future actually.
So a total summary here now over the portfolio and it is then 2020 + 38% as I said
Plus DKK 213,000
The best month was November and the best stock was Sinch
I'm glad I kept it and that I
Still holding on
We'll see how long it lasts
But yes it will be fun to see how 2021 degenerates
And I would very much like to know how it has gone for you
So feel free to comment below on how much you earned or how much your portfolio went up or down
And keep in mind that what I invest in you should not see as any advice or recommendations
But it is
Totally my decisions
You must take responsibility for your particular purchases
it is you who must do your own research
Before you choose to buy something
Do not trust others
And yes I look forward to the coming year and I think we are celebrating
Just this one
Special
The special Year with a little soda I actually think
I wish you a good continuation and hope that it will be
a fantastic 2021
Have a good time