null
came to change.
We come from 2021 and 2020
Nice years where everything went up.
But in 2022 became one year
that no one could have predicted.
An inflation that went from 0 % to 10 %.
Interest rates that were at minus
as now at 2.5%
mortgage rates
up to 4 percent.
Russia's evil entry, the war in Ukraine.
This and much more.
Got devastating consequences for the stock exchange
is 20 22.
There were many incidents that occurred under 20 22 that
Very few could have predicted.
In this video I want to go through how my
Twenty -sided two have gone there.
I will go through my overview at Avanza.
I hope you may have given the fuck in the sales button exactly
As I usually advise,
But there are some exceptions that one must
Pill on it.
Whatever you have done, I hope you have health in retaining,
After all, that's the most important thing.
So now we jump into my twenty twenty -two
On with the cyclop first we look at the stock exchange at large
how deeply the stock exchange made its deepest dive in a long time
minus fifteen and half percent for o m x thirty
but we look at the wider o m x s p in because o m
x thirty is a pretty narrow index
Then we see
That the stock exchange as a whole went down it is significantly more.
Minus fifteen percent does not sound so dangerous indeed
So what can we learn from previous stock market cases
Large dips are usually followed by even greater upturns
just as we can see is certainly shows this now now it goes
after all from ninety -nine which is quite long
but o m x thirty have gone up six hundred nine percent
since
and in these dips so the stock market is usually recovering
a lot.
But.
It is not the important thing but the important thing in
This video is to go in and check out how it went
for me and for me for twenty twenty -two so it went
minus thirty -three come thirty -seven percent
Tough now, to say the least.
But I'm actually pretty happy because I was after all
down and touched on minus forty percent
during the year and it managed to recover the portfolio up
to minus thirty -three percent
And it was a bit lucky this I do not know we have after all
a pair of drawbar that has
stood for having recovered the portfolio a great deal
If you then look at the start, however, we see
that overall, I'm plus just over ninety percent
Since I started investing.
So I don't know how accurate these numbers are,
How correct it is and has a little more money on others
Places too, but it's nice that you
Located plus anyway.
If we move on, we see that compared to others like that
I am lower than the average for the year
t o m x thirty minus fifteen avanza jane cut minus
twenty -one percent and D J U S A minus twenty percent
So that yes a little worse than the incision simply.
And we look at Kronoberg so we see minus two hundred
nineteen thousand four hundred four -nyste -two kronor
of which development stands for minus four hundred forty
thousand crowns.
Yes, it's a lot of money,
But I had a pretty good year seen for deposits.
I put in the whole two hundred eleven 1000 SEK so that
The total change in value is, as always, doped a whole
part of my deposits dividends actually went up
to the entire elvatus four hundredths sexty -six kronor,
Which is a record for me.
Fun to see that there is actually some money left anyway
Despite this shit year
so we may hope that it will be better next year
And we look at my purchases and sell here and then we see that three hundred and thirty,
Five thousand one hundred and eighty dollars I bought for and 100 fourteen thousand,
I sold nine hundred and fifty kronor.
This is how it traded in January, so I bought as absolutely the most
And since then it has been so that I have had a whole
Part of cash during the year that I have put in and invested.
And I have also started investing in my business account,
which is separated from my private.
But these are entered in these figures then
and my sales were in April and June and November at its greatest
in April.
Then I see that I sold for 83 three thousand kronor,
Which I can suspect has to do with Sinch.
If we go on, we see exactly
Investor was the ones I bought most in.
I have invested a great deal in Investor this year
and I have sold since for fifty -thumb three hundreds
in the beginning of the year.
If we move on, we see we have the most you invest 12
months in line and so many months you bought something 12
months so 12 out of 12.
It's cruel.
That's exactly what I usually tell you about
continue to invest all the time regardless of whether it is
shaky or not
and now we get into individual holdings here so see
We best and worst securities during the year.
Twenty -sided two so we see that hexatronic die for plus
Forty -five thousand kronor
Waystream plus thirty -few thousand kronor and savlend for
one thousand -two hundred crowns so very nice to have 3
Pieces of holdings that have actually gone well and these
The shares I actually went through in my video about my 3
Best shares.
Twenty -sided two so check it out if you haven't seen it
Because there I go through this company gives little
elevator spitch and so there talks a little what I think and think
The 3 worst
that is the largest drawbar that pushed down the portfolio
During the year, Sinch is for minus one hundred and eighty thousand kronor
Play SEK 89,000.
And Castellum minus eighty thousand kronor.
Juicy sums there so really
And now we'll see what the countries look like you have the most
Money invested in Sweden about ninety percent
a little u s a and then a little other in scattered then
and now we get into funds
What do we have on funds then yes we see the companies that are most
Owned in the funds
Investor that I invested a great deal in Industrivärden
Lundbergs Kinnevik and Hexagon
I suspect this is because I have a very
Big thing in Spiltan investment company.
As these companies are in.
Durability value better than the incision o k fun
now and the funds that have the best sustainability value are then
Spiltan Investment Company Plus Real Estate and Avanza
Sweden fun.
So thank you for this year, they say now.
So my avanza overview minus thirty -three percent
Two hundred ninety -thousand SEK in value change excluding
Deposits then
Best Month July Best Share Hexatronic Cronimet
yes that was the year it was tough to see
But then it is, after all, we have to have a little downturn before
Breaths too
As one usually says after rain comes sunshine and after
Sunshine comes rain
so that after the rise we must have a small slowdown sometimes
And that's probably what we get to know what we'll see well
How it will be during twenty -threatening.
I think it might be going on
shaky this year,
but hopefully we will get
a little recovery in perhaps the last half of the year
Hope I at
maybe that inflation begins to come down a little neighbor and
That you do not have to raise interest rates so much.
It may probably give
A small spark for the stock exchange to recover, I think.
How did it go for you under twenty -twenty -two write?
Great this below and I really want to know
If you have any tips on more videos that you think I
will do wonders for the year, twenty -twenty
hopefully so the year will go better than it
did last year, but now don't forget that
Continue investing all the time.
Ongoing, continued to invest in funds
shares.
And is it that you are not comfortable so to run a
Monthly savings constantly saves a little neighbor?
Make sure you don't pull down on your savings even if you
gets tougher times this year so always have some savings
running after because when it goes down, it buys after all
Cheaper to get more share for money.
So it is important that you continue to save
Even if it is hard for you, but it is better that you
reduces your savings than you completely turn it off,
so keep investing all the time and doing it with
money that you can afford to be without
Thank you so much for watching this video.
Have a good time and we'll see you in the next well.