You looked right!
I have already earned over SEK 40,000 on shares this year
It is not that difficult to make money on stocks.
I tried to tell this in my previous videos
But I think that in this video
so we should simplify
We go through the only two ways you can make money on stocks. I will also show you mine
stock trades that I made money on
So you can see
Exactly how it works
When making money on stocks
A small bonus is that in the end I will give you my best tips for when to buy shares.
So that you can make as much money as possible.
If you did not know, my name is Marcus Lindblad
I run SparaCash.se
SparaCash is for you who are a beginner who wants to learn how to save in shares, funds and much more!
I want to make it simple and easy for you who are a beginner.
Pick up a good cup of coffee because now we start the video. And thank you so much to you who have invited me for a coffee.
Briefly explained, there is
Two ways you can make money on stocks.
The first way is when buying stocks
How to buy the shares for a certain price
Over time, the price of your shares can go up
And then you sell them for a more expensive price
and then you have made money on your shares.
The second way
Which you can make money on stocks through
It is that you buy
Shares that pay a dividend
This means that companies share their profits as they do
Thus, you earn
Money through it
And then you get this money
directly to your account in which you own the shares
and then you have made money.
Coffee break!
Nice
So we start with way number 1. And that is that you make money
when the price of
The shares are going up
And in my first video
called 'Aktier för nybörjare' (stocks for beginners)
I showed you how to buy shares
And I bought some shares in the company called Plejd
"And now the purchase of the shares went through and I now have 1 share in Plejd"
And then it was like that
That I June 8, 2020
Bought shares for
Just over DKK 5,000 in Plejd.
What I did then was that I bought into Plejd with a small security post as I call it.
What it simply means to me
I force myself to read more about the company
Then I will not lose a profit if the share goes up very much.
But I also do not go in too heavy if it is the case that I have missed some detail on the road
which means that the share may fall very much. It might not hurt as much!
But if we wind up the band a little, then I bought a little more shares
Closer to SEK 15,000
In total, I then invested SEK 20,000 in Plejd
As time went on
so it went better for the company Plejd and thus I decided
To buy a little more shares in Plejd.
Then I bought for SEK 10,000 more
So invested a total of DKK 30,000 in Plejd.
If you look at the value today of my shares
As I have invested in care
So today they are worth SEK 95,000
Which means an increase of just over
65000 kr
On my SEK 30,000 that I have invested in Plejd.
In percentage terms, this means an increase of 216%
right now
So if I were to sell my shares
Then I would have made a profit
At SEK 65,000 today
And this is not something that is normal for a stock to increase so much in one year
I was simply lucky
And I should thank myself for that ...
You need to know
If the company is doing poorly in the future or they may go bankrupt
Then come mine
Shares may theoretically be worth 0
And then I did not make any money
You have not made money until
Sold or taken home his profit
And for you who are a beginner who may not really
Understand why the price of these shares
In Plejd has gone up so much
Then I'll try to explain it now
The simple explanation for why the price of the shares in Plejd has gone up so much
It's simply that company
Has shown
That they can make more money than they have done before
And what happens
That to other individuals like you and me or
Banks and other companies
They believe that Plejd's shares are
Attractive and they also want to invest in this company
If it is the case that they continue to do just as well in the future
And what you do then is that
to raise the price
As one is willing to pay
For ordinary shares
And what happens is that the price of the shares goes up
Which makes my investment worth more than it was before
Put number 2 that you can make money on stocks
I made a video about dividend stocks
As you can see here and in that video, I go through some basics about why a company pays dividends
How to make money on it
But simply put, it's about
Companies - usually slightly larger companies
share a piece of the profit that they make
They thank us shareholders for what we want
Be part of the company
But also then to
Those who own a piece of the company like you and me
Or those who have founded the company should get
A small part of the profit simply
Eat a small piece of the cake
Not all companies share the profits
Plaid that I talked about earlier
They do not share their profits
Because they think
The money they earn
Will stay in the company
And should not be distributed to
Because they consider the company
Will use this money in a better way
But larger companies such as banks and real estate companies
Who gets a stable
Cash flow as it is called
they make a lot of money every month or every year and so on
They are generous and want to share with us
Like Thank you for investing in their business
But what I like about dividend stocks
You get a little
Money that thus pure cash into the account
And the money they drop into the same account that you own your shares on
So you have few shares in a dividend share
on, for example, an Investment Savings Account
Then the money will fall into the same account that you own the shares in
And then it's free for you
Take out this money and do whatever you want with it
Or buy
More shares
So you get a higher dividend next time
Or whatever you want
Buy a Snickers or whatever
For example, Castellum
Last year I received SEK 3,600 in dividends from Castellum
And now I have bought a little more shares
Castellum
Partly for this dividend money
But even so, Castellum has raised the dividend this year
Which means I'm getting a higher dividend so this year I'll get it
4000 kr
in share dividend from Castellum
But do you then have to choose either or?
No you do not have to! It is just as well to have both a dividend share and a growth share.
If you think the price will go up on the shares instead.
I have both.
That it goes well for you too.
And you think I'll give you my best tips for making money on stocks.
These tips You should think about before buying shares.
So you make the right choice.
Tip number one to 1 for you who are a beginner
Who may not have bought shares yet.
Only invest money that you can afford to be without.
The stock market fluctuates a lot, it goes up a lot and it goes down a lot.
Money that you invest, you should be able to afford to be without for at least 3-5 years.
Let's say you have
Just started working on something and then you have set aside some money
let your salary say SEK 1,000
Do not invest all that money
Maybe starts with SEK 100 or SEK 200 that you can afford to be without
And test a little with them just to feel and learn a little how it works
This way you avoid
To go in too heavy and burn yourself
And then maybe you lose a lot of money and you think it's hard
And then you simply will not continue to invest ...
Start with a small amount
And do not sell without Let it lie!
Then you will learn how it swings up and down
Tip number two
Only buy shares in companies that you understand
Think of it as lending money
if you had lent money to a friend
Which you trust
Yes but then Can you trust this buddy will pay back the money to you
But if you would instead lend money to a stranger on the street that you have never met before
How sure are you that you will get your money back?
It's a bit like investing in shares
Invest in companies that you know how to make money
So that you can get a little more feel, Yes so you can understand a little
This company will use yours
Money the right way
Very many beginners buy companies or buy shares in companies like
they have no idea how they make money and if they even make any money!
Some companies make a loss
And people are just wondering
the stock should go up or down
But do you know what the company does and how they make money
So you will make much better investments
Number 3 be patient
To be patient
This is how you will earn
Terrible much more
Money on the stock market
I remember when I was a beginner
so I keep buying and selling and keep going back and forth like that and followed the stock market every minute
From 9 a.m. to 5:30 p.m.
Do not do it
Invest, log out
Do something else that is fun like
Rather want to redo the days
Do not sit and check every day all the time.
so much you will not learn from a stock market day.
Have patience. The less you do and shop and buy and sell
So you will make a lot more money
This is usually when you go in and try to make quick money on stocks
In short term
as one usually loses money.
Have patience
Log out a little
So you will earn much more
Tip No. 4
Buy shares in an ISK account.
From the beginning
When you start investing
So you get to choose which account
you want to invest in
And then there is the investment savings account
Endowment insurance, equity fund account
By having your shares and funds for that matter in an investment savings account
then you get a low tax
And you do not have to keep declaring your business
You get tax-free dividends and you can just enjoy life and chill and have a good time
And the last tip
Buy a company
Who makes a profit!
If you are a beginner
Do not go on buying lots of companies that you have no idea what they are doing
And then they go with a loss
For What do companies that make a loss do?
Well they are doing something wrong!
Because it is not sustainable to run companies that do not make money
Or who does not make a profit in any case
Then you need to be very confident in your investment
Start by buying for-profit companies
You can only check the P / E ratio
If the P / E ratio is above zero, that is positive - then the company is making a profit.
If they are at a negative P / E ratio, they are at a loss.
Avoid them in the first place.
until you have learned a little more
Then you can consider buying other companies.
The most important lesson when you want to start investing in stocks.
It's just getting started!
Dare to invest Do not be afraid to invest.
Start with as little as just SEK 100
Buy a Swedish company that you are aware of that is listed on the Stockholm Stock Exchange
At Avanza you can do it completely without brokerage and also at Nordnet.
It's perfect for you who might want to get started and learn investing!
I'm incredibly glad I did.
I started just over 6 years ago.
And yes I could never believe I can live on this right now.
I do not live on my stock portfolio
But working on this
To teach beginners like you
About this with investments and stocks and mutual funds.
So start today
Open an account via the link in my description
And watch my other videos and check out SparaCash.se
There is an incredible amount of info that you can learn
And you will thank yourself in the future if you take this now
Good luck with your investments and if you have any questions, ask it down here
In the comments field, I will respond to it as soon as possible.
Thank you very much for watching the video. Have a good one!
Hello!
That I have to do a little more research