Each country has them, national symbols that adorn postcards
And attracts tourists.
Sydney has its iconic opera house, Oslo its marble -covered opera
Milan the legendary La Scala.
And Sweden's 250-year-old cultural pride: the Royal Opera.
The opera's CEO has testified about mold and smell of stool
And also stones have come loose from the facade.
Physically, the 250-year-old feels very bad. It's really a crisis.
Flying stones and stool smell.
Is it the opera or Christmas dinner with my grandmother?
She is so angry all the time.
The opera house falls apart. Should no one cook it?
Yes, but this someone is full of
to produce sneaky recruitment films.
It is the love of the houses and cultural heritage
And to the special assignment.
We preserve the properties for future generations.
That is why we exist.
Without us, many of our cultural treasures would have disappeared.
State Property Agency, SFV
which manages Sweden's cultural -historical heritage.
They must ensure that every village halt has a castle in fine condition.
Where one can go with the family when you have to find something
Because you do not endure being in the same apartment.
In total, SFV manages 4,000 buildings:
Citizens, castles, museums, theaters and state building memories.
Varberg's fortress, Kronoberg's castle ruin - you name it!
SFV is there and does a questionable job.
Unfortunately, many tenants do not seem to feel as good as the Royal Opera.
It is hardly possible to work there anymore.
We are very crowded already.
Musicians warm up in the corridors, the dancers' gym is in a corridor arm.
Under the roof it gets extremely hot.
It rains from time to time when the snow melts or it rains outside.
What a shame! Every civilized country should have a national scene.
An important symbol for culture in this country.
I love a finely tuned opera, just last week I took part in
One of this year's cultural highlights: The set "Where is the sandwich?"
That was unbelievable! Wow.
The whole show I wondered: Where is the sandwich?
Culture can really move one to other places.
When digging, you realize that the opera house has become pure horror experience.
The other night I had guests in the house. They needed to go to the bathroom.
When they turned on the water, small flies poured out. It's not so fun.
No, that is not fun at all.
I got flies in the crane myself after a wild week at Rhodes in 2001.
I had to burn them away. Why am I telling this?
I just want to remind myself that once I was a viril young playboy
And now I'm talking about state real estate.
Where were we? Just that, flies in the crane, it's not good, no.
So instead of an iconic landmark, a dilapidated ghost house.
The Phantom has to leave the opera and walk on the city streets like an ordinary man.
And the opera is not alone in slowly breaking.
The Natural History Museum also seems to be severely neglected by SFV.
300 kilos of roof plaster that loosened.
The ceiling at the Natural History Museum in Stockholm
risks collapsing, and now they have to keep closed.
As if dinosaurs were not extinct enough!
First a comet in the skull, now roof plaster.
Not easy to be Dino in today's Sweden.
Nightclubs refuse to let in raptors.
Try to get bank loans like Tricratops! Handelsbanken possibly ...
What is SFV doing? What happened to the mission to preserve cultural treasures
And with their "love for the houses"?
Well, behind the decay of the houses lies a rental model
The Persson government introduced 20 years ago.
The model is called cost rent and the intentions were obviously good.
Five central national cultural institutions
would not have to pay market rent, which is the basic arrangement
And instead pay cost rent.
The work charges exactly what it costs to manage the house.
Yes, and these five buildings, The Big Five
Is the opera, the Dramaten, the National Museum, the Historical Museum and the buffalo ...
Sorry, Natural History Museum.
The Big Five has cost rent:
The rent must correspond to the house's operating costs.
The problem is that all costs for SFV to manage and run the premises
has increased, and because of the rental model they are plus on the rent.
All costs end up on the rent, even major local renovations.
The rent on the building can increase by 50 percent.
The increase will include: Because they build a lift to the entrance.
Because according to the agreement with SFV, the Dramaten itself will pay for renovations.
It will be added on next year's rent.
The new elevator is double bad news for Dramaten.
Height rent, and so women must now share a lift with Örjan Ramberg again.
It is apparently tough.
The drama received a 50 percent rent increase due to an elevator!
Then think what happens to the opera's rent about SFV in the end:
Celesting roofs, leaking pipes, flies in the tap and poop smell.
Such plans exist, but can cost several billion.
It will be a huge damn rent increase.
It has already happened to another of The Big Five: National Museum.
The rent for SFV includes the costs of the newly renovated premises
And make large holes in the museum's budget.
Staff have been terminated and exhibitions have been canceled.
It would be sad if one is not prepared to bet money
so that it is enough for a reasonable business.
You can choose between large holes in the ceiling or large holes in the budget.
The National Museum's rent is so high that they may be forced to close for good.
Do you understand what this means? We kill the culture.
We risk losing magnificent cultural experiences
As the opera "Where is my sandwich?"
You think you know where the sandwich is - and poff! So they sow doubt.
Art can really ask the big questions.
Cost rent is not sustainable, and the government has realized this.
They will investigate a new rental model. But it seems bark in another direction.
A review of the rental model has recently been conducted.
The investigation proposes a transition to market rent
And thus the same rental model for all properties with cultural activities.
Voldemort here ... sorry, he who must not be mentioned by name.
The Big Five will receive the same rental model as SFV's other tenants.
Thus, market rent. But tenants with market rent
Seems to have it even tougher.
In September, the Blåsar Symphonics leave the Musical Quarter in Stockholm
where one has been in twelve years
After SFV in Christmas announced a strong rent increase.
Now the music has been silenced in Sweden's oldest concert hall
Because the Blåsar Symphonics cannot afford the rent, which was increased by 60 %.
Thank you and hello, poor orchestra. You may take your bass violins and flutes
And go home where you came from. Strängnäs, maybe.
Not the person, or Ikea's affordable candle holder.
The town of Strängnäs! Well, you are from Skaraborg?
I should understand that when you danced one way, then the other way.
No no no! No applause. It is Per Andersson's script.
In the market rent model, SFV sets the rent after
What they could get in an open market.
If a concert hall has an attractive location, such as central Stockholm
So the rent becomes very high, and there is probably a logic.
The state can house a really big O'Learys there instead.
But many cultural properties are built for what they are used for.
The Royal Opera is an opera, you can't have it for much else.
And the opera cannot move. We only have one royal opera house.
Market logic does not go together. Same with the National Museum.
But it doesn't really seem to have gone up for SFV.
What do you do about the National Museum forced to evacuate?
What should you have the property for?
I haven't thought about that, I really hope
that the National Museum may retain its fine business.
You believe that the National Museum will continue to be the National Museum
In the National Museum's own premises? Yes, that sounds reasonable.
But why should government institutions have to get on your knees
Because a state authority requires them on sky -high rents?
Like the state renovating itself. A self -harm behavior.
Several stage art dealers come back to what they describe as
A KAFKA-ARTER MONOPOL GAME. Tax money moves back and forth.
Through an authority, the state makes a new performance.
Then the state raises the rent through another authority
so the theater must take from the same money and return
to cover the rent increase.
Did you hang out? Client, landlord, tenant, victim, perpetrator
Everyone involved turns out to be the state itself!
It was one and the same person all the time. What a plot twist!
It was eerily like the end of the opera "Where is my sandwich?"
It emerged that the sandwich had been in the wardrobe all the time.
At least the kids in the salon got goose bumps.
The last place to look for a sandwich. In the kitchen maybe ...
But why does SFV do this?
Well, for some reason I do not understand, they are imposed on a profit requirement.
They have to generate profit to the state
And their way of doing it is through rents, and this is good.
Last year the profit requirement was SEK 97 million
But they pulled in over half a billion.
Don't tell this to Strängnäs!
But I have a populist suggestion: Take that money and spend the culture.
Make a new sandwich show or make sure it stops smelling poop at the opera.
Or one can imagine a world
where some selected cultural properties completely avoid the rent.
That it is seen as a higher value for society
That these institutions are doing well.
But such a special treatment is not SFV, you think? Yes, sometimes.
Through the over 200 -year -old agreement
Does the royal family need not pay rents, renovations
or operating costs where they live. The taxpayers must stand for it.
SFV must treat the opera and our other cultural institutions
A little more like the king - big letters, pictures in the books.
Let them avoid the absurd carousel of profit requirements and market rents.
This performance with an oppressive, greedy authority
And a dilapidated and terrified opera house must come to an end.
Release the opera free from the Tyranni of the Property Agency
Before the curtain goes down for good.
I got goose bumps again. Take care of you, and we'll see you in a week.
There is my sandwich!
SWEDISH SUNTING: M TAKALA & C Engström @ Sveriges Television AB 2023
Huh?