There are many different gear you can connect to a clear saw
And today I was going to test one like this.
It is a steel brush that should be connected to the trimmer and what do you have for?
Well, to clear plates and paving stones
which have been overgrown by grass and moss.
Here in front of my house I have just that.
It is paved many years ago and over time has grass and moss
Slowly worked itself up and taken over so now it is on the border.
It is like an intermediate between lawn and paving.
But should see if this steel brush works.
You have to think about a little safety requirement.
Maximum 10,000 rpm it stands and
You do not come up to this when it comes to the cleaning saw.
And then: Use eye protection.
It feels pretty natural too.
You do not want a unloaded steel wire that gets away and gets stuck in the wrong place.
Start by switching to the right gear.
This one would fit and use for it
Protection you have for saw blade and grassy.
But I put on the protection that is to the trimmer wire because I suspect that
It will go about some stuff with this.
The next step is to rake the paving to the habitual
and get away as much stone as possible, so I suspect it
Will splash down this aggregate and then Happi may go in.
This is no activity you do
Together with the dog, but she has to wait while I give up on this.
This is the first time I try with
This one, so hopefully it goes as it is intended.
Here we go!
Yes, it was definitely a dirty job.
You might have done it before there was so much soil on top.
But now I have gone over so I have to take and rake away and sweep and see the result.
I guess it may require another round, but decent promised.
I had problems. I didn't really know.
Because when it has gone this far for this paving
You do not know how large the paving is, but think that the edges only had soil.
But then you start shoveling a little neighbor, or
Brush and then it turns out that there are stones underneath as well.
But as I said, it's not easy.
Now let's see the result soon.
Far from perfect, but 90% better anyway
I would say.
Had I had the waters -
I haven't put on the water yet -
Because it is still frostric.
So I had gone over this with the high pressure after.
But how it gets will come up on
My Instagram, when some water has come on this too.
Then maybe some post -work is required.
It's hard to see in this dust cloud as
You work in, but this is how it worked anyway.
You can see more movies about cleaning saw here if you are interested.
Thanks for watching! See you again soon.