Tonight we're here with Jacob, how old are you?
Eleven years old.
How old are you Mateus?
13.
How would you react if they asked YOU for a lighter for a cigarette?
Excuse me, can I borrow your lighter?
Your too small, I've got moral.
I'm eighteen.
You can't smoke, you're too young!
Excuse me can I borrow a lighter?
How old are you?
11..I mean..18.
No.
Stop smoking.
Why do you smoke?
I'm old and stupid, my generation is dumb.
I'm trying to quit smoking.
Don't start, you'll get lungcancer.
...and you will look lime me.
Can you light my cigarette?
Would you like to borrow a lighter?
Can you light it?
Why?
I want to smoke?
Can u light it.
..Cause I can't
How do I light it?
Can you light it please?
No problems.
You don't want to light it urself?
How do I light it?
Put it in your mouth.
You want to smoke, right?
Do you have a lighter, for my cigarette?
You're like ten..
No..
Yes.
How old are you then, nine?
No..
I'm sorry but you can't be doing this.
(Takes his cigarette) Thanks!
Give me the rest as well, let's throw them away.
Give that to me.
I'm going to break it.
Why?
You shouldn't smoke.
Can't you be cool about it?
Absolutely not, we're cool that we don't let you smoke.
Throw it away.
Let's throw them at the same time.
1,2,3!
Can I borrow your lighter?
What?
It's easier if you inhale at the same time.
Is it lit?
You need to suck on it, are you going to smoke or not?
Can you light my cigarette?
Do you got a lighter?
You can light it.
Why do you want to give me a lighter?
You can borrow it.
But why..I'm a minor.
Why do want to give a lighter to a minor?
Oh.
How old do you think I am?
I have no clue, don't got time for this.
Are you stressed?
Yeah.
How old do I look?
You saw the cigarette in my hand.
Yeah, so?
You got a lighter for my cigarette?
Excuse me?
You kidding me?
Do you approach a police to ask for for a lighter?
Don't got one, ask somebody else.
I need to light my cigarette.
Actually you or me shouldn't smoke, but you get it anyway.
Thanks.
You got a lighter for my cigarette?
You going to smoke little man?
You going to smoke? Awesome!
Light it, if you want too.
Why did you give me a lighter?
Because, you shouldn't smoke.
I've been smoking since I was 11, it's hard to quit.
How does that stop me from smoking?
No..that doesen't make you quit, but..
If I was to be nice, I wouldn't let you smoke.
We're shooting a social experiment.
Oh, okay.
How old do you think I am?