WE PLACED A HIDDEN CAMERA IN AN ELEVATOR
Who the hell is he?
Who the fuck is he?
WE WANTED TO SEE IF PEOPLE REACTED WHEN A GIRL BECAME A VICTIM OF VIOLENCE
Who's in charge of us?
You must listen to me, you know that?
THESE ARE THE REACTIONS WE GOT.
Am I right?
Do you understand that?
Konrad, stop it!
You'll fucking listen to me!
I will kill you, I will fucking kill you!
Oh really?
I haven't done anything, I promise.
He was looking at me.
It doesn't matter!
So?
Do you fucking get what I'm saying?
I'm here too. (Older woman)
Please let me get off first.
You fucking listen to me, understand?
Who the hell do you think you are?
You know that I haven't done anything wrong!
I get so fucking mad at you, understand?
Stop it.
No, seriously!
I decide over you, you are just crap!
You are not worth anything, I hope you get that!
Please, stop it.
You're not worth anything!
Beware as hell! You should be beware as hell!
I haven't done anything.
You..
Seriously!
Stop it!
You're nothing, you understand?
You're worthless!
Help!
Who do you think will help you? Do you think anyone cares about pathetic little you?
Beware as hell!
Thank you for reacting.
You're the only one who has reacted today.
It's a social experiment.
Thank you!
53 PERSONS GOT INTO THE ELEVATOR, JUST ONE REACTED.
EVERY 20 MINUTES A WOMAN IN SWEDEN IS ABUSED.