"Every year, 20,000 people move to Stockholm".
"Many of these feel that they have difficulty fit in".
"That is why we have created the Stockholm course".
Well! It is I who lead the Stockholm course. I'll teach you to fit in.
"We teach you to change your behavior through exercises".
What do you work with, then?
Stop. Why do you direct your attention?
Nice.
Go and sit down.
"And we learn to communicate properly".
Either you are from the south or from the north of Stockholm ...
You also learn how to speak Stockholm
For example: "Excuse me, may I go by?", Will be: "Move you".
Women voice: How do you translate "I was wrong"?
What does it mean?
"On the excursions you will learn from really sharp situations".
It is more difficult to get past if you stand in the way.
It is easier if you are not in the way.
A bit like that.
How to do if someone is like this?
You pass by?
No, we're not heartless
Cocking: No! We move the person off the bike lane so people can get by. So!
"There is also time for question time".
Men's voice: Do you think Stockholmers that you are better than everyone else?
No absolutely not. We know we are.
Women's voice: Isn't that a little over?
Cocking: She says that with the ugly sweater!
"Now search as a successful Stockholmers with us".
They are so j*vla left
I'm not palleting this course
You can go home, because it's over.