Hello everyone! Hello!
Hello and welcome to a new video!
We are in Kläppen.
Down there is our cabin.
Up there we are going to ski.
Look over there!
How beautiful!
They are ready!
Come along!
There is a hotel.
There are various restaurants.
There are many small cafes and restaurants.
There is also a restaurant up there, we are going there.
Watch so many people.
Everyone is good and keeps their distance.
It is important in these times to keep your distance.
Are you ready to ski?
I'm going to go myself.
I'm going with my mother.
We are at the top.
a children's hill
Look what a small cottage!
a small cottage
at the top
There you can simply cook, grill, eat and rest.
in the small cottage
Here is wood.
Here we will fire and grill.
How cozy!
Here is a children's hill.
There is a lift.
You can go up and then you can go down.
We can go there too.
There is also a hill with a lift.
What are you saying?
I can ski myself now!
You are really good!
barbecue places
You can grill here.
There is also a heating cabin.
If you freeze, you can go in and then you get hot.
You can eat there too.
There are toilets.
What do we do?
We ski!
What did you find?
a heart ice
heart
This is also a lift.
It's called a gondola.
Each gondola can accommodate 10 people.
10 people can ride in a gondola.
It's so nice to ride the gondola.
The kids like it.
They like to go up in the gondola.
The sofas are electrically heated.
They are hot.
They keep warm.
It's nice to sit.
Especially when it's cold outside.
It's so nice out there.
You go and look out.
It's blowing up at the top.
It's very windy.
Here is a restaurant - Toppstugan.
We have coffee in the restaurant Toppstugan.
The girls eat a bun and drink hot chocolate.
Thank you so much for watching!
See you in the next video! Bye!