Hello Hello
I was going to keep talking a little about
how to improve one's writing
and in the last movie I did about it
So I talked a little more big about that
Writing is about thinking
and discuss, both discuss with
self and discuss with others so
To write better so you need to be curious
on the world and so to speak
develop your thinking too, not
Just your language
In this movie I will try to go into a little more on
The language part then
If one thinks of yourself
the language you need to
able to express your thoughts in a good way
And then I don't think exactly
on grammar and order and such things
Without liters more how
one should find and learn
a language that one can use when one
Writes
and
A good goal
a simple and good goal to have
When writing a text, it is to
The one who reads the text should not
at all need to think or be
unsure what you mean
so especially if you write any type
by investigative or debate
or accounting
text and so on
informative text in the school, ie one such
academic or formal text
Then I think a good goal is
that the reader should have as easily as possible
To understand your thought
And it is not always easy to write
so that it is completely
clearly what one means
okay and how to then
get better at this to express their thoughts
Well you need exactly
right word
one needs many different words
and expressions of expressing one's
thought exactly
So then you need to learn it