Hello everyone!
We drive to Väddö.
Come along! (- No, we fly to Väddö!) The
road from Märsta to Väddö.
Väddö is an island located approximately 100 km northeast of Stockholm.
We're at a farm dairy.
Here the children can watch all the animals that are here.
(not just children, adults too)
There is a cow.
They are hiding in the shadows.
It is hot.
Here is water they drink.
- Who are you looking at? - Pigs!
one pig - three pigs
- Check what I can! - What are you doing? You jump!
Now I'm going to jump in there!
There are rabbits too!
One Rabbit - Several Rabbits
One Little Rabbit - Several Little Rabbits
What a Dirty One!
Come on, let's go and look at the goats!
one goat - several goats
- They are so cute!
They rock together.
From the farm dairy we go to a small beach nearby.
Here there is a bathing place, a beach.
But it blows so much. It's cold.
The water is cold.
But it's nice here.
It is very late now, it is five o'clock in the evening and we are going home.
It has been a great day today here on Väddö.