Hello
I go on on this
Social theme
The theme about
cultural differences, to get in touch with
with people and talk
In a new language in a new country
and i text the movie
So put on
the subtitles
on your mobile or your computer
so can you read what I say at the same time
and
I constantly think that this is
a language training focus, the question is
How we should
train in Swedish to get better
And to communicate
but to
Lift your eyes a little
Look a little bigger and a little further
than only on words and grammar
and I think I will use
some slightly more difficult words
When I talk and sometimes I explain them
so you get a chance to
expand, build on
your vocabulary
And you can always ask in the comments
If you wonder about any expression I use
Yes
And now I'm going to try to take up
Two little
Different but
Subjects ... two questions, two points
that is a little different but connected to each other
and I think both are
Relevant
= they are important to
Language training
and that is
conversation topics
So what one is talking about
and that is
Cultural culture
I think I start with
conversation topics
For I think we
should talk more about it
in other words
When you want to start talking more Swedish
in everyday life
What to talk about?
And then I want to make a comparison
With Somali as I work out orally
At work the most
For I can talk pretty much
and can understand some
and I feel that one
an obstacle for me
or a challenge, something that
I would have to work a lot with if I want to
get better at talking to people in everyday life
It is to understand which conversation topics
that works and as I said, conversation topics are,
what you are talking about
What things can you talk about
and I believe that
I think
This may be something that differs quite a lot
from different cultures, I don't know
But my feeling is it anyway that
that what one is talking about or maybe a little how
one is talking about certain things
can differ quite a bit
And I think that if you think a little about it
Well we take a very simple example
Many people say we talk about the weather
In Sweden, okay, that might be true, I don't know
So then you can think a little about
How can I get better at
to talk about the weather
I'm pretty sure of
that if you learn some more words and learn to talk
a bit more like Swedes talk about the weather
then it will create a little
nicer and better contact
with new people when you do
it can work anyway, it depends very much on
other things, how is the person you are talking to
And how are you yourself?
How are you perceived?
perceived - how are you perceived?
So: What do others think about you when they meet you?
It is very different how
people think about us, we are different as people
Some are lucky enough to be
nice and charming and happy
everyone likes them directly
Although they talk, for example, very bad Swedish
Others have a little harder
But in any case, everyone can win at
to improve one's ability to, for example
Talk about the weather
But honestly, it is very boring to
Talk about the weather.
Maybe you can do for five minutes
in the best case
So, of course, maybe it can
break the ice
Thus: Break the silence,
break the first little uncomfortable
the moment before man
find something to talk about - break the ice
maybe the weather can do
But then I think it would be interesting
For everyone to start thinking about
What could we talk about more
What subjects could I take up, what subjects
may others be interested in
so that it becomes one
exchange, that it is not just becoming
I tell you something and the other is not answering
I have no finished recipe for this
I just think
all who learn a new language
especially if you come from a culture that is quite different
so i think there is a lot to gain on
think through
what subjects you want to be able to talk about and then work out
themselves on it and look for words and expressions
I think absolutely
and let me ... I have to comment on a thing
As I have heard a few times
lately
and as myself .... it's like a big question mark for me
I don't understand this
For people say that Swedes
not want to be personal and not
enjoy personal questions
And I just
huh ???
Who doesn't?
They are certainly available
there is certainly something in this
But I think there is also a lot of misunderstanding in this
I would even, just as an example now
take this with a pinch of salt
Don't believe I mean this 100%
But I would like to reverse the generalization
and say that almost all
Immigrants I meet does not seem
be interested in talking about
personal belongings
It is extremely rare as someone I meet
at work anyway or who contact me
on chat or like this, it's very unusual
to those people
Shows any interest
for something more personal
there are exceptions, that is not true (always)
And I know I meet people in the role of teacher
so it might make people feel like
shy or uncomfortable with that
more
contact me personally or take up
personal things, but my feeling is to
many people are not so interested too
or not know how to ask
But maybe it's like this, maybe it's like this
This prejudice that no Swedes
want to take up something more personal
lies in the way
And it's a shame because I think many of my friends
in all cases
gladly could answer more
personal questions
Then maybe you have to build up
a trust or
take up the subject in the correct manner
and it can be a bridge in
So talk about it properly
It can be a bridge into conversation culture
So I mentioned for example in a video
on instagram that it is better to ask me
Why have you just raised a child
than to say
you should get a sibling to your lonely son
Poor he, it's like a very
in Swedish culture, at least
in my opinion and among my friends, I don't know
there are certainly different, but I think
Generally in Swedish culture it is very uninvited
and disrespectful to directly express
views on another person's life choice
and as well as lay in
How many children that person has acquired for example
so that
I'm a little used to, I work at SFI so I have
understanding, but at the same time I see after all
how person by person, who comes from a more
It is great to have many children-culture
such a culture that they miss the chance to
learn something about how I think by the fact that
immediately give in to more comment
and in relation to
The person Kalle So it closes the discussion
I just get a little like this
Tiring
and trying to get out of there
However, had a person asked a personal question
To me so I would have liked to try to explain
how I think and why
My life is like my life is
Then of course it can be sensitive for different reasons
Ask why someone just has
a child for example but
For me it had no problem
to explain it, but then I have to get an open question
I can't get a comment
about how I should do
And I meet that pretty much I can say
So there I think there may be such a cultural difference
what might actually be meant as a joke
or as just small talk
gets in my world
something that closes the door
and I don't get the desire to continue that call
null
and it's just one example
but
I want to take another example that maybe
End of this with conversation culture
Because it was very interesting
my friend Josefin who has a
Instagram account called "Swedish with Josefin"
and that are teachers
But she is also the one that helps people in their spare time and so
she came and greeted me
at work and
We sat in the cafe and cooked and there sat
a bunch of Arabic -speaking men above all
it was probably one
little gang gang sitting there talking
and they became very curious and also very happy
When Josefin showed that she can talk
some Arabic and understand some Arabic
and it became a very lively
And loud conversation
where people interrupted each other and everyone wanted
say their opinion and what was interesting was to
I looked at Josefin that she thought it
was great fun, she really liked
with the
she was like, one says
in its proper element
in its proper element, that means that
that situation suited her
perfect
I, on the other hand, in one such
In such a call
In such a conversation culture where one speaks loudly
and talking a lot and everyone seems to be interested
of telling their opinion
But not so interested in listening
So it feels to me anyway
I really want to go from there
I don't think it's funny and
I have to exert myself
So I have to say so go outside
that which feels comfortable for me
and I can do it, it's not
it is like a workout for me too to adapt to different
people's ways
to talk and interact and communicate
but
I still believe that many would agree
that it might be a little smaller
common in Swedish conversation culture
that seven people (= people) sit and fight
about the conversation space and talking in mouth on each other
I saw a little movie with an American
person, a man who lives in Sweden and he
It described that difference
Americans speak louder and more in their mouths
on each other and Swedes are a little more
Silent
And maybe a little more waiting
Now it's my turn, now it's your turn
Lucky, who is talking
now i talk later
Is it your turn and you talk
It is called the take -off
How to take tours in a call
And I think that is
such a thing one can study
If one wants to be better at communicating in a new language
How to take tours
In this language
both which sentences one uses
to take the word and hand over the word
And also a little
How to make it more social
If you interrupt each other much or
Is it more that one hands over the word
and get it back a bit like this
And as I said, I am Swedish and Josefin is Swedish
null
We experience this very different
We talked about it afterwards
So it's also about ...
Here will probably the last expression I want to
sell in, it's about knowing (a particle verb)
know, a particle verb
to know the one you are talking to
and
So you talk to Josefin for example, then it's just
to drive on
And she will think it's great fun, it will be a good contact
If you talk to me then it is
or a person who is like me
then it is better to be a little more cautious, ask a little
Tell a little, so to take some more
responsibility for
The take -off in the conversation
it would, so to speak, work much better because
Get a contact with a person like me that is a bit more shy
And a little more cautious
and so on
But there we have a little different things if I try
repeat, yes but we have
Call cultures there
one can speak higher or lower
one can cancel more, ie that
you take the word from the other
one can cancel more or cancel less
We have the take
Do you talk a lot yourself or try to ask the other
We have this to know
We have the big question mark
Want Swedes to be personal
Or don't they want it?
can it be about how to
Takes up more personal subjects?
perhaps
How is it where you come from
How is it in your culture, in what way is man
Personalized with you
was that maybe it me
Just that .... and really think about this with the topics of conversation
conversation topics can be quite
important to get a call to
flower
For example, if I take myself again
Do you start talking about music on a curious
interacting manner
so you will probably get my attention
I love music
Do you start talking about politics
so it won't work as well
it depends a little but i can't be able to keep up with
so much so i'm a little bit
If you start talking about like this, what happens in the government
or what is happening
In something like this trade agreement between
China and Russia
it won't work so well on me because i can't so much about it
But with another person so maybe it really is
The best tip
Talk about things you read in the newspaper
so will you really find a lot to discuss
I definitely know such people
who might think it's the most fun to talk about
so it is different and there must be but
be curious and feel in
and as well as try a little
What can work with this person?
and sometimes you fail and sometimes you succeed
and that said for me
is this really
a matter of learning a new language
one can go down to word level and
What a grammar and
which phrases you use to get a call better
But it is constantly linked to these larger ones
perspectives, what are we talking about
and how
We talk
in different contexts and how differ
between cultures
And between people
okay
I hope this was useful and useful
and
all reflections and comments
are welcome and I
My goal is to answer all the comments
as
have some kind of content but sometimes
it takes some time before I can go through
But I try to answer all that
I am thankful for thoughts and comments and questions
Hope to see you again soon
and have it so good, hello hello