Hello everyone
Who trains Swedish
Today
I thought
give a small example of
or at least attempt
Give examples of
How I talk
If i do not
are teachers
in Swedish
In my classroom
Or on Youtube
It's a little hard
When I don't talk to a person
But I was going to try
so i was going to tell you a little about
What I have done today
and what to do later in the day
so let's see
Today I have evening course
on sfi so i'm free
in the morning
And then I always clean up
and vacuuming, dust dry
maybe carry out the recycling and go to the sopage center and so on
And today I have also listened to a speech book at the same time
So I listen to a book called "The Power of Habit"
which deals with how our brain is largely guided by
controlled by habits
so it deals with both individuals and groups
and how habits form our behavior so it was very interesting
But now I have finished listening to it
and it is ten o'clock in eleven
As soon as I will go to work
First I have ... I have my usual SFI group
And then so
Then I'll have my evening course then
But between the evening course and the usual course
so i usually take a little walk
And sometimes I go to the library too
And read a little
To get a little break
It gets pretty late when you have evening course
So it's nice to get out a bit and get fresh air
Yeah, so my day looks about
On the tram I might answer a bit like this
Some comments
on the workout Swedish or youtube or so
and i hope this was a little taste test
on how I sound when I speak more relaxed
and not
thinking about talking slowly
okay
I don't know if this was easy to understand
Or difficult
It is not meant to be mean
without
I think it's important that we think about
How important the hearing comprehension is
and that it is
For most people I think
that this is what we need to practice most at
And it is both about understanding
Fast Swedish, fast talk
But it is also about
To understand huge words
both more formal words
And hose
For in Swedish
Just as in all other languages
so there are many expressions
we use
and then one must try
learn as many as possible
In order to understand better
Feel free to ask
Words I use or things I say
Comment, discuss
The intention is that these videos
shall become a way of thinking
What is important to practice when training Swedish
and what is difficult and how we can get better
so
Feel free to write something in a comment
and will be seen soon again
Take care, bye.