Hello Hello
maybe you are one of those who have easy
to learn grammar
that can teach you a lot
grammar
Outside quickly
then just congratulate and say congratulations
But I'm not such
There are many who
cannot or
can or have time
to
memorize
to remember a lot of grammar at one time
That way to study does not fit all
and I was talking after all
in a video pretty recently about
How you can practice prepositions by reading and listening
and I was going to tip about about the same way to
consider when it comes to verbs
And then I think like this that if you
beats up a grammar book or
Maybe find a piece of paper with a list of many many verbs
Then it is very easy to feel that
This is what I will never learn, this is too much
It is too difficult
it won't get stuck in memory
and
a way of thinking then
is to
to prepare a little
first
and then
try to learn slowly step by step
By reading and listening
and maybe study a little at a time instead
and when I say prepare then
So if we think of Swedish verbs
So there are
can you say, four large groups
one can split a little different but
But to make it a little easy for us
so can we say there are four groups
it is not that much
Four different ways
as we
Thus bending verbs in present and past
And in supinum, the important forms are then
It's a little more but ...
We can start there, you need to be able to talk about now
you need to be able to talk. If then
and you need to be able to use have and had
For example, if we take, look then
Do you have to be able to say "I'm looking now"
I looked yesterday
I have looked
There you have supinum
and then you have to
Understand how you do infiniv
So I want to look, I'll look and so on
So it's done
There are a little different things you need to keep track of
But the first
As you then need to get some control over
This, how do I do the present?
= looking
How do I do that time?
= looked
And how do I do supinum?
and then there are four groups
Three of those groups are pretty easy to learn
so they follow pretty clear patterns
And then it's then the fourth group
which is more
you have to remember
a little more because it can't
Guess so easy
if you have
For example, present, present
so is it hard to guess
How past and supinum become
An example would be
That I run
In the present, I ran in the past
I have been running
you can't guess so easily
Without it one must learn
so can you say that
There are four groups of verbs
Three of them are pretty light
and the fourth is a little harder
But then my tip is that
you prepare you by studying
the four different groups
I will give a tip on a website
As I think is pretty good and it's called SFI with Viktor
he has a good
Summary with examples
And movies
on its website sfi with Viktor, so I put a link to it in
in the description
but there are certainly lots of different good
Explanations of this
In your SFI book
or in your Swedish grammar book
But if you don't have then
If you are unsure of verbs then my tip is that you look
a little on: how does group 1 work
How does group 2 work?
How do groups 3 and 4 work and thus
I don't think you should be really stressed and think
Oh, I have to learn
100 verbs in group 1 at one time
without my tip is that you learn a
or two
maybe three examples first
so that you remember
a few
example
in each group
it might be enough with one
and that you like
Looking and thinking a little: Okay, if you have this
I want to look
I see-r
i look — the i have look t
Okay, so you are looking at infinitive
on the one you use with should
I will, I want to, I will
look
and then you see how
How do you change, how do you change
a little
the appearance of the verb
To get the different forms
and then group 1 works
in a way and group 2 is a little
different
and group 3 is a little different, so you try
seeing systems, trying
See the pattern
not remember a lot of things
Understand the system
so that you recognize it
And then I mean that if you've seen the system
and understood it roughly, how it works
so you come then when you hear people talk
And when you read books you will
Repeat automatically
For you will see: Aha, that was group 1
or you may not even think, that was group 1
You just think, mhmm ...
it was such a m m m
aha, it was one of those
I can say that is about the way I have done
with Somali, because I can absolutely
not memorize a bunch of different verbs
I don't have time with that either
But on the other hand, I know a little how the different varieties
Works, so when I hear people talk so I can guess
or can i think that aha
that verb was like that
that verb was so instead
And then I think that
so it's the first three groups, it's pretty easy to
see the system, or ask someone
please can you help me
explain a little, how does group 1 work
Group 2 and Group 3
What is the difference?
between the groups of verbs
and then also group 4 then, and then there is even more
just look at examples
For there is not a very clear system
Without taking any examples at a time
and try to understand how they work
Learn them by the way
and then when you have any examples
on common verbs in group 4
so can you add
New you hear
If you have learned to run, ran, ran
And then I say: "I drank coffee"
hmmm, drank .... drink
I drink, drank, drank
So runs, ran, run
and drinks, drank, drank
is like
Follows the same system
but there are .... they are more different
So you need to work more with examples
learn an example and late
see new examples that are the same way
null
So okay
A suggestion on how you can do this
It is that you take a week and so do you say
This week so I'll repeat verbs a little
every day
so the first day maybe you just look a little at verb group 1
looking at some examples, trying to understand the system
late the next day so you take verb group 2
and so the next day verb group 3
then maybe the fourth day that you just repeat a little
and see if you remember how it works
Then maybe the fifth day
How to start watching verb group 4
and maybe for two days
you just, like repeating verb group 4
trying to find words that you can use that are useful to you
and that said, not try to remember
too much, memorize some examples
But above all, try to see how the system works
And then when you have done that, I think you can like
learn by reading and listening
that you begin to think that
There are these different varieties
And, as I said, only four different groups
three lightweight, one difficult
so that you just need
think about it that "aha, now he said so" or "now, she said so"
it must be group 4, okay that verb
Okay, that verb bend you that way
so that I'm sitting here
and talking to you today, I sat
Here last week
I've been sitting here many times
Okay, sit, sat, sat
sitting, sat, sat
Even when you hear something so repeat
that a few times for yourself: sitting, sat, sat
so that you only give
You get examples by reading and listening and then you help
the brain to remember that by the fact that
Repeat it in a slightly more natural way
and sometimes you forget and then you just have to repeat it again
and if you want
so can you at the same time
Maybe for example
teach you a verb
From Group 4
every day, or every other day
perhaps
Look at a list of verbs and then you take it
Group 4 that is a bit more difficult
Find a verb you need, which you think is important
And then you train on it one day
Next day you interrogate on it
Then you take a new one
And so you interrogate it, you can take it very slowly
step by step by memorizing
example
Then you will still learn between
Say 300 and 150 verbs
In that group in one year
and you probably don't need a huge number to
manage in most situations
so
What I want to say with this movie is
that if you have a hard time learning a lot of grammar
at one time I don't think you need to stress so much
without
try making a small
Map, a basic map, a kind of sketch
About this is how verbs work in Swedish
Then you bring it with you
And then you start collecting examples
When you meet them
in ordinary texts and in ordinary numbers
Then you will also
Exercise on things you actually need the kind you actually hear
the kind of people say
and things like you read
Instead of learning a lot of things and so maybe
a lot of what you learn
will you not use
maybe later, but not at first
I hope you understand what I
about what I mean
I mean that
It is possible to learn
in a fairly relaxed manner
by doing some work to prepare
and then sound a little time and
The amount of Swedish
You hear and read a lot of Swedish
can work for you
without having to sit and tear
and struggle with remembering
However, you have to spend a lot of time on the language
but you can train verbs when you look at your
Favorite TV series
only you have some control
on how the verbs work first
so it is excellent to train on the TV couch or when you
talking to a language buddy
It is also to train grammar
so
Don't stress too much
relax
Learn by the fact that
Using the language a lot
have a lot of time with the language and so
I actually believe that
if you
watching this video
in a year again and think back
so I actually think you will be much safer
on Swedish verbs in a year
If you do something like I said now, I actually think so
test
And as I said
You are always happy to comment, ask and so on
Please tell us how you do to study
are you one that memorizes very much
or are you a little more like me to try
learn a little at a time
By reading and listening
It is interesting for me to read, it is interesting for others who read
The comments on the videos
to read, so please write a small line about how you do and how you think
and so we'll see you again soon
Have a good time so long, goodbye.