Good morning everyone!
Today is Monday, January 3.
The time now is 7.33.
I usually listen to the radio in the car.
It is now 7.34
Today is my first working day this year, 2022.
I have been off for quite some time and now I am going to work.
I drive to work. Come along!
It's 7.48 and I'm at work. I'm in the parking lot.
Good continuation! I forgot to say at first.
It is said from January 1 and a few more days.
First you say Happy New Year!
and then they say Good luck!
Today you can come with me to my job.
I take my books with me. I'm taking my computer with me.
I take my lunch box with me. It's my lunch box.
I take off my jacket.
I change my shoes.
I go to the coffee room.
I'm having a cup of coffee.
I pour the coffee.
This card is a key to all doors at work.
I take out my computer.
For the lesson I need my computer,
My books
Student lists
A water bottle with water
It is important to drink water!
And of course I have my coffee cup!
I drink coffee without milk and without sugar.
The lesson starts at 8:30 and ends at 11:45.
I'm having lunch at 12:00.
After lunch I have planning time.
So I'm sitting here planning my lessons.
I work here, it's my workplace
my desk
I have my computer
I have different books and papers.
I have many small notes everywhere.
I have a bookshelf.
This is my bookshelf. I also have books here.
I am going out.
We have two buildings in the school.
We have two houses, two buildings.
It's one building and another building.
There is some snow left here. It's quite hot today.
The snow is melting.
Over there is Arlanda Airport.
There is a parking lot.
There's my little car.
We go and have a look in the other house, in the other building.
Here is a door opener.
I press it and the door opens.
Here is a huge corridor.
With many classrooms, there are different classrooms there.
There are toilets here.
There is a mirror.
Toilet out of order The
toilet does not work, you can not use it.
Here is a sofa, a chair.
There are dictionaries here.
Here is a classroom. I go in and look in a classroom.
It's dark in the classroom.
I have to turn on the light.
An empty classroom The
time is 13:40.
There are pictures on the walls.
Very nice pictures
In a classroom there is a table, many tables.
There are also chairs.
One chair - many chairs
This is a painting.
A fan
If it is hot, you can use a fan.
There is an extra door.
Escape route
There are windows in the classroom.
There is also a clothes hanger. You can hang your jackets there.
I turn off the light.
I open the door. We're going out again.
Here it is very bright and fresh.
There are also flowers.
But these are not real flowers.
These are plastic flowers, plastic plants.
It looks nice, right?
There is also a kettle and tea.
Students usually drink tea during the break.
There is a fire extinguisher here. This machine is used for cleaning.
There are pictures on the wall.
We go to the other building.
It's a little wet and sloppy.
Here is our kitchen, staff kitchen.
Here we have a copier to copy and print.
Here is our staff room.
We have many workplaces for many teachers.
We have shelves, we have real flowers.
This is my place.
There is a café here but it is closed due to Corona.
Here is a computer room for the students.
Students can study here.
A blackboard
Tables and chairs
a sofa
a bulletin board
Here there are classrooms.
Here are toilets.
There are more classrooms.
We also have a kitchen for the students.
It was micro
There are books for the students that I think the students can take home and read at home.
Goodies
There is also a kettle,
a dishwasher or two dishwashers
An oven
a stove
There is also a refrigerator
There is a refrigerator. This is a freezer.
There is milk here.
More classrooms
An empty classroom
many tables
two windows
Chairs
And
a painting
Now you have seen my workplace, my school.
I'll go back to the study and keep planning.
Thank you very much for watching. See you in the next video.
Bye!