Hello Hello
I hope everything is fine with you.
In this movie I was going to talk a little
About pronunciation and practicing pronunciation
I got a comment for
A while ago, I think it was before Christmas
There was someone on the channel here who
told he felt sad
because his pronunciation was not so good
So when he then tried to talk to Swedes
so they didn't understand what he is saying
or they do not understand what he is saying
And then became
the result that he pulled
back and became silent instead
because it is hard to try to talk and not be understood
and this I think many can recognize themselves in
somehow
And the question then is how to do
I can say directly that I
focuses a lot on pronunciation in
my classes when i am teacher
But I wish I was
Even better at teaching in pronunciation
that I had even more control over
both the theory behind and how to do
It's something I work on but
That's why I thought about referring to two teachers
and scientists too, writers
would I say that is
very good at this with pronunciation, as I know
and it is partly a man named
Olle Kjellin
and he has written books about pronunciation
both more theoretical and more practical
For those who want to train
He also has several Facebook pages called
Swedish pronunciation and
Swedish Prosody in Pratic and there is someone
In English too
I put links to his pages in this movie
There is another man named Bosse Thorén
that lectures a lot about pronunciation and
pronunciation education
I don't keep track of his books
But I'm sure there is a lot
to pick up there too
So there you have two tips on
Good people to check out
If you want to know more about how you can practice pronunciation
in a good way
and I was going to summarize
Little Olle Kjellin's method card
at the end of the movie, because he has a very
clear and concrete method
For how to practice pronunciation
And he writes
good about it yourself on their Facebook pages
and in their books
So my tip is really to check out
what he writes but I can do
A little summary as well as I understand
As I understood his methods
But before I do
So I thought I can summarize
the three most important things with Swedish pronunciation
For I believe that
If one knows about
what to listen to or listen for
and what to train on
so you can get pretty far on it
Olle Kjellin's method requires discipline
And motivation, I think it's great
But I have never really exercised like that
hard as he thinks one should
When I have trained other languages; I have tested
a little, but it really requires you to work hard
So if you can't cope
So you can still think of three things and
Exercise a little more relaxed on three things
and there are then three points and the first
is the most important
and the most important thing in Swedish pronunciation, that's the difference between
Long sound and short sound
both if you listen to one word at a time
single words
So if I say
work
So it is very important to get the rhythm right
Both the melody
and itself short and tall affects
so it's something you should listen to when you learn new words
and listen to when you hear people talk
and even more important than just the words
So it is to listen to whole sentences
So for example if I say
I live in Gothenburg
I live in Gothenburg (then da da daaaa)
that rhythm is very important
and very often when people don't understand you
so is it because you have the wrong rhythm
in the speech
so listen to it
listen to examples and try to mimic and train the rhythm to
It is so important in Swedish
the second then is how you form
the mouth
And then you might think mainly about vowels
A, o, u, å, ä, e
And so on, that is perhaps the most important thing
to get the vowels right
But there is even when you do
The consonants so you also have a shape on the mouth
that can sometimes affect
your pronunciation
so
it is others are simply
work out on vowels, practice on getting the mouth
shape right, the mouth is flat
or round and so on
work out on it and
Your pronunciation will be better
Number 3 is what is called reductions
or you can only say that
Some letters are silent
so if you look at a text then there is
a lot of letters like we
not pronounce when we talk
and this is important
many slopes with it or do not understand that
Like, real Swedish is to remove
those where * the words * the letters
such as “R” at the end of many verbs when we speak
fast
or there may be other things like
g inside of words and so on
It's something you simply get to listen for
If you do not have a teacher who can show and explain
so you get to listen when people talk and compare to
text and understand that
that word we write like that, when we talk
naturally, normal, at normal speed
so we don't pronounce those * words * the letters
And your Swedish will sound much better
unless you do it either
Your Swedish gets choppy
and stopped, it stops
For example, if you say
I live in Gothenburg
It's not called "I live in" " - it's called" Jabor "
or “Jabori”
And so on, there are many examples, but believe me
If you choose which sounds you should not pronounce
so that you don't pronounce as
as a reading output
As it looks in a book, your Swedish will let
More Swedish and people will understand you better
so these are these three things, listen to
long sounds and short sounds
train on shaping the sounds
vowels especially properly
and number three, learn which
sound you should not pronounce
or which letters, not sound, which letters
you should not pronounce, don't talk like a book
Talk naturally
Ehm, yes
and Olle Kjellin's way of training on this
It's about this way
You will find either sample sentences
on the web in any language course or
retrieves from someone ... whatever
a news broadcast, a movie or something
or you get a Swedish person to
record sample sentences for you
not very fucking but not very long
a little just long like that so that
You may get ten sentences for example
that have the natural
the parts of Swedish pronunciation in themselves
you get the rhythm, you get the different vowels
you get these reductions, that it is silent
you have ten sentences
you have the recorded
somehow so you can listen to them many times
The best way is if you have them
some kind of computer program so you can
repeat them many, many times
But you can also have a small file
in your mobile for example and that you
playing again and playing again
and listen and listen
So first just listen
and then train to mimic these sentences
giant, giant, huge times
until you pronounce them perfectly
So if I had one of my students
so could a sentence might be
I live in Gothenburg in Sweden
And then you really should repeat it
The sample sentence
A thousand times maybe
five thousand times maybe i don't know exactly
Check out what Olle Kjellin says, you should train very much
and in a few sentences
As one learns to say perfect
and then it will help you pronounce all
sentences with the correct pronunciation late
so this is something you can test if you are justified
and really want to train good pronunciation
record some sentences or pick up any sentences
from the net
Listen, listen, listen - train to repeat
a thousand times
Are you a little lazier as I am
So you think of these three points
and in everyday life you train
on trying to get it right by listening and mimic
things you hear on TV and radio
and when you listen to real people talking
But then not coming
your pronunciation become as good
If you make this concentrated
focused and intensive effort
Like Olle Kjellin
recommend, then your pronunciation will be better
I am pretty sure of
That said, check out what he writes, check out his books
you won't regret it
he has a lot of good tips
so this about pronunciation
If you are a beginner or if you have friends who are a beginner
tell them to
focus on pronunciation from the beginning
Don't think you should learn it later
Without trying to learn a good and natural pronunciation
From the first day you train Swedish
It is much easier to learn right
from the beginning
than to try to learn one more time
When one first learned wrong
and received bad pronunciation habits
so tip all your friends
Start training on the pronunciation today
and don't give up without fight it until it's so good
As you can only cope and can
yes
It was well
As I said, ask, comment
so
can we discuss if there is something special you are wondering about
In the comments
Have a good time and we'll see you again soon.
Bye