Hello
I was going to talk a little about
how to learn and
Exercise on prepositions
Pretty many ask about prepositions
in Swedish
and thinks it's hard
so my first tip
And the most important thing I think is to
Learn prepositions
in ordinary phrases
So I think it's
wasted time, I don't think you win on
to try to learn some kind of rules
For all the rules have exceptions
and there are none
Clear rules for how prepositions
will be used
in different types of sentences and phrases
There are no determined rules
For how prepositions are to be used
they do not have such a definite meaning
so start step by step to
learn them in regular phrases
As you often need
so it can be good to start with
stuff you might say quite often
As I study at SFI
or I am studying at
high school, I go to the movies
I am going to party, I go
on the toilet
Pretty common sentences so you learn
on along with those words, but maybe then
I'm in the shop, I'm
in the center, i'm
in school
and so on, at the dentist
at the doctor
so start with the most common
that you can use frequently