Hello Hello
And good morning
Today it is Long Friday so I have to wish all happy Easter
And I want to talk a little about something I think is very important
When you practice language
And that's what we call attention to Swedish attention
Attention, it is simply that you
concentrates you
Focus
Listens carefully
And read carefully
that you think about what you do
And simply
Listens for details and ...
thinking about details, ie the little things
for if you do
So will you see more things in the language and hear more things in the language
It applies to all things
It applies to how the words are written ...
It applies to how the words are pronounced
This applies to grammar
For example, order
I would think that the most important thing to train on: It is to listen carefully
Both on the order
..... brain drop ....
As I forgot to cut away
Both on the pronunciation
How we pronounce words. How we pronounce sentences.
And then on which words use
Which grammar people use.
What different expressions people use in different situations
Anything this can teach you very much
And I think that those who learn Swedish faster are them as
are more attentive and think more about what they hear and read
If you think about it then you will perceive more
And you will learn only from listening to the language and reading the language
And I think it's something you can train on
So if you know for yourself that you are not so attentive and concentrated
So when training in Swedish and when you use Swedish
so try to decide you
A few minutes maybe, for a while, a few times during the day that ...
Now I really will try to think about
What others say or what I read in a book.
Maybe, in a way that it is easiest to exercise when you read for then you can also
decide to read a little slower and really look at the words and grammar
and which expressions are used
Which word sequence is used
the spelling
for you will learn just from thinking about what you do simply
And then of course: when you have the chance to speak Swedish. When you have the chance to listen to Swedish.
So really listen and you can almost talk a little quiet with yourself
When you hear a new expression ... note it (you say)
It's like: make a small note in your head
Think "Aha!", He or she uses that word in that situation
That expression means the same thing as that expression
I think it can help to become more attentive. It's almost like you talk to yourself a little.
When you listen to someone
Who speaks Swedish
It may sound simple but it's not always that simple
And anyway, I think we can all be more attentive
Exercise our attention
So do it!
I remind me to text my videos
So you haven't seen this video with text
so find the setting that allows you to watch the video with text
and it will be easier for you to understand what I say
Like the video, please share it with friends if you think it was good
Feel free to check out my blog too. I usually write something almost every day
There you can get more tips and learn more words and expressions.
And so everyone who sees this now gets this weekend
Have a really nice Easter weekend and so we'll see you again soon
Have a nice day! Bye!