We drive to Kolmården.
It's a zoo.
Come along!
Are you tagged?
Kolmården is the largest zoo in the Nordic region.
Now the adventure begins!
Here are elephants.
I think this elephant is pregnant.
She has a big stomach.
At Kolmården there are many animals.
There are many animal species.
How many animal species are there at Kolmården?
Search for their website and write in comments!
At Kolmården there are many aquatic animals.
There are dolphins too.
Excuse me, may I ask you one thing?
Where is the exit?
The output is over there!
Then we go there!
There is a playground at Kolmården, a large playground.
"Thanks for keeping your distance!"
There are hand spirit stations everywhere so you can spread your hands.
There are many rides for children and adults.
You can look at theater.
At Kolmården there are rides for brave adults and brave children.
I'm not brave, I dare not go this attraction.
We look at the map.
Another favorite is safari.
First, we disinfect our hands.
Then you have to stand in a very long queue.
We sit in a gondola.
The cable car is very long.
You sit in the gondola, look out ...
You look at all animals and rest.
It takes about half an hour to ride the cable car.
Here we are the guests of the wild animals.
There are many different animals.
So exciting!
Have you ever been to Kolmården?
Or do you want to go there?