Hello
and welcome to Swedish with Kalle
Today you will get a little task from me
For this week
If you want to understand
and I think like this
To our brain
enjoy having fun
And the brain
So the brain in here I mean
enjoy variety and
null
that you do things in new ways
And it's very easy when we ...
... when we study something, to example
Swedish
that we end up in
the same routine all the time
that we do the same way
And this is of course very good
also because it means that we
not have to think so much without
We have our routine we work
with our dictionaries with our
Text books with ours
apps, websites, whatever it may be
and
to do the same thing and have a routine
is of course in many ways good
But sometimes it can get a bit boring
and it could be like we fall asleep a little
We make it too much on routine
So my suggestion is that ...
You plan to ...
Exercise in a new way this week
Think a little about how you usually study ,,,
And then so ....
Plan in a time to make
in a way you don't usually
So for example if you read
Very many books
Try watching a movie on Youtube instead
Or test that
Test a new app on a mobile
If you work very much digitally test instead to
read books or
Try to write by hand
If you mostly read
And writes
so try to listen a lot someday
during the week or find an opportunity to
talk
It might be that you go to language café or
go talk to yourself at home or
Record a video just ...
just because
Feel that you have someone to talk to.
But of course it's just the imagination
that sets the limit on how you can exercise.
null
Read a magazine
magazine about something that interests you
borrow a newspaper about fashion or politics
or cars or football
Walk around town and ask people about
the way to any place
buy
nice post-it notes in new colors
and put up at home
in new words
You can come up with just about anything
Call a friend, decide,
Call a friend and decide that you should speak Swedish
for five or ten minutes even if
The friend does not have Swedish as their mother tongue
It really doesn't matter.
Go into a deal that you don't usually go into
and read on the signs and price tags
And everything that is in the store.
maybe ask someone who works there
and bring with you five new words
You may only be able to learn
some words that really
are completely meaningless and as
you don't think you have any use of
But that are fun to know
So simply, schedule some time
do something you don't usually do
When studying Swedish
Just to give your brain some entertainment
and variety and hopefully
also something fun to do
for it can give you new energy
When you study and
simply even your routine
becomes more fun when you mix it up
with things you don't
usually do
This was my tip for today
You can always ask about
You don't understand anything I say or comment.
And please write a comment and tell
What you tested to do this week
that you don't usually do.
Thanks so much.
Have a good one.
See you again soon.
Bye.
null