Hello Hello
Here's a tip if you want
Understanding people better
where you live and get better contact
with people where you live
and it is simply that
Learn common names
In places where you live
and learn some abbreviations
And hose words
In places and things
and house and stuff where you live
It happens quite often
that I meet SFI students
that has lived in Gothenburg
Pretty long
and still become unsure if i
Says, for example, Avenyn or Götaplats
Or Nordstan
it is different but it happens and
When that happens, so I say the name of a
very ordinary large place
in Gothenburg as everyone
that are born in Gothenburg knows
If then the person does not know
Then it creates a distance
It creates a feeling that this one
the person is not interested in
the place he or she lives on
while if the person knows it
so it creates a feeling that
by proximity, that yes, we both live in Gothenburg
and of course we know what
Different places in Gothenburg are called
so
My suggestion is that you, when
You've been ready for this movie
Take a few pages in a book
thus a writing book and
and write at the top there
places where I live or names
In places where I live
and so start asking people a bit and gather on you
So think about a little, what's the name?
What's the name? And what calls
People who live here
that and that thing
so
yes, right, and then the other
then that ... it is also very common
that you in, when you live in a city you get
Also give short names and nicknames
to
to places, you want to talk fast and you want
one thinks everyone understands what one means
And that's why it can be difficult to understand if you listen then
On people, for example, from Gothenburg
and they talk and use abbreviations
or slang words for different things
and thus, if you
uses the same, or as well as talking in the same way
like those who come from
the place does, so you will again create more proximity
It creates a feeling of a contact
It shows that you are interested
and have looked up
what ever
hands on that spot
How to talk and so on
it can be simple stuff like there are
Two hospitals in Gothenburg, it is called Östra Hospital
Eastern Hospital and Sahlgrenska Hospital
It is almost never someone who says that
without saying Östra and Sahlgrenska
so "where is ...
it and that person? ”
Yes he is lying on the east
And it can be hard to understand if you talk quickly
But that means' he lies on the eastern
The hospital '
Or "he works at Sahlgrenska"
Yes, what does that mean? Well, he works at Sahlgrenska Hospital
Sahlgrenska Hospital 'there may also be places
so
I often call the library
for the bible
so that "I'll go to the bible" and borrow books and all
huh, what is the bible, yes the library
or if you buy beer or wine
so you normally go to either
The system or company
There are very few Swedes
that says: "I'll go to Systembolaget"
without saying the “system” or “company”
There are certainly a lot of different such examples
I think like this: cinemas or restaurants
Or cafes
squares, statues
fountains, that is, there is a mass
different things that may have
small names of their own as they
that comes from the site uses
My colleague who comes from Stockholm
said, for example
"Yeah, are you going to Stockan"
Log that is short for Stockholm then
Yes, many such things
so
simply check it up, ask
People around you, it is also a fun way
to get in touch with people because if you show interest
for that place people come from and live on
so they will be happy and it can be one
There may be a conversation that continues
Plus that
It is fun to be able to such things
I also think it can give a greater feeling of being at home
in a place if one knows how
so to say, locals
talking about that place
Yes, that's what I wanted to say here
Please write a comment about you what is it called
Learn something new, I can most
Name of places in Gothenburg where I live
so it could be a bit of fun if you find some
funny nicknames or abbreviations
from the place where you live
So you might be happy to write it in a comment
It would be fun to read
Have a good time so long so we'll see you again soon
Bye