Now we are in Pippi Longstocking country.
Today we will go to Astrid Lindgren's World.
a flag
Astrid Lindgren's World is a theater and theme park.
It is located in Småland, in Vimmerby.
Vimmerby is Astrid Lindgren's hometown.
She is known all over the world.
Astrid Lindgren is an author.
She is a children's book author.
She has written many books.
Her books have been translated into over 100 languages.
In the park you can meet many of the characters from her books.
In addition to theater, there are many play environments in the park.
It has been a great day today. We are tired.
Now we have to go home.
The journey home takes 4 hours from here.