Hello everyone!
Hello!
Welcome to our cabin in Kläppen!
Welcome!
a hall - the hall
a mirror
This is our cabin.
There are two planes, two floors.
In the hall we have a drying cabinet.
for wet clothes - so they get dry faster
Here is the hall.
Here is a bedroom with a bunk bed.
A small bedroom
Here we have the toilet with shower.
shelves
a shower
A small kitchen
a fridge
a freezer
a dishwasher
a stove
a coffee maker
a toaster
There are also porcelain: plates and mugs.
Everything you need.
a living room
with a large sofa and a large dining table
We also have a large window.
Look what a good thing!
There is a small patio there.
What a view!
It is snowing so beautifully!
a fireplace - a fireplace
a TV
There is also a microwave oven.
Upstairs
Come we go and watch!
Here is a children's gate.
If you have small children, you can close the gate and
Then they can't come down and fall.
There are two double beds here.
a bedside table
a mirror
An extra pillow
a highchair, a cot
a small bedroom for many people
Thanks for watching!
See you in the next video!
Bye!