Hello everyone! Hello!
Today I want to tell you about my workplace, about my job.
a workplace - my workplace
This is my workplace, my school.
I work at Komvux.
What does municipal adult mean?
Komvux means municipal adult education.
Education for adults.
What do adults mean?
Komvux corresponds to compulsory school and upper secondary school.
Komvux is a school for adults who lack knowledge corresponding to primary and secondary school.
At komvux you can study Swedish.
You can study SFI (Swedish for immigrants)
When you finish SFI, you can continue studying at SVA basic.
SVA = Swedish as a second language
You learn to read and write from the beginning of SFI course A.
I teach Swedish at SFI course C and SVA basic module 3 and 4.
Before that I worked with SFI course A.
Right now all students study at home, online , due to Covid-19.
They study digitally with a mobile phone or computer.
The school is located by a fire station.
Look what firefighters do - they go sledding!
I enjoy my job very much.
I love my job!
It's visible, right?
Do you study Swedish at school or online?
Write in the comments!
Look what nice snowmen we have!
a snowman - two snowmen
We also have a nice tree for birds.
They got scared of me and flew away.
Otherwise, there are usually many small birds here.
Thank you for watching this video!
See you in the next movie!