Hello everyone! Hello!
Look what the weather!
Fantastic!
It's great weather today!
A real winter!
It's snowing.
It's not cold.
It's so wonderful!
I want to tell you about how we throw our garbage - sort.
We live in a chain house.
We have two bins.
A rubbish bin is for ...
What a nice snow!
We can watch together.
stained glass
food waste
residual waste
newspapers and recycled paper
There is a lot of residual waste and food waste.
But not so much stained glass.
and no newspapers
They are empty.
Here's it:
This bin is emptied every two weeks.
once every two weeks
Today we have received a message.
We have an app in the phone.
We have received a message that we must exhibit rubbish bin 1 for emptying.
The emptying is tomorrow.
The garbage truck will arrive tomorrow and then they will empty the rubbish bin.
The rubbish bin must be emptied by the rubbish truck.
The garbage truck must empty the rubbish bin.
We're looking at what's here.
Here it is plastic packaging.
paper packaging
colorless glass, only bottles and jars
There are a few pieces there.
metal packaging
It's Monday, January 11th.
The garbage truck is coming.
They're going to get the garbage.
See for yourself!
Thank you so much for watching!
See you in the next video! Bye!