Hello
In this movie so will
talk about a question like me
think many people can recognize themselves in
which is about perfectionism
to want to be perfect
and about being stressed
When one learns a language
And then I was going to answer a little short
on two questions I have received
but we start with
Perfectionism and
The stress
and the question of how to
Should choose
what one is trying to learn
and what one is waiting for for later
For I notice that many
On Youtube and on Facebook
and on my instagram
and in my classroom
becomes stressed
And frustrated
And sad
When they don't understand
and sometimes it feels reasonable
I can think that "yes, this should you understand"
This I would also like to understand
in your situation
But many times it feels unreasonable
and unreasonable means that
one hopes too much
too fast, it's not
logically to believe that one should be able to
Understand difficult things
In the beginning without one must accept
that it takes a long time
to learn some things
And then this one feels
frustration or the sad feeling
A little unreasonable
Because I think "yes but, it's natural ...
that you don't understand or can this yet "
it must get to come later
so
Just that, this can be called, I think everyone
have more or less
by perfectionism
and perfectionism is thus
the will to be perfect
to manage something to 100%
Not to make mistakes
For example, you want to speak Swedish
perfect
it is different but many have
a bit like that anyway
And there may be many different
Psychological
Thus, thoughtful
Causes behind it
It may be such that
you feel sad or frustrated
When comparing to whom you are
and how you can speak on your
mother tongue and who you become
and what you can say in your new language
It's hard to
When you talk in your mother tongue
can you say exactly what you want and express
exactly what you think and feel
But in Swedish it becomes
So little and
so bullied you might say
bullied means approximately poor
It feels like you can't say what you want
and
Another thing that I think many anyway
A little affected
It is a feeling that one wants to impress
There is a word for it in Swedish and it is
vanity
and vanity is the will to
be good and good
and impress others
simply appear as a very
good and good person
and that ... I can for example
feel it when I speak English
I understand that my English is not perfect
But somewhere in the back of my head so I would
want to be able to shine as one says
impress, have a perfect pronunciation
able to express me exactly
As I want because it feels pretty close
but
If I try to speak French
or Somali
so i have to let go of it altogether
If I study
Somali for ten years to
So maybe I can talk
fairly good
But now ... there is no chance
To expect
to hope I will talk even close
perfect
So it's good to ask yourself a little ... Why
am i sorry why am i getting frustrated
When I don't
Speaks as well as I want
and if it is that I want to impress
Then I don't think it's such a good cause
Then you should probably think a little about it
maybe think more about
How can I communicate the most important
I want to communicate
It is much more important to get
Being able to express it as you want to say
and think about what
is most important
In order for you to be able to express yourself
a little better, a little more efficient
A little more advanced
and here I come to the last
the point in this thought
and that is that I think one must try
feel for yourself where man is
in their language development
so that one is trying to understand
that this is reasonable
this can actually
teach me, this can I try
use yourself or understand
But this is too hard
This is too specific, it is for special words
or this is too small grammar
Right now I can't
use or understand that
I have to try to cope with something easier
And then when you talk, for example
with someone or reading a text
or you may be looking at my instagram as some do
and sometimes thinks "oh, what difficult words
it was today ”
Then I think you have to ignore
So do so; okay
I will take that late, I don't care about it now
I focus on something that
Fits my level right now
and there is something one must balance
and think about all the time
what is just hard
For me right now. If you get yourself
a sense of that
So I think you will put the energy
better, ie laying the energy
more effective on it as
that fits a right now
and one won't waste
as much energy on it that is too difficult
so that somehow
Prioritize and
opt out
Choosing what is most important right now
And it can be different for different
people, it's both different
Depending on what you want to do
What you want to talk about
in Swedish and it depends on which
level you are and a little what you have
difficult for and what you have easy for
But it is not possible to stress, it is not possible
to push too much
and therefore one must try to follow some kind
Natural development
where one first learns the light and then
Step by step learns more and more
Then I think you will have more fun and
and enjoy more of learning the language
If you just look at what you can't
and trying to grasp
that which is too difficult
Then it will be very painful
very hard
and it is easy to criticize
itself
and it's not good when trying
learn something, to criticize oneself
it should try to avoid it
Try not to
So not do
So I think about this
And please say what you think
Feel free to comment and I tried
Using some different interesting words now
So if there was any word
As you think was interesting
and that fits your level
So please ask me
If you don't understand then I try to explain
Just that, then I had received
two somewhat interesting questions
one was about the slang word
“tagged”, to be tagged
So often you can say that about
A party for example "I'm tagged"
Before the party
I am tagged on going to a party
or to go to the party that means that
I'm enthusastic
I am looking forward to, I'm happy
I feel a lot of energy, I am tagged in learning Swedish
I would like to learn
Swedish, I am enthusiastic
so it's a pretty common expression
you can test to use it
It's not like a
dangerous slang word to try I think
Many people use it
Then I had a different question about
why we delete them
in many
preteritumverb, ie when
We use a verb in preteritum
and it ends on d e
so we remove D and e when we talk
Quickly
and it applies to verb groups 1
When we have such -ade
Look-a-they
asked, so if you listen
On Swedes they often remove
-They at the end and say for example
I played)
football yesterday so that you hear
is just play t
But if you were to write it, it will be played
And why do we do that, then
because when we talk so