Hello everyone. Good evening
I'll keep trying to talk a little about.
How to train yourself to speak Swedish
and I will try to give a tip
for a little more advanced
Swedish teacher
My first thought is to try to see this with learning language
and to practice talking like a practical problem
thus something, a problem that you should try to solve
By finding roads, finding methods
that works for you
and that you are trying to make
so to say, make harder and harder things
But at a decent pace for you
and to give oneself tasks
to give oneself things to train on
I think it's important to try to find good and just great tasks
So, for example, to think like this
I will learn to speak perfectly Swedish
It is a very big and very unclear task
I think it's good to try to split up
Language training in small and clear tasks
For example: I will learn to order coffee at a cafe
It is much easier to train on it than to train to become perfect in Swedish
You can practice asking about the price in a deal
You can practice asking what someone has done on the weekend
So here comes a suggestion if you are a little more advanced and that is to
look at that city or the place where you live on
If there are lectures on something that you are interested in or that you think is quite interesting
thus a lecture is a person or more persons
talking about a special subject for an hour or a few hours
There may also be more a call for audience where some people meet and talk about a particular subject
and people can get there and listen
For example, there may be writers talking about their books
It can be people who are researching about something interesting
There can be lots of different subjects. It can be the environment. It can be culture
It can be society. It can be technology
There are lectures on many different subjects
So the best thing is if you find a topic that you are interested in
And usually you can too
Check out and read a little about the one to talk before
So that way you can prepare for the subject person will talk about
such as read the introduction to
a website or on the information sheet available for the lecture
But you might also read an article by this person
If it is a famous person you can certainly find something this person has written with the help of Google
okay
Already this, already there you have two very practical steps you can do to train yourself to listen to Swedish
Find a topic that interests you
Find a lecture where you can go and listen
and prepare yourself by reading a little about that subject
so that you know a little more words, that you can a little
sentences and understand the context slightly
It may even be that the person you are going to listen with is on Youtube
so that you can listen to a lecture with the person before
And then when you go to the lecture you have already heard how this person is talking
and can understand some of the subject before
If you want the chance then say you come to the lecture and you feel brave
and you want to try to talk a little
If you know the subject a little before
so can you be prepared with one or a few questions
As you can set to the person or persons
At the end of the lecture when you almost always have a question time
So it may not be that you say so much but it still becomes that you dare to talk in Swedish
in front of many people
and you will get an answer too
maybe if you have a good day you ask something, you get an answer and you can ask back once to
What may be the advantage is that if you dare
get up, maybe even talk in a microphone
or if it is a smaller room talk before a group
Then people will have seen you
You can even look here; People understand that if you express yourself in a language
that you are not so used to expressing yourself so you can say that
Excuse me, I would like to ask a question. I'm a little unsure of Swedish but I still want to try
Here's my question
Okay, then people have seen you
and they've heard you
And if you are lucky there is someone there, someone else in the audience
who thinks: This seemed to be an interesting person or that was an interesting question
So you are lucky then maybe someone will come and talk to you afterwards
And say, yes, it was a good question, yeah what exciting ...
What brave of you that you dared to talk even though you don't have Swedish as your native language
Do you understand, there are no guarantees. I can't promise it will happen but
If you should have the chance to meet people and talk to people
So you have to go to racks
where there are other people
and at least give people the chance to come up and talk to you
so you just got a little luck
So there is any person there who comes to you and maybe at least want to switch a few words
and I think so to say that if you are this person who wants to train you to talk o
and want to train you to understand and want to train you to interact
so it is like: every minute counts
every situation where you become safer
every situation where you know a little better how you can answer
How you can ask
what different sentences the other will say to you
The better you will be talking, the better you will be understanding and the way ...
the more confident you will be and the greater the chance that you
Looking up situations where you get to talk
Ok i'm gonna stop there
Hope it is possible to understand how I think
And that you have been able to listen to the whole video because it was a bit far now
And I will continue to think and think and I would like feedback
I would like to have your comments, questions, own ideas
and then I will soon record a new movie where I give someone
some new tip, pondering a new situation and how you could do to
Get the chance to speak more Swedish
Thanks for tonight. See you again soon. Have a good one!