Hello everyone!
Today I am going to get vaccinated.
Today I will get my first injection, my first vaccine dose against Covid-19.
I booked an appointment via an app called ...
This is how I did it.
I log in with band ID.
book
I choose ...
After I have booked an appointment, I receive a confirmation via text message.
In Sweden, it is free to get vaccinated against Covid-19.
Now it's my turn. Now I'm going in.
I'm wearing a mouth guard.
Now I have been vaccinated.
Now I have my first syringe.
Now I have my first dose of vaccine against Covid-19.
Now I'm waiting for the second shot, the second dose of vaccine.
I have received an information sheet that I will read at home.
It's blowing so much!
I've been given a card to remember.
When should you get vaccinated?
Have you already been vaccinated?
Write in the comments!
Thank you so much for watching!
See you in the next movie! Bye!