My suggestion is that you
Learn Swedish as a photographer
Like a documentary filmmaker
As an author, as a poet
I will explain a little more how I mean
Hello and welcome to Swedish with Kalle
The movie is texted so turn on the subtitle
so it becomes easier to understand what I say
yes
In this movie I want to talk a little about
that the language is around us
continuously
only we are attentive
So if we are curious
And pay attention
and notice things
and think about what is around us
and what is happening
so can we also learn
much more language by thinking about
What things are called
and how to express different things
I think it's a bit like a
maybe a writer or a photographer
working, they look all the time, they listen all the time
They think a little all the time: what is this?
What does this tell you?
How can you say this? how can I
Catch this feeling in a poem?
And a little so
can you think or you can be inspired by
This when you practice Swedish
and I do it above all
When I work with my Instagram account Swedish with Kalle
for almost always when I walk in town
or when I listen to some who talk
So I have it in the back of my mind
that I always think a little that
How can you say this?
Or what is this name?
or there is a broken stick on the ground,
what expressions are there as
who uses this?
so that there is a concrete situation
But then there is also something more abstract
or an expression or a metaphor
As we use in everyday life perhaps
So then you can connect this concrete situation to
to one more
poetic or metaphorical use of language
and we do it all the time in everyday life
and I think that
If you arouse your curiosity
If you sharpen your attention
So can you learn more Swedish
in this way
like only when you sit down at
the table in the morning and will
eat breakfast
What is it really called? How do you say this when you take the sandwich and ...
For it to the mouth aha ...
one can bring the food to the mouth
What is it called when you
sets and puts different things on the table
What do you do when breakfast is over and you ...
Smits away
Can you all these expressions?
How do you say in your language?
What expressions exist in Swedish that express the same thing?
When you go out the door
and you are looking up at the sky
and the sun shines brightly
What synonyms are there for that?
What expressions do we use?
or when you get to school or work
and you are a little delayed
and you feel a little stressed
and the heart beats a little fast
How can you say that?
Yes you can say that the heart is pounding
or you feel a little stressed
you open the door fast, you
rushes you in
Yes you know, you can find as much as possible
and if you think about your own language
How to use ordinary verbs
In more metaphorical expressions
How to use different adjectives
to perhaps describe feelings or
the atmosphere in a room or
How the weather is or something like that
The clouds in the sky were dark
they threatened up threateningly
I mean it doesn't say in the sky when you go out through the door
and
Looking at the sky and thinking: Oh, it may start to rain today
So it doesn't stand in the sky the expression
"The clouds are threateningly threatening in the sky"
But if you are curious then you can start to become more attentive
* for* on when people use
More advanced language
And when you see it in books, but you can also ask
What are there to express that
say that it will soon start raining
What are there for different phrases and sentences
You can use when it's hot?
Great hot so it feels hard
This I think is a little more creative
attitude to learning language
and it requires you to think
and reflects and is curious
and looking for the language and
finds a joy in finding
More words, more expressions