All cardboard
Look
This was delicious
Gosh...
What's with you? Do you throw the food on the floor? Don't you like the food?
What are you saying? Potato?
You want potatoes? Where can you find it then?
Robots eating potatoes. It's the strangest I've heard.
Do they sell potatoes here?
No ... this is a fish shop.
Here you buy fish.
Do they sell potatoes here, then?
Where are you going now? Wait for me!
Sorry.
Little red, wait for me.
Where did we?
To a place there are lots of potatoes?
Yes, but where is it somewhere, then?
A surprise? I don't like surprises.
Huh, a cycling potato?
And here someone has built a potato machine.
A potato.
Of potatoes you can make ... potato chips,
Oops.
And mashed potatoes.
Well, little red. Where are the potatoes?
Huh? Where are you going?
Gosh...
No, little red. Now I want to know.
Take out the potato.
I can not take it. I want to go home.
Is potatoes grow here?
But there is only soil and grass and stones here.
A potato field? What do you mean?
Nämen, look ... look
A tractor with lots of potatoes.
Huh? Do you want to ride along?
I do not want that. Never.
Drop off me. I want to go off!
Look here. This potato is very nice.
Little red, check out this one.
This is wonderful.
Hello Hello.
It's wonderful, little red.
It was not believed this morning,
That you and I would foam among potatoes.
Great
This potato is the route.
Hello Hello!
This one is fine. Take out the wagon, little red.
Well, there it is.
Now we go home again.
Can you guess what this is?
A potato!
And now several vegetables.
Asparagus, tomato ...
...broccoli...
And even more broccoli.
Little Red? Fried potatoes smell really good.
Soon it's done. We fry a little more.
I've never heard of a robot eating potatoes.
There you go. Now it's finished.
You are welcome.
Do you spit out the food?
But you wanted potatoes. Now ... now you can actually eat up.
Nämen, what are you doing?
Disgusting? You want something else to eat?
Well, you are craving a fork.
Do you want the roasting pad too?
Yes, the roasting pad is delicious, right?
I said that. Potatoes are for humans, not for robots.
Are you full now?
Yes, how nice!