Hey my friends!
Good morning!
It's early in the morning.
It's half past seven.
It's Friday today.
Tomorrow it is Saturday.
My children eat sweets on Saturdays.
Saturday candy
I'm on my way to work.
But first I will shop.
I'm going to buy candy.
Follow!
Open every day
candy
A lot of candy
Loose weight candy
Now I have to weigh candy.
Now I go to the checkout.
Continue!
I will pay by card.
a receipt
I shop on Friday morning, then there are not so many people.
There are not so many people in the store.
On Saturday and Sunday there are a lot of people in the store.
Everyone shops.
I try to shop on Friday for example,
Or on Monday, Tuesday, Wednesday, Thursday in the morning.
Or when it's lunchtime, then there are some people too.
I've received a receipt.
We read together.
I have to hurry to work.
The job starts at 8am.
That's almost 300 grams.
I have three children so it is enough.
My children eat sweets on Saturdays.
Dentists say that you should eat sweets max once a week.
not every day
Children in Sweden eat sweets on Saturdays.
Now I will go to work
And you may be moved straight to tomorrow.
They are eating breakfast.
It's Saturday Today.
The kids have eaten breakfast.
Now it's time for Saturday candy.
Hello children!
Look!