Hello Hello
I got an interesting question
After my movie about
to write review
and I will of course text this movie
so turn on the subtitles
so it becomes easier to understand what I say
Well, the question was, can you make a movie about
How to write a story
And it's a fun after all
and difficult question and I have to
first say
I do not write directly stories myself
Sometimes I write small stories
on my blog, but it's any more
fact stories, that I tell
about something real
Not fantasy storytelling
and I believe that
This question was primarily about
fantasy stories, that one finds on
something that is not true
But what is a bit fun is to
My son has worked with stories at school
and he is now thirteen years so he goes in sixth grade
So I asked him
So I think I start with what he said
and then i add a little how i think
because just like the reviews
So I think that if you write a story
or if you want to be better at writing a story
so you have to think a little about
why you write a story
and
I will talk a little more about that, after I raised
my son's tips and
what they have said in school then, as they have trained at
It is that a story must have a good
heading, a good title
It must be interesting or exciting
it must arouse the reader's curiosity
so that the one as
sees the headline becomes interested
of reading more
so a good title, a good heading, it's number one
late
Should you have a good introduction
one can sometimes say appropriations too
or introduction = beginning
You have to start your story
In such a way that the reader directly
becomes curious and interested and wants to read
the rest of the story
So the first paragraph
First page
it needs to have something a little extra
so that you attract, you suck in
the reader in your story
And of course you can do that in many different ways
But it's something you need to think about
When you write, and it's something you can work out on
and it's something you can think about when reading others
persons' texts
how do they start their texts so that
It will be interesting to continue reading
Just that, then
So do you need it
As my son calls
an event or
a problem
So a story must
about something interesting
it has to happen something special
something that is not ordinary
something that is interesting to read about
Something dramatic maybe
Or something horrible
or something exciting, there can be different things
or there must be an interesting problem
in the story, perhaps that
The protagonist is facing
a difficult challenge or
the two most important people in the story
have a conflict that they cannot resolve
so that there is something that makes
The reader thinks: How is this going to go
How is this going to go?
and therefore wants to read on
and the last thing to think about then is that you need
A good ending so that this
that happens at the beginning somehow
gets their ending, one will know
how it went or how it continued
somehow
or this conflict
This problem
the problem, the conflict presented at the beginning
is not the same way at the end
any kind of change
some form of development, it's like
important in a traditional, a classic
An interesting story
Then of course there are many ways to
violate these rule
And, for example, write a very boring
story like
Still is interesting in a different way
But if we are to take the foundation
So should you have an interesting problem
and an interesting change
that something new is happening
right
the last my son said was to
they have trained that, it is important to have
same tempo, the same time
in your story, so you have to choose
Choosing if you tell us in the present
That things
happens in the present in the story, so
For example: Kalle enters the kitchen
There is a cat on the table
the cat jumps down on the floor
So I tell you as if it is happening now or
that I choose to recount
in preteritum so that
Kalle went into the kitchen, on the table sat a cat
the cat jumped down on the floor
and that you don't mix the two
so that when you are going to write a story it is
Very good opportunity to repeat
the presence system and
the preteritum system
There are other teachers who have made good videos about it
so think about it that you like
keeps a consistent time
the same time in your story
Yeah that was all my son said
At breakfast today
and I don't have that much to add really
because all of these points he takes up and that they train on
in school
is what I really think
So: Why do I write a story?
Well, because I want to make my reader
Curious, I want to do
My reader engaged
I want my reader to think it's exciting
I want the reader to think
oops, what happens later
How does this end
and all the tips except the last
Grammatical is about that
to make the story exciting
and that I can add
There is
Yes, one thing, is that in addition to
It should be an interesting problem
Interesting events, special events
So you have to think about the people in your story
The characters
Often it's good
If the characters are special in any way
It's something that stands out
It is something that is not exactly
as usual
it must not be the main character
Sometimes the main character can be completely
ordinary but that it
partly happening unusual things
for an ordinary person and that
An ordinary person has
unusual people around them
I will take an example
I recently read a collection of poems
that was a kind of story
It was narrative poem
The main character was a regular girl
maybe ten years old
What was unusual was that the main character's big brother
was mentally ill and had a schizophrenia
and therefore it became very interesting to follow
How this protagonist felt
in relation to the brother who had one
Especially problems then
The situation and events were interesting
The main character was really an ordinary girl
so that is one then that
you need to have interesting situations
interesting events but also keep in mind that
have interesting characters
and also think about your language
You can make the story
more or less interesting
by using
A little unusual formulations
imagery, comparisons
Metaphors
it can be too much like that
But when you practice writing stories
So I think you should try
play with such things
You can too
Switching to describe things
In the outer world, what is happening
in the room and then you can go in
and tell us what people think and feel and so
so it can also make it more interesting to
read a story
because you also have with inner life
what people feel and think
After all, it is usually people we are interested in
What do people think
What do people know what do people do
Why do they do it, there are such things
We can investigate when we write a story
And do you also have an interesting and exciting language
so can you give more life
to your story
For example, my favorite author Birgitta Lillpers
has a very special language
so she writes a kind of stories in her novels
But much of what is fun with her books
is that the language she uses
To tell us about this is very special
and I came on one last
Interesting thing
As my son actually said and that is to practice writing
Dialogue, your story may become more interesting
about the people in it actually
talk with each other
so there is also something you can practice on
write dialogue, to let people
talk to each other
so yeah i think
that that was what I had to say first
It is possible to discuss this for any length of time, there is
Long courses
One year, two years; three years
At folk high schools and universities
about how to write well so that
This was a start, if you ask and comment
And say what you think so maybe I can do
Another movie if I get new ideas
But then I need a little input, a little
feedback, some ideas from you
So maybe I can give more tips
Hope this helped, hope you who asked
thought the movie gave you some new ideas
And have a good time so we'll see and hear again soon
good luck with the writing
bye