Hello Hello
In this movie.
Should I talk about one thing that I think is important to think about
When learning a new language
and we use a little difficult word when we talk about this
and that word is idiomatic
It is similar to the word idiom
meaning expression
and it is related to each other
When you speak idiomatic
so does that mean you
Uses such words
And such expressions
As a Swedish person
a person with Swedish as a mother tongue
would choose in a particular situation
that you use words and expressions that fit
In a particular situation
and like
Sounds natural
that sounds like a Swede would say
and this is something you get to learn step by step
When learning a new language
for one cannot know
exactly which words fit and which expressions sound natural
When one begins to learn
But I think one should try
strive ..., make an effort, ... try
get closer to an idiomatic language
and as .... a very simple example
can i hear students say to me sometimes
"I have stress"
And to say "I have stress"
It's not really wrong
I would say it's grammatically right
But the problem is that no Swedish person
as I know
says “I have stress”
We say instead "I'm stressed"
So to say "I'm stressed"
is more idiomatic than saying "I have stress"
Another example is that
Many people learn and ask "How are you?"
in order to greet
How are you?
And this might be a little different
Because I know Swedes who greet
for example in the morning
with "How are you?"
But I would never do it
And I always think it feels ... It's a bit strange to greet that way.
To me it doesn't feel so idiomatic
It doesn't feel so natural
to use "how are you?"
as a greeting
Without I may say "how is it?"
or "is it good?"
or how is the situation?
To me they feel the expressions
the ways of greeting
More idiomatic
more natural, they sound more Swedish to me
And here, after all, a problem that ...
There's not a ...
There is not a rule
or rules.
There is not an exact way
to say what is idiomatic
For people will not think exactly the same
about what is suitable for saying and not fitting
But quite a lot of things
would at least many Swedes agree on
that this sounds Swedish
This does not sound Swedish.
For example, I think no one
Think it sounds especially good to say: "I have stress"
Although it is (what is it called) grammatically right to say so
right
and I think that
This is important for many different reasons
To find idiomatic expressions
An important reason is the social
the function.
The social part of the language
That if you express yourself more naturally
on one that is suitable for the situation
With expressions that Swedes would use
so you will more easily be accepted
easier to get closer to people
We work so ...
Psychological we humans
that about someone
seems to be like us
So it is faster to get to know each other, to accept each other
So I think you have a lot to win socially by ...
Start using more idiomatic, more natural expressions
Then I don't think you should be afraid that ....
The most important thing is to communicate
If it gets wrong or sounds a bit strange
It can also be fun and ...
Only you understand is usually okay
But if you want to reach a high level of your Swedish
that's how it is
An advantage, the more idiomatic you speak.
There will also be, in some way, more relaxed
For those who have Swedish as their mother tongue to listen to you.
So at least that's the most important advantage I think
When you talk anyway
that you come so to speak
You will get it easier social
If you use more natural expressions
And how do you learn this then?
I think the most important thing is simply to listen
On when Swedes talk to each other
And of course you can learn a lot of idiomatic Swedish ...
By listening to
TV programs and radio programs
where they talk to each other
in everyday situations
So I would think that for example
a documentary or a docus soap there ...
people more are social with each other
In an informal way
I think you will learn more
Everyday Swedish.
More spoken language.
From such a program
than if you watch a movie
or maybe the news or something
For the most natural speech language
We have that when we just talk to each other.
Of course everything ...
that you listen to and watch will help you.
And then you can of course ask ..
Ask very much
How do you say in such a situation?
How do you express yourself if you want to say this.
How to greet?
How do you say goodbye?
How do you say Merry Christmas?
How to answer?
How to ask?
Ask your teacher.
Ask your Swedish friends.
Ask at Language Café.
You can learn a lot by just asking people ...
About how they talk in different situations.
Maybe it got pretty far this ...
But I think this is an important topic
And I would like to hear your comments.
Or if you have any questions.
This word idiomatic ...
And the idea that it is important to find ...
A natural language
It's something we should talk more about
Within SFI teaching and at all
When we learn a language
So I think this is an important part that we must not forget
And then this word thinks idiomatic
Is so good, because it ....
Exactly describes
What it is we want to access.
We want to find expressions and words ...
that sounds like a mother tongue speaker
It sounds like a native language speaker would say
That's what we mean by idiomatic
So please learn that word
And think about how you can train so that your Swedish becomes more idiomatic
Have a good evening and then we will see you again soon.
Thanks so much.
Bye!