Hey!
This is my workplace today.
I work at home today.
I work on my computer.
My husband is free today.
We plan to go out and have lunch together.
We're going out to lunch at a restaurant.
Come along!
We have arrived.
We're going to a restaurant called Stenladan.
The restaurant is open
Monday - Friday 11.00-18.00
Saturday - Sunday 10.00-17.00
Today's menu
a buffet a salad
buffet
food - a lot of food
You can take as much as you can eat.
We are so hungry!
Have a nice meal!
After the meal we have a cup of coffee.
We ate, it was delicious.
Now we sit and drink coffee.
The coffee is also good.
We can look at the receipt together.
We received a receipt.
The address is also here.
There is a telephone number.
There are dates.
There is time.
It's almost slippery one.
two farm carts.
155 kronor costs a portion.
We paid for two servings.
We paid SEK 310.
Welcome back!
Lever the receipt - the customer's copy.
Now we are full and satisfied.
I am full and satisfied.
We are full and satisfied.
Now I have to go home and keep working.
Thank you so much for watching.
See you in the next video, hello then!