Look what wonderful weather!
It's great weather!
The sun shines. It's warm and nice.
I want to tell you about our walk in Viby village.
Viby town is located in Sigtuna.
Look what we did on the walk.
We drove from Märsta to a village called Viby.
It was overcast. The sun did not shine.
one sheep - many sheep
Sheep breaks.
They broke.
We walked in the village.
We walked there.
We looked at old houses and farms.
This is a fence, an old fence.
It was very windy when we were there.
We walked around and looked everywhere.
We could see how people lived before.
There was a play corner for children where the children could play.
In the village there is a cafe.
We were hungry so we wanted coffee there.
We bought a sandwich, two buns, a chocolate ball,
two coffees and two pear juices.
We paid with Swish.
How much did we pay?
There was hand alcohol.
We disinfected our hands first and then we took coffee.
The girls drank pear juice and ate their buns.
We ate a sandwich and a bun and drank coffee.
After coffee we picked ourselves.
We threw rubbish in the bin and sorted the dishes.
We washed our hands afterwards.
After coffee we went and looked at the goats.
Then we looked at chickens.
This is a rooster.
Over there are chickens.
We also saw some tomato plants.
This is how houses were built before, a long time ago.
Then went to the car and went home.
Have you ever been to Viby village?
Maybe it's time to go there.
Bring the kids and have a great time in Viby village.