Hello everyone!
Today is Friday.
It was my last day of work.
Now I'm free. I'm on holiday.
What have I done today?
I worked first.
I worked in the morning.
I worked in the afternoon.
Then the children came home from kindergarten.
It was their last day in kindergarten.
It was warm.
We grilled sausages.
We ate sausages with bread.
a sprinkler
Kids love to play with the sprinkler.
They played and laughed.
They had fun.
I've baked a cake.
a strawberry cake.
It stands in the fridge.
Why did I bake a cake?
My daughter Arina turns one tomorrow.
She is 6 years old.
Tomorrow we will eat cake for breakfast.
Do you want to see?
We have to pump!
We'll be cycling, the whole family.
We will cycle to Sigtuna.
They fish.
Look, they're sitting and fishing.
Now we cycle home again!
Thank you so much for looking at the short vlog.
See you in the next video! Bye!