Hello Hello
Anyone who trains Swedish
I usually forget to say what my name is
So my name is Kalle
And are SFI teachers
And today I have a little tip
It is that
Listen very carefully
on how we pronounce the words in Swedish
for if you only read
or if you read
But don't listen carefully
on how we pronounce the words
so it becomes harder to understand
When a Swedish person
speaking Swedish
Quickly
and
an important thing to
listen to
that's all we don't say
anything we take away
that disappears
or as we reduce
when we speak
So I'll give some examples
If I speak slowly
and just as one writes
So I say
I have one child
I have one child.
okay
But if I talk quickly
I say
I have a child [Jaaettbarn]
Yes. About so. I have one child.
I have one child.
so you hear yourself
one more time
I have one child
or
I have one child.
Yes you understand
It does not sound exactly the same
And I say or I don't pronounce all the letters.
available
on the paper if you read
We could take another example
At least like this
This is how I talk. This is how I say.
If I read.
So it says: I don't know
I do not know
But if I talk quickly
for example with a mate
So I say
I don't know [yes ve'nä]
listen again
I do not know
I don't know [yes ve'nä]
There is
Many many examples
on how we don't pronounce
All the letters you read
on the paper
and therefore it is very important to
Exercise you
on that
Listen to how Swedes really talk
It will be much easier to understand then.
What we say
and a simple way is if you have a book
With sound on the internet
or a book with a CD to
so listen carefully to the text
at the same time
As you read
and think carefully about
How we pronounce the words for real
so you don't think we pronounce the words
As they stand in the book
Without listening how it sounds
What letters do we pronounce
and which letters disappear
when we talk
You can also do it if you look
For example, on my videos
When I have both talk and text
So look at how we write the sentence
and then listen how I say it
If you work out a bit on it every day
so it will be much easier to understand
When Swedes talk quickly
Okay. That was my tip for today.
Hope you benefit from it.
Keep training Swedish
And then we will see you again soon.
Thanks so much. Bye!