Hello Hello
I got a question about
I could make a movie about how to write
a review
and i'm pretty sure of
that there are movies from
For example, SFI teachers and
Swedish as a second language teacher who is about how to write
a review
So I want to try to answer the question
In a slightly different way maybe
Because I think it's always an important issue to ask
Why do we write reviews
What is the meaning of a review
Who reads it and why does someone read
a review
Then I think a little about myself that
I am reading reviews sometimes, not a huge
in newspapers and online and so
And then I read reviews
because I want to discover new writers
or i want to find new books
or i might want to know
How a new book is, if I have read
books by a writer and so have that writer
released a new book, published a new book
Then I want to know if that book is good
what it is about, about it is the same
as previous books or about
The author has written in a new way and such
So you might say that is the summary of that is the summary
of why do you write reviews, JO
because a reader
Reads the reviews because that person
Am curious