Hello Hello
Here's a little tip
As I think I have given before
But repetition is everything's mother (wrong: repetition is all the mother of knowledge :- D)
As one usually says
Repetition is the key to learning
So I take the risk of repeating myself
and I think about this with talking
and get the chance to work out
to talk in everyday life
so
I think of such situations
When you meet a person
At school, perhaps at work
Maybe on
The Language Café
Where you now get a chance to meet people who speak Swedish
and so we ask things like
Hello, how is the situation
How's the school going?
How's the new job going?
What happens nowadays?
Is it good with you?
such things
and then it is very tempting
to answer briefly
You just like to: Yes, it's good / Yes, it's going well
nothing special
But then you actually miss a chance to
talk a little more and get a little conversation
and very often when
When I meet maybe my work mates
Although we see you every day
or
can be friends i meet frequently
It doesn't matter if someone asks
How about you or
how was your weekend?
such things
then it often becomes a small story
from me or the other person to
If you say, yes it goes well
I have had a great weekend
We were home and spent time with family
blah blah blah blah blakaa or
If I ask someone: How's the new job going
Then they tell you a little about that job
what new colleagues they have
What they do. If there is any difference from the old.
Maybe something that is a bit difficult or hard
or something funny that has happened
This is simply the tip.
That such simple questions as "How is the situation?"
How's it going with ...?
It is an invitation to tell a little more
So take that chance if you notice that
The person is relaxed and not just say ....
Hello and then want to run on
But if it is a slightly calmer situation
so try to be prepared to tell you something
So for example
If you recently have
started a new job
or received an internship
And someone asks
how is it going or how is it or so
so have some sentences finished
such as the Dukkan use and tell us about
about the practice or job
and so on
So, I think it's
It can help you build up some such everyday phrases
that then can do that when you can
can you take some more steps
and tell me a little more and find new sentences
But that everyday spray is very important
This is how we get to know each other
When someone tells something
and so maybe the person reacts to it or
will think about
job they have had before
or will think of a person they feel
it may be so little that makes
As we say in Swedish
The ball comes in rolling
thus that something begins and continues
It won't just stop
so
bun on a little story about your day
about your new job, about how it is going to school
and the chance is great
that you will get some more fun and longer calls
in Swedish
ehm, yes, it was
Please write and
Tell us what you think about this
What calls do you have in everyday life?
When do you get the chance to talk a little
About different things in Swedish
or in Swedish anyway
Write and tell us and so we'll see you again soon