You have written a text that we will look at.
I can say that not much was good in that text.
There were so many grammatical errors
and so many word choice errors!
I wonder how you got to SVA ground really?
How can you study there?
Look here! Now I'll show you one thing.
Look at this sentence.
This is a main statement.
What is your word order in it?
You start with time.
What must come after time in Swedish?
You have to write a verb here.
If time is the foundation of the sentence then there must be a verb.
This is not acceptable at SVA basic level!
Look at your whole text, look at the structure.
There are almost no pieces!
The sentences are not whole.
There is a lack of both subject and verb in several sentences.
It's actually hard to understand what you want to say!
You are not kind! You are mean!
I'm just trying to help you!
You have to be able to withstand a little criticism!
How can you get better if you can not hear what you are doing wrong?
Have you not heard of two stars and a wish?
What did you say to something?
Two stars and a wish.
What is it?
You tell two positive things and one thing you can get better at.
But you're just saying I'm wrong!
Now let's talk about that chronicle you wrote.
I was going to start by summarizing the content just to see if you think I have understood it correctly.
As I interpret it, you wrote about when you discovered that so many Swedes love nature.
That it is almost like a religion for some Swedes.
Is it true?
I thought - what a great topic!
I really like it and I agree with you, I have also thought that it is so.
You can see that there are so many Swedes who are out and about in nature all the time.
You really recognize yourself in what you write.
You start so well, it gets exciting from the beginning.
When you are out there in the woods and you describe these people so heavenly alive and well.
That's really good.
And then comes the message.
Nature can also be religion, almost.
Something that gives a person a lot.
It's really connected: the story itself, your example and the message.
There is a clear common thread.
You could say that.
I remember our teachers talking about being personal but not private.
This feels like such a topic.
It's not like you're wondering - What had she done herself? and what guilt does she have in this?
It is more like an observation but described in a personal way.
So it was great I think!
We would have a painting language as well.
I found some places where I thought you might have described ...
When you are out in the woods, it may be easy to describe nature.
I find it difficult to describe, with a pictorial language.
Do you have any ideas?
Yes, for example, here you just write that you were out in the woods.
But you can try to come up with a good adjective that fits the forest.
For example, if it might have rained before
Then you can say that the forest was dewy.
It is a difficult word, I have heard some Swedes say that word.
You can come up with your own adjectives such as - the newly bathed forest.
A forest can not swim but you can always test if it works.
We can test it on our teachers if they think it's ok.
Sounds like a good idea, thank you very much!
In a few more places you can post it.
Or you can take a side note.
"The forest it had just rained in"
Although it may not sound so nice.
I understand what you mean.
The forest with the dense leaves and the green vegetation.
It will be a prepositional phrase, I think the teachers have said it is.
That's really good! and then there are some grammatical errors that I can also help you with.
We can take it later, we go and drink some coffee first.
Thank you for your response! You are welcome!