Hello again
I was going to record a new video
And I will remember to say that I am texting these videos
I write subtitles
So if you put on subtitles in
the movie on your mobile or computer
so can you see quite exactly what I say
So it is good if you find it difficult to understand just by listening
So check it out, how to put on the subtitles, so you get more out of this video
And last time I gave some ideas or discussed a little
how to practice writing
in a systematic way
gradually
with a small plane
And today I was going to continue a bit on the same theme
but talk maybe more about telling things
And then I think orally orally
But really so
fits this way of thinking both
When you write and when you tell
But my main point, the most important
What I want to come up with is that I think you will gain very much from ....
study and train with a plan
to always have a small plan
And then I don't mean any big one-year plan but more how you train day by day
And then I just think about
So, all the chances you have to train something
by telling something
and it may be in class if you go to school
or it can be with friends you train with
Swedish friends or other friends who also learn Swedish
or it might be a language friend or a language café, it doesn't matter
I think about this when I work in school with my students
But this way works in many different situations
And what I think is to
when something happens
small in your life
It might be that you greet someone
that you go to a party
that you go to language café, that you go to the dentist
that you buy clothes
It really doesn't matter
All these small situations, things that happen in your life.
You can use this to train Swedish
By telling us about that
So for example if you
went to a concert and listened to music
or you went to a theater or movie
and looked at something
So maybe you can tell it to your classmates at school
the next day
Maybe you can ask your teacher
Is it okay if I take five minutes and tell you about this movie I saw for example
Or take one of your friends and say that now I want to try to tell something in Swedish
Can you listen a little to me then I will try to tell
what happened yesterday, or last week
or something you should do in the future
It doesn't matter, it can be both past and future
But the important then, this I mean by having a plan
It is that if you are going to tell us something, for example for the class
as you have done or something that has happened
so prepare a little
Don't just think yes yes, I'll tell you something uhh
and then when you stand there and tell you you notice
that there are many words
As you cannot in Swedish
thus important words that you need
for the others to understand you
This is where you can become more efficient and learn faster
if you
for example in the evening when you get home and you have done something
Sit down for a while with lexicon
And look up five or ten more important words that
you need to tell us about this thing
and maybe think of some sentences
I do not mean that you should write a whole text
But when you think about this situation
So will you find words that you can in your mother tongue
that you would use if you told a friend in your mother tongue
But as you have not learned on the Swedish end
And now is a fantastic opportunity
to teach you those words and try to use those words
and that said, it can be about telling you something in two, or three or five minutes
The important thing is that you
actively trying to find words you need
To tell you something that has happened to you in person in your life
Why is it so important to tell things? Yes...
I've been thinking a lot about this ...
lately and we work pretty much with this in my class
... that stories are an important way to get to know each other
Both to show themselves and as well as presenting who you are
and also just get social contact
We do very much by telling little things about our lives, about what has happened to us ...
It can ... and also just ....
In everyday life to tell you that you had problems with the car or that you bought a nice shower yesterday
And you got it cheap ...
or that the train was delayed
all this we do
To get in touch with each other and get closer to each other and ...
Then you can step by step
train yourself to get better at doing it
in Swedish
And it is not just to learn new words or use better grammar
It is important and you also practice that but ...
The most important goal of that is to get a chance to talk
with people in Swedish in a more relaxed manner
Get more contact and better contact and would I say in the end
become more yourself in Swedish
When you are new or not great in a language, then you are not really yourself
So I can feel for myself, so I can feel anyway
And to practice telling, it's a way to
be able to step by step
be more yourself in your new language
In this case Swedish
And if you are a beginner then you can't start with difficult things
This is where the plan comes in
Tomorrow you can tell me that you listened to this video for example
And the day after tomorrow you can tell me that you woke up a little late in the morning and be really tired
And after the weekend you might be able to tell us how you called a friend
and tell me something about what you were talking about
Think about it! There is an incredible force
in telling simple things, to develop their language
But you have to look for the situations and opportunities
and you have to look for the words and expressions
that allows you to tell
So that's my tip
Prepare a little! It doesn't take long.
And then find an opportunity to
Exercise on what you've prepared
And you will learn something
every time you do it
Those steps together can take you long way
With your Swedish language
so take that chance
Tell us something in Swedish!
Every day, you will learn a lot
I am pretty sure
That's what I had and say
Thank you so much for listening and ...
Please check the links in the description
There is a link to my blog among other things
and there you can read
About more tips on how to work out
and just practice words and lyrics too
And as I said, don't forgot to put the texts on the video
so it becomes easier to understand what I say
Have a great time. See you again soon. Bye!