Hello everyone! Hello!
Today we are going to a grocery store.
We will look at the Christmas theme in the grocery store.
Come along!
a red flower
a poinsettia
There are many flowers.
There are red flowers and white flowers.
lots of clementines
lots of gingerbread
There are different gingerbread figures.
It's gingerbread house.
Gingerbread costs SEK 24.90.
a heart
Look how nice!
a nice heart
Merry Christmas!
cheese
soft cheese
Lots of soft cheese with different flavors.
There are many different flavors.
I like to eat gingerbread with blue cheese.
buns with saffron
saffron buns
louse cats gingerbread
balls gingerbread
house
You can build yourself at home.
You can decorate.
There are also Christmas eggs.
Christmas crispbread (crispbread)
Christmas wort (Christmas bread)
You can order the packaging.
Saffron cake with real saffron.
boiled Christmas ham
herring
There is a lot of herring you buy for Christmas.
Herring in various marinades, such as mustard.
There are many cans.
different flavors, crayfish marinated
mustard herring ,
Santa Claus - Christmas sausage
file - gingerbread
gingerbread
file file with taste of gingerbread
And it's a lot of mulled wine.
mulled wine without sugar, with chocolate and chili
cloudberries
different flavors
mulled wine mix
Here it is cranberries and almonds, you can also have raisins.
Christmas must of course!
In Sweden, people drink a lot of Christmas must.
poinsettias - christmas chips
christmas napkins
candlestick
lots of sweets, lots of chocolate
gift wrap
christmas cards
chocolate
elves christmas foam
It's sweets for christmas.
My kids love it!
Thank you so much for watching this video.
See you soon! Bye!