Good morning everyone!
It's Saturday Today.
I'm free, I'm not working.
We are all free.
What are we going to do today?
I'll wash clothes.
I'm going to go with my son to tennis.
He plays tennis on Saturdays.
We will meet our friends today, our friends.
They come to us and we will grill.
We will grill out in the yard.
It's nice weather today, look.
It is beautiful weather, the sun is shining.
The sun is shining but it's not hot.
It's cold.
That's about 0 degrees.
But it's nice weather outside.
I woke up at 7 o'clock today.
I woke up at 7am but my children woke up earlier.
They woke up at 6 in the morning.
They usually wake up at 6 every day.
Join us and you will see our whole day!
First I will braid my children's hair.
released hair - braids
a braid - two braids
We eat breakfast - oatmeal with nuts and apple.
We drink coffee.
I drink a cup of coffee.
I'm washing clothes.
dirty clothes
clean clothes
But wet clothes
The clothes are wet
They have to dry.
I drive a car.
I drive my son to tennis.
They are playing tennis.
My son plays tennis.
Me and the girls, we wait outside.
There is a playground for children.
She swings.
Do you also want to swing?
You both swing.
There is no snow, but look here!
a ski slope in Sigtuna
There are some children skiing, what fun!
They're playing soccer.
They are skiing.
He bikes.
There is an outdoor gym.
You can work out here.
There they come, our guests.
Hello girls!
We roll and talk to each other.
That's very nice!
Bye!
Now it's evening.
Our friends arrived at 4 pm (four o'clock).
We grilled.
We talked to each other.
It was very nice.
They went home at 7 pm (7 pm).
I cleaned the floor.
Now it's ten o'clock in the evening (at 22.00).
The children sleep.
And I sit and make the video on my computer.
Thanks so much for looking!
See you in the next movie!
Bye!