Hello Hello
Here comes some more about the subject
verbal interaction
to get better at talking, on talking
to converse
In a new language, such as Swedish
and how to train on it
and what is good to think about
and
this may really be the most
Basic of what I talked about so far
and it is simply that
yourself contribute to
the conversation, that
say things that the other can
answer, to give things
To contribute things
to throw things into the conversation
to open the call
with interesting things as it is possible for the other to
give response to, to react to
to reflect
but also to spin on
As I talked (about) in the last video
Because if you just say
the most mundane phrases
If you just ask "How are you?" and "How's the situation?" and
"How's your family?"
"It's cold today", such things
It is not possible to continue a call very long
If it's the only thing you
gives, if that is the only thing you say
Without I have thought about it that
So, I try to think about, when I talk to
Friends and colleagues and so on, how do we do?
and very often a small conversation begins with that
someone, myself or someone else,
Make a very common statement of claims
"I saw....
on TV yesterday ”
"There is a new series on Netflix"
"I met it and that person yesterday"
“We trained on
verbs in the classroom today ”
And then my colleague replies: "Well what is the series?"
or my buddy: "Oh, grammar is hard"
Or: “Yeah, did you meet him ....
I know him too. He ........ ”
and a lot of these things
As I talked a bit about, to ask
"what have you done this weekend?" and then answer that
That's how you get to know people, I think anyway
I do not know if
I talk a little about having read a book
Someone asks: "What have you done this weekend?" - Yes, I bought a new book
It seems good. Yes then I may notice that.
one of my colleagues, she also likes to read
So then we start talking books with each other
and then there will be a longer call
and someone else is interested in music
and a third is interested in talking about the job and so on
It is based on you throw in something
you give a small hook that the other can
spin on / build on
yeah so to, think a little bit about it
were you around you
in your life? What are you doing?
What are you interested in? What do you think about?
What are you planning in the future?
As you can mention
in a call or when you meet someone
it doesn't have to be much to
it will be more anyway
you need to start somewhere and the first step is to say
something more than just these usual greeting
the phrases
for they do not lead so far
and
There are those who are not so good
In a language that does this anyway
It's not about what level of language you are
Just ... really ...
Without you can do this with quite a bit of language
you can do it with almost no language at all
by
Pick up your mobile and show a picture
There is something to start talking about
so find ways to
show yourself, to bid on yourself
to tell something small
about yourself as the other can answer
In order to build more calls
and I know it's scary in the beginning, I know it's
hard. It's easy for me to say that
But it can be difficult to do it in a new language.
But I think it's a way forward
and I think you can train on it by thinking about
what you can and want to tell
Yes, so think about it
And as usual
Comment, discuss
This is how we are moving forward by communicating with each other
and I need your
your reflections, your response to
Get ideas for new videos and think further
So I am very happy and grateful for all the comments I get
I try to answer everything
I might miss sometimes and sometimes I just like
I promise, I read all the comments so that
Yeah don't be afraid
Write and comment
and so we will see you so soon again I hope
Have a good one; bye