Several Russian oil depots have been knocked out by Ukrainian drones.
In Bachmut, Ukraine accuses Russia of using phosphorus bombs.
And 35,000 Ukrainian soldiers are ready to attack.
When will the counter -offensive come?
The war this week - about the latest news development in the Ukraine war.
Russia has carried out a series of attacks against civilian goals around Ukraine.
In Odessa, in Chenerson, in Charkiv and here in the capital Kiev-
- If several houses have been razed and civilians injured after drone attacks.
Oscar Jonsson, you are a doctor in Russian warfare.
Why does Russia go on these civilian goals?
Russia has since October had a strategy to bomb civil targets -
–And civil critical infrastructure. It fulfills several purposes.
One is to make life miserable, one is to terrorize them so that they can give up.
It also sets a military dilemma.
Ukraine can either protect the most important big cities -
- Or the front line, which will be extra important for the counter -offensive.
We have heard that Kiev has good air defense - yet the drones manage to get through.
How to explain it?
An air defense is never 100 percent, but consists of different systems-
- From short-range to medium and very long-range.
The Russian robotic attacks are often a mix.
First it can be exercise robots without explosive charge -
- Or drones, to saturate the air defense systems.
Then you strike with cruise robots with the explosive effect.
An air defense is never 100 percent. And the drones that cost 200,000-
- Don't want to knock out with air defense robots for two million.
Even Ukraine has performed a number of drone attacks -
- Especially against oil depots, including here at Russian -cooked crime-
- But here too, here and here.
Why is Ukraine on oil depots in this area?
These are those closest to the shooting range.
Oil depots are important goals. The armed forces depend on fuel-
- In particular, when the counter -offensive starts -
–And Ukraine quickly trying to break through some of the Russian lines -
- And Russia must move its associations to meet the counter -offensive.
If you have a lack of fuel, their ability to respond.
We have also heard about sabotage against the railway -
-Here in the Brjansk region north of Ukraine.
How important is the railway for the Russian military?
The railway is very important, a supporting part of all Russian military logistics.
Assessments before the war from the total defense research institute SA -
- That Russia can carry out offensive operations the railway plus 30 miles.
This is about where the invasion ended after the first few weeks.
Then you had logistical problems.
We move on to Bachmut, where fierce battles have been going on for about nine months.
How is the situation there right now?
It is extremely tense. Russia continues to take a few blocks a day.
They have control over about 80 % of the city.
They try to get a pinch maneuver here-
–When you cut off the Ukrainian livelihood to the city -
- And force the Ukrainian forces to retreat before being completely surrounded.
- For these roads are vital? -Exactly.
And there Ukraine this morning conducted a counter -offensive against this road -
- Where you try to interfere with Russia's plan to cut off Bachmut.
- How important is the advance? - It's important.
If you can disturb the pound maneuver, one can maintain the livelihood of the city -
- What makes the defense of the city much stronger.
In focus this week is phosphorus bombs.
Russia is accused of using such in Bachmut.
These pictures are said to show just that, according to Ukraine.
We pause there. How can we be sure that this is a phosphorus?
It's hard to know in this event -
- But there is some form of fire combat, termite, e.g.
It is extremely warm fragments. It gives the fireworks -like effects.
They have the ability to burn through even buildings-
–And causes very severe burns to humans.
It is war crime to use such indiscriminately.
Why does Russia use this type of bombs?
It's a way to beat over a fairly large territory -
- When the Ukrainian defenders are in the city of Bachmut where they are fortified.
You do not know exactly where they are.
But you can use such to knock out people in buildings.
Over 1,500 armored vehicles and 230 tanks
has been delivered to Ukraine's counter -offensive.
According to the Financial Times, 35,000 Ukrainian soldiers are ready to attack.
If we take the Russian -cooked area - what could a counter -offensive look like?
The most important thing about a counter -offensive is that it also generates a political victory -
- As the Russian leadership in Moscow affects.
What could really do it is an attack in this part -
– There Ukraine would attack towards Melitopol -
–To cut off the railway connection in particular down towards the Crimea -
- As you depend on for logistics.
Russia, then, what does their line of defense look like?
Since October, Russia has actually dug several layers in stock -
–A of minefields, shooting boars and tanks -
- To make the Ukrainian offensive more difficult.
You may not stop it, but you buy time -
- For Russian reinforcements that may come where Ukraine breaks through.
Here it is also important to remember that the Ukrainian counter -offensive -
- Can be several counter -offensives who see where you break through.
If you break through in one direction you can continue there towards different goals.
But most important is to break the supply that goes all the way to Crimea.
- The railway then? -Yes exactly.
When does the counter -offensive come, then?
To some extent, it has almost already begun.
Ukraine has started some minor attacks.
Then maybe you can see that it really starts when the tanks come.
But in principle, the Ukrainian forces are ready.
The last clay will disappear within one to two weeks-
- And the conditions then be the best for this.
Thanks, Oscar Jonsson. We're back next week.
Texting: SVT Language & Accessibility © Swedish Television AB 2023