American tanks with controversial ammunition will soon be in place.
From the Russian side, this is raised as if it were nuclear weapons, which is completely wrong.
At the same time, Ukraine continues to make progress along the front.
Here are presents, Russian damages!
North Korea's Kim Jong-Un is soon expected to make a rare foreign visit to Russia.
And what does Putin hope to get out of that meeting?
The war this week deepens the latest news development in the Ukraine war.
Ukraine continues its advance at the Robotyne resort along the southern front.
Russian leaders in the region have confirmed that one has withdrawn -
- Of what you describe as tactical reasons.
From robotyne, one spreads in both eastern and western direction, towards Verbove -
- Which is located nearby to move on to the next Russian line of defense.
This is an important step, maybe a breakthrough.
The goal is set to inta or isolate the strategically important city of Tokmak -
- Cirka ten kilometers south of Robotyne.
In these battles, it now seems that the Ukrainians have takeover with artillery -
- That you shot a lot of the Russian.
It is one of the most important factors in this battle.
Heavy drone attacks have been directed at Ukrainian port cities -
- Several nights in a row, during the week.
Russia, since they withdrew from the grain agreement a month ago -
–Have invested a lot in trying to knock out the Ukrainian economy -
–And Cereal exports, which is a large source of income for Ukraine.
The attacks against the cities of Izmail and Reni attracted considerable attention -
- As the cities are located right on the border with Natoland Romania.
And the countries had different views on what really happened.
The drone attacks performed by the Russian Federation -
- No direct threat to our national territory.
For us, it is clearly what happened. We have evidence.
The Romanian government is allowed to draw the conclusions.
That one chooses to hit goals that is so incredibly close to Natoland Romania -
–Is that from the Russian side is prepared to a large risk -taking -
–But also expecting the weapons to have enough precision -
- To not end up wrong, but it is high risk.
Ukraine's Ministry of Defense has been plagued by several corruption scandals.
I.a. Should you have paid SEK 210 million for winter jackets that cannot withstand cold.
You have also bought food for the army for three times as high as normal.
That there is corruption in Ukraine, it is well known, but it is also well known -
- That you have an extensive endeavor to fight this corruption.
This week, one of the country's richest businessmen for money laundering - was charged
- And several high -ranking officials have been allowed to resign after corruption charges.
Most recently the country's defense minister Oleksij Reznikov.
Although Reznikov personally has not been accused of something -
- So Ukraine's Ministry of Defense has been affected by several corruption scandals.
Oleksij Reznikov has lived through more than 550 days of full -scale war.
I think the ministry needs new approaches -
- And other forms of interaction with both the military and society at large.
The problem is when corruption becomes structural.
That it becomes high level safety - that the state is corrupt.
And that is what you do not want, because it is a legacy from the Soviet Union -
- And not least characterizes Russia.
President Zelenskyj has had as stated the goal of stopping corruption in the country -
- Something he went to election in 2019.
During the war, billions of investments from allied western countries have
- Pumped into Ukraine.
It is about everything from weapons and investment support to pure charity.
Given the corruption challenges, the question is whether the Western countries should be worried.
In the Russian information war, one tries to target areas -
- Where you know you can hear in the West, that is:
"Your money is leaking. Your weapons will return to organized crime."
There are no such clear tracks, but Russia would like to get that message out.
On the part of the West, Ukraine should of course be best supported and in that support -
- In the fight against corruption.
It includes control and audit -
- That can be implemented together with the Ukrainian authorities.
They are also keen on this. Former Defense Minister Reznikov-
- Have talked about having to be open with how this works.
I don't think we should be worried, but we should be vigilant -
–And we will help Ukraine collectively to overcome corruption.
In mid-September, the first Abrams tanks are expected from the USA-
- Delivered to Ukraine. It states sources for Politico, who say -
- The first delivery of ten tanks is currently in Germany.
Something that has attracted attention is that the tanks may be delivered -
- Together with ammunition containing depleted uranium.
To the modern tanks, and also to the Challenger wagons like Ukraine-
—Thely has received from the UK, something called arrow projectile -
- Of depleted uranium.
When using uranium, you take some of the uranium and enrich it for nuclear power plants.
That which is the residual product, with low radiation-
- Is just a very heavy and dense metal and with it you make alloys -
- To the arrow projectile, as the United Kingdom, which the United States has - as Russia has.
That which can form a danger with radioactivity -
- It is precisely at the impact, that gases and small splits are formed.
They are dangerous, especially for the crew of the vehicle hit -
- But they probably have other problems to think about when they are met.
North Korea's leader Kim Jong-Un is expected to visit Russia and Vladimir Putin-
- In September, there are sources for the US defense ministry.
Russia has very few friends left and North Korea is one of the countries -
— Which is under major sanctions and does not have much to lose on -
- To help Russia. I guess Russia mainly wants artillery ammunition -
-Rocket Artillery amnition. Maybe robots, but it's not quite as likely.
But quantity goods of what you consume all the time.
What North Korea wants can be nuclear technology and robotics, but not least food.
North Korea always needs food, because there is almost always starvation in North Korea.
Kim Jong-Un rarely leaves North Korea, and according to the sources-
- If the meeting is likely to be kept close to the boundary between the two countries.
But it is clear that this would be a continued Russian preparation -
–For a long -lasting war, to ensure
- In addition to your own production, you also have the opportunity to import.
It may not get any immediate effect -
- But Russia wants to ensure that you can hold on for a long time.