The biggest attack against Kiev since the start of the war-
- And the Wagner Group leaves the broken Bachmut.
Swarms of Iranian Kamikaze drones attack Ukraine's cities.
What do they fulfill for military function? This is the "war of the week" -
- As the latest news development deepens in the Ukraine war.
Kiev has been attacked by a record number of robots and drones.
Several people must have died in the attacks, which began at the celebration of Kievdagen - -
- The anniversary of the city's founding over fifteen hundred years ago.
That you see these attacks during the day, when you simultaneously see school children out -
–And people try to live the everyday life that exists in Kiev-
–As clearly connected with Russian attempts to spread horror -
- Among residents in Ukraine's capital and Russia's psychological warfare.
These images from a car camera show how a downed robot -
- Hits a road in Kyiv.
But the constant air attacks have not produced the desired result for Russia -
–Noly the British Department of Defense, which writes -
- That the goal was probably to knock out the Ukrainian air defense.
A hospital in the city of Dnipro has been completely destroyed in a Russian robot attack.
At least two people must have been killed and more than 30 injured -
- In what Ukraine describes as a war crime.
Dnipro is one of the larger cities in eastern Ukraine-
- And its geographical location also shows its importance.
Therefore, Dnipro has also become a kind of logistical hub.
Both militarily, for Ukraine's military, but also for civilian organizations -
- As aid organizations or media.
Many are based on Dnipro in their work on eastern Ukraine.
Fortezza Bachmut!
Pictures from Russian news agency Tass provide a rare insight from inside Bachmut.
In this picture with the gate, you see how it stands -
–Ad bachmut ... that the city is open, or "opens for the good" -
- But it is not directly what you see to take place in the pictures.
Of course, it is striking how total destruction is -
- And how empty the city has become.
This silence and calm is due to the fact that the battles have reduced drastically -
- Cut central Bachmut, but also because people have moved.
The battles in the city must have calmed down since Ukraine lost control.
Something that is now confirmed by several Western analysts.
But Ukraine, of course, has a continued presence in the area around the city -
- And from Ukrainian perspective, one expresses the hope of regaining the area.
Today we were hit by one of the biggest Russian attacks -
-With 54 shahed drones at the same time.
This is what they look like, the Iranian Shahed drones-
which attacks Kiev and other cities around Ukraine.
The Kamikaze drone is called at Swedish patrol robot-
- And militarily fulfills a function in the middle of a drone and a robot.
What mainly defines them is that a drone normally shoots a projectile -
- While a patrol robot is the projectile itself with a battle tip.
The main advantages of such patrol robots are first ...
One: they have the ability to fly around - for an extended period of time -
- And look for a suitable target.
Two: They are relatively inexpensive and easy to produce.
Three: They are relatively small and therefore more difficult for air defense to detect.
The drones have become a well -known detail during the Ukraine War -
- And made the light directed against Russia and Iran's relationship.
Western countries point to in -depth military cooperation between Russia and Iran-
- Not at least around these patrol robots.
This is nothing that Iran disputes in substance, but on the other hand describes man - -
–Wester reactions as hysterical or as an attempt -
- Keeping Iranian products away from the Russian market.
Stop for Iranian drones!
After the last attacks, Ukraine has now introduced -
–50 year long sanctions against Iran, including Total Trade Ban with the Land-
- And a travel ban for Iranians through Ukraine.
Ukraine says this will have consequences and western countries -
- Have tried to push Iran not to send these patrol robots to Russia.
In fact, experts - admit the experts -
- It is very difficult to do something about this, for example with sanctions.
One of the main causes is that there is an open transport route -
- Between Russia and Iran across the Caspian Sea.
Russia's capital Moscow has been attacked with several drones -
- Computer Russian authorities.
Two buildings must have been met, but no one should have been seriously injured.
These continuous attacks, such as Russia and Russian media-
–Not can ignore, becomes a kind of reminder of the war -
- And that the war is closer than you want to believe or claim from Russian.
In addition, it fulfills some practical functions.
Not that the attacks themselves did any major material damage.
However, it can force Russia to redistribute its forces -
- To e.g. secure their boundaries-
- Or increase the defense against drones or robotic attacks against Russian cities.
New drone attacks against a Russian oil -refinery and border town of Belgorod -
- Has got Russia to once again accuse Ukraine for shootings.
More recently, we have seen more and more attacks even in Russian territory.
Normally, Ukraine has tried to keep this a bit at arm's length -
- And deny a direct involvement in the attacks.
But here most recently we saw how to from Ukrainian perspective -
- Warned that Russian attacks on Ukraine would have consequences.
The Wagner Group has announced that it has begun to hand over positions in Bachmut-
- To Russian regular forces.
But exactly how and when to happen is still unclear.
According to Prigozjin, you need to "regroup" before a long war.
What role will the Wagner Group get in the future?
As long as the Wagner Group is a useful tool for Russia -
–And Russia has a need for military capacity and forces that can fight -
- So the Wagnergruppen will continue to play a role.
About the Wagner Group, or Yevgenij Prigozjin thereby -
- In one way or another, be seen as a load -
–On if there are other forces one would rather use -
- So the role of the Wagner Group will also be fond of.
Texting: SVT Language & Accessibility © Swedish Television AB 2023