The gang criminals have started running family homes and HVB homes.
It is absolutely true and it all started with and in Strängnäs.
This is the 35-year-old who is suspected to have acted as a kind of manager
to the Foxtrot network.
In an eavesdropped call, Rawa Majid refers to him as "Strängnäs".
No one touches Strängnäs. Strängnäs is my area.
Strängnäs is thus both a city and a person. It paves the way for confusion.
"Are you going on a weekend to Strängnäs? Are you sick in your head?"
"Well, to the gangster! Health."
The person Strängnäs is gang criminal with connections to the Foxtrot network
But shootings are not his thing.
This is a real monster. He works with invoices.
He has invoiced Swedish municipalities millions
by running family homes. We have looked at two companies in the industry
As he has been involved in: Svea Placing and Second Chance.
The family home is thus called "Second Chance".
Tashed to name a family home after something we associate with mello losers.
You want the children to get a good start in life.
You should have named it "Congratulations! Direct to Final Family Home AB".
It would have been a more reasonable name.
But besides the second chance, Strängnäs, the person, did not the city
Also the company Svea Placement Journal
Who works to find homes for vulnerable children.
It feels like that. Gang criminals will decide where the children end up.
Why has the gang entered the family home industry.
Are they philanthropists? No, they do it for the same reason as this man.
Ex-politician and Robinson winner is one of several players
which has entered the lucrative industry.
His company makes a gross earnings of SEK 30,000 per month and children.
Still pretty juicy with money. 30,000 per child per month.
If Jan Emanuel has placed ten children he has casted in 3.5 million
In just one year. Strängnäs, the person, has realized that this is a cash register.
They say that the gang criminals lack male role models
But then a inflated welfare millionaire steps forward
And breastfeeding that role.
But joking aside. It is damn good.
These are children who need help, sometimes protection from the gang environment.
Whose wrong is it that it has become so?
I think the municipalities have a huge responsibility.
They have undertaken to place these children.
You choose to do so with private players.
The municipalities again. They have the responsibility, as usual, and cannot take responsibility.
They always do away with themselves, the municipalities.
But even to be municipalities, this is exceptionally handled.
How can they let gang criminals run family home business? Yes, like this:
Just when Jan Emanuel began his orphanage career, they did it in 2015
during the refugee crisis. The municipalities were flooded by children in need.
The municipalities did not keep up and Strängnäs, not the city
and not Ikea's affordable heating light holder
Without the person Strängnäs. The person took advantage of this.
As a specialist at the Swedish Crime Authority says:
"The checks were deficient. It was difficult to follow up on the efforts."
Perhaps the municipalities were tricked because Strängnäs had a well -plastered facade.
A few years ago they showed high ambitions
when they did a real star recruitment.
They hired the recognized skilled socio -economist Johanna Möller.
Yes, the Johanna Möller, the Arboga woman - she who is so child in love.
So Strängnäs on the board and the Arboga woman as manager:
Could it get worse?
Now the gang is starting to get into the healthcare system and start health centers
Warns the Swedish Crime Authority.
We look at it seriously. When health centers are conducted by criminals
So we do not get the quality that we need to have in these businesses.
Exactly, that's where the shortage lies. Gang criminal neglect with quality.
That is the problem.
Regardless of quality, you dare not press what you think on the Smiley buttons.
"How satisfied were you?" - Do not know. You put a knife in my thigh.
It will be a green old man.
But I think the gang criminals can do wonders with the care queues.
There is not a disease that not a bullet in the forehead can cure.
You pay at the checkout. Preferably cash. It's tick with the card machine.