He can take over the Wagner Group after Prigozjin's death.
And Ukrainian drone attacks deep into Russia.
New images show a rare insight into Mariupol.
What does life look like behind the Russian occupation?
A classic trick used at Stalin era when moving whole people.
This is the war of the week -
- As every week, the latest news development in the Ukraine War deepens.
Here, Ukrainian drones fly over the Russian city of Smolensk -
- Cirka 30 miles from the Ukrainian border.
Ukraine has recently invested in drone attacks on various goals in Russia.
Many drones are built on your own. It is its own production.
The most important thing for the allies is -
- You don't use weapons that come from the Allies.
This is because Russia should not be able to say: "Now NATO shoots Russia."
It could lead to an escalation in the war.
We move to the front, where there have been news in recent weeks -
- From the parts where Ukraine previously had success.
If you zoom out, it looks like it is pretty still at the front.
At the same time, we have known that this is an offensive that will take a long time.
It cannot be compared to previous offensives-
- There you quickly regain, for example. The chermen or the charkiv region.
Here Russia has had months of preparation for themselves -
- To build up their line of defense.
Along the eastern parts of the front -
- If Russian forces have been on the offensive lately.
SVT's team visited a mobile health center near the front during the week.
We hear that the Russians have increased the pressure here. The Ukrainians are pressed over here in the east.
But the pressure is also hard here - at the small mobile health center.
Everything works perfectly until the Russian terror begins again.
/EXPLOSION/