Hello. Hello Darling how are you? I'm tired. Who the hell wants to train before 8 in the morning? You and I are so different.
Ivy, are you ready for some real food today? Yep, wait, wait, you're going to get to piss yourself, can't you please promise and eat it now that mom has been cooking.
Please. You are welcome. The silence that is in here now, you can touch it. Wow, you seem to like it. Hello, hello, hello, Ivy. At least she tastes, she seems interested.
She'll take another one. This is good that she gets to play, I say so Jhon. You know what, with this said, I say welcome to a new fucking vlog.
Forgive me, but I saw on TikTok yesterday a disco bath like this and I just felt, wow. I'm just longing even though I want to enjoy Ivy every day which is now.
So I'm just longing for Ivy to be a little individual and talk and she just says like this, mommy I want to bathe or mommy I want to bake or whatever.
And this disco bath, I understand that Ivy is too small now, but I couldn't help myself so I went in, I ordered one thing from... No, I ordered 2 things from Adlibris.
Forgive me, I have to raise them because this is not a collaboration, nothing I pay just like usual but I actually have to raise them because I I placed an order yesterday.
Check it's already here and it arrived last night when we were sleeping so they sent it the same day. It's actually sick.
However, I ordered extra for express delivery. No, I didn't even do that. I don't even think it cost extra but it was really like this you can get it tomorrow.
And I got that and then I ordered another thing from like Young rooms that was like a frog that squirts foam so this is going to be so much fun.
I think I'm more tagly than Ivy is. Ivy will just sit like this. But me, on the other hand, I'm so damn hooked on this disco bath.
We'll have music, it'll be atmosphere, so tagged so we'll see now what came here now.
But what, Jhon, there was only one thing that came, it was just... Look, this is the disco ball, so you should put this in the bath and it will be a disco light.
I'm so fucking busy, but there will also be a whale that sprays water. Yes, maybe it will come in the next order then?
It wasn't so good Adlibris that you put it in 2 different orders and I didn't really like that, no, I didn't like that.
If we're now going to think about the environment as well, everything should come in the same package, I feel, but this, so tagged.
Good baby, so god, what you notice now that she thinks it was more fun to eat if she gets to eat herself.
Because before when I have served eggs, have I shown it? I think I showed it last time. So she barely eats, so then she just thinks it's weird with pieces.
Even if she spits out 70% of the food, it's still there, she takes it in, she tastes it, she gets interested.
You create an interest in food, which I noticed a big difference now. So it was fun and now she got a little banana to sit and suck on for a bit.
It can always be fun too, she'll actually take her first nap soon and then I'll sit down and work. It is half past nine in the morning.
Today we wake up as early as 7. We have actually slept until 10 every day now. But yesterday Ivy fell asleep very early so it was an earlier morning.
That's how it can be sometimes, so today she woke up at 7 and then before the first nap she usually stays awake for like 2 hours and later in the day she usually stays awake like between 3 and 4, not 4 hours but 3 hours before she sleeps.
What did you say? What do you want now? If you unpack things in my office, feel free to grab them and throw them away.
Hear what he says. The funny thing is that he only if you mess up my office then it's like this too. Well, these days it's not even called an office,
for any of us, but these days it's called... It's in John's room. It's in my room because you sleep in Jhon's room.
It has become that Jhon sleeps in that room and I sleep in our room with Ivy. I don't know why we do so much now that we have a slightly bigger bed too.
So I don't know why it has become that way, but it has only become nicer because it feels like everyone sleeps better if we sleep separately.
I get to sleep on my own surface without it being cramped in the bed. Ivy gets her own surface on her part of the bed, because now she's kind of stopped sleeping in her bed because we've gotten lazy.
I think it's so nice that we all sleep so much better and Jhon gets to sleep undisturbed when he still has to get up to work and such.
So that it has turned out so well, wait sorry, there were several who questioned John's gift. And I actually have to step in and defend you Jhon.
Because you misunderstand there were several who just waited so you got as a gift that he will take care of the home or your child or your child which of course he has to do?
It wasn't like that, then you've misunderstood everything, so me and Jhon share everything equally, but that was, for example, that I could throw in and only today I don't want to do anything I want to be served.
It was more like that or like, for example, I take care of Ivy all day now, for example, we split it up, for example, when Jhon comes home from work, he takes care of Ivy.
Then he takes the position. It's like that, but such a day. Then, for example, it could be like this: you take everything, you take everything and it's luxury, so whatever you say, it's luxury.
No, have you taken out the whole banana and mashed it now? No Ivy. No. No. This one then, what happened to it? Now you get to take that and play with it a bit.
Ivy is just as awkward in my vlogs when she just sits and stares and checks in on you as Jhon was in my last vlog when I was making breakfast with the lifesum recipe.
Then Jhon stands like this in the background. Man only, you are exactly like Ian or Ivy, kind of on camera. It's actually great fun, but you know what, we're starting this damn day.
We go and put Ivy to her nap, I sit down and work a bit and then I hear and fucking in amazement. You will be so shocked now. But then I'll go and train.
And this hasn't happened since I gave birth basically so today I'm going to train and I love my PT Kalle. So that we will probably mostly catch up rather than train.
We will mostly joke and flame, have fun and laugh. That's kind of what our training usually boils down to, exactly. But that's what we're going to do.
But first of all nap for Ivy. I actually also want to say one thing, Ivy has basically said mom now for the first time, she says this.
Ma ma, that's what she says, but she says mother, you understand that it's me calling. For example, if she is on someone else's lap.
Then you call up mom, don't you? Yes, you actually do. Now it's actually not just what I want to believe, but she actually started that way. There are several who just, God, she says mother.
So it's actually not just me, it's not a desperate mom who just wants her to say mom, but you've actually started saying that, haven't you?
But you don't say to order, because you still don't understand what I'm saying do you? No, exactly. But as I said, now we go and nap her.
We can go do a little dance first just Ivy. But we'll meet when I've put her to her first nap and we'll sit down to work and have a cup of coffee and enjoy the silence a bit.
So, the baby is sleeping and I actually even managed to take a shower so now it's coffee.
I would sit here and work now. Then Dora came here to visit. I'm sitting and then only god I have to check some clothes for Thailand.
She just, oh, that one was so pretty, and that blue one. I just yes, do you want it to Thailand? If you wear that Dora, if you put that on. If dora then comes in it.
So I can wear it, what should we wear? But what shall we bring to me Dora? Should I get in this one maybe? Should I get in it?
My God Dora, I'm sitting here trying to find something to wear in Thailand. This color, great color. It's actually nice.
But I'd like to wear something and not just lots of threads, right? You like the one who is ite, little, little. Who is it that likes the little one, I think it seems to be you.
You Dora, I would like to wear something that covers the body. I think this one was nice, that one, now we're talking. No. Was it too much coverage? Does it even exist?
No, it is not even available in size, of course. I think it was great. Dora is actually coming with us to Thailand, so we're going to have a real little family vacation like this.
I hope we don't get robbed this time Dora? No Klara, please. It won't be good if we do that again. I'm not going to bring anything. No, bring your ugliest clothes because you never know.
But now at least we each have a bathing suit. It's fun anyway. So now I'm on my way to the gym and as usual it's always last minute for me.
But I have ordered an uber and I know you will say this. It's not OK to take an Uber to the gym? Well, it's damn OK because even going to the gym is damn OK.
Like I said, I've been to the gym once since like week 20 when I was pregnant there a while ago if you remember. And I just feel this way, are there any more of you who just feel this way.
Why did the butt become flat after giving birth and being pregnant? My ass is flat as hell. I've never had a trained tail, but I've always, you know, had a little putt.
And it just like this, why am I all... It's just a back and a thigh all of a sudden. It could be because, as I said, I've never exercised, that could be the reason, but yeah, whatever it is.
Now I feel like this, maybe we should build this cushion again if it even works, if you even fail, I will fail once.
Hello. Hi welcome. Thanks, we'll see how this pillow goes, but at least we're on our way to the gym now.
Thank you very much, bye.
Here she comes. Exactly yes but thank you thank you. Welcome back. Then we'll take this one, Kalle. Good job, see you tomorrow. Yes, but now I have booked. Right.
Kalle, do you know what I hate? It's that you talk to everyone else during our shift and when it's over, you're very harsh with like this at 11 you must be ready, because then I will have someone else.
But when it's my pass then there's no respect for me, then you talk to people, I've booked you. It's like 20 people in a room, then everyone has to get some time.
Do you understand? Not when I have booked you because then I will have all the time. I'm just going to fill up with water.
So so, so now I've trained and I can say this to take the stairs now. It makes my legs shake.
I'm like spaghetti. I'm so damn untrained. I can say this, exercise is fucking boring. I hate it, but the feeling afterwards, as I always say, it's amazing.
That's why I train and I love hanging out with Kalle, my trainer. He's a rock, I just want to say, so that's the only reason why I train.
But now I'm going to take an uber away to fermano and blow dry my hair. Then we take a small Uber there and blow dry, thank god for that, what a damn luxury. Hello. Hello.
So now both fully trained and fully blow-dried, wonderful. Now we're going to get up and have some lunch and then I don't know what else is going on here, to be honest.
I kind of need to put in some laundry. I have to fix some things at home and then just be with Ivy as usual.
But this is how we try to divide it so that I can, for example, if I want to work out or if I need to go to a meeting.
Jhon take her to his lunch for when he works at home. After all, he has lunch for an hour and then that's when I usually go away.
And then I make sure she sleeps during that time, so that's good anyway. And when he works in the office, yes, I have her 100%, but it actually has to be that I work 100% and am on maternity leave 100%.
I'm not on maternity leave and taking money out, but I'm on maternity leave because I have a child and I'm a mother, but you know what I mean.
But yes, it's not that easy in that industry to have time off and be a mother, unfortunately. It doesn't quite work the same way, does it?
But we have still set it up well so that for us this arrangement works as well. I don't know if I have a key with me and it's locked of course.
Hi, I don't have any keys. Bad for you then. So, forgive me, it's always like this you know, I can stand out there, knock, knock, knock or you screw me then because sometimes I'm starting to feel like you're doing this just to resist.
You just have to learn, you come in when I want you to come in. So he drives, Jhon now they will realize that you are a controlling boyfriend, that we have a toxic relationship and that I live in oppression.
Oh my god, I fucking forgot to tell you oh my fucking god you know what happened, so listen to this. No wait.
It was like this, huh, Ivy and I are at home. we lie down and sleep until 11. John has gone to work and then there at half past twelve when we are going out.
Yes, then I notice that we don't get out because the door. I don't know what has happened. The lock just broke somehow.
Because Jhon locks as usual in the morning so we don't get out, so then we started having this nightmare scenario and just oh my god what if it starts a fire in here and me and Ivy don't get out.
I panic so I have to call a locksmith who comes. He gets my keys, it can't be opened from the outside either. It's broken so he just has to break the whole door off.
Yes, this party costs us SEK 5,250, great, and then I wonder, can this be deducted from the home insurance? Several of you have said that you can deduct this from your home insurance, but I don't know.
In any case, it was crazy that it was so damn expensive, that it was such an expensive damn expense, but there was nothing to wait for. I had to get out and it was also a safety risk to open the door like this.
I have to get out of there. It was so uncomfortable, but it went well anyway. Here I am and I and Ivy are alive, it didn't start a fire, but we are, however, SEK 5,250 poorer.
Too bad it was so expensive. But, now we're going to go inside and see what Ivy does.
So I can say this, I hung out with Ivy. Then I just felt no, now I need a little refreshment, so I went and got a spray tan.
So I haven't washed it off yet, but then from that to this. Now we decided somewhat spontaneously that my father and his girl Agnet. Girl? You say so? Girlfriend or partner, wife are they married?
No. Together, I think my father and his partner Agneta would come out for dinner and Jhon and I have a special one and it's the New Year's dinner that we did.
And I think you should follow along now with how we made it. We're going to make these starters on potato buns, so if you haven't made it yet, do it.
Check exactly now how I do it, just do it for everyone's sake, do it because it's so fucking good. It's so good and to go with it we'll have beef fillet and potato gratin and salad.
And to top it off, Jhon has now decided that he should cook a cake. It's just because he wants, because I said so, he just, don't you think your dad would have appreciated it if I baked a cookie?
I just, Yes, but I will if you want. I'm like this, a baked cake is never as good as a seeded cake.
Maybe I'm weird now, but I think so fröding kladdkaka is the best I know and you can't beat it.
It sounds spoiled when someone wants to bake for me, but I kind of feel that way. Then I said in any case that if you want a cookie, go for it.
But your father wants. I think dad will be happy about the food and then we can have an ice cream afterwards. I'm thinking about your dad. Jhon you want the scratch cake? Yes. I just do it then.
But at least now I'm coming to the conclusion that I'll start with the food, so I think we'll start setting the table a little bit. Now it won't be as nice a setting as last time.
But we start setting the table a bit and then we can start making the salad because we can just put it away and then what do we need to do then? We can put potato gratin in shape and everything so that it is ready.
Because now there is an hour left until they arrive, so there is quite a long time left. But we get started and set the table.
What did you say? Finduken is on. Your dad would have appreciated a cookie. Jhon, if you want this scratch cake, I think you do.
Dad appreciates... Three courses. Yes, but he can have 3 courses, we can still make ice cream. We don't make ice cream. No, we bought ice cream.
You know what, make the scratch cake. I think fröding is tastier than everyone's. Okay if I hit the seed... But you know you won't come because no one I've tasted so far, even when I tasted this...
It's nothing against you honey, I think you're fine the way you are . I'm telling you, I'm going to beat the froedinges. Challenge accepted.
Oh baby, you're always going to beat my ass. Of course it's mine. Now it was this destructive relationship again. I don't care, you understand? Mine is mine.
Oh mine is mine too, you know, now he's starting to say I'm his property here. 100%, didn't you tell me I'm locking you in here. Was it not in this vlog that I have told it. Yes.
Exactly, are you going to behave or am I going to lock you up. I'm kidding. There are people who misunderstood. I'm kidding, I'd never locked up Klara. Or? or?
He makes that joke every time you just where is the joke Jhon? I do not follow. John, you can't be standing here baking now that I'm cooking.
You are like a fly. I wave you off and you come back. Listen I told Jhon was with Ivy now I'm going to cook.
Then he should promptly stand here now and make food or cake. And I was clear darling that I need this spa.
And now for the potato buns and then you will have this parmesan cream and then you just take regular crème fraiche and then you take grated parmesan, like finely grated parmesan.
And then I usually take garlic spices, salt, pepper and this is what you put as... This is what you put as a base.
That's what you add as a base before you add shrimp like this, red onion roe before you add all that, then you add the Parmesan cream.
So that's what we're doing now. What are you doing? So now I've just mixed together crème fraiche, this kind of finely grated parmesan and now we take garlic powder and then salt and pepper.
Like, it was as much parmesan as it is crème fraiche, just so you know. So it really should taste like cheese and garlic and salt and pepper. Delicious.
Now it's time for the sauce and on New Year's Eve I had funnel chanterelles and it was damn good. But now I didn't find it.
So now it's just regular mushrooms and then whipped cream and then a little crème fraiche, like it's going to be damn good. And then I usually add in veal broth and a little soy.
And I usually run on this one. That veal broth. And then just a little soy salt and pepper, and then we're home.
And as I show, plain damn cream and plain damn crème fraiche. Nothing like where you know light cream fresh or anything like that but regular creme fraiche to get this creamy.
I'm just saying, this sauce, divine.
The Lordship has come.
OK, now I'm going to jump in the shower right away. Dinner is ready. Dad and Agneta have gone home and I just have to say your sloppy cake darling, wow.
No, it was wow. It was very good and the dinner was very good. I didn't actually film the meat and everything because you controlled it.
But no, it was a very good dinner, very very good, and now I'm going to jump into the shower and we're just going to watch love island right here.
Well, I can only say one thing and that is that I hate Johnny, so. I hate him. No, I think he's so fucking... What are you doing?
No, I'm checking. Yes, surely he is troublesome? He is a player. Yes, but then, I think he's terrible, that is, a terrible person.
And I just feel like this, please can someone just put him in his place? Oh my god, now he's going to choose my fucking god.
He is so disgusting. He's sick in the head. So, he changes all the time. Oh, my God, now I have to jump in the shower.
We'll see each other in a little while, I thought, but we don't. See you in a few days.
Don't forget that I love you. Don't forget that I die for you and on the next vlog maybe we can have even more love island talk. So, my God. Goodbye, see you soon, you say? Bye.