Hello Hello!
We are in...
Thailand!
YES!
If you follow our Instagram then you already know it,
Because we update with pictures and stories every day!
Yes.
But ... here comes a Youtube vlog of the trip from Sweden here to ...
- To ... - to Khao Lak.
Oh, I would say "Thailand".
But, Khao Lak is in ...
- Thailand!
- Exactly.
Here it comes!
Ugh, how cold it is!
How are you?
Good.
- Are you peppered?
- Yeah!
God, what you chew.
Rocket...
How many bags do we have?
We have three checked in, then we have the children's ...
- It wasn't Alma and Harry.
I thought so!
- Just ...
We have three bags that we checked in, and then we all have each ...
... cabin bag.
I have a backpack, Joanna has a backpack, and the kids ...
We each have a backpack, simply.
Then we have this little thing, with our passports.
Then we have these, and we do not know how to check in.
They may be special luggage.
We'll see when we arrive at the check -in counter.
Come on, friends!
Yes!
We swish away!
Let's go!
- How do we do with these?
Is it...?
Should we take that?
- Yes do it.
- The scooters are special luggage.
- Yes.
- So that ... Axel got a bag.
- mm.
- Now we are on our way to check them in another place.
- Yes!
Dad, check out what I can do.
Oh, what good!
So.
And then Alma, yours.
Aah!
What is it?
I turned on like legs ... The leg lump in my knee.
Oh no.
Silent!
They will talk like that all the time we are at the airport, you understand.
Now we have submitted the children's scooters, and should go through the security check, and there you must not film.
So see you on the other side!
Oh, wow!
- Here you have a lot to choose from!
- Really.
What is this?
- Scooby-doo.
- That's Scooby-Doo.
Scooby-Doo we checked at Tanja at home.
I think ... that.
But that is not a newspaper?
- Do you want it instead of newspaper?
- Yes.
I have decided on this one.
Good!
- We are actually in a hurry, so now we go to the cash register.
- Yes, now we are in a hurry.
- Are we in a hurry?
- We are in a hurry.
It is ten past four and our plane goes twenty in five.
So we have half an hour on us.
- I want to open ... - I want my scooter!
- Mom, can I open the gift I got on the plane?
- Yes.
- We can.
Great!
It's been so stressful in recent days ... hard to even explain.
I will end up in a coma on the flight, I feel.
Yes.
Don't wake up, just ...
- Do you know what's behind us now?
- No?
- Our gate, and it's boarding!
- Yes!
Yay!
- Now we leave!
Goodbye Sweden.
- Yes, we are so ready!
I will miss you!
Should I say one thing I won't miss?
What?
The darkness.
You don't like darkness because it gets dark in the camera, and just ...
Yes!
Then we can't use what we film, and then just ... we have to put down the whole vlog.
For that reason, and several other reasons, I do not like darkness.
So, it is not even five, and it is black as the night out.
Yes.
It's unpleasant!
That is out ...
- Joanna has a fixation at the dark.
- Yes I know.
- Hello Hello!
- Where are you sitting somewhere?
- 6 C to F. - Yes.
Then you can go ...
- It's forward?
- Yes!
- Should we stay here?
- Yes, there we are going in.
What is this?
It's a blanket!
So Harry chose ...
... instead of a newspaper ...
- ... a turtles ... - a turtles guy.
Check!
Gosh!
Show.
Nämen, which ... what a tongue!
I know.
You do this ...
- Check out what I got in the newspaper, Dad.
- What a fun.
I got this one in the newspaper.
Oh, wow.
What is that?
Keep it up.
It is a small one where you hang.
I can hang it on my backpack or anywhere else.
The plane lifted a little late.
We got away just after five.
It was completely extinguished, as it needs to be when you fly away in the dark.
Then they lit, and this fun gang sat with each screen.
Now it is half past seven.
I hope the food is coming soon.
We are all hungry.
- Yes, this is here.
- It's here.
Alma ...
Harry, now comes the food!
- What's that?
- It's a dessert.
It looks like a lemon cake.
- Looks good.
- But first you should eat that.
Meatballs and mashed potatoes.
Good, of course!
Where is the dessert?
What is happening over there?
He is angry and unpleasant.
- Tired.
- Yes.
This is how it is with children, when they are tired and you should fly with them, and it is uncomfortable, and so there.
Sometimes it is, at least, not always.
Sometimes.
The water cannot be drinked.
- Is it in English?
- Yes.
Vat ...
... er ... Vater.
- "Water".
- Good!
Water ...
Note...
For ...
Drink...
... ing.
It is a quarter to nine, and we are getting ready to sleep.
We hope we will be able to sleep, anyway.
Good morning.
We just woken up.
Alma sits watching the baby boss.
Harry is still sleeping on the floor.
What time is it?
It is 8 Thai time - I've switched to it.
But in Sweden it is two at night ...
I feel it in my body and soul.
I am very tired.
Yes.
The positive is that we have 2 hours left of an 11 hour flight.
Soon it's over ... It's nice!
- It's really warm here, mom!
- Yes!
- Is it nice?
- Yes.
Do you know what we are waiting for now?
No.
Not really.
- Pass stamp!
- Yes!
- Stamp in ... - Passport control, it's called.
Yes!
- They have a little trouble letting each other be.
- Yes.
There is a bit of a retry and thief type all the time.
But it will be good when we arrive, because then there are a lot of other children, and a lot of baths and play.
It's so hot!
- Hello!
- Hello Hello!
- Warm welcome!
- Thanks!
- Where are you going anywhere and swimming?
Which hotel?
- The Sands.
The Sands ...
I must say;
I actually know who you are!
I looked at you the other day.
Oh what fun!
After all, we haven't told us that this trip is a collaboration with TUI.
- They sponsor us these two weeks in Thailand.
- Yes.
Which is the beginning of our long journey, so we will continue on another.
But it is a very wonderful start that we are very happy for!
- Oh!
- Oh.
Yes, I stepped on something.
- Now we are going to take a bus to Khao Lak.
- Yes!
- And it takes two hours.
- Two and a half hours, I think he said.
- So we are landed at Krabi Airport.
- Yes.
There our bus goes.
Here is our hotel.
That trip took type three hours.
Harry fell asleep a bit at the end.
- Which is a hotel?
- This is our hotel.
- Here is our hotel.
- Here we will live.
Finally, Harry!
(in English) Welcome to The Sands!
These are your bags, huh?
(in English) Hello!
Yes please.
It looks like a small safari car.
Large hotel area.
It looks huge.
(in English) There is the Kids Club pool.
And behind the Kids Club ...
Check out, Alma and Harry!
Wow!
What did you think of that?
Very cool!
The cat the sausage almost rubbed ...
(in English) Okay, now we're there!
(in English) Welcome to your room!
(in English please!
Oh!
- Straight out to the pool!
- Oh, what a nice!
- Here you can just plum in!
- Yes!
This is an interesting solution ...
... to the toilet.
Here Alma and Harry will sleep.
So you can close ... with this.
- And that's those stars!
- Cute, huh!
And here is mom and dad's!
Now we have been here for a couple of days, and of course there will be several vlogs from here.
Yes!
We have a question of the day.
Football girl07 wonders:
"What do Alma and Harry think about going away for so long?"
Super long!
What do you think about it, then?
Good!
I think it's totally okay, actually.
I don't think Alma and Harry understand how long we should be gone, in total.
We talk about four months.
I have a hard time understanding it, myself.
Yes me too.
It feels really strange.
But at the same time Supernice to start with a more holiday - ie holiday - for two weeks.
Yes indeed!
Thanks for watching this video!
Feel free to leave a thumbs up ...
... or down!
Preferably up!
Comment, ask questions, and have a great time until we see you next time!
Bye!