- Harry is in hospital ... - mm ...
Dad Axel sleeps with Harry at the hospital.
If you follow our Instagram, you probably already know about this.
We update with pictures and stories daily.
But if you do not, Harry is in hospital.
- Great fever.
- Great fever, exactly.
I dropped like the words.
He has had a fever occasionally for five days.
Great fever, then it went down ...
Very high fever, then it went down.
In fact, when we recorded our last video;
Gingerbread house Challenge ...
... then he had a fever, and then it was gone.
In all cases.
On day five - yesterday, he also began to complain about stomach pain.
Then Axel and I felt that this does not feel good, we take him to the pediatrician.
We come to the pediatrician, they take kissing and some other samples, and say that we have to move on to another doctor.
We move on to another place where they made an ultrasound and saw that his one kidney was swollen.
It was big.
Then we had to move on again.
At Astrid Lindgrens, Harry was hospitalized, and there he remains.
- Mom?
- Yes?
- What is the disease that Harry has?
- It's called renal pelvic inflammation.
How to get it?
He has had a urinary tract infection that was not treated, and then it went up in the kidneys.
But he did not show any of the signs I thought were typical of urinary tract infection.
So it stings when you kiss.
It is true that children do not react in the same way as adults.
This is a very important thing for all parents there at home to remember!
- Have a nice day at school Alma, and we'll see you this afternoon!
- mm.
Bye!
- Now I'm going to Harry.
- Yes.
Hello!
How dark you have.
- Is Alma here?
- No, she's at school.
She is so worried about you!
What have you?
- We have received a Wildlife Christmas calendar.
- Huh!
We sit and open all the gaps we have not opened.
- Oh, what a lot of blood.
- Oh, have they taken new samples?
Check out what a lot of blood, Dad!
They took a stick in their finger a little while ago.
It hurt even though I didn't cry.
You're so cool, Harry!
- Listen, I have to get hugged with you now!
- Although I'll throw this.
- Okay, but you come and hug me then?
- Yes.
Now you have to tell you what the doctor has said.
- Do you remember what the doctor said, Harry?
- No.
- Should I tell?
- Yes.
The doctor said that Harry is feeling better and that he may be allowed to come home today!
It all depends on what the blood values say.
If they feel they want to make one for ultrasound, then we will have to do it.
They say he feels so good that they may change to ordinary antibiotics, which you can swallow.
Then Harry can come home!
Yes.
As it is now, Harry gets his medicine in here, straight into his arm.
Right.
- Does it hurt?
- No.
- Do you see?
- Yes, I see.
The hose, that hose, flows into my body.
Harry rests a bit.
We were out in the corridor and ate lunch, and then he got another dose antibiotics in his arm.
The staff here is absolutely amazing!
They are so good with children.
But we can't film anyway at the hospital, of course.
We came across some clowns, but there were other children around so we couldn't pick up the camera.
What is Dad doing?
Blips and blopper with the computer.
- What do you want to do now?
- Check out CKN Toys.
Check out CKN Toys.
What is it, Harry?
Can you tell our viewers?
It is a man who opens toys.
- A child, huh?
- Yes.
A child is in itself a human being ...
Should he be able to watch CKN Toys?
Yes, he can do that for a little while.
One section he can see.
Three programs ...
- Dad, three programs?
- One.
- No, three?
Okay, then it will be two.
Hard negotiation, ie ...
I'm going to knit and pick up Alma, then maybe we will come back here, so she gets to meet Harry.
They miss each other quite a lot.
Harry, you are going to go on ultrasound now, said the sister.
We are waiting for the doctor, and Harry is watching a movie in the meantime.
I don't think we will be able to film during the survey itself.
We're back in the room.
How did the survey go, Harry?
Good.
Was it hard to get a batter on your stomach?
Yes.
The doctor laid translucent gel on Harry's stomach.
Then she pulled a machine like this to see how the kidneys felt.
- Do you know what she told me, Harry?
- No.
That left kidney is not feeling well.
- But ... now we wait for a ... - should I sleep here again?
We don't know that.
We are waiting for a message if you are allowed to go home, or if you have to stay.
I get sick if I drink all this.
You've been drinking it up now!
Good!
Harry has eaten very bad today.
Almost just an apple.
Now he drank up such an energy drink.
- Do you see?
It's a dinosaur on!
- Yes.
This means that you are getting big and strong as a Dino!
Do you remember what you can do now that you have been drinking it up?
- No.
- Dont you remember?
- Paste!
- Right!
Harry has got such a book where you paste when you have eaten and drunk.
Should you see if you find that drink?
There it is.
The time is now...
Where.
Soon half past six.
This means it's time to pee again.
Okay...
Where!
And then kiss.
- Here at?
- Mm!
Just that, I kissed the poop.
The doctors were in here a little while ago and told me that Harry had to stay another night.
The bacterium that created the urinary tract infection that then went on to the kidneys is an unusual bacterium.
They dare not let him home.
Hello.
Hello friend.
Oh, what you are bad.
This one is to you.
He is totally groggy.
Yes, he got very tired when he got this medical drip.
Well.
Alma, check down!
Right high up ...
Hello Hi, kids!
This is all the way up, what we can go.
- What are you doing?
- Eat french fries and go elevator!
♪ Hey Hops, butt fails!
♪
♪ When the butt comes, every butt should be happy!
You have never been so happy that the children sing about kiss and poop!
I also want to lie down.
He felt so damn crass for a while, but now the energy came back.
Now Alma and Joanna will go home and sleep.
Harry and I are going to get ready and go to bed.
I have ordered a taxi.
It is already nine o'clock.
- I am very tired.
- Me too!
We end today's filming now, we will resume it tomorrow, Harry!
- mm.
Okay, then we say ... "good night" I was saying, we don't say ...
We say;
See you just as soon.
Then it's a new day.
What are you holding up in?
A balloon sword.
Where did you get it from?
Clowns.
- Has there been clowns here?
- Yes.
He feels much better!
He has responded to the treatment, so now his infection value in the blood has gone down.
This means that we may be allowed to go home today!
Yay!
I killed.
What was that clowns?
It was Fjodor and Milda Matilda who knocked on and came in.
They trolled with balls.
- Yes!
- And played with pillows and knotted balloons.
They were great.
Great for him!
Does it hurt, Harry?
No.
Then I pull it out ...
So.
How good you were!
So, how cool is Harry?!
You do not touch a mine when they keep you and remove sticks and things, huh!
- I think he's superball!
- Like the worst superhero!
Yes, much cooler than your mom!
I'm just standing ...
... holds the camera and feels a small tear.
You may be silent.
- Do you know what is happening now, Harry?
- No?
We get to go home ... we have to go home!
I get a throat.
How cozy...
We're home again.
And it's so nice!
Or what do you say, Alma?
Yes, nice as just that!
It's great!
We have an important thing to do ...
- Cut the hospital band!
- Just that, as you get when you are in hospital.
- Are you prepared, Harry?
- Yes.
Bye.
Oh, nice!
Group hug!
What an emotional carousel this has been ...
- I'm completely exhausted.
- Me too.
Completely finished.
- And grateful!
- Yes!
- That Harry is home!
- It is so nice that he is about to recover again.
- I have such respect for all parents with sick children.
- Yes!
After our short hospital stay, I only know;
God, there are people going through this ...
Mm ...
- ...day out and day in.
Year in and year out, for some.
- Yes exactly.
And who will celebrate Christmas in hospital, with their sick children.
- You are heroes.
Everyone!
- Yes!
Thank you for looking at this long vlog!
Feel free to leave a thumbs up if you liked it.
It is quite slow compared to what we usually post.
It is exciting to hear what you think.
- Write a comment if you have time and desire.
- Yes please!
And...
Excuse me, I'm losing my voice.
I'm so tired.
- Merry Christmas, from us to you!
- Have a great time until we see you next time.
- Have a good one.
- Merry Christmas!
Bye!