- Yes, it's daddy.
- Daddy.
Did you hear that?
People were staring at us.
It was pretty tough.
New Year's resolutions!
What are you doing?
Good morning.
- We are in...
- Kläppen Ski Resort.
We got here...
Harry is standing on a chair.
We got here two days before Christmas Eve.
We have had such a cozy time here.
- Here comes Laura!
- Yes.
How are you?
Completely silent.
She's doing quite well.
- Shall we go and eat breakfast?
- Yes!
- Yes, a high chair. Shall we take one?
- Mm.
Morning coffee. Important.
- Morning hot chocolate.
- I know. I was just kidding.
This, however, is the most important part.
Whipped cream.
Oops! There we go.
We are staying at Hotel Kurbits, located right on the slope.
We have stayed here before.
Mm.
Two years ago.
Then, there was a big difference in our family.
Yes!
- This one was in my belly.
- Yes.
- She was almost not thought of.
- Yes, she was. She was ready to pop! Well, I was.
- Yes.
- I was very pregnant.
But the difference is so cool
because now we have a little girl who talks! Right?
What?
You're talking!
Talking. Exactly.
Welcome to our 6-bed apartment, this time.
Here we have a quite nice and spacious hall
with a drying cabinet. Very good.
A guest restroom.
And behind the camera is the large restroom with a shower.
A guest restroom for all our guests.
Exactly. We don't have too many guests,
but it's quite nice when you're a big family.
It's daddy's poop toilet
where he can cozy-poop for two hours.
- Someone was just very honest.
- What the heck! The things you have to take.
- Hey...
- I don't cozy-poop for two hours.
Hey. Don't swear, please.
- Don't swear!
- Okay, sorry.
- Now Alma takes over and shows her room.
- Yes, I lost the floor.
This is where I live.
Well, I don't live here. Well, I kind of do
because I'm here most of the time I'm not skiing.
You have your own room.
Yes. I really wanted to have my own room.
I have a spare bed here, if anyone wants to sleep over.
And here we have Harry and Laura's room.
It looks kind of the same as Alma's room.
Mirrored.
Laura sleeps down there and Harry sleeps up there,
and they have not made their beds.
That's how it is sometimes.
Joanna and I sleep in here.
And it works great.
It's a small apartment
but it still has quite a large common area.
But the best of all...
I never get tired of this view.
We are not a family that's out on the slopes
when the lifts open.
Laura, are you out in the lifts at all?
What does that mean?
- Are you out skiing?
- No!
No.
Laura is with a babysitter
a few hours per day.
We have found Elma, 17, who comes and looks after Laura
for a few hours when we're skiing. She'll be here any moment now.
Yes! She'll be here soon.
- Hey!
- Hello! Good morning.
Good morning.
- How are you?
- I'm fine. And you?
Fine, thank you.
Little rascal!
Yes.
- Someone who likes their babysitter.
- Yes, indeed!
- What's happening now?
- We're off to ski school.
- Take one each. I'll pull you guys.
- Okay.
Alma and Harry are in the same ski school group.
Children 9-11, right? Oh, looking good!
- "Kidz" 9-11.
- Yes. "Kidz."
- Harry is a bit young for his group.
- Yes, and...
But it's nice to have them in the same group.
Sorry.
There are kids from other countries here as well.
Quite a lot more than in previous years, I think.
I feel like you hear families from all over Europe.
- Yes. Exciting!
- Yes.
- There are only Swedes in their group, though.
- Okay. I have no idea.
I do, because I listened to them yesterday.
Shall we do some skiing, or?
Yes. I need to put on ski boots and a helmet,
then let's hit the slopes.
- Alone time. Luxurious!
- Very good alone time.
It's one thing to get in,
but then you have to get out.
Here comes Alma and Harry's ski school group.
- Hey!
High five!
Alma, you're so cool.
- How's it going?
- I managed to turn around.
What are you doing?
Axel! Give me the camera.
- What are you doing?
- It looked so nice to lie down a bit.
I think Alma got embarrassed.
She skied away very fast.
That's my job!
My job is to be embarrassing.
Alma! Wait for me!
"Gary." (scary)
A little scary this high up.
We are in the gondola, on our way to "Toppstugan" for some lunch.
The family is reunited.
Yes.
Have you had a good time?
Yes, you've had such a good and fun time!
She has so much new energy
when she's been free of us for a little while.
Yes.
- How's ski school?
- It's actually fun!
- Harry, what do you think?
- It's really fun.
- Good.
- Oh. Cough, cough.
A good thing about ski school, besides getting better at skiing,
is that you meet new friends.
Yes, exactly.
- That's a big win.
- Yes.
Good, Laura!
Laura is sitting with Joanna's phone,
because she's completely done.
I don't know if I like it, but it's very difficult
to get her to eat anything when she's tired and hungry.
- Of course you don't like it.
- No.
- But desperate times call for desperate measures.
- That's true.
Be happy those two are eating without a screen.
- Is it good?
- Mm.
Don't forget about the vegetables, kids.
- So many in there were staring at us.
- How did that feel?
It felt weird, kind of like getting attacked,
because I'm eating and at least 10 people are looking at me.
You get quite nervous
and don't really know what to do.
- We're not really used to it anymore.
- Yeah.
When we've lived in Portugal, we haven't really
experienced that in the same way. And then we come here...
Someone wants something.
Yes, it's daddy.
- Daddy.
- Yes. Daddy.
Daddy has just flown the drone a bit.
- Oh! My fingers.
- I interrupted you, what were you going to say? Well, Laura did.
In Portugal,
we have been a bit anonymous.
You can, like, walk around and be yourself and yell at the kids
when they're mean towards each other, and things like that.
Here, it feels, like...
It's a bit more difficult.
- You have eyes on you.
- Yes, a bit like that...
You have to be your best self.
I mean, it's our own choice and it's a very good exercise
to always be your best self, I think.
And I love our viewers. And I love that they come up to us
and that they whisper and look and point...
- Do you love that part in particular?
- No, but... Yes, it's a part of it. I love everything about what we do.
I don't love to be famous.
That sounded really weird.
I mean... I love our viewers.
I love you guys!
What goofballs!
Now me, Alma, and Harry
are going to ski a little.
- Yes.
And Laura and I will go back to our room
and rest for a bit.
- That'll be nice for you.
- Yes, I think she's cold.
I know she's cold. And super tired.
You guys take this camera.
We have this... Not the glove. This camera.
- Yes!
- Okay! Kisses and good night. "Boa noite." Love you!
Love you!
- Have fun! See you soon!
- Bye-bye!
Bye-bye!
"It's going away. Now it's good."
- What are you doing?
- What am I doing?
- I saw how you put away the phone.
- I do that when you guys come. It feels nicer.
- What secrets are you up to on the screen? Tell me, tell me, tell me.
- What do you mean by "secrets"?
This was a very ugly image.
You look like Froggy Ball. Come now.
That was your punishment for hiding in here alone.
No, don't post me looking like Froggy Ball.
Come on now. The others are sitting out there reading
and having a nice time. Don't hide in here with your phone.
- I don't have the energy.
- What do you mean you don't have the energy?
I hardly slept at all last night.
Hey, you've been out skiing a bunch
without any problem.
- You don't get energy from being on your phone, I promise.
- No, but I don't lose energy.
- What? Do you lose energy from being out here?
- Yes, because then I have to move my legs.
- You will help cook dinner.
- No, mommy...
- Yes.
- No.
- I don't want to.
- Yes.
- Please?
- What have you been thinking of doing?
- Lie in my room.
- No, forget that! Let's cook food, right?
- Yes, let's cook food.
Can you guys understand
that this is the last vlog of the year?
- No.
- Of the last days of the year.
- Yes. I mean... It's crazy, I feel like this year has flown by.
- I agree.
- Yes, it has gone by very quickly.
- What's that supposed to be?
- Mozzarella.
- It looks like a little turd, kind of.
- If your turds look like that, you have a problem.
No, they don't.
But it looks like something strange.
What's been the best thing about this year?
I think it's funny when you say...
I mean, Laura's words are probably the most fun thing.
When you say, like, "The Summer Shadow!" to her,
she gets, like...
Did you hear?
She was, like, "Gary!" (scary)
And when you say other words.
And when she farts and you go like this, she starts, like...
- When you fan your nose because it smells bad?
- Yes.
It's so fun that she has
started to understand things.
- Mommy?
- Do you want a hug?
Oh, you want to help film?
Come here.
I think the best part about the whole year,
if you think of things we have shown the viewers,-
-is our trip down to Málaga, and then home.
And the whole summer at home
was absolutely wonderful.
- From Portugal to Sweden, you mean?
- Yes.
I think that the best part about this year
was when we had Skara Sommarland for ourselves.
That was so much fun!
I think the best part about this year was...
Oops! She fell.
...the autumn in Portugal because it was so nice and warm
and we could be in the pool and such.
- Yes.
- Yes, that was cozy.
I'm surprised you said the summer in Sweden
because we did so much packing.
- Yes, but...
- Selling a house. That was pretty tough, I think.
It was tough, but selling that house
was also a very big and welcome step for our family.
We had to do it,
and it feels so nice that we have done it now.
- I think it's time to eat.
- Yes. Now it's chaos.
We are one day closer to a new year,
and we have a fitting Question of the Day.
Yes!
What are our New Year's resolutions?
- My New Year's resolution is to learn to snowboard.
- Oh, good!
- My New Year's resolution is to learn division.
- Okay, math. Good!
Laura fell asleep when we sat down here to film.
And she's a little too young for a resolution.
My resolution is to take care of my health.
- Oh, good!
- Make better choices in everyday life.
Yes. Mine too.
- The same?
- Yes, the same.
What are your New Year's resolutions?
Comment down below!
And remember to be kind to yourself.
No one should change.
- No.
- Don't be, like, "I'm gonna go on a diet and get skinny."
- You can get better, but not change yourself.
- Yes!
Thank you for watching this video!
- Please leave a thumbs up, or down.
- Mostly thumbs up!
Comment, ask questions
and take care until next time.
- Happy New Year!
- Bye-bye!