Good morning. We are in Thailand.
- Shall we go and eat breakfast?
- Yes!
- Shall we leave?
- No.
You don't want breakfast? I want breakfast.
It was boring.
- I think you need something in your belly.
- No, it's just boring.
- Do you know what we can do on the way there?
- No.
Feed the fish!
Come on! They are hungry at least, even if you aren't.
Okay then!
Don't throw too little, and not too much.
Because then it will... it won't last that long.
- Do you want more?
- Yes.
Oh God, they are going crazy!
One can do this every morning and afternoon.
Harry's mood in the mornings isn't the best,
but I feel like this helps a little.
- Yes, indeed!
- The mornings get more fun.
It's like... he...
He gets something else to think about.
- Let's have breakfast!
- Yes.
Fruit and muesli for breakfast. Super tasty!
Harry's having strawberry yogurt with chocolate cereal.
Is it good?
Oh.
- He needs help wiping his mouth.
- Get it off, get it off!
Yes, calm down. I'm taking my napkin.
Napkin ambulance.
Okay?
Harry gets stressed out sometimes...
...when it gets messy.
The kids have already jumped in.
There are several pools at this hotel,
but this kids area is Alma and Harry's favorite.
You guys, here I come!
What happened with the crocodile?
Do you want a push?
Hold on!
- Okay, are you all set? Do you want a push?
- Yes.
Oh!
- It didn't hit my face.
- Nice save!
It's really difficult!
I float to the surface like a sausage.
Guys, the water slides are open!
Shouldn't we all go there?
- Yes!
- Come on, Axel!
Look. Here's your pizza, Harry.
Oh!
- Really hot.
- Yes, yes I see. Thank you!
- What! This one's mine?
- Yes, let's remove these.
It got wrong.
Sometimes things go wrong.
After a morning like this, everything tastes good, Harry.
You have jumped around and played so much.
You guys just got a pile of salad each, it's so weird!
Dad and I have ordered more food.
Delicious.
- Yes. One here and one over there, please.
- Yes.
Fanta!
What should Fanta eat?
- Who is Fanta?
- Him.
This is Fanta.
Alma and Harry slept for a bit after lunch.
- Nice, huh?
- Yes!
- We are headed for the main street to...
- Come here, Harry!
...pick up our laundry,
which we dropped off a couple of days ago.
Come!
Alma and Axel found a laundry service
where you could get...
...1 kilo laundry done for 50 Bath, right?
(2.2 lbs)(1.5 USD)
I think so, I don't know. I don't remember.
- And how much is 50 Bath? Around 10 SEK?
- Mhm, something like that.
- Do you want a push?
- Yes.
It is actually starting to rain. Let's open these.
- I'll take this one.
- The camera!
Yes, exactly. Let's keep one above the camera.
- Which one can I take?
- You can take this one.
- Do you want to share?
- Yes.
- Or... Alma can have it.
It's quite nice! It's really, really...
What do you say? The air is very humid.
And I'm wearing so much sunscreen...
I feel sticky all over.
It feels good with some rain.
These were jam packed when we handed them in,
and now when it's all folded it's almost half the size.
It feels like a good investment!
Axel is dropping off the laundry in our hotel room,
and we are heading to the beach.
I mean - the beach by our hotel.
- Hello...
- Hello, hello!
Hello.
How are you getting on with your English, Alma?
Okay.
This hotel is booked through TUI.
We are collaborating with TUI,
who have sponsored our trip to Thailand.
We are super happy about that, of course!
We will not only be staying at this hotel -
we are switching to another place after one week.
Right.
When we've met other travelers... Swedes,
we've noticed that combination trips are quite common.
- Being at one place for a week, and then another place.
- Mhm.
Alma was a little upset this morning,
because her new friend switched hotels today.
Yes.
Harry is yelling something.
Come down on the beach...
...and let's go to the Love Tree.
But it's getting dark now, Harry. We are going back to change, and then we are having dinner.
Yummy, yummy!
- Do you like it?
- Mhm.
- Do you like yours?
Dad says I can only choose something healthy,
not nuggets and french fries and stuff like that...
...so this is all healthy foods.
- It's a good thing that healthy can also be tasty!
- Mhm.
NOW
WE'LL
GO
FOR
AN
EVENING
DI...
...P!
P... what does "P" mean?
An evening swim.
Woho!
- The best balcony!
- Aha, aha...
Here comes a diver!
Sleep tight now.
- Goodnight, dad. I love you.
- I love you both.
It's pitch black.
Not pitch black, but a little darker.
Goodnight.
We have a Question of the Day that works pretty well, because this day has revolved a lot around the hotel.
Jocke Bröms asks:
"What is the best thing about your hotel?".
Swimming!
You should be asleep!
"Swimming".
I actually agree. Harry is right.
I want to go to the pool now...
...to the water slides.
- Yes. All the pools - it being so close to water.
- Yes.
I can also reveal that the worst part
are these walls that are just made of glass.
Yes, it's a wobbly and loud glass wall...
Sorry, I just knocked on it. It's like a paper wall.
We have a very hard time being able to do things
in the evenings, after we have put the kids down.
Mhm.
Thank YOU for watching this video.
Please leave a thumbs up, or down.
Leave a comment, ask questions,
and have a great time until we see you next time!
Yes.
- Bye, bye!
- See you. Have a good one!