- Whole thing?
- Whole thing.
Oh my God. 1, 2, 3.
It tastes like uncooked pasta.
4 out of 5.
I'm not in the frame.
Zero!
- Zero!
Hey, hey!
Today we are trying candy
from Portugal!
Many have asked for this particular video
since we moved here.
We have actually made one before.
A really long time ago.
You had been on a work trip to Madeira
and brought some candy home.
Yes.
Since moving here, we've noticed that
that wasn't typical Portuguese candy.
- No.
So, today we will give you
candy that's typical for Portugal.
- Well, we will give it to ourselves.
- We will try it, quite simply.
- Yay! Shall we begin?
- Yes!
"Flocos de Neve"
It's hard candies in a red wrapper, and they're white.
"Flocos de Neve" means "snowflakes".
No, Laura. You can't eat that.
Not yet.
Laura has a piece of apple
while the rest of us try candy.
- Ready?
- Yes.
Let's go.
- It's good.
- Mhm, it is.
- A bit of a floral taste.
- Yes, a fruity taste.
- Wait, how does a flower taste?
- Good question. I know how flowers smell, though.
- Laura likes her apple.
- She's, like: "Apple is yummier than candy."
We give each candy we try between 1 to 5 points.
Who wants to go first?
I do. I give this little hard candy...
...4 out of 5 points.
- Oh, how high!
- It was really good.
I give it 3 points.
I give it 2 points. I wouldn't buy it, but it's perfectly okay
if I'd get it for free at, like, a bank.
At a bank?
- Isn't that where they offer free hard candies?
- You're right. A bunch of these in a big glass bowl.
- I think I'll change mine to 3 points too.
- Okay.
I also give it 3 strong points.
It was good, but... one or two is enough.
- "Bank-y".
- Good, but "bank-y."
If you notice that the light changes...
- I'm not in the frame.
- Now you are in frame.
...it's because the sun is setting, and we are trying to
make the lighting be the same throughout the video.
It might change a little here and there.
Hope you can stand it.
Sorry about that.
"Regina's Chocolate Umbrella"
This is what it looks like
inside the paper.
It doesn't seem to rain much in Portugal.
This is their definition of umbrellas.
- Shall we?
- Yes.
- I still have the other candy.
- What?!
- You still have the other one?
- Here.
- But I...
- Oh!
That's the crazy corner over there.
I don't know what they're doing. I've already tasted it.
Here we go.
- I need more! I need more!
- It tastes like the chocolate in advent calendars.
- Yes.
- Exactly like it.
- Pretty good.
- A bit better than that.
I agree. Like Milko, or...
- Milka!
- Milka is better than this one, though.
I like that you don't have to hold the chocolate.
You have this little handle.
Yeah, that was nice.
It's like a chocolate lollipop.
What are you doing?
He's shooting me with the umbrella.
A candy that can be used in many ways.
I like the aftertaste of this one,
so I give it 5 points.
- 5 points?
- What?! 5 out of 5?
I give it 2 points.
I wish it was a little more fun.
- Sorry, Laura is so funny. She's, like...
- She's singing into her microphone.
- She's, like: "Is this thing on?"
- She's stealing our show.
- How many points do you give it?
- 3 points. The chocolate is good, and I like the umbrella thing.
I also give it 3 points.
"Gelatina Banana"
It's a jiggly dessert-like... jello.
Is that's what it is?
Yes. Jello.
It comes in a bunch of different flavors.
It tastes like mallow banana,
but in a different form.
- Mm.
- Yes.
- But not as sweet.
- No.
But a bit worse.
- Laura really wants some.
- Do you want a little taste?
- She didn't get any.
- Was it good?
She got a little lick.
It really tastes like it's for kids.
I feel like this is what you get
at a bad children's party.
- "At a bad children's party."
- "Here you go, instead of cake. Eat up."
Okay, then we won't serve these.
- Harry, you have a history of liking these jello things.
- Yes, but this wasn't my jello.
Not your jello, no.
There's a difference between jello and jello.
Yeah.
- I give it 1 point.
- Me too. 1 point.
- 0 out of 0.
- I also give it a 0.
"Pipocas Doces"
It's sweet popcorn.
Oh, how sweet.
- Quite good.
- No.
- I prefer salty popcorn.
- Me too.
- I've never understood this.
- Sweet popcorn? No.
I understand it.
- You like it?
- Yeah.
I give it 3 out of 5 points.
I give it 1.8 out of 5.
- Oh. Okay.
- Specific.
- I give it zero points.
- I also give it zero...
- Zero!
What is it you two do?
Zero!
Zero! Zero!
Everything is zero!
- Laura's just, like...
- Pipita's head is zero!
- She doesn't understand a thing.
- No.
Her eyes are zero.
"Tiras Ácidas"
It's sour little gummy candies
in different colors.
- It's not that sour.
- No.
There's sugar on it.
It tastes like uncooked pasta.
- It's the same texture.
- Very boring texture.
I mean...
This feels like a candy... that parents buy-
-when their child is having a masquerade party
where they're dressing up as, like, princesses and Batmans.
Then this is the candy
that's in the candy bags.
- I give it 2 points.
- I give it 3 points.
- It was yucky and worthless. I give it zero...
Zero! Zero, zero, zero!
"Bem Me Quer"
It's chocolate pralines...
filled with liqueur.
- Laura had enough and wanted to sit with me instead.
- I think she wanted to sit with anyone, just not in her chair.
No. She only wanted to sit with me
because I'm calm and secure.
I'm sure she'll want to get down on the floor soon and cause havoc.
We'll see how long she can stand sitting here.
She'll be like King Kong
Are you ready?
King Kong...
I'm ready.
- I'm ready.
- The whole thing?
- The whole thing.
Oh my God. 1, 2, 3...
You're cheating!
- Look at Alma. She did the Scream mouth.
- Mmm, how good.
What are you doing?
Don't run around and spit.
- I had to...
- It's very... liqueury.
- A lot of spirits.
- It just poured out.
Yeah. And it's like a cherry in there,
with a bit of chewing resistance.
This is probably
one of the worst ones we've ever tried.
It's non-alcoholic.
- What is this?
- That one was so gross and strong.
- So...
- Who even wants to eat this?
Can I just say something?
I feel like you'd have to have, like, a leather tongue to enjoy this.
It's like drinking hand sanitizer.
Yuck! It was so gross.
- I give it zero...
- I also give it 0 points.
- Zero, zero, zero...
- Zero!
Zero, zero, zero, zero!
- The zero choir! The zero choir!
- The zero choir!
We will take a well-deserved break
to answer today's Question of the Day.
"Will Hussein..."
Oh? You say so?
I agree.
"Will Hussein come and visit you in Portugal?"
- Yes! Yes! Yes!
We really hope so.
We are trying to find a sensible time for him to come.
I have something really fun to tell.
He has taken his...
Driver's license!
- In Sweden. We are so happy and proud!
- Yes.
Hooray for Hussein!
"Sugus Laranja"
It's little fruit chewy candies.
- A strong orange flavor.
- Like Maoam.
Exactly! Laura is really jealous.
She also wants to try it. She can't.
She's, like: "I'm King Kong!"
"I'm King Kong!"
It tastes like any other orange fruit chewy candy.
- Yes.
- Mm.
Like the ones you get at a nail salon
when you go with mommy when she has some time off.
I love your descriptions today.
The bank and the nail salon.
You've really been all over town.
- And at a Batman and princess party.
- Yes. Eating candy everywhere.
- Laura thinks we should give out points.
- Okay. I give the orange candy... 2 points.
4 points.
I didn't fart.
That was Laura's foot.
- 5 points out of 5!
- Oh, five!
Oh, wow.
I give it 2 points.
"Solano Café Espresso"
"Sin azúcar"
It's a small sugar-free coffee hard candy.
- This sounds like something for me.
- Mm, indeed.
It smells good.
- No, it smells really gross.
- Oh, it smells like coffee.
- Eww, do you two think this smells good?
- Yes, and I don't even like coffee. Here we go.
Yes!
- I refuse. I didn't take it!
- Cheater!
- Yes. You have to.
- You have to.
It wasn't that bad.
A pretty bad flavor.
Like coffee that has been sitting around in a cup.
It's probably that it's sugar-free.
- It reminds me of the teacher's breath...
- Oh, yuck!
...in middle school, when you asked for help.
The teacher came up to you after lunch, like...
"Yes, Axel."
You were, like...
It tasted like disappointment.
I give it 0 points.
0.000001.
- Oh!
- 0.01? Okay.
- So, it got some points, at least.
- A little.
I give it 0 points. Not for me.
I give it 1 point because it was sugar-free.
It gets a little bonus because of that.
- Zero, zero, zero, zero!
Ouch.
♪ Alma's face is like a zero!
Look at her face! ♪
♪ And her eye is like a zero! And Pipita's, and daddy's
and mine and mommy's! Everything is like a zero! ♪
Help!
- Oh, God.
- I don't know what's happening here now.
"Dr. Bentes Peitoral"
It's hard candies.
- It tastes a little musty.
- I recognize the flavor.
- Yes, from another candy.
- It's like a Greek ouzo hard candy.
I give it...
Laura definitely has had enough of this.
Shall we try and bite into it?
- Yes.
- Okay.
- Ouch, my tooth!
- Did it break?
- Yes.
- What?
- It's the same thing inside it.
- Yeah yeah, but your tooth didn't break?
Oh! No.
Look at this baby!
This has definitely freaked out. I'm sorry, viewers.
You know when you're, like, going with your friend
to their dad's job... and their dad is a broker...
It tastes like that hard candy they give you there.
Exactly like it.
- Really boring hard candy.
- Yeah.
- Yuck.
- That was the most specific description of a candy... of all.
- Yeah.
- I will actually still give it 2 points.
- Oh! I give it 1 point.
- Alma?
- 1 point.
1 point.
That was the last candy for today.
The sun is setting outside. Our faces look nice and orange.
Laura is all over the place.
Thank you for watching this video!
- Please leave a thumbs up, or down.
- Mostly thumbs up!
Comment, ask questions
and take care until next time!
Bye-bye!