- It looks absolutely awful.
- Yes, it looks awful.
It's like a toilet!
Hey, hey!
We are standing outside
Skara Sommarland!
Yep!
- The time is 7:30 - in the evening.
- Yeah.
- The park is closed.
- Everyone has gone home.
We will get to have
the water park to ourselves!
Let's go!
- Welcome!
- Thank you!
Look at all the bubbles!
So many bubbles!
Oh... look.
Laura, look at this!
You love soap bubbles!
Oh, she's trying to eat them.
That's not a very good idea, you stick with the rice cake.
But you can chase them.
Karl is with us. He's the park manager,
and he will be helping us tonight.
Yes.
I almost said "today", but it's "tonight".
It's so funny.
We have been here once before.
Do you remember when?
- Scary Sommarland.
- Exactly. Then it was cold.
- Then it was cold.
- We have never been to the water land.
- No.
- Or do you say "water park"?
- Both names are fine.
Both names are fine.
We haven't been there. This will be so much fun!
Yes, it will be.
- We are overly excited about this.
- Yes.
Oh, wow.
- Here it is!
- Oh, wow! Oh, wow! Oh, wow!
- I mean, how nice with the evening sun?
- This is going to be great!
- Now it's time to switch cameras. Let's go!
- Let's go!
Alma, Harry, and I will start with Racer.
Here you go, a...
- A girl with a sweet tooth.
- Yeah!
Good. See you soon!
- Here you go.
- Thank you.
- Ready?
- Yes.
Ready, set, go!
Now I will ride Vortex.
It's kind of like a toilet.
Okay, here's the entrance.
Oh my God!
Jesus Christ!
Oh, wow!
Sorry, Laura!
Oh, my!
It's fun!
Laura is eating some baby food... and making a mess.
Good thing she's wearing swimwear.
Harry is eating ice cream.
Isn't it a little cold?
Yeah.
- But good.
- Yeah.
Alma and Axel are riding Cobra.
Okay. Ready?
- Oh, the water is so cold. I wasn't prepared for that.
- Some are warm and some are cold.
- Okay!
- Let's go!
- Bye-bye!
This is perfectly fine.
Oh, darn!
Cobra is the best one.
Want to ride it with me, mommy?
- I'd love to! Daddy looks a little...
- I was not ready for that.
I flew the drone over it and thought:
"That one looks scary."
Then, when I rode it, I didn't think it was the same one.
And I rode with my back first, like...
...and just disappeared.
It was so scary.
Oh, Laura!
Hi!
It's so good that you're eating, sweetie!
Oh... but that's good.
That's good.
One-year-olds,
they need to eat with their whole body.
- It's great today.
- Yes.
- In those clothes, I mean.
- Yes. It's perfect.
We have washed Laura.
She looks sunburnt, almost.
- Yeah!
- From the baby food.
Alma and Harry went to a pool to just splash around,
and we are on our way to...
- What's it called?
- Big Drop.
Oh, God.
The family has managed to talk me into...
No one else wants to ride it,
but we definitely want someone to ride it.
- It looks absolutely awful.
- Yes, it looks awful.
Here it is.
Axel is going to drop straight down
through the floor up there...
...go down this slide,
and through this hole.
It looks crazy, because it's open.
It's not, like, a capsule.
Oh, my...
Oh, God.
Yes, I'm ready. Oh, my...
- How was it?
- Oh, God...
That was so unpleasant.
There was just so much water... everywhere.
I swallowed so much water.
But it's so quick. Two seconds!
- Only two seconds?
- Yes! They told me. A two-second ride.
- Oh, God.
- 60 km/h (37 mph).
It's the drop, when the trapdoor opens,
that's when you're, like...
- Yeah, you whizzed by us.
- Yeah.
- Here, you take Laura.
- Yes. Hi, sweetie.
She didn't understand what happened.
Daddy just flew by, screaming.
- She got a little worried, maybe.
- Yes, I think so.
And now daddy has a funny hairstyle.
- What are you two doing?
- We are playing!
- We'll take Laura to the Lagoon area. Do you guys want to come?
- Yes!
- It's up there. It's for the younger kids.
Oh! Look!
Was it scary?
Oh, she got a little scared.
- A little scary.
- But it was pretty fun.
One more time.
Shall we ride it again?
- And those two, terrorists.
- Yeah. They can't refrain from terrorizing each other.
- They're in such a play mode.
- Are they?
- Oh, yes!
- Of course. Who isn't, in a place like this?
Are you okay?
This one was a little more fun.
This is "Forsfärden".
Yabba dabba doo!
Look out!
- Was it fun?
- Yes!
Yabba dabba doo!
That was so much-
- Fun!
- ...fun!
- In unison! It was a blast.
- It really was.
- Look how beautiful... No, you can't see the light.
- We can see the light.
It's pink and orange over there.
It's 10:30 in the evening, and we have energy.
Yes. Laura, too.
So, I thought I'd wing a Question of the Day
because we haven't prepared any. And that is...
"How do you guys prepare
to film a video like this?"
Because this is very late for our kids, especially for Laura.
So, how have we been preparing today?
We... Harry and I took a nap.
- They slept for...
- In the morning.
- Afternoon.
- 2 minutes.
- 2 hours.
- What?!
- 2 hours?
- Oh, yes. Yes, yes, yes.
- God, I thought it was, like, 30 minutes.
No. And Laura slept for 2 hours in the morning,
and 1.5 hours quite late in the afternoon.
- So, we rest up...
- And we ate well.
- Exactly. We eat well.
- A great lunch. It's like when you get ready for a race.
And we charge all the camera batteries, pack all the bags...
It's a whole process.
Mm. To be able to have as much fun as possible,
and film as well as possible.
What do you think of Skara Sommarland's water park?
0-5 points.
- 4.
4.
- A strong 4, for this water park as well!
- Yes.
- I also think it was very good. Better than I thought it'd be.
- Yes. And the water was warm.
- So you didn't think it would be good?
- No, I didn't think it would be that good.
- But it was!
- Yes, it was!
Thank you for watching this video!
- Please leave a thumbs up, or down.
- Mostly thumbs up!
Comment, ask questions, and take care.
See you again soon!
Bye-bye!