This is our hotel room.
Pink.
- Is that your favorite color?
- Yeah. Pink.
I'm so pumped.
Alma, come!
I've never felt like such a bad parent.
No!
Hey, hey!
We are standing outside...
JumpYard!
In Madrid!
And that's in Spain.
Yes! Shall we go in?
It's early in the morning and we're the first ones here.
And it's very cold outside, so let's hurry inside.
Good morning!
- Hello!
- How's it going?
- Great! How are you guys?
We're good.
Of course Mister JumpYard is here.
You'd think there's a Mister JumpYard
at each JumpYard.
Exactly. I've cloned myself and work everywhere.
- Could you give these to Harry?
- Yes.
Yes, come on!
Are these for me? How nice of you.
Jumping socks are a must.
Thank you, thank you!
And these for daddy. Do you think they'll fit?
What?
So shall I have ten, then?
One for each toe.
Tiny, right?
Oh, God. This is Laura-size, isn't it?
- It sure looks so.
- XXS. Extra extra small.
Now you're coming with some that might be better.
These look good. Thank you, Laura!
- Wow, she really likes working here, huh?
- Yes. She might be their youngest addition.
Oh, thanks, Laura. How nice of you!
- Too short.
- Is it too short?
- Mommy... put it on.
- Yes, I'll put it on.
- It be there?
- Yes. What color did you get?
Pink.
- Is that your favorite color?
- Yeah. Pink.
- She's obsessed with pink.
- Yes. Pink is my favorite color too.
- It was Harry's favorite color before.
- Yes, but Harry's favorite color is actually yellow now.
Look at that.
- You guys take so long to put them on.
- Oh, you were so fast. What a pro!
High five!
- Oh, what a climbing section!
- Oh, wow!
- Oh, do you see the disco ball?
- A proper climbing section!
Yes, that's a disco ball up there.
It's so cool that it's two floors.
It's so much bigger.
I'm so pumped.
Alma, come!
- Can we just run off?
- Yes, go ahead!
Wait! Harry, wait!
So, up here are the trampolines,
and here you see the end of the climbing walls.
Very cool layout.
Is that how you say it? Layout.
- Yes, you could say that.
- Layout, of the park.
- Really cool.
- Yes.
There are very large windows
so I have a feeling there's a cool view too.
Oh, for sure. You don't really see it, but it is.
A view of Madrid.
Even though we're all alone in the park,
it's not just us who make noise.
It's a...
Well, some type of air conditioning
that just whistles and makes noise.
- They hear it, I promise.
- I hope you can stand the noise.
- How's it going, Harry?
- Good.
Woho!
This one gives me anxiety.
Does anyone remember?
What was that?
Someone did something you shouldn't do.
As I was saying...
Remember when Harry broke his arm?
- How could they forget that?
- Maybe they haven't followed us that long.
That's true.
He used to hang on monkey bars like these,
as they're called, and fell down.
He lost his grip and fell, and then he put his hand down
and then both bones were broken.
I have never felt like such a bad parent
as I did in that moment.
- No.
- Never again, we hope.
But now he has a fully functioning arm
and is up and climbing new stuff.
Mhm.
No, no...
No!
- Good thing the ground is soft.
- Yes.
- It's only the top one.
Isn't the point that it should be different?
Now! Look.
57.
- Oh, you won big!
- Yes.
Nice job, Alma!
JumpYard has an offer in the Swedish Family Club.
Yep. 20% discount on the one-hour jump,
the two-hour jump, and the family jump.
One and two hours.
Now we're talking about JumpYard in Sweden.
Yes.
And for those of you who don't know,
our club is completely free for members.
In there, you will find many good discounted offers,
and also sometimes giveaways and contests.
Mhm.
- And JumpYard also has a giveaway in the club.
- Yes. Twenty 500 SEK...
- Gift cards.
- Thank you.
Very generous.
20 club members have the chance to get it.
So, if you're not a member
you have to become one, you see.
Yes.
- There's a link in the video description.
- Check it out.
Yes, do that.
- What are you doing?
- We're pretending to sleep, as if we've been waiting a long time.
You have to be quiet.
It was a competition with the elevator.
Gosh!
You took such a long time.
- Oh, what a super YouTuber!
- We're home now.
She didn't even react to you lying there sleeping.
What a fail!
- Daniel?
- Yes?
- Want it.
- Do you want it?
- Mhm.
- Yes.
There. And the other foot, nice.
And let's pull it up.
Oh, wait.
If you hold your arms straight out...
Can you climb when you're this little?
We'll try and see.
If the harness fits as it should, there's no problem.
- It feels very small.
- Wait, Laura.
But shouldn't it feel small and tight?
Isn't that the whole point?
- No.
- I do not want it to feel big and loose when I climb.
- Mommy.
- Oh.
Shall I help you? Shall we ride the elevator again?
Come, let's ride the elevator.
I'll hold you.
Now feel the elevator.
- Daniel, I'm starting to climb.
- Sure.
One more time, come on.
And the elevator, hold on.
- It was a little scary, huh?
- Aha.
- That's why we take it slowly.
- Do you want to ride the elevator again?
- That one.
That one? Go ahead and climb.
Grab here. Can you do that?
Walk up to it.
Yes, I'm holding you. Come.
- Nice!
- Oh, the first time in a harness like this. Sweetie.
Now you can grab this one.
Use that hand. Exactly.
Oops!
It's a little difficult. Let's do it like this.
And grab there.
And now, Laura, you can put your foot there.
Now pull yourself up. Nice!
And now it got difficult.
Alma, you're so fast!
- (Daniel) How old are you now, Laura?
- (Laura) Uaua.
(Daniel) How old are you, Uaua?
- Was it fun?
- Yes.
This is so smart,
this system where you secure yourself.
- I just want to feel that it's okay to climb on.
- Daniel said that you can get some scratches on this wall.
Yes, it's a little scary.
It's made to mimic a mountain.
Well, it is some kind of rock, but yeah…
It's like a volcano. Look.
Ah, now I see. I get it. But yeah...
One that hurts a little, maybe.
Yes. I won't climb it now, I think.
Nice!
- What did you say? Do you want to take it off?
- Yes.
Sure.
You did great! You got super high!
- Yes.
- Yes! Yes, almost all the way up.
It's a joy to film with Daniel.
Partly because he knows how to record and what to think about.
That you shouldn't talk over each other, for example.
But he's also so very good with the kids,
so it's like having the world's best babysitter with you.
- Yes. All kids love Daniel. Mister Jump Yard!
- Mister JumpYard, yes. Exactly.
What passion!
This is life-and-de*th.
Are you tired, Laura?
Tired and hungry.
That's what happens when moving around so much.
Yep!
- What are you guys doing?
- We're trying to... do this. Can't you show how to do it?
- Let's see it again.
- Now we're tired.
Wooo!
- And you're not very good at it yet. Or?
- No. Yes, actually.
Soon.
So-so, I think.
You can practice a little more, Alma.
- What's your plan, Harry?
- I don't have a plan.
Do you remember last time?
Then she had a hard time hitting when it was tight, didn't she?
- Mhm.
- So build it as tightly as possible.
What are you doing, Alma?
We are building a... fort.
Then, we'll try to...
You take ten of these and build a fort.
Or, like, a wall.
And then you have to try to get the other person's wall down
by just throwing these.
You have to be behind these.
Five. Three.
Laura wants to play Valo Jump.
- Turn on the TV.
- You have to jump on the trampoline to get it going, Laura.
YAY! I can do it!
- Are you ready?
- YES!
Ready, set, go!
No!
- Yes!
Nooo!
- We won! Nice work!
- Well done.
Now he comes. Harry doesn't like to lose!
Oh, wow! Watch out, watch out!
Come on, Harry! Fight, fight! All the way.
All the way!
You're not there yet, we still have one left!
Whoo!
Good, Harry.
Fight! Fight, Harry!
Yayyy!
You keep bouncing…
even though we're at the hotel.
- Uaua jump more.
- Yes, you want to jump more. It was so much fun at JumpYard.
- Did you have fun too, Alma?
- Yes, it was super fun.
- Sit down, JumpYard, sleep.
- Are you going to sleep a little now?
- JumpYard, sleep.
- Yes, you need that when you've been up so early and filmed.
We are in our hotel room.
- No, the airplane!
- No, we're not on the airplane.
Ride the airplane again. I want to go to Japan.
You want to go by plane to Japan.
But I think we should drive home later.
But maybe we should show what it looks like here.
- No, don't go home later.
- Yes.
- No.
- You want to stay here and be at JumpYard with Daniel?
Yes.
This is where we're staying.
Mommy, daddy, and Laura
sleep in this room.
Mhm.
And we have two hotel rooms,
so it's like a double room with this door.
Right. A connecting door that can be unlocked.
- Yes, exactly. And Harry and I sleep here.
- Yes.
- That's pretty much it.
It's quite small and very messy,
but that doesn't really matter.
- No, we're only here in Madrid on a quick visit.
- Yes.
- To visit the new park.
It's great fun that JumpYard is expanding abroad.
Spider-Man!
- Come.
- Spider-Man.
Spider-Man is expanding abroad.
No, but JumpYard is a Swedish company.
I don't think everyone knows that.
No.
- And then we go around and then we meet Daniel in every park we visit.
- Yes.
We call him Mister JumpYard.
He's always there when a new park opens.
They're opening new ones in Sweden, and also abroad.
We have been to Lisbon. More...?
And now Madrid.
Yes.
Västerås, right?
- Västerås. Very fun.
- And Nacka, many times.
Yes, we have been to the one in Nacka many times,
in Stockholm.
- Västerås.
- Västerås. Yes. We might have to go back there.
- Västerås! Go to Västerås!
- She wants to go to Västerås.
- But listen.
- Yes.
- Question of the Day.
- Mhm.
One popped up very naturally when we entered the JumpYard
this morning. Our favorite color.
- RIght.
- Pink. Pink.
Yes. Pink and pink.
- Green.
- Green?! She said yours was yellow.
- Yes.
- Oh, right.
YELLOW!
- Do you have two?
- Yes. Yellow, grey, and green.
Three. Yellow, grey, and green.
Mine is...
- Yellow-grey-green.
- You're really a talker, aren't you?
Pink.
- Mine is red.
- Like JumpYard's colors.
What about you?
I feel that I answer this question differently every time.
Yes.
But maybe orange, or orange-pink.
What's your favorite color?
Comment below!
Thank you for watching this video!
Please leave a thumbs up, or down.
Mostly thumbs up!
Comment, ask questions,
and take care until next time.
- See you!
- Bye-bye!