Iceland, here we come!
- Laura, was it good?
- Ah... No!
Not my cup of tea.
I think licorice tastes like burnt car tires.
Okay, let's go!
Hey, hey!
Today we are trying candy
from Iceland!
We got this package a long time ago
from a very sweet viewer, named Freya.
Yes.
- "Ouii!"
- Yes, it's full of "ouii"! (Candy)
It kind of got lost in the house.
Then we found it and was, like, "Let's do this!"
What did Alma and Harry say then?
- No.
It's only licorice, and we hate licorice.
- It's not only licorice.
- Yes!
Let's be positive. How sweet is Freya
to have sent us this candy from Iceland?
- Very!
- Yes, of course, but it's just...
They're not feeling it, but heck, let's do this!
Are you ready?
Yes!
"Sterkur Draumur"
It's a chocolate candy
with a licorice rope inside.
The rope inside is salty licorice.
- How do you know that?
- It says so on the packaging.
- Laura has already started. We need to catch up.
- Yes, let's go.
- He didn't eat it.
- You're cheating!
- You didn't eat it?
- No.
- Try it, Harry.
- Was it good?
- Yes, it was good.
- Mm!
Laura, you seem to really like it.
- Exciting with a rope in the chocolate.
- Yes.
Exciting execution, you could say.
Alma was, like...
- What do you think?
- I mean...
Harry disappears.
I've had worse licorice.
This one wasn't that bad.
- I think the licorice was better than the chocolate.
- Mm.
- Mine!
- Okay, okay.
- Laura seems to like it a lot.
- Yes.
Not really my cup of tea.
How many points do you give it? 0-5.
2 points.
I give it...
- Oh no, she's throwing up over here.
- ...an easy zero.
- Zero, zero, zero...
- Zero, superhero!
- Harry, did you notice what just happened here?
- No.
- She's, like, throwing up. Laura, was it good?
- Ah... No!
- I give it 3 points.
- I also give it 3 points.
♪ Gimme, gimme, gimme some time to think
I'm in the bathroom, looking at me ♪
- Are you a little ashamed of me?
-  ♪ ...is all I need. ♪
♪ Gimme, gimme, gimme some time to think
I'm in the bathroom, looking at me ♪
"Old fashioned licorice"
It's soft licorice pieces.
They look like parts of a... licorice roll.
This will probably be the candy I like the least.
Pure licorice! Who eats this?
You're so negative.
Lots of people eat it. I eat it.
I thought we would eat this last.
It's not good that you've already seen the candies.
We normally don't do that.
- No.
- I can tell now that this was no good idea.
- Let's try it.
Okay then.
Oh, sweet licorice.
Well... it probably is a bit salty.
It was good.
I'll have another one.
How can one dislike licorice that much?
Are all kids like this? No.
- No.
- No. Only you two are this silly.
Eww. No, I can't do this.
- No, eww.
- You don't like it either?
"No, eww."
I mean...
Does Iceland have a lot of licorice?
We can throw out the question to those of you
who are from there, live there, or have been there.
- Maybe there are a lot of sweets from other countries there.
- Right.
Maybe the Icelandic candy
consists of a lot of licorice.
Hey, this is my seat!
Musical chairs!
How many points do you give it?
Zero, zero, zero, zero...
- Zero, zero, zero, zero, zero...
- ...zero, zero, zero, zero, zero...
- "Zeo, zeo!"
- "Zeo, zeo."
I love that you have a big zero
on your chest now too, Harry.
- Yeah, exactly. Here.
- ...zero, zero, zero, zero, zero...
"Zeo, zeo, zeo..."
Okay, the kids agree on zero points.
How many does Axel give it?
- I give it 1 point.
- I give it 2 points.
Don't forget to give the video a thumbs up
if you like when we try candy.
"Sambó Thristur"
It looks like an ordinary chocolate praline.
An ordinary chocolate praline...
with licorice in it.
- What?
- Mm.
- I don't really taste the licorice.
- Neither do I.
- That's because the last one was so strong.
Harry, eat it! Stop cheating.
- I like the texture.
- I also like the texture. It's very special.
- This one actually wasn't that bad.
- Like a mixture of chocolate praline and chewing gum.
Maybe now it's happening...
they're starting to like licorice.
- Exactly.
- No.
Iceland, here we come!
No, never. Never!
I think licorice tastes like burnt car tires.
- But you're for "Iceland, here we come!", right?
- Yes, I am.
- Who doesn't want to go to Iceland?
- Good question.
Laura has put her pacifier in her mouth.
She doesn't seem too excited to try it.
Harry, how many points do you give it?
- 3 points.
- 3 points?
- A strong 3 points.
- Me too.
- Oh.
- Oh, wow!
- Me too.
Hey, now you have to stop that drum orchestra.
We all give it 3 points.
- Yes.
- Okay, let's go!
"Lakkrís Karamelluperlur"
Round chocolate pearls
filled with licorice.
- I think this one could be pretty good.
- Why do you think that?
Because... it's caramel.
Let's try it!
1, 2, 3.
Mmm...
Pretty good, Alma.
Pretty good.
The chocolate tastes like dust.
Or maybe it's the licorice
that tastes like dust.
- It almost tastes like alcohol, in some weird way.
- Yeah. Very adult and boring.
No, not fun. Not fun.
D*mn.
No...
I'm sorry.
This is like one of those candies that old people have
that never gets eaten.
God, I got all giggly.
This one was actually awful.
Yeah, it was really boring. And I took another one.
I don't understand why I took another one.
Okay, mommy starts with:
Zero...
Zero.
Zerooo...
Zero!
Very nice! Very good!
- We take a break to answer today's Question of the Day.
- Yes.
It's from Freya, who sent the package.
"If Laura had been a boy...
- Uaua.
- Yes, exactly. Uaua.
...what would his name have been?"
- Very good question.
- Do you remember?
I don't think we had any names.
- Yes.
- Leo.
- No.
- Yes. That was Harry's suggestion.
- We talked about Eliott.
- Eliott was my suggestion.
- What was my suggestion?
Sten. (Stone)
I'm sorry to all the Stens out there,
but to imagine Laura as "Sten"...
- No, she's not a Sten. She's a Laura.
- Yes. Or a Pupita!
Pupita!
"Nóa Kropp"
It looks like chocolate with bubbles.
- This is the first candy that doesn't contain licorice.
- Yes!
- Let's go!
- There weren't any bubbles.
- Yes, there's a wafer in there. Like little wafer bubbles.
Yes, okay.
The chocolate on the other candies
was so much better than this chocolate.
I agree.
- Is it good?
- Aha.
- That's good.
- Laura likes this one. How many points do you give it?
I give it 3 out of 5.
- And Harry?
- 3 out of 5.
2 out of 5.
- Why are we saying "out of 5" all of a sudden?
- 2 points.
I give it 2 points.
- Do you need help getting up?
- Yes, please.
Ouch. Harry...
God, you guys are too weird.
(Song from That boy Emil)
♪ I am a poor farmer, but I live anyway ♪
"Lakkrís Rjómasúkkulaði með Lakkrísbitum"
It looks like an ordinary piece of chocolate
but with little bumps on the underside.
- I feel like we've eaten the same thing over and over.
- Yes.
- Chocolate with licorice in it.
- Yeah. It's getting a bit repetitive.
- This one had sweet licorice in it though.
- What? I think it's salty.
I seem to have a bit of a hard time telling if it's sweet or salty,
but... there's licorice in it.
- Tiny sticky squares.
- Yes.
I think this tastes like old Kinder Surprise Egg chocolate...
with burnt car tires in it.
I give this chocolate 1 point.
I give this chocolate... zero!
Zero!
Zero.
ZEROOO!
Zero!
"Djúpur"
That is... white balls with licorice.
Eww. Oh, no!
It wasn't fun. It isn't fun.
It's very sandy. It's licorice sand.
Not fun.
But it wasn't strong or anything like that.
This is the worst licorice I've ever had.
It gets stuck in the teeth. You're like, eww...
You're picking your teeth.
There's like fine dust in the whole mouth.
He's pulling out his tongue.
Do you know what?
This was the last Icelandic candy.
- YAY!
What do we think of Iceland? Good!
What do we think of Icelandic candy?
- Bad!
- No, this feels awful.
- Maybe Iceland's licorice...
Yes, exactly!
What do we think of Icelandic licorice?
But...
I feel a little guilty for Freya who has been so kind
and bought and sent us candy.
Yes, that was so nice.
It's just that Harry and I really don't like licorice.
- No.
It's not our thing.
Is it your thing, you guys at home?
Is licorice your thing?
Comment down below!
Thank you for watching this video!
- Please leave a thumbs up, or down.
- Mostly thumbs up!
Comment, ask questions
and take care until next time.
Bye-bye!