Zingo, spin around.
Do you want a treat?
Here you go.
He is quite disobedient.
This is the robot dog Duke.
Alma has been trying it out in collaboration with Silverlit.
If you saw our video "What's in the box" you know that
we tested Robo Kombat, which became Harry's favorite.
- Should we turn him off?
- Yes, let's turn him off.
There, off.
It says "Duke" here, but Alma named him Zingo.
You record different.... what's it called?
It's called...
When you train them... Calls? No.
It's called "commands" in English.
Yes, commands.
Then the dog should do what you ask.
It works pretty good.
Yes, but I would rather
have a real dog.
Yes, of course. That brings us into
Question of the Day - at the start of this vlog.
Elina Larsson asks:
"Do you want any pets?".
- Harry, you can answer first.
- I want...
I have to think.
- Should I answer it first?
- Yes.
I want a rabbit, a cat or a dog.
It doesn't matter which, just one of those.
- Cat.
- Cat, yes.
Axel and I can definitely imagine getting a pet, but not
when we are about to travel nor while we live in the city.
If we move to a house
you can definitely get a pet.
- When we move back home.
- No, not when we move to the apartment.
- What?
- No. It's nicer to the pet if it can run outside.
Yes, even if it's an indoor cat
or an indoor dog or whatever.
- In the meantime something like this is pretty good.
- Yes.
A robot dog.
From one animal to another,
now we will go to a horse stable. Fun, right?
Yes!
Alma has been in riding school this fall.
Many of you have asked for a vlog from the stable.
We asked Alma's riding school and they didn't want us
to film there, so we put out a call on Instagram.
- So great.
- Indeed.
A girl named Emelie reached out and we are now
on our way to her stable, Hästravaganza.
- And... Harry will be riding for the first time.
- For the first time, yeah! ♪
I don't know the horses and I have
never been there before, so I'm a bit nervous.
Merry Christmas!
Hey!
- Daddy.
- Hey, Harry.
- Welcome to Hästravaganza.
- Thank you!
The horses are ready for you,
shall we go and get them?
What a luxury, you don't need to
groom them or pick their hooves.
- In here are things you can borrow.
- Oh, there are lots of things in here.
- Let's see what we can find.
- Here are different vests.
Yes, exactly.
Oh, it's so hard.
Ouch.
Fully equipped.
- This way?
- Yes.
This is Erik, we will ride him today.
He's a Norwegian Fjord horse, an older gentleman.
Hey, hey.
He didn't wave back.
Wave, you have to wave back!
This is Dorina.
Hello, Dorina.
- They are a bit bigger than what you are used to, Alma.
- Right. Dorina is a Black Forest horse.
- Are you nervous?
- No, I'm scared. Scared, scared!
She loves to give kisses,
she loves people.
And food.
- Do you want to kiss her?
- No!
- Should I kiss her?
- Yes.
No thanks, I would rather not.
But I can pet her.
- How are you?
- I'm fine.
Oh! There's the track.
Put your foot through here. Nice.
Nice, Alma.
Don't fall off now.
Are you ready?
Brave!
Brave, brave, brave, brave, brave...
- Want to come to this one, or are you good over there?
- I'm good over here.
Okay, I will come to you then.
Oh... this will be a bit tricky.
- Put your left foot through here.
- No, your other foot.
There you go,
and put your leg over.
- What should I hold onto?
- Either the saddle or this handle here.
- I think I have to... well, it's on max.
- We will just have to twist another turn.
There.
- Does it feel cool? You are so high up!
- I'm bigger than you.
Yes, you are.
I think this is a sport for Harry.
I think he will love this.
- Should I go now, daddy?
- Very soon, we just have to fix this one as well.
- This is so scary.
- She is so kind, just stands still and waits.
Here we go.
Yeehaw!
Alma! Alma!
- Straight in the saddle. Does everything feel good?
- Yes.
- The movements are bigger on a bigger horse, right?
- Mhm.
Lean forward a bit while we walk up this hill. Hold onto
the horse's mane - its hair, and stand up in the saddle.
And let's walk up the hill.
- That was scary.
- It's like being on a roller coaster ride.
Yeehaw, roller coaster!
Let's speed it up a bit.
- Alma, has it been harder with a bigger horse?
- No, easier, and more fun.
- Why is that?
- I don't know, it's just more fun on a bigger horse.
- Hey.
- Where have you been?
- I flew the drone while you were riding.
- It seems like they have had so much fun.
- Great fun! When they trotted... Harry went "Yeehaw!".
Now we will go inside the riding arena and trot
one more lap before it's... done, or what you call it.
It will be so fun
to see this footage.
- We are home.
- Yay!
I, Alma and Harry are, anyway.
He is playing a game in there.
Daddy Axel is out to dinner with his dad
and his sisters, and we went home.
- What do you think of the day?
- It was fun.
It was fun to ride at a different stable
and on different horses, I must say. Very, very fun.
I'm drawing a dog.
It's obedient
and it's called Sötnos (cutie).
- Are you hungry?
- Yes.
- We will make our own pizza.
- Yay, yay, yay!
- Harry, come and make pizza with us.
- No, I'm busy.
- Hey you, one is never too busy to eat.
- But can I play a bit more?
- No. Alma, is that your towel over here?
- Oops, sorry. I forgot it there.
I had a shower after the stable.
Harry will begin making his pizza,
and I'm his assistant.
- I need cheese.
- But Harry, you need tomato sauce first.
Oh, right.
I put that on my last one.
Thanks.
Let's sprinkle it on.
There we go.
- How was it to ride?
- Fun. It was most fun to trot.
It was like...
And faster.
I ran like this.
What did you say or do
to make the horse start trotting?
- They turned out great!
- Mommy, can you cut it?
Yes, I will help you.
In our family we cut our pizzas
with scissors, and eat with our hands.
♪ Yeah, I'm gonna take my horse to the old town road
I'm gonna ride 'til I can't no more ♪
♪ I'm gonna ride 'til I can't no more
I got the horses in the back... ♪
- It's really good.
- Yes.
I'm back home.
It's very late, the kids are asleep.
- This was such a fun day.
- Yes, it was actually fun.
- Good riding school.
- Yes.
We have to go to sleep,
we have so much to do before our trip.
Well, not right this moment,
but these next few days.
Very much, so we will kind of
go into radio silence.
See you in our next video
and thank you for watching this one.
Thumbs it up or down.
Let us know what you think, leave a comment.
Take care until next time.
Bye bye!