Hello Hello!
We're going on an adventure!
- Yes!
What a stupid I sounded ...
Yes.
- She's a bit goofy ... - Yes.
- ... but very, very good!
- I'm so ridiculous.
We have taken a taxi, for two hours, from our hotel.
Yeah!
And now we go out to the Phang Nga Gulf and ... go some boat.
Turn around, so they see.
Right now we are waiting for them to call us up.
Well!
Pink!
(pink) They call us up now.
- Yes, what good!
- Alma and Harry!
- But I want to buy a water ... - We'll take it on the way back!
They let go of us at a small shop, where we would like to wait.
We got these pink stickers.
And yes ... now we will go a boat with others who have got pink stickers.
- We are a bunch on, what can it be ... maybe 30 people.
- Yes.
From different hotels.
- There are actually no Swedes.
- No.
... what we have noticed so far.
- Mom, my suit has dried.
- How nice!
Alma's swimming costume was a little wet this morning.
It is very hot.
(in English) Hello then!
(in English) Hello!
(in English) No, please.
(in English) Good morning!
Welcome!
A small bus ride to the boat.
- Are you peppered?
- Yes a little!
We're going to jump on a boat.
Now we are far out on a pier.
Now you can go carefully.
Good!
- We will go this boat.
- Oh, what a nice!
Dad, check out everyone ...
(in English) Yes.
Thanks!
(English speech throughout the stage)
Welcome, welcome!
- Good morning!
Welcome!
Hello!
- Thanks.
Good morning!
- Good morning!
- Hello!
- How many are you?
Four people.
- Yes.
- boy or girl?
Girl?
- Boy.
Boy.
Hello, boy!
- Boy with long hair.
- Yes Yes!
Good job, Harry!
This is really typically us.
We embark on a big excursion two days onto the trip, when we are still jet lagged.
We had a really strange night.
Alma couldn't sleep, and we three were up to half past four.
Yes.
Nine we were picked up with the bus.
We were up at seven.
But it will be very exciting anyway!
- Fun to see the Thai island world.
- Yes, we should not just ride this big boat!
We are going to paddle kayak.
Into caves.
(in English) Do you want something to drink, sir?
(in English) Yes, please.
(in English) Coca-Cola or Sprite?
(in English) Sprite, please.
Alma, you must not point.
(in English) say please?
(in Thai) "Thanks".
(in Thai) Thanks!
Yeah!
(in English) and you, a little drink?
(in English) Thanks, that's good.
(in English) No thanks, that's good.
- We arrive at our first stop.
- Yes!
- An island called ... - Panak Island.
- We will take a kayak into a beach and swim a little.
- Yes.
It will be great, because as soon as we stop moving forward with the boat ...
... as soon as it stops fan, it gets very hot!
Yes.
The island is crap!
- Hörrudu, you say so?
- Yes but ... shit means poop, and poop is not a swear word!
I think it's a swear word.
What do you think?
You can vote!
Should Alma get a fine?
That's how it is in our family.
If you swear, you have to pay 1 kroner.
- Answer Yes or No.
- Alma.
Give 1 crown to me.
- Reply no no, answer no, no ... - now I'll take a crown of you!
Here we go!
Up there there is a cave!
Should we go check out?
- Yes, yes, yes.
- Okay!
A small, small cave.
Here you could live.
- You could live in it ... - mm!
- ... but you can't close around.
- No.
- There is no such cave with a large stone in the way.
Are you hungry?
- Yes!
Now it's lunch.
Check out, show ... it looks really mug!
Come, Alma and Harry.
(in English) ... carrot, corn cob.
Okay.
What do you do for something cozy?
Harry wanted to share a towel with me.
- Is it good?
- MHM!
We are at the James Bond Island.
On this island, some scenes were recorded for the James Bond movie The Man With The Golden Gun.
It's a big deal here in Thailand.
Our...
Our guide has been talking about this very much, and danced around with guns and stuff!
Yes.
But, yes ... so it looks, anyway!
We arrive at an island, and we will jump in the canoes again.
Then you can go canoe into a cave.
I don't know if you look there ...
- There are a lot of tourists here.
- Yes it is.
- These are popular excursion destinations.
- Yes.
(in English) Okay one, two, three.
Sit down.
(in English please!
- Harry?
- Yes?
It's a guy who paddles for us now!
I know.
(in English) Excuse me, where are you from?
(in English) Sweden!
(in English) What's your name?
(in English) My name is Joanna, and this is Harry.
(in English) My name is Tche.
Tche.
- His name is Tche, Harry.
Can you say it?
- Tche.
Hello Hello!
Hello!
- So, how spoiled is this not?
- This is very nice!
We are going into a cave now called Bat Cave.
There are bats!
So it will be dark now ...
Exciting!
- Will you see the bats?
- I do not know.
(in English) Can we see the bats?
(in English) Yes ...
(in English) okay.
What?
Perhaps.
(in English) lie down.
Well!
Harry, we have to lie down now.
- Why?
- Because it's so crowded there.
Okay, this feels ...
Interesting.
How does it feel to you?
You have to lie down all the time, Harry!
In here it smells ...
Fart.
Oh, how dark it is!
If you look up in the ceiling now it is full of bats.
I do not see anything?
Check out where the lights are.
(in English) Very many.
- Can you sit up now?
- No!
Not yet.
Now?
(in English) okay ...
Now.
I saw lots of bats.
- It was full of bats.
- It was completely crazy!
It was cold ...
... and it smelled of a bargain.
Yes.
I think they have pooped in the sea.
Do you think it was the bat bay that smelled?
Alma, Alma!
- Alma, did you see the bats?
- Yep.
I was a little scared.
I thought the bats would wake up and fly around.
They were awake!
- No, they slept.
- Don't scare me ...
- What day!
- What a fantastic day!
- Fantastic ending I think, Harry!
- Yes, it was so fun to dance a little.
And what you danced well, Harry!
You flossed fantastic there in the background.
Now that Harry eats pineapple, we will take a question of today, which I came up with ... fits very well.
Melba Jansson wonders:
"If you were a pineapple, who would be allowed to eat you then?"
- None.
- No one, okay.
Some kind man would be allowed to eat me.
A prime minister, or a king, or someone who has influence ...
... and which then chooses to do something good.
Alma disappeared with her friend.
When we come ashore we will go to our hotel, and just ... cover.
I don't know ... Clock is kind of sex now?
In the next vlog we will show our hotel, and the water land that is there!
Right!
Thanks for watching this video!
... thumbs up or down!
(in English) See you next time!
Bye!