- These make you sweaty.
- I felt that.
- Zero, zero, zero.
Hey, hey!
Today we are trying candy
from Finland!
Where they invent things.
Oh? Maybe so.
In our latest "Opening mail"-video we received
Finnish candy by a kind viewer in Finland, named Ingrid.
She asked if we wanted to try
Finnish candy, and we said "Yes!".
Shortly thereafter,
this showed up with "Posti".
Here's a letter!
This package, full of Finnish candy, was sent to us from
Liam and Tindra, and their parents Sabrina and Robert.
They live in Ekenäs in Finland,
and they want us to try this Finnish candy.
- Of course we will.
- So fun! Are you ready?
- Yes!
- Yes! Let's go.
"Pantteri - Sour Cat"
It's jelly candies
shaped like panther faces.
- Do we just pick a color each?
- I'll try this yellow one.
- I'll try a pink one.
- I'll try this one.
- Orange. What's left for me?
- Green or black.
I'll try a green one.
- Ready?
- Yes.
1, 2, 3...
- Fruity. Quite sweet, not that sour.
- No! "Sour Cat" - I don't think it's that sour.
Harry seems to like it.
No, Harry...
- He's doing the... "flappity-flap man".
- Help! What does this mean?
- Scatman?
- I don't know.
- I flew away.
- You flew away. Was it that good?
- Don't smack. The viewers go crazy.
- Oh, sorry.
We get comments about that
every time we try candy.
If our smacking annoys you, I'm really sorry.
It's difficult to avoid.
How many points
do you give it from 1-5?
Harry first.
- 4.
- 5+.
- 5+, wow. 3.5.
- 3.
"Suffeli"
It's a chocolate dipped wafer.
Oh, there's caramel in it.
- It just tastes like "Kexchoklad". (a chocolate wafer)
- Nice! I've had so many boring wafer-candies.
- It's much better than "Kexchoklad", Harry.
- And much better than the wafers in bags. Really good.
- There's something white in here too.
- That's banana-mallow-mallow, or something.
From 1-5, I think...
Maybe... Let me think.
Two fives.
- Two fives?
- Yes.
I think 5+, again.
I think it was so good!
- Yes. Me too.
- Me too. I give it 5 points.
I give it 4 points.
- Almost a "full potter".
- Almost.
A potter?
- It's a saying. (full score)
- Oh, I thought you meant a full potty.
- "Almost a full potty". No.
- No, absolutely no full potty.
Don't forget to hit the thumbs up button
if you like when we try candy.
"Pepe"
It's a soft licorice stick.
I ate these when I was a kid, it's delicious.
Well, I thought so back then. It's sweet licorice.
- Eww...
- It's super good!
It looks like
the world's longest cigarette.
- Cigarettes aren't usually black.
- And you don't usually blow in them.
- Good texture on licorice.
- Super good.
Hey you!
Don't try it, Harry.
Awesome, Harry. Good job.
I mean... what's wrong with you guys?
It sounds like he's spitting down my neck - he's not.
There's a sink back there.
How can you not like sweet licorice?
- It's delicious.
- I think so too.
I don't like licorice because it's
black, gross, sticky, long...
Oh, a hiccup.
It's gross!
I don't like licorice because it's
salty and sweet all in one, and it's a "biter" and...
- "Biter"?!
- A biter flavor, I wonder what that is.
You haven't understood
the good things in life.
Or maybe a slimy snail
mixed with black pudding.
Is it just our kids
that don't like licorice?
Do your children like licorice? Or if you are a child,
do you like licorice or not? Please comment below.
- Comment.
- Please do. A lot.
♪ Zero, zero, zero... ♪
Okay, we get the hint.
Stop throwing candy!
- I give it 4 points.
- I give it 2 points.
"Maxi Pätkis Crunchy"
It's a crunchy chocolate bar.
- Oh, mint...
- Yes. Mint, yummy.
Mm, it was pretty good.
- It could've been so much tastier.
- Mm, if it wasn't minty.
I agree, but not because of the mint.
It was alright, but the texture wasn't very fun.
Where's he going? Oh.
0 points.
- Zero?
- I don't like mint, at all.
1 point.
I'm nice now, I give it 2 points. I liked the puffed rice
and the chocolate, but I hated the mint.
Oh, okay.
I also give i 2 points.
"Ässä"
It's little jelly candies in different colors,
and they're shaped like letters.
- I think you say "ässä".
- What did I say?
- You said "ässä".
- Oh, what a big difference.
Let's try it.
- 1, 2, 3...
- Go.
Good. Nice and sour.
I'll take another one.
- Oh, these are ones that make you sweaty.
- I felt that.
Sweaty eyelids.
Don't smack, don't smack.
- Oh, they're really sour. Good!
- Have you tried the yellow one?
- No.
- Yes. It was good.
- Don't smack!
- Oh... so synthetic.
The smack-police.
- I give it 5 points.
- Oh! Good. I give it 3.5 points.
- Five fives.
- Oh!
They're rolling around in my head.
I give it 4 points.
"Karl Fazer - Maitosuklaa"
It's milk chocolate.
The Finnish equivalent of Marabou.
- But a bit more boring.
- According to you.
- I think so. It tastes more like... hot chocolate.
- It kind of tastes like "grandma" to me.
Good. Nice.
More tasty.
I mean, more flavors inside.
It was good.
I give it 3 points.
Everything at once.
I also give it 3 points.
And Alma?
4 points.
I also give it 3 points.
Let's take a break and answer Question of the Day
which is from Liam and Tindra, in their letter.
They wonder if we will ever come visit
their small town, Ekenäs, if we travel to Finland.
We would love to.
I actually think I've been to Ekenäs.
- You have?
- I think so. With my dad, like... oh God, 20 years ago.
Oh my gosh!
We're old.
We would love to visit Finland.
All of Finland!
This darn virus
just has to go away first.
Yes. But, we would love to
come to Finland and visit you there.
Yes!
"Suffeli Puffi Snacks"
It's chocolate puffs.
Oops!
♪ The inside is corn,
but it kind of looks like poop. ♪
♪ And it looks like
a tiny deer turd. ♪
The sugar has gone
to their heads.
- It tastes just like corn.
- Mm, it tastes like corn, kind of.
Well, puffed corn, with chocolate.
I liked the other "Suffeli" better.
Me too.
It tastes like badly popped...
I mean, like not well-popped popcorn
with like, a chocolate coating.
I give this candy 1.5 point.
I didn't think it was that good.
I give it 3 points.
0 points.
3 points.
"Hedelmä Aakkoset"
It's diamond shaped jelly candies.
Oh, my poor little "H".
- Did you eat an "H"?
- Yes.
They all have letters.
They like alphabet candies in Finland.
I think.
I think this candy was like
a boring "Gott & Blandat" candy. 1 point.
2 points.
- 1.
- 2.
"Jim Bites"
It's a piece of chocolate
with a white filling.
- It's like, foamy...
- Oh, eww...
- It's a weird mallow flavor.
- It's like a really bad mallow candy.
- It's a little sour.
- It almost tastes like alcohol.
I popped up
at the wrong place.
- What's happening?
- I don't know.
Things are going south here.
What are you two doing?
- They're spitting out the candy.
- Oh.
♪ I give it 0 points! ♪
♪ Zero... ♪
♪ I give it 0 points.
Swimming around... ♪
- 1 point.
"Gifu"
It's tiny black pastilles.
- Too hard.
- It tastes like "Viol" pastilles.
- Yes, it does!
- It's really good.
- Calm down. You have to taste it before you react.
- You have to really chew on it.
I liked "Viol"-flavor when I was little.
It has xylitol, so it's like... fresh.
- It is a bit like "Läkerol" pastilles.
- Mm.
- It's good for the teeth... xylitol is.
- Candy that's good for the teeth...
- Xylitol is good for the teeth.
- Yes.
- I give it 2 points.
- I give it 1 point.
- 1 point.
- 3 points.
"Tyrkisk Peber"
It's a black hard candy
that many Swedes have tried.
But not Alma and Harry.
- You have to chew this one.
- Chew it to pieces.
But "Tyrkisk Peber" is so good!
Are we not good parents, or what?
- I don't think it's that bad.
- I love "Tyrkisk Peber"! I loved it as a kid too.
Yes, it's so nice!
- My mouth is on fire, for real!
- But it's in a good way.
- Did you break it?
- Yes, it was like a grainy sauce inside.
No, it's a powder.
And it's like... in the mouth.
Look, it's a fire. A yummy fire.
- Harry, did you bite yours?
- No. Luckily.
- Luckily? Yeah...
- Then you haven't even tasted it for real.
It's a pretty fun candy to have on Halloween
when someone comes knocking on your door.
I give it 4 points.
I give it 1 point.
I give it 4.5 points.
Zero!
Thank you for watching this video!
Please leave a thumbs up, or down.
Most up, most up!
Leave comments, ask questions
and take care until next time.
Bye bye!