We have created a family club!
♪ Happy birthday to you! ♪
- The last push for the autumn semester now.
- Yes.
I feel like I'm wearing my school uniform.
- Hello!
My very own plushie!
Look!
- Good morning.
- Good morning. It's a weekday morning.
- Yes, and I'm actually going to school soon.
- Yes. New braids.
New braids that mom made.
I'm doing volume, volume, volume.
Now I don't understand anything.
What do you mean "doing volume"?
Volume, volume...
I'm pulling on them a bit, like this.
Oh. I didn't understand anything.
What did you say, Laura?
What did you say?
- I'm drawing.
- Yes, you're drawing. It looks so nice.
An ant.
An ant. Well...
A lobster.
An ant.
- Okay, it's a Laura ant.
- A lobster.
Today I thought maybe we should
do some gaming.
- Yay, how fun!
- After school. It could be fun, right?
Check out that smile.
There's someone who likes gaming.
- The last push for the autumn semester now.
- Yes. Bye-bye!
- Have a nice day at school.
Alma and Harry have taken the train to school
and I've dropped off Laura at kindergarten.
- So now it's just the two of us in the vlog.
- Yep, for a while anyway.
There's a lot going on in our family right now.
Well, that goes for all families before Christmas, I think.
But, we've had an idea
which we've been working on for quite some time.
Yes. An idea we can finally talk about.
- Yes. We have created a family club.
- Yes, a community.
- Where the membership is free.
- Yes.
- And we think you should become members.
- Yes. The basic idea is to save time and money for families with kids.
We know that there's a lot you want to do as a family,
but the more people there are, the more it costs.
Yes, and we know it's hard to find the time
when you have kids of different ages.
So in the club, we will collect
nice offers and discounts-
-on everything from necessary things such as grocery bags,
to fun experiences that you want to do as a family.
Yes.
Over the years, we have built up
quite a large experience-
-about what our family and our kids think is fun to do,
and what you think is fun to do.
So we have contacted places that we have been at,
and they're in the club now with great offers.
- We have built a website with very small means.
- Very, very, very.
We don't have a bunch of money.
We are doing this in collaboration with Miia and Ramin,
our friends down here, who have been in our videos before.
- Yes. And now we're actually going to go in and meet Ramin.
- At their office in Lisbon.
- Yes.
- And take a look at the club website.
- Aren't you supposed to say, "Come along"?
- Come along!
- I always feel like a child when I wear a backpack.
- And I feel like I'm wearing my school uniform.
Yes, you're also wearing a backpack.
But it's the best way to carry a computer.
Yes, I feel that my back is getting old,
so I can't seem to carry it any other way.
Then I get back pain.
- Oh, it got so dark.
- Oh!
There. Now.
- It takes a while before the camera catches on.
- Yes.
- Hello!
- Welcome!
- How's it going?
- Fine, thanks.
- Hey!
- Hey! Oh, what a colorful shirt!
- Right?
- Stylish!
- The African find.
- Yes.
- Perfect. Welcome.
- I'm very happy with it. Thanks.
- I see that Ramin has filled the fruit plate.
- We need the extra calories.
- When we were here last, we ate everything.
- It's necessary.
God, how funny. It really looks like
it's the one who's listening to music.
- It's my pal in the office now.
- So cozy.
You can turn off the music,
it may be copyrighted.
Yes, exactly.
- Oops!
- They fell off right when the music stopped.
This is Harry's squishmallow.
He'll get to talk more about that later, won't he?
Yes.
- Look. Here's Laura's.
- It doesn't look quite as happy.
I know.
But yeah, this is how they come packaged.
God, we're being so secretive now.
We'll talk more about that later, simply.
- Shall we check out the website?
- Let's do it! Fun!
I really like this green color against the blue
which comes back here in the picture of Alma drawing.
And... the gray one fits great.
And the pink pops really well
so you really see where to click.
It'll be great.
- "This way." Can you click it, then?
- Click, click!
Yes.
- It took us to the page. Good.
- Yes.
We've talked about separating these,
"Weekend Adventures & Everyday Projects."
- Right.
- Exactly.
It's in the making,
but it will take some time.
- Yes, but now the final push is here.
- Yes, I know. So now it's full intensity. Now we just go.
Here we go!
You know much more about all that than I do
and have someone you usually work with and so on.
...and get back with your thoughts,
and then we can try one meat and one fish.
For a long time, we have wanted to give back
to families and followers.
That's why we're starting an online club
which will become Sweden's most active family club.
- Hey, what's going on?
- They're fighting.
- You're home from school.
- Mhm.
- Where's Alma?
- She's at padel practice.
- And Laura?
- She's at her "crèche". They're very slow there.
That's actually true.
Harry's after-school center closes at four.
If we go to get Laura then, she hasn't even eaten her snack yet.
The whole day is pushed back
here in Portugal for the little ones.
- But Harry?
- Yes?
How about you come up instead of being under the bed,
in your little room there.
Get on the bed to show your…
plushie, or squishmallow.
What do people call these?
- I think they say plush toy.
- Plush toy, okay. Your very own plush toy.
They've seen it earlier today.
What is this?
It's a plushie.
My plushie.
Yes, that's your plushie.
I don't know if you remember,
but we talked about it a long time ago.
When you did "Kids in Charge",
we were in a toy store.
Remember we asked:
Would you like it if we made our own plushies?
- Yes!
- Yes! The viewers definitely wanted that.
So we've been researching this
and it's a jungle, I must say.
It's a fun project, but it also takes time
when you have to design yourself,-
-and you look at different designs
and what you can do and so on.
During the time we've been looking,
we found this one, and...
- Could you bring Laura's over here?
- Yes. Here.
We found a manufacturer that had one each
which suited Alma, Harry, and Laura.
- Yes.
- Shall we get Alma's too? I'll do it.
Check this out.
Here's Alma's bunny.
Listen, it's very tidy here now
because we had a house cleaner here today, I must admit.
- It has such beautiful cheeks.
- Yes. Look, when I squeeze it...
- Check this out!
- Yay! The whole family is together.
Yes!
We sell these in our members club,
in a little webshop that we have.
And in that webshop,
we have some selected products.
- A few selected products.
- Exactly. A few. And...
There, we try to push prices down
as much as possible.
We know, for example, that we have put these at a price level
which is about half compared to in a toy store.
- And they're very soft!
- And big, almost like a pillow.
Right, this is a pretty big plushie.
You can squish it so that it becomes small,
but for a large plushie, it's about half the price.
But if you're going to shop there,
you must be a member of our club.
So, first you have to become a member,
and then you can check out the webshop.
- And it's free.
- Yes, membership is free.
But... we haven't even said
how they get to the club.
Right. The URL is:
www.swedishfamilyclub.com
- We will put a link in the video description.
- The link is below. But first, you have to watch the video.
- Yes, because now we're going to pick up the girls!
- Yes!
Let's go!
Are you going to bring the plushies?
- No, they can stay.
- They can have a conference with the other friends there.
Yes.
Here's the local padel and tennis club.
Alma!
- Hello!
- How did it go?
- It's gone well.
- Was it fun?
- Mhm.
- It's so yellow in here. Such a Christmas feeling.
- Yes.
- It's actually decorated for Christmas.
- Yes, I see that.
- Hello, girls!
- Hello!
Hi, Laura! How are you?
She wants to kiss. She wants to kiss.
This was my first time inside Laura's kindergarten.
I didn't know you could go inside.
Of course you can, it's not c*vid anymore.
Well, it is, but...
- It was really cozy in there.
- Yes, it's a really nice kindergarten.
But I can't film in there.
I can't come along.
No, because there are lots of other kids there
and we don't have their permission.
I want my pacifier.
- Oh, was it...
- I want my pacifier.
- You want your pacifier?
- Yes.
- When don't you want a pacifier, Laura?
- Exactly. Pacifier and playing with earlobes.
- Let's go home!
- Yes!
This is my favorite food.
This pasta sauce.
But that pasta...
You'll have to fix that.
- Yes, but wait. Stop, stop.
- Push it down.
I need to do it perfect.
Look, it goes down, because it gets wobbly.
Okay.
And also, this is normal...
- I want ice cream!
- You want ice cream. But we're going to eat dinner first, little one.
- You can have ice cream after dinner.
- No, "omeal!"
No, "omeal!" "Omeal!"
- Oatmeal.
- Yes.
- But listen, take out the pacifier so I can hear you.
- Want "omeal!"
Okay. I'm fine cooking you some oatmeal.
She's so hard to feed right now,
so I'm fine making oatmeal for her.
What I was saying was that
this is normal spaghetti, Alma.
Hey you, who has been eating wheat-free
for all these years.
Yes! My doctor has told me that I'm not gluten anymore.
I've grown out of it.
She's not gluten.
You have done new allergy tests.
It's funny, "I am gluten."
No one is gluten. Right?
- I mean... Gluten allergic.
- Alma is gluten. Or, you were gluten.
- No, she was hypersensitive to wheat. Hello?
- Yes.
- But anyway. She's fine. She can eat anything!
Happy days!
We have received a lot of Question of the Day about it.
Now you got an answer.
Yes.
There.
Oops. Difficult.
Now Laura wanted pasta anyway.
But I cooked oatmeal.
Do you want it?
No. Anyone else want it?
Me!
- You're welcome.
- Thanks.
And Alma's favorite is pasta sauce
with ham and mushrooms.
- No, I don't want it!
- No, you don't want it.
Is it the same in your household?
- Don't want it!
- No. Okay, okay. Would you like some ketchup, maybe?
- Okay! My turn.
- Good. Your turn. Mm.
It's enough.
- Here comes the cuddly duck!
- Is the cuddly duck coming? How cozy!
- It has walked down the stairs.
- Oh, has it? Come sit here with me.
How cozy.
What are you guys doing?
We're having a game night.
I promised Harry we would play a little,
so now I'm Spider-Man and I'm fighting Harry.
- No!
- Yes! I won.
We have a gaming console
with thousands of old games.
So, games from when I was a kid.
Like, 100 years old.
Such as Sega Mega Drive games,
PlayStation 1 games, Atari...
- Dad, fast! Now! You're fighting!
- Oh!
And arcade games. Great fun.
- It doesn't look very modern.
- No, but it's fun.
Oh! A power-up!
No!
No, your mushroom!
Wait there and it will probably go back.
Mom, come on!
Now it's my turn.
♪ Happy Birthday to You! ♪
Is it "Happy Birthday"?
Back.
It's Lucia, isn't it?
- Do you want black?
- Aha.
I don't think there is a black one.
What day is it today?
It's Friday. There's no school or kindergarten today
because it's a red day here in Portugal.
- Pink.
- Yes, it can be a pink day.
A pink day...
But Alma, what happened to your room?
It was so nice and tidy yesterday.
I know, it got really messy.
And Laura doesn't help much with the mess.
Speaking of messy homes,
we actually have an offer in the club on house cleaning.
I fit that in nicely.
There's a lot of good stuff in the club now,
and there will be more!
Yes. This is just the beginning.
The more members we get in the club,
the better the discounts and offers we'll be able to negotiate for you.
So now we want you to click the link
at the top of the video description and register as members.
It's a simple registration.
You have to be an adult to do it,-
-so if you're a family, then one of the parents enter
the children's birthdays, because we have an idea...
Laura has birthdays!
Yes, you have a birthday too, and everyone likes birthdays,
and many like to receive a greeting.
- Laura's birthday.
- Yes, you'll be three next time.
That's just two. One more.
We have an idea about being able to send out
birthday greetings via the club.
- To all members.
- Yes. That service doesn't really work now, but it will eventually.
Eventually.
Thank you for watching this video!
Please leave a thumbs up, or down.
Subscribe!
Comment, ask questions
and take care until next time.
- See you!
- Bye-bye!