Move them around,
move them around, move them around.
Hot dog-flavored chips.
Hey, hey!
In our previous video, we asked you guys
what videos you want to see.
We got a lot of different requests.
- Kung Fu!
- Kung Fu? Yes, maybe.
Oh.
Ouch, ouch... Hey, you!
Many of you want to see challenges.
- Challenges.
- Yes!
We have done "Gummy vs. Real Food" before.
But we have noticed that there are so many exciting chips flavors
here in Portugal, so today we are going to do...
Kung Fu!
No, not again.
We are going to do Chips vs. Real Food!
- Are you excited?
- Yes!
- Shall we begin?
- YES!
- Okay!
Ketchup-flavored chips...
...or ketchup.
Here you go.
- Harry, shall we move them around?
- Okay, one time.
Move them around,
move them around, move them around...
Okay, ready?
1, 2, 3.
Ketchup?
Ketchup chips?
Yes. It's ketchup-flavored chips,
or ketchup.
Okay!
- Do they taste like ketchup?
- A little. Maybe you should dip them in ketchup?
That made them taste a little better.
- Can I try?
- Mm.
They're delicious!
Don't take from someone else's plate.
- Okay, next one.
- Yes, next one.
Parma ham-flavored chips,
or parma ham.
- Bon appétit.
- I don't want to move them around.
- No, Harry.
- I don't want that either. 1, 2, 3!
- Ham?
- Ham chips? What the...
I mean...
Oh my God.
Try it.
Next chips.
Was the ham good?
No. Yuck.
This wasn't really a hit, was it?
But guys, another thing. A challenge has to have a winner,
and I don't really know how we should rate this.
We could go with whoever gets the most snacks wins.
Or we could let the viewers decide.
- Yes. What do you think?
- Most snacks.
- But then you'll win!
- How do you know that? We have many left.
Yes, we actually do. We have many left.
If you have any ideas,
please comment them down below.
Or if you think that someone won,
you could leave a comment.
Comment down below!
But you have to wait to comment
until you've seen everything.
- Yes.
- Jinx.
- Jinx!
Paprika-flavored chips,
or bell pepper.
And since there's some red paprika powder in the picture here,
we'll put some paprika powder on the bell pepper.
Here you go.
- No, Harry, don't peek.
- No, I'm smelling it.
- I want to switch.
- I don't want to switch.
- Okay.
- 1, 2, 3.
I knew it.
- Bell pepper?
- With something on it.
- What's that?
- Something. Yuck. What is this? A bell pepper with something on it.
Try it.
1, 2, 3.
They're all right.
- Try mine.
- Okay.
Ouch!
Eww, how gross! Can I have water?
Mommy, can I have water?
I also hate bell peppers.
Pizza double pepperoni-flavored chips,
or pizza double pepperoni.
Oops! Here you go.
Thank you.
- I don't want to switch. This smells like something good.
- Move them around, move them around...
- Stop smelling it!
- I don't remember what it smells like.
- Shall we move them around?
- No!
- Move them around, move them around...
- No.
Okay, then.
1, 2, 3.
- Pizza!
- Pizza! Wait, so this has to be pizza chips.
- Pizza, pizza, pizza...
- Okay, shall we eat?
- Yes.
- 1, 2, 3.
They were pretty good,
but they don't taste like pizza.
Corn-flavored chips, or corn.
- That pizza is probably my new favorite pizza.
- It's called pepperoni pizza.
Tasty as heck.
Double pepperoni pizza.
This, however, is something else.
1, 2, 3!
- What's this?
- Corn chips.
Corn! Corn! Corn!
They're so good!
They taste like little corn!
No. Okay, then.
- Do you like corn?
- They taste like little corn. I love corn.
These chips are so cute.
They're my new favorite chips.
- Good! So they're good?
- Mm.
Nice. Have you been keeping track of
who has gotten the most chips?
- Me! Me! Me!
- You?
I think it's Harry.
Now that we are halfway through our challenge,
I thought we would answer a Question of the Day.
Yes!
Where do you two want to live when you are old?
Well, not old. When you grow up.
Tokyo in Japan. In a high-rise.
Oh. Then we all have to move to Tokyo.
- Or only Harry.
- Mm.
I think I would rather...
Well, I'd like to live... everywhere. For different periods of time.
I don't want a permanent place of residence.
I want to be able to, like...
You guys get what I mean.
- You want to be able to travel and discover the world.
- Yes!
Okay. Next round?
- Okay.
But...
But, hello...
- What are you doing?
- I did that too.
Hot dog-flavored chips, or...
a hot dog.
Move them around,
move them around, move them around.
There.
Move them around,
move them around, move them around...
Okay. 1, 2, 3!
Hot dog.
Hot dog-chips. Okay.
They're really good!
Cold hot dog.
Yes, unfortunately, the hot dog has gotten cold.
Hope that's okay.
It only has mustard on it, and that's because
the hot dog on the chips bag only had mustard on it.
These were really good!
I would definitely buy these chips.
Sour cream and black pepper-flavored chips,
or sour Cream with black pepper.
There we go.
No, you have to headbutt.
- Are you ready?
- Yes!
Yes, we are ready.
Here you go.
Move them around,
move them around, move them around...
Okay. 1, 2, 3!
What flew off?
Oh... I accidentally...
- I mean... What is that?
- I don't know.
- Like, sour cream and something.
- Sour cream and pepper, I think.
Not that bad, actually.
Try it.
Mmm.
Eww.
- I wouldn't buy any of this. Never in my life.
- I'd buy that and that. I think both were really good.
- For real?
- Mm.
Okay. Next chip flavor.
Large cheese puffs,
or a large cheese.
- Here you go.
- Thanks.
1, 2, 3.
Cheese! Cheese!
Mommy... you know that
Alma is crazy about cheese.
I like these, anyway.
- Aren't these two very classic? These with cheese, and that.
- Yes. Are they boring?
They're really good.
- Can I try?
- Mm.
- It tastes like regular cheese puffs.
- I'll try this.
Dang, what a big bite.
I'm going to get a cramp in my teeth.
I have to spit it out!
No, just kidding.
- Now you have almost had dinner, it seems.
- Yes.
It looks like you guys are starting to get full.
Those bites certainly weren't small.
Now it's only one chip flavor left.
- Shall we go for it?
- Yes. Moment of truth.
Moment of truth...
That sounds like a Thor movie. Really cool.
Red chili-flavored chips,
or red chili.
I thought you guys got like this when we try candy,
but it seems to be the challenge itself.
Move them around,
move them around, move them around...
1, 2, 3!
No! No! I mean...
I refuse this.
- What? That's fine, no?
- I've tried these, they're so spicy.
- You can do it!
- Sure. Let's do it together.
- Here.
- Okay.
- 1, 2...
- What about Harry? Here.
- No, I eat my own thing.
- He has chips.
1, 2, 3.
- How are your chips?
- They're all right.
Isn't it spicy?
No. I think I'll try one. It's probably going to burn
the tongue. Have you tried chili before?
Mm.
- Does it hurt?
- No.
- Is it warm?
- No, it's fine.
- What's up, Harry?
- I ate one.
Whoa.
I will never do that again!
That was awful!
That was very spicy.
I think I lost count of who got the most chips.
- My breath is still warm.
- Yes. It almost makes your eyelashes curl like little roller blinds.
I think I have won because I ate this thing,
and I put on the biggest show today.
Oh, really? I think the viewers should get to decide who won.
What do you think, Harry?
Same. The viewers.
This spicy ending kind of took it out of us.
Shall we...
Hey, I don't want any more!
- Shall we say thank you for today?
- Yes!
Thank you for watching this video!
Bye-bye!
Oh my God...
Okay. Bye-bye!
BYE-BYE!