Here's the deal...
Here are our house parts.
Yes.
What the heck?
Don't bump it.
No!
Laura, you must jump down.
- Let Laura down.
- I can't. I have to hold the parts.
Hey, hey!
Today, we are doing...
The Gingerbread House Challenge!
The longest word in the world.
- It's a competition where you build a gingerbread house.
- Yes.
- A nice, funny, lovely, inspiring house.
- The one who makes the nicest one wins.
- Exactly.
- And is the best.
We've split into two teams.
I'm a little worried about today's challenge.
Here in Portugal, they don't have those
gingerbread house kits from, like, "Mor Annas".
- No, exactly.
- Is that what it's called?
- I think it's called "Farmor Anna".
- Or just "Annas Pepparkaka".
Yes.
Anyhow, they don't have it here.
Portuguese don't eat, or build, gingerbread houses.
They basically don't eat gingerbread at all.
- That's true.
- Yes.
We have to start by drawing up what our houses should look like.
You have prepared a dough.
- Yes. I made a huge dough yesterday, so it's ready.
- Mm. And what are the teams?
- Me and Alma. The best team.
- And me and Mommy and Lauris.
- What? You get help from her?
- Yes, she's the world's best mascot!
The winning mascot.
Let's split up and start working on our house dreams.
That's why we have so much paper here.
- I think we should go to the kitchen.
- We'll go to the kitchen, and you guys stay here.
Shoo, shoo, shoo! Go!
- Bye-bye!
- Laura doesn't understand a thing.
We have had a few different ideas.
First, Harry thought we should do a horror house.
"Poppy Pli Time"
- Then you thought about a sushi restaurant.
- Mm.
Then we thought a lot about the shape and decided that
it would be easiest to just print out templates from the web.
So that's what we did,
and we will put more energy into the decorating.
What kind of house will it be?
Do we know?
Harry's Toys store!
We will see.
We may change our minds again.
Anyway, here we have little Harry.
Can you see it in this light?
- Are you filming?
- Mm.
- I didn't even notice.
- Want to tell us what you're doing?
I'm making a hat
for mine and dad's Moomin house.
Ta-da!
Yes, the scissors are scary.
It's very sharp.
No, Harry. Little rascal.
And you're eating candy
even though it's not Saturday.
Is that allowed?
So, here's the deal. Mommy and Harry think that
we'll make the same gingerbread house they're making.
Let me see.
Because we took these papers.
But we really made this thing for the dough.
This is for the roof... like so.
And now we will
prepare to make the walls.
I'll just draw here.
- Alma.
- Mm.
- Which piece is for us?
- This one.
- Ah, the big one.
- What? I thought they were the same size.
Let me see.
- These are the same size.
- Kind of.
There!
Time to roll the dough.
Here are our house parts.
- Are you happy?
- Yes.
- We're just missing the chimney. It's in the oven.
Yes, what's that?
You have to take out the pacifier
so that we can hear what you're saying.
No? You don't want to show it.
Stop, stop, stop!
Harry, you should probably save that from Laura.
Gone!
No!
What's happening?
Our house parts are breaking and falling off.
- You're making it so advanced!
- This will never work.
Never say never.
Don't bump it!
No!
Alma, what are we going to do?
Oh, no!
You'll have to make a new part.
No! This must be repairable.
Everything can be repaired, especially in Portugal.
Everything can be repaired with icing.
The houses are crooked,
and they can still be repaired.
- Laura broke our freshly baked chimney.
- Laura, your little rascal!
We can probably make it work, I hope.
Now we have all our parts.
God, my hair...
It's so hot to be by the oven, or what do you say?
- Yes.
- You also look a little... ragged.
First we tried to put our parts together
with cold baking glue. Was that a good idea?
- No.
- No, a very bad idea. So, now we've had it in a water bath.
God, the way I'm sitting...
Having Laura on your team should give you a handicap.
Shall we assemble it
with the warm baking glue?
Put some there.
Now it's easier, right?
- Is it still a little hard?
- Yes, wait... Now, now.
Okay.
It was rock-hard before the water bath.
Wait...
There, some glue.
Now let's put them together.
Ooh, two walls.
And let's put this here.
- No, no, no!
- Don't take it.
- Do you want it?
- Mm.
- Oops!
- Of course she does.
- Let's take this one.
- Yes. I wonder how long it takes for it to dry. It doesn't say.
This is our side, with a door. It's gonna go there.
Shall we put glue on it?
Yes.
- I think it comes out pretty easy now.
- Yes.
It looks like this.
Yes, you want that.
But we need it as a little weight there.
Okay, take it.
Do you want to go to daddy and Alma?
I'm like, "Bye-bye."
Now. Now, Harry.
- This will be our roof.
- Without the aluminum foil.
Yes, the goal is to be able to lift it.
I mean, this isn't going to dry today, I don't know how...
Laura is having her best day ever.
She's just walking around and playing with things,
and she loved rolling out the rough.
Cutie pie.
Oh, are you going to bake cupcakes now?
This will be interesting.
- Now you're also at the assembly stage.
- Yes, but I mean...
Mommy is here.
I've never made such an advanced...
Oh, our heads are getting cut off,
maybe we should raise the camera.
We'll have to sit down.
I'll go and get more parts, Alma.
- That's an incredibly high level of ambition on your part.
- Oh, yes.
We lowered the demands instead.
We just printed out a template.
Oh, they're different heights.
How could that happen?
They're made from the same template.
- This is going to turn out so good.
- Mm.
Harry, I need your help. The roof.
I'll take the most durable part.
Wait, wait, wait!
Don't touch it.
- Harry, I need your help.
- This is never going to work.
Stop laughing like that, like a ghost!
You can hear the panic.
It's pure and utter.
- No, no, no!
- Oh my God! Laura... Laura, you have to get down.
- Let Laura down.
- I can't. I have to hold the parts.
Quiet!
Our gingerbread house
is starting to feel more and more like dough.
Yes, the parts feel a little wet.
No!
- You have to wait with your little figure, Harry.
- It broke its leg.
Harry is just focusing on his gingerbread man
while I'm struggling with the house.
- He amputated his own leg, on purpose.
- Yeah.
I talked to another parent
at the Swedish School here in Portugal-
-and told him that we're going to make
gingerbread houses.
He said, "You better do it fast because they don't last that long.
They, like, collapse due to the humidity."
And that seems to be correct.
It's much more humid here, indoors too.
In Sweden, a gingerbread house could last all winter.
Here, forget about it.
It barely lasts a week here.
No...
What the heck!
No!
No! But...
Oh, how messy. Shall I help you?
- No.
- It's too late.
Our house doesn't have an entrance, Alma.
We are done!
Well, almost done.
The sun sets at 5:20 PM in Portugal.
- More? More gingerbread houses?
- Mm.
- No, thanks. We are done!
- Yes.
We have moved to the brightest house...
No.
...the brightest room
in the whole house to show you...
- Our creations.
- Yes.
- Why did you go like that?
- It's so hot.
Yes, from the oven earlier.
This has been one of our hottest, sweatiest, and most stressful...
And messiest.
- ...recordings.
- Yes.
- But when we edit, it probably won't look that bad.
- No.
- Okay. Who starts presenting their house?
- Me and Mommy.
- Okay.
- And Lauris.
- You remember the story, right?
- I do. I'll move the house closer and let you tell it.
Once upon a time,
there was a toy store called Harry's Toys.
It was created by Harry himself.
One beautiful day, the roof collapsed,
and then it was over.
So, he decided to give all the presents
to the kids that lived in the town.
Ever since then, it's called Harry's...
- Ruin.
- ...ruin.
- Great!
- It looks like this.
- Right. The roof was difficult to put on.
- Incredibly.
It just slid off.
Once upon a time, there was a happy Moomin family
that lived in a big Moomin house.
They loved Christmas, and this particular Christmas
they had bought a bunch of presents.
However, some burglars got in
and took all the presents.
The Moomin family
were absolutely devastated, so they left.
Then, the roof collapsed
and pretty much the whole house cracked.
Yes, and now we don't know who lives here.
There are some Christmas tree lights and other things hanging here.
- Exactly. They light up every winter.
- Yes.
- Here, you can see traces from the break-in.
- Yes, there's a ladder here.
Now it's up to you guys at home to decide
who won today's challenge!
Yes.
- Team Harry, or...
- Team Alma.
Comment down below.
Thank you for watching this video!
- Please leave a thumbs up, or down.
- Mostly thumbs up!
Comment, ask questions
and take care until next time.
Bye-bye!