We'll be moving back to Sweden soon.
That's the problem.
And we're very embarrassing, often.
And we don't understand a thing, most of the time.
Exactly. You will not be allowed to come inside.
And when we were going to…
Welcome to our home.
It's a perfectly ordinary Sunday.
A rather messy Sunday.
We're reading a book where...
Pink!
- Yes, it's pink.
- Pink!
There's text and then there's an image,
so you should say...
On the chairs. Under the bed. On the cabinet.
Yeah...
Laura thinks it's super fun.
But I think you should clean up a bit, Laura.
Look at the mess she's made here.
It looks terrible.
- Huh? I want to read it.
- Yes, you want to read it. Matilda the Mouse Builds.
Those two would also need to clean up a bit.
- You guys?
- Mhm?
What do your rooms look like?
Quite tidy.
Um...
Mine is not cleaned at all.
Okay. I think it's time for us to get stuff done.
Get cleaning done.
- Oh no.
- No, it's so boring.
- Yes, but then we can start the day, for real.
- Okay then.
Have you talked about Alma's braids?
The viewers haven't seen it.
- They haven't? God.
- No. This is one of the last things you did in Kenya.
Yes, exactly.
- How long did it take?
- Four and a half hours.
Now you've had them for a while,
so the real hair is starting to show.
They don't last that long.
You don't really have the right hair quality to do these.
No, my hair will probably be very damaged when I take them out,
but I think it's worth it. I think they look very nice.
They suit you.
I often look at you and think I see someone else.
Especially from the back.
Like...
Long, long blonde braids.
It didn't really register.
I agree.
What's it like to sleep with them?
- Very difficult. I can show what I sleep with.
- Yes.
- This is the one I wear, and...
- What's that?
It's a satin cap.
I can show you what it looks like on.
- Mushroom!
- Yes, you look like such a little mushroom.
And then I sleep, like this.
This way, they're not, like, everywhere.
Very good.
- It's like an extra pillow.
- Yeah, but not a very comfortable pillow.
No, I want it.
It's always like this when we have to clean,
then you suddenly want to play with the toys.
Then it won't be cleaned.
Play with it, play with it…
The never-ending pacifier fight.
Gone!
No. Not there.
Not there.
Laura, that's ruining your teeth.
You have to stop it. That's just how it is.
Now I'm going to a classmate's house
for their birthday party.
- I'm just following you there.
- Yes, exactly. You will not be allowed to come inside.
- No, no. And neither will you.
- No, neither will you.
This one... I thought I would
carry the camera in it when we're not filming.
Now it's empty and just in the way.
Flopping around.
- Anyway. Our house is tidy and Alma is going to a party.
- Yes.
Yes! Beautiful Sunday!
What kind of present do you have?
I have this... little bag.
I didn't have a nice bag, so…
- You made one.
- It's a little worn.
- Yes, but you drew on it nicely.
- Yes. I bought a toiletry bag in a toiletry bag in a toiletry bag.
- Several toiletry bags.
- Yes. In a nice color.
Oops.
And...
God, I'm sorry.
And a bath bomb.
Yes!
- Oh, are they going to jump? Do you think they dare?
- Yeah.
Do you?
Oh, how brave!
Laura is going through a very
emotional period in her life right now.
She will stop using diapers, she will stop using pacifiers,
and she wants to dress all by herself.
- She wants to do everything herself.
- Yes.
Oh, what do you want? A banana? Or an apple?
Yes, you can take the apple.
And if we try to help her,-
-then she usually lies down on the floor, rolls around,
and screams as loud as she can.
So that's our everyday life right now and I think that's the case
for a lot of parents of young kids in periods.
It's completely natural. But...
We have had the chance to try an app called Peppy Pals.
It's filled with games for kids between 2 and 8 years old.
Games and situations, right?
You help these peppy friends.
- Exactly. In the app, there are a few different friends.
- Animals...
- My turn!
- Oh, sorry. Sorry.
Mhm. Here we go.
- My turn!
- Yes, sorry. Sorry. We'll play it one more time.
Laura really likes that game.
Yes, she thinks it's super fun.
You can ask her nice questions about the friends
when they help each other, comfort each other,-
-or when they get angry,
or when they get happy.
The app is supposed to practice children's EQ.
Emotional intelligence.
Yes. It also has a lot of other games.
You can draw and you can do puzzles.
You can do a lot of things.
And it's completely childproof.
There is no third-party advertising in it.
And yeah, it's safe, simply put.
- What's happening now, Laura?
- Oh, now they're riding a whale. Gosh!
"How did Gabby feel when they were criticized?"
There's discussion material.
Maybe he got angry.
Or sad? He got sad.
Or they got sad, you say.
- Yes, the animals are gender-neutral.
- Exactly. All the characters in this app are gender-neutral.
Red.
Green.
We have an offer for those of you
who might want to try Peppy Pals.
A 14-day free trial,
then the app costs SEK 39 a month.
You can cancel at any time.
Follow the link at the top of the description
and download the app and give it a try.
Grandma will be visiting us, from Sweden to Portugal,
so I will pick some flowers.
It's so wonderful that it's November
but there are still flowers here.
Oh, look.
- Nice!
- This one's nice.
Take a few, then we can put them in a vase
in the guest room.
How does it feel that she's coming?
It feels great.
She's kind of been my best friend since I was, like, two years old,
so it's great that she's coming to visit.
I'm going to pick a lot of flowers.
Oh! Look, the flowers are falling off.
They're really delicate flowers.
It will be difficult to carry them.
Here's a really nice bush that you can pick from.
We'll be moving back to Sweden soon.
How does that feel?
It feels really bad.
Such great friends here, and...
now I have to move home.
I hope I find good friends in Sweden.
Don't you still have your friends from before?
Yes... I do.
- But you're going to switch schools.
- Yes, exactly. So... That's the problem.
- I think it will go great, Harry.
- Mm, let's hope.
Come. Let's pick some more flowers
down by the meadow.
Okay.
There are mostly green plants here,
not that many flowers.
- Yes, one little flower.
- Yes, that's small. Tiny.
Where are you going now?
Over there. I'll pick one of those flowers
because I'm not really sure if you can pick from there.
If it was up to you,
would you want the family to stay here in Lisbon?
Easy. Yes.
- There!
- Nice!
Now I have all the flowers!
This is our guest room.
It's at the bottom of the house
next to the garage that's behind this wall.
We don't usually film down here.
No, but we're very happy to have it.
The guest room.
Yes, of course.
And now we're preparing for grandma's arrival.
Yes.
I don't like this duvet at all
because it's a double duvet.
It's very Portuguese.
Incredibly difficult.
It's a two-man job,
but I'm standing with the camera so I can't do much.
Two-man job and two-man duvet.
It hit me just now when I was out with Harry
and picked some flowers...
This vlog's theme will be emotions.
Will it?
Yes, because it's not just Laura who has a lot of emotions.
Harry has a lot of emotions.
- We all do.
- He'd prefer to stay here.
He's going to switch schools when we move home to Sweden.
So he has a lot on his mind right now.
And Alma, who's at a party right now...
She also has a lot of emotions.
She's very pre-teen. You don't see that, but...
We see it.
And we're very embarrassing, often.
And we don't understand a thing, most of the time.
Yes. According to her.
So what I mean is that our family is going through
a lot of emotions right now. A lot of feelings.
- You let go of it.
- Oh, sorry. Now there are more emotions in here.
Yes.
But I think... that's how it is in families.
But right now, it's extra much for us.
Yes, and it won't be any less
because we're getting closer to the trip home.
- No. It's not just a trip, we're moving home.
- Yes, exactly.
How do you feel about it?
I think it will be fun.
It will be fun with a fresh start.
I miss Sweden and I miss my friends, family,
and business partners in Sweden.
I think it will be wonderful to come home to a winter landscape.
Hope there's snow in Sweden when we get home.
- In some places, there will be.
- Yes.
- Maybe not in Stockholm.
- No. We'll see. And how do you feel?
I hate the darkness, as our loyal viewers know,
so I'm not too happy about moving home this season.
No. We're really moving home
at the most fun time of the year.
- He says, ironically.
- Yes.
But... We have a lot of exciting things
happening in Sweden going forward.
Mm.
So in that way, I'm looking forward to it.
And of course, friends and family. But I love living here.
Yes.
Mixed emotions.
I've taken my hair out.
Removed the braids.
Yes, exactly. But I've taken out the fake hair,
and it was much more than this.
But I haven't been able to throw this away yet.
I threw away about half.
It's been a few days since we last filmed.
You took out your hair - or, the braids - yesterday.
Yes, exactly.
I got help from a friend.
But my hair is very damaged now,
up here and such.
But it wasn't as bad
as I thought it would be.
No, but also,
they were quite annoying and limiting.
I have quite a lot of activities,
so it was difficult to attend those with the braids.
Yes. Hardest to get the swim cap on, huh?
Yeah. I'm in swimming practice and we have to wear a swimming cap,
and it was very difficult to get it on.
Is Laura a little sad?
Well... No more than usual.
But there's a bit of crisis and panic here sometimes.
Yes.
There was also a bit of a crisis and panic last Sunday.
After we picked you up from the party,
we went to the beach, and…
- It wasn't me.
- It wasn't me either.
Laura... Like a chainsaw.
When we were going to film there...
Talk to the camera, I mean. Not just film us swimming.
Then the battery ran out,
so there was actually a bit of a fight.
- Yes.
So today Harry was like,
"I don't want to film."
But that's okay.
- That's okay.
- Sometimes, you have to take a break.
- Oh, yes. You have the right to have your feelings, right?
- Yes.
- This vlog's theme is emotions, Alma.
- Yes, indeed.
- I'll take the opportunity to remind you of the offer.
- Yes, check it out. At the top of the video description.
The link.
We have a Question of the Day.
Where will we be celebrating Christmas?
- Here. We will be celebrating Christmas here in Portugal.
- Yes. Probably here in this living room.
Yes.
And then we will go to Sweden
sometime around New Year's, we think.
- Yes.
- Exactly.
We've not decided if we'll celebrate the New Year in Sweden,
or if we're going to celebrate the New Year here.
- No, but it'll be one of the two.
- Yes. We'll see.
Where will you be celebrating Christmas?
Comment below!
Thank you for watching this video!
Please leave a thumbs up, or down.
Comment, ask questions,
and take care until next time.
See you!
Bye-bye!