Is it hard?
I felt nothing about that.
Cheating!
Oh no!
This has balled out.
A papaya coconut!
No, what do I say?
Hello Hello!
Today we will do ... Draw on my back challenge!
Yeah!
And you may wonder what it means.
"Draw on my R*MPA Challenge!"
- No.
Almost.
- It means: "Draw on my back challenge".
- Yes!
- No, you're wrong.
It's great fun, we think.
We've seen it on Youtube, when others do it.
- Yes.
We thought, "It looks funny. We have to do it!"
- We have to test.
- It is very simple, so you can test it at home too.
- Yes.
But before we start with today's video we want to say ...
THANKS!
Thanks to everyone who participated and donated money to our collection in collaboration with Save the Children-
-What the money went to children in Ukraine, and around the world, who are having a hard time.
Yes.
Together with you we collected over SEK 200,000!
Very good.
"Aplausos! Aplausos!"
We can help many children with that sum of money, so it was so nice of you.
Several thousand children.
We are super happy that we have such a nice and fantastic community.
Really.
I almost get a tear in my eye.
I would also like to take the opportunity to say thanks to everyone else who made their own initiative-
-And maybe gathered toys at home, or clothes or whatever, to help someone else.
Thanks.
- An applause for that too.
- "Aplausos! Aplausos!"
You don't have to be part of our collection, it's enough to just be a fellow human being, right?
- Yes!
- One more time.
- "Aplausos! Aplausos!"
- Now "Aplausos" is enough?
That's enough.
Now we start today's video.
Challenge!
- Harry is ready to tell us how this goes.
- Yes.
We have taped a paper on Alma's back, and here we have a paper on the wall.
Then I'll draw one thing.
We pretend I draw a tree here ...
Then Alma will feel it and draw here.
Yes exactly.
I'll try to draw what I feel.
- It sounds easy.
- But it also sounds difficult.
We'll see if it's easy.
- (Axel) I think it's pretty tricky.
- (Harry) I think it's very difficult.
- Are you ready?
- Yes!
- Wait, wait, wait.
Is Dad ready?
- Yes.
I'll just put on "play" here.
Yes.
- What do you think it is?
- God, I don't know.
- Harry, don't draw so fast.
- (shoulder) must draw harder.
(Axel laughs at)
- It is actually difficult to draw on a back.
- Yes I understand it.
Sorry I laughed.
I'm finished.
Did I draw right?
- No!
- Oh no.
- Then Alma gets 3 guesses.
- Right.
- My first guess is 2 cherries.
- No.
- My second guess is an ice cream.
- It looks like an ice cream.
- That looks a bit like Donald Trump.
- Is it an R*MPA?
- NO!
Absolutely not.
It is...
Pipito!
- Oh, wait.
- Pipito!
- Oh, what a lot of hair she has!
- Yes indeed.
She is in the future.
I have seen her in the future, she became a paper guy.
Laura is not here now because she can't draw, so she was not allowed to join.
- Who got a point in the first round?
- Harry.
- Harry, Harry ... - Harry.
Oh no!
Sorry!
I'd hug you, and you just ...
Harry dies, Harry dies ...
- May I take your score?
- No.
Don't forget to push thumbs up if you like when we do challenges!
Cha-cha-cha, Cha-cha-cha, Challenge, Challenge, Cha-Cha-Cha!
(Joanna) Is it difficult?
- Is it hard?
- Yes Yes.
There is full concentration here.
(Axel) But what is this?
I do not get it.
(Axel) oh my good.
(Alma) I'm done!
What?
What is this?
So ... you are kidding.
(Joanna) I can say so much as it is not right.
- It's wrong.
3 guesses.
- Okay.
- I think it's an old man.
- Error.
- A car?
Gosh.
Come on.
Then it's a ... flower pot.
- Error.
It was a ... pineapple!
- Oh, God, so hard.
- Because my favorite fruit is pineapple.
- and dad's with.
- Well ... is that?
Yes, maybe it is.
- You probably said it at some point as a question of the day.
Yes exactly.
Indian pineapple, in that case.
With chili and salt.
- I like regular pineapple.
- Yes, it's much better.
- And which is your favorite fruit?
- A papaya coconut!
No, what do I say?
(Alma) Harry, what do you eat, type ... What fruit do you live on, Harry?
- Banana!
- Yes, my God.
The banana man, that is.
The banana man!
He is kind of crazy in bananas.
He eats kind of bananas for breakfast and bananas for dinner.
Except on the weekends, he also eats bananas for lunch.
- How many bananas in a day?
- I would say type 5 bananas in one day.
That is pretty good.
When we have bananas at home.
Usually we have it, but they end very quickly.
My favorite fruit is actually the one that Harry sang about.
A papaya coconut!
You-you-you-you
And a place in the sun!
That sounded awful!
But we offer it.
The position in today's Challenge is 1-1.
Mm.
Now Axel will draw me.
Alma is filming.
Let's go!
- Are you ready?
- Yes, I'm ready.
I do this, then it feels better.
It is really difficult!
I felt nothing about that.
Cheating!
But what do you do now for ...?
(Shoulder) clear.
No?!
- (Alma) So, a little does it actually look like ... - No?
Is it the same?
- (Alma) a little.
Tiny.
- It's very abstract.
- Okay.
I guess I'll guess, then.
- mm.
- A pair of glasses.
- No.
Good guess, but no.
- A pair of br*st.
- It could have been me, but no.
Could it be you?!
Who drew it.
But there are lots of sticks and stuff.
So, there are not so much sticks in br*st.
I think.
- A stick.
- No.
- It was a ... - bike!
Aaaah ...
- A pretty ugly bike.
- Yes, it was actually an ugly bike, shoulder.
FUL J*DRANS Bike, Dad!
(Axel) This looks like bicycle parts, so I think mom gets half a point.
- Do I get half a point?!
- Yes.
- Do we share the score then?
- Yes we can do that.
Mm, for Dad drew so badly, so he doesn't get a point.
He doesn't deserve a point.
Yes.
Now Mom will draw on Harry.
- Are you ready?
- Yeah, man!
- What did you say?
Well!
I thought you said "Jermaine".
Okay.
Jermaine.
Now I drive!
Clear!
Please and guess, Harry, because you drew completely wrong.
So, I don't even see what you have drawn.
I don't understand what you have drawn.
- huh?!
- That can be anything.
- No, I think this is very clear.
- Yes, I also think it's pretty clear.
- Is it a car?
- No.
You can join in and guess, Alma.
Should Alma get a guess?
She has seen what it is, so you get the worst help.
- I think it's a pool of something ... kind.
- No.
- Isn't it a pool of any kind?!
Okay, Harry.
You have the last guess.
Is it...
...a car?
But you have already guessed that!
But is it kind of a rickshaw?
No!
No no no!
It is the country Sweden!
Well, what a ugly!
Who takes that?
It looks like a P*nis!
It doesn't look like an "hmm-hmm"!
Don't you see?
Here is the Stockholm area, here is ...
There is the thing that stands out and here are the little balls, as you call them, and here is the other ball.
Shhh ... Here is Öland and Gotland!
I like that Gotland is kind of a square dot.
It's a little Roblox feel.
Okay, it's actually very difficult to draw on your back.
Should I tell you why I drew Sweden?
- Nah.
- Shouldn't I tell you that?
Yes, yes!
Tell us why.
I drew Sweden because the most common question we get is:
"When will you come home to Sweden?"
And what is the answer?
- You can say the answer, because I don't know.
- Don't you know that?
Or yes, we come home this summer and are there on the summer holidays.
- Exactly.
- Ouch ouch ouch.
Oh.
Careful with little brother.
We will drive up to Sweden after the school closure, and it is type 11 or June 12.
Yes.
Yes, Yes, Yes.
- So that's why I drew Sweden, and I think ... yes.
- I thought it was kind of slave or kind of kiss.
The name, so ... this has balled out.
Now we have all drawn on each back and on the wall.
- On a paper on the wall.
- Yes, on a piece of paper.
Just.
- And we will count our points together.
- Yes!
- A half.
- One.
- And one and a half.
- Wooo!
So Joanna won.
Yes, but it is very stupid, because it became the case that the one who drew on his back all the time got the point.
Yes.
And I was definitely not the best in any way, so you have to decide who has won today's Challenge instead.
So we usually do.
And then you have to look at these and think through ... who drew the most fun ...
- Or who drew most like.
- Yes.
Or who drew the ugliest and needs a consolation prize.
You can write down in the comments section simply, who you think should win.
- Yes!
- Yaaay!
Thanks for watching this video!
Feel free to leave a thumbs up, or down!
Most thumbs up.
And have a great time, and we'll see you again soon!
Bye!