Hello Hello!
We are in...
New Zealand!
YES!
If you follow our Instagram, you already know about this, because you have seen pictures.
If you look at the channel a lot, you probably know that we have been to Thailand with TUI.
There are several vlogs from there.
But now you will be able to follow our journey from Thailand to New Zealand!
We are at Phuket Airport!
It is fortunate that the children feel embarrassed, because we have a long journey ahead of us.
Very long!
- Yes!
- Rama x ...
Mom, check out.
Rama X.
- Who is Rama X?
- Thailand's king.
As usual, we have a lot of bags with us.
Yes, I don't know what happened here, but ... it's change clothes.
- Passport and boarding cards, please.
- Yes.
Hello.
Harry, they said "Hello" to you.
What do you say then?
- What should I say?
- You can say "Hello".
Hello.
- Thanks!
- Thanks so much.
- Bye!
So there, now we have gone through Security.
Yes.
In an hour, at 14:30, our plane goes from Phuket to Singapore.
And then we will go to ...
New Zealand!
Yes it is true!
Do you know which city, then?
Ehm ...
- Auckland.
- Correct.
Oh!
Auckie-Landie, Auckie-Landie ...
Auckie ... Auckland.
How's it going?
It is good!
I am tagged to experience something new.
Thailand has been a great start to this long trip.
Yes indeed!
- So ... - s ...
We talk in the mouth of each other.
- Hello!
How satisfied are you with Thailand?
Br ... br ... br ...
Good!
It sounds like a good rating.
- Great to stay at a resort.
- mm.
Leopard...
But...
Alma, go and play.
Bye.
I don't know what it is with them today!
I think there are some butterflies in the stomach for us to travel.
Yes, I believe that.
But...
Hello!
Pussy away.
- No, but go away now, please.
- Go and play there!
Quite Spartan Kid Zone when compared to the hotel we have just lived on.
Yes indeed.
- It's been like a kid zone, the whole resort!
- Yes.
It was only a bunch of children who have pulled around and had as much fun!
Yes!
I want to take the opportunity to strike a blow to travel in the off -season.
- Yes.
- How nice isn't that?
There is no congestion, neither in restaurants nor on sun loungers or anything like that.
Everything goes very smoothly.
But there are still lots of children for the kids to play with, and good things to do.
Yes.
And the beach was ...
- Some days it was almost empty!
- Yes.
- If you can, travel in low season.
- A tip from us.
- Good tips.
This flight is only two hours.
Me, Alma and Harry are at the back ...
... and foam!
Dad Axel sits two rows.
That's right.
There we have him ...
- Hello!
- Hello Hello!
What is it, the old man?
I get scared.
Come, take my hand.
Tell me, why are you scared?
The aircraft will probably crash.
No, no, no ... it's just raining outside, it's nothing dangerous.
They can land anyway.
- They will land on the sea now.
- No, we will land at the airport.
Yes...
- If we don't land on sea ... - no ...
- If we land on the sea we will go on a boat instead ... - No, Harry ...
... and take those disgusting masks on us.
We will land at the airport, I promise.
It just rains and is a little gray.
No problem.
- We will be at the other island soon!
- Yes!
We will soon be there where we would travel.
You were right, we will land on land!
- It didn't take that long to go here.
- No.
It was super close!
Alma, now we're coming soon!
Singapore!
- It felt like that flight went fast.
- Very quickly.
But now we have ...
... 3.5 hours here, I look at the clock that we will go by.
Oh, now comes someone who is in a hurry.
Sorry!
There is the time, do you see?
18:05, local time, and we fly on to Auckland ...
I have a hard time talking, as usual.
- 21:30.
- Yes!
Now we have a few hours to ...
- Hello!
Have a safe trip.
- Thanks!
- Thanks, have so nice!
- Thanks.
Yes ... eat, hang.
So there ...
...little food.
A lot of exciting food!
- You might think we're in a playground.
- Yes.
But we are still in Singapore, at the airport.
At Changi Airport.
Is it good, Alma?
Giant.
Ouch.
It's time to change to long legs.
Nice, because it felt like I kind of twisted my foot when I went in this one.
Now we have just changed and we were going to check out a bit in the stores here at the airport.
- It's a huge airport ... - Yes, it's huge!
... with a lot of shops.
Yes.
We actually go over to another terminal and then you have to take trains in between.
- How are you?
- Good.
- What are you sitting in?
- Wheelchair.
Now Dad has purchased something very good for the trip!
It may not look so fun, but it's a little headphone jack ...
... which you can plug in two pairs of headphones.
So you can sit and listen with your headphones ...
... and you can listen with your headphones!
- Good, is not it?
- This wasn't fun.
- Isn't that fun?
- It's really fun!
It will be great fun!
Doing, doing!
Now we have a nine -hour flight.
Axel and the children here, three.
And I ... there.
- At least in the beginning, we must see later.
- Yes, we are testing a new variant.
Yes.
- They are pretty well tired now.
- Yes, and they are in the hood on each other all the time.
I don't think we will be able to sit like this.
I probably have to sit in between.
- Listen?
- Yes?
- Can you open this?
- Yes ...
- You hardly see you, Harry.
- No, that hair ...
Mother?
Can you put this on for me?
- The braids were so nice when they were newly made.
- And now they have like ...
- It's a bit depressed.
- They have rolled out a bit.
We can make new ones later.
When we get to New Zealand we can find a cool hairdresser that can do something cool with your hair, Harry.
Harry, I can't help you put on now, I can help you later.
The TV doesn't work now.
You have to eat a little.
Hello Hello.
- You talk so much with your headphones on.
- Yes, but they hear nothing.
... Must scream.
- At
Is 23:30, I don't think they will get that much.
- (Alma) What is that?
But it's worth a try.
It is difficult to find a good position to sleep in in these chairs.
It is two and a half hours left on the flight.
The children have slept for 4 hours.
It is half past five in the morning, and then we lay down in the middle of the night.
Or, "Leak us" ...
Type covered for a little while.
- It bumps a lot.
- Yes.
- It has made it all the flight.
- Yes, it has.
Woho!
- We are in New Zealand!
- Yes!
Here is half past two in the day.
We are 12 hours from Sweden now!
Yes.
- As far away as you can get on the globe.
- Yes.
At home is half past two at night.
For us, who are in Thailand time, it is very early morning.
- Yes, and we have slept very little.
- Yes.
The last bag, everything is included.
Great!
Yes, you found it.
How fun!
Yes but it is quite hot, at least.
- Yes!
It is hot.
- Yes, it was actually warm and nice, after all.
We were a little prepared to freeze now.
- Taxi.
- Shall we take a taxi?
Now we are on our way to a house that we have rented in central Auckland.
- Yes!
- But God, what scary!
- Very exciting ... - I didn't see you!
He made an "Alma".
Oh, God ...
- To make an "Alma", it is to just show up behind.
- Yes.
Oh, God.
We have arrived!
Yey!
- Should we go in and check out the townhouse?
- Yes!
We rent this from a family living abroad.
Wow!
Oh!
Great!
You can put on Netflix, in addition!
There is an upstairs!
Yes, but we have to check the kitchen and the patio first, then we go up and then check.
I stay here.
Here we can sit and eat.
Here we can cook our food.
Here is our upstairs!
Here's my room!
- Do you take this?
- Yes, I'll take this.
I pax it.
Here Harry can sleep.
- Should Harry have such a big bed?
- Yep!
The toilet.
Oh, nice!
Oh, it looks good!
- Oh, how yellow it got in the camera.
- Well!
That's how it is.
Mom and Dad's bed!
- Here is a small balcony.
- and a mirror.
Wow ...
Super nice, after all!
And very hot!
Oh, it smells like food!
I get so hungry.
Yes ... I understand that you are hungry, you did not eat so well on the flight.
Hi, Harry!
- Do you want to build with me?
- Yes, we come down and build with you.
Alma and Harry ...
We should take out your braids.
No...
They are not so nice anymore.
Now we have been here for a few days.
YES!
And the children's braids have left.
Harry, your smile, so ...
We have a question of today's question that very many have asked.
And it is: "What should you do in New Zealand?".
I know!
Going motorhome for a month!
- Yes!
- Just right!
We will stay in Auckland for a few days, then we have rented a camper that we will go around with.
And of course we will vlog throughout the trip!
Thank you for watching this video!
Feel free to leave a thumbs up ...
... or down.
Comment, ask questions, and have a great time until we see you next time!
- See you!
- Bye!