- Good morning.
How are you?
- Good.
What is happening today?
- We will go to swimming school.
- Yes.
I go on the brand stakeholders and he walks on the bats.
- What are the brand stakeholders?
- You swim and take marks.
- Is it hard?
- Yes.
I will swim 8 meters underwater, so I will dive 8 meters, and it is very difficult.
- Do you do it, then?
- No, but I'll do it today.
I have promised myself.
- Alma, did you say exactly 800 meters?
- No!
8 meters.
I thought you said 800 meters!
Swim 800 meters underwater, then you die.
- How is Dad, then?
- Not good.
- He is a little pain, he has stabbed his neck.
- Yes.
Hello.
Dad, are you doing well?
Yes I am fine.
I have a little pain in my neck only.
I lie here and rest.
If you follow our Instagram then you know that Dad Axel injured his neck when we were at a trampoline park.
Yes.
We didn't film a vlog then, we were just there to jump and bounce.
Mm.
- And then Axel would make a backwards down into a foam pit.
- mm.
And I stood and filmed with the cellphone.
Yes.
It hurt my neck so I really thought that something had broken, so I didn't dare move.
The staff believed that too called 112, and then came an ambulance.
Ambulance could not get yourself up, then the fire brigade came.
It was totally crazy!
Four firefighters and two ambulance personnel lifted me up on a stretcher with a lot of Velcro, type.
We have got a lot of time on the day's question on Instagram about how you feel.
I went to the hospital and was x -rayed.
They saw that nothing was wrong, so I had to go home.
- So now we have a little ... what do you say?
Stucking dad.
- Yes.
- But you shouldn't be all day?
- No no.
- You have to move a little.
- Yes some.
We will fix a picnic and go to the lake.
First it is Harry's swimming school, and then Alma's brand recipient.
- mm.
What a sunny day.
- Nice, huh?
- Yes.
- We are not spoiled with the sun.
- No.
- It's been pretty bad weather in July.
- Yes.
- We're a little late.
You may run into your group, Harry.
- Yes.
- I can't jump the bomb so well.
- No, it can ... it ... it ... I know that.
- Although I can float.
- Yes you can.
You are good at that.
You are great on that.
Hello Hello!
Now the swimming school children heat up.
Other directions, the other way!
- Come all my little kids!
- How?
Like little old man, gallop!
Good!
Good, Harry!
It's not very hot.
Harry, you have to eat properly after swimming school.
You were very capable after all.
- I'm freezing.
- I understand that you are freezing.
It's not a huge gun.
No.
Only the sun is warming.
- Alma, soon it's your turn to jump in. - No!
- Yes!
- No!
- Nice, Alma!
You are very close.
Here I am.
- Oh!
- You've been there.
- It's too far away!
And it's harder than I thought.
You can do it!
Just push away properly from the bridge.
Press away properly from the dock.
- Oh, check out how far you came!
Now you got even further.
- You're so close!
It is very giant.
Come on, Alma!
Swim, Alma.
Swim.
Continue.
Oh, check out!
Do you see?
Where are you?
No!
It was great!
I give up.
It was a little cold in the water but I still dived.
- Give a towel here!
- Oh oh oh!
Here you go.
She couldn't do it, she was really aware!
Yes, but then, that you dive from the edge and that you do not hold for your nose, Alma.
It is absolutely incredible!
I'm really impressed.
Oh!
Harry massages my neck ... which I have so much pain.
He is actually very good at massaging.
He takes in his whole body as well.
It is very nice, Harry.
You can make money like this, by massaging me.
Did you know that?
I don't want to make money, it's just that I want to watch.
Well.
But then you can serve a look minute.
I want to watch Youtube and play.
Obviously he wants it.
Well, all children want it.
We have gone to Gustavsberg to wash our car.
Or, it's not really our car.
We have a collaboration with Mitsubishi who lends this pearl to us over the summer.
And I never want to return it.
We go on a road trip with this.
So it is a plug-in hybrid which means we can only take a cord ... into our electrical outlet.
Then we can drive for 4 miles and when the electricity runs out we drive on gasoline.
It's absolutely amazing, I'm in love with it.
Now that we live in the countryside we almost only drive on electricity.
It's absolutely fantastic!
It is great for nature.
- You should suck in here.
- Yes!
- It's really great.
- Can I suck?
Yes.
This is how we will do more with the children.
They will be able to work more this summer.
So.
Thanks and ticks.
Since Dad Axel is injured and behind the camera he is our supervisor now, children.
Listen to him.
- Okay.
Then you help mom remove everything from the car.
- Okay!
You can put this on.
- Should this be thrown away?
- Just put that.
Look what I succeeded in!
I picked it up all by myself.
I pressed the button up there.
Good!
- Oh, Dad has packed down car cleaning stuff.
- Yes.
How good cargo space?
- Look!
My phone.
- It's not yours, it's Dad's.
- But that's my shell.
- Alma has not received her first phone yet.
- Harry, are you prepared?
- Yes.
- That one will start to suck.
- Okay, hold it.
Look at it.
- Yes.
Now I stop!
- Now the inside of the car is clean.
- Yay!
Good job, everyone.
- And I found money on the ground!
SEK 5.
- How nice.
- You're rich.
- Yes, worst Lyllo.
Now we will drive a giant card and then we will wash the outside of the car.
If you wash the car then I can build a hut with you a little later.
- Yes!
- Kurrisin ...
- "Kurrisin" ... Kurrisin Frances comes over.
- Yes.
Cousin.
Yes, I know - cousin.
I have a little trouble talking, you know how I am.
- Sometimes you stumble on the words.
- Do you really manage to build with your neck?
Eeh ... Yes, it feels pretty good.
I'm a little stiff, but I think I can be a supervisor there too.
Here I have found.
Top, Harry!
This will be great.
- Here I have found!
- Oh, what good.
- Mine wasn't that big.
- No, though mine was very big.
You can use all planks when building a hut.
You do not have to follow any rules.
You can build with any planks.
- Dad, take this.
- Yes, we will probably use it for something well soon.
- And then we'll find a door.
- Just that, the door.
- The blue door.
- mm, the blue door.
- It's behind Brännhögen.
- Yes, you can try to see if you can lift it.
Here I have found a plank!
The blue door that Harry talks about is the door to our old playhouse that I have been torn recently.
I actually made a time Lapse on it so we might be able to put this in.
That one, yes!
Now I found something that should be on the floor.
This should be on the floor.
- Harry found something on the floor.
- How nice.
- Although there were two nails.
- Well, oh.
Yes, it happens to be.
It was just that.
Ah!
Oh...
God, how heavy.
I have to release it and then I have to wear it.
Lol!
It went well.
Dad!
NEM GOD, HARRY!
Beware so you don't hurt yourself.
- Strong, huh?
- Very strong!
- Much stronger than you.
- Yes, a lot.
Oh, don't crush your feet.
Ah!
Oh oh oh.
- There.
- We can build it.
Now I can't bear to carry anymore.
That one can be on the floor.
- Should it also be on the floor?
- Yes, for it ...
- Now we have planks to the floor, I think.
- Yes.
We will continue with this tomorrow.
- Do you think so?
- Yes.
Okay, then we're laying down now.
Now it's time to sleep.
How does it feel in the neck, Dad?
It feels very stiff.
But it gets better and better.
I have no problems with it, that it hurts so, because I am so grateful that it went well.
So am I.
Thanks for watching this video!
Feel free to leave a thumbs up, or down.
Comment, subscribe, ask questions and have a great time until we see you next time.
- Bye!