P*NIS, COOL.
That one was actually not me.
Out of chaos comes order,
and pretty funny moments.
Just stop rowing because you're ruining everything!
You're making us hit the rock.
Good morning.
We're sitting here, in a parking lot, in Stenstorp.
We are discovering Skaraborg this week.
Harry, can't you sit up and join in a little?
We took the car here today,
and Alma and Harry started to argue in the car.
When we arrived,
they went in different directions in the parking lot.
Alma went that way, and Axel and Laura followed.
Harry sat down here, and I followed him.
Now the others are coming.
- Hi.
- There's been some fighting.
- I know.
Welcome to the parking lot.
Well, the small patch of grass next to the parking lot.
- In Stenstorp.
- I know.
You guys.
Can you make up, please?
- Please?
- Please, please?
- Let's bury the hatchet.
- Okay.
Okay.
- Hugs!
Now we are going in here,
to Dalénium Science Center.
Go ahead and enter.
Oh, Harry is holding the door. Excellent.
Hey, hey!
- Hey! Welcome!
- Thank you.
- 1, 2, 3, 4. There's one missing.
- Yes, he held the door.
- A gentleman. Welcome to Dalénium!
- Thank you!
So, this is a science center.
Do you know what that is?
- No.
- A little. Kind of.
A little. Yes.
There are 20 science centers in Sweden, and a bunch abroad.
We all do about the same things.
There are things to try out, and experiments.
We also have shows.
Everything centers around different phenomena and properties
in the technical and scientific field.
Oh, look at this.
Ah, I get it.
Can I play with you?
- "Pipe organ."
- Wait, I'll use my own.
Oh, Laura is dancing to it.
- Daddy, your slippers.
- Thanks.
- Come! Let's keep going.
- Yes!
- What are you supposed to make?
- The letter F.
- There.
- Yes, smart.
And then, like so.
Now. Now, now, now!
Yellow.
Green.
Black.
Blue.
Pink.
Yes!
Yes, there.
- There was something else to look at.
- The pretty, red lamp.
- Are you there?
- Hello?
- Oh my God, it works!
- Can I hear?
Oh my God.
Jesus Christ! Oh my God.
- God, this is so cool.
- Yes, it's really fun!
Harry is standing over there.
1, 2, 3!
I think this has been a great activity
when it's so hot out.
I'm very tired
from all the brain gymnastics.
I'm not used to exercising
these parts up here.
I think it's easier for kids.
Oh, definitely!
They're going at it back here, building and stuff.
Alma is building a house for Laura,
with the help of some newfound friends.
I also have to say that it's been a great activity
for two arguing siblings-
-because they've had to work together
and come up with things.
Mm.
- The argument from this morning is forgotten.
- Yes. A bit difficult to film here, though.
Yes. I often think we end up in situations
that are difficult to film, and then I'm like:
"What footage do we even have
from this place?"
- And then it is what it is.
- Mm.
This is Laura's house!
- Does she like it?
- I think so.
- Is that the bed?
- Yes.
- It looks a little small.
- No, it's fine.
And I've built two cars for Laura.
- How great to have a little sister to build for!
- Yes. Super great.
- Has she tried them?
- I think she'll like this one the most.
What's daddy doing now?
What is that?
It's a long spring.
You can learn about waves and how they propagate.
Laura, this is your car.
Ready, set, go!
How was it?
So good!
It was so much fun!
- What did you think?
- It was fun. Really fun.
- The car is over here.
- What?!
I've prepped, just like on cooking shows
when they've already baked the bread.
Are you also the one who prepped this?
#P*NIS
#COOL
That one was actually not me, but I wrote #COOL
because I miss my old beanie that said #COOL.
Well, it wasn't really mine.
It was Alma's.
- And who is #P*NIS?
- I don't know.
- Harry.
- No.
It wasn't me!
I don't write that ugly.
So, about #COOL...
It was a - sorry, Alma - really ugly beanie that Alma had,
that Axel wore once when we filmed.
I used it for quite a while.
I had lost my beanie.
I know, it was awful.
- It's in a vlog. I just don't remember what it's called.
- Me neither.
- It's so long ago.
- You can look for it.
Anyway. Now we are on our way to a place called Maplelake,
where we will spend the night.
Yes!
Look.
Here is where we will stay.
- I'll sleep here, double dibs!
- "Double dibs." I wonder if we're all staying in one tent.
- I hope we have both tents, but I don't know.
- We will see.
Look!
Oh... Look at this.
Daddy. Your favorite sport.
This was cozy!
Oh, wow! Speed badminton. Wow!
There's a little fan there, buzzing.
It's really hot in this tent.
- Yes.
- It'll probably be cooler in the evening.
- Shall we guess that's for Laura?
- I think so.
Or shall we all squeeze in here?
- I don't know. No, that'll probably be too cramped.
- Alma and I will sleep here.
- Laura fell asleep in the car. We haven't just left her.
- No. Well, yes. But she's sleeping soundly.
- Candy.
- No.
- Soda.
- Smoothie for Laura.
- That's good. You'll have to save the other stuff for Saturday.
Come!
- Hello! Welcome.
- Thanks!
- Fun that you're here.
- It feels good to be here.
That's nice.
Have you been to Tidaholm before?
Never.
We have no idea what's going on here.
It's a small town, but there's still a lot to do here.
That's good.
Yes. How cozy.
For starters... I don't know how peckish you are right now,
but here's something for the boat ride.
Or if you feel like you can't even
paddle a single stroke before...
- How lovely!
- Some Swedish Fika and fruit.
Oh, how nice!
The kids are, like: "Oh, wow. Yum!"
Both tents are for us.
This one was meant for the parents
and the other one is prepared for the kids.
We'll need to make some kind of switch.
Yes!
It's so fun, because this campsite is located
in the middle of the town, Tidaholm.
So, we will stay in a tent
in a town with more than 12,000 inhabitants.
- It'll be so fun!
- Pretty unique, right?
A completely new experience.
We haven't booked this place ourselves,
just like in the previous video.
We make this trip in collaboration with
Visit Skaraborg.
No! Experience Skaraborg.
But it's kind of the same thing.
And here comes a little troll.
- Yes, who I think is a little eager to go boating.
- I think so too.
What are you laughing at?
Harry just told me I'm a p*nis band.
I told him that he needs this p*nis band.
He was, like: "You're a p*nis band."
Sometimes things happen between takes
that are pretty funny.
Now we are going to ride a boat.
The boat is just 50 meters from our tent.
(55 yards)
This is going to be exciting.
"Ride a boat" was a little... exaggerated.
We are actually going rowing.
- On this river.
- Yes.
- It's called Tidan, and runs through Tidaholm.
Good! Professional, Harry.
Here comes an oar!
- Don't kill me.
- I won't kill you.
- No, we're going the wrong way.
- Now you're going backwards.
Wait, Harry. Stop it.
Harry, stop.
How about I do the rowing instead?
It looks like Harry thinks that
you should row together.
- We are spinning around, at least.
- Yes, but...
In circles. Now we're going back.
Hello, jetty.
- If we are going that way, as you said, this is correct.
- Alma just has to row a little more. Come on, Alma!
Harry, stop rowing like me!
Just stop rowing because you're ruining everything!
You're making us hit the rock.
- This is a great group exercise.
- Yes.
- No, it's not.
- Yes!
- That turned out pretty good in the end.
- Yes, it was really cozy.
- It just started out a little chaotic.
- Yes.
- Just like our day.
- I almost said, "Just like our life."
- Exactly. Just like our whole life.
Out of chaos comes order, and pretty funny moments.
Something like that.
Yes.
- Now we are going to eat... there.
- At a restaurant.
- It's called La Familia. That's fitting for us.
- Come along!
Yes, come along. I think Alma and Harry
are really hungry, because they're so quiet.
- And a little tired, I think.
- Yes. Being on summer break is tough.
- Hey!
- Hey! Welcome!
- Thank you! How are you?
- Fine, thanks. You?
- Fine, thanks. Is this your restaurant?
- Yes, it's mine.
- Nice!
- Hi!
God, how cute!
- You got an antenna when you took off your hood.
- Yeah. Joanna is fascinated by hairstyles.
- No, it fell.
- I felt how it, like...
- Was the hood to be anonymous when you walked in here?
- Yes. The first thing that happens is that four moms...
- Shall I put together two tables?
- This is great, thank you.
This is perfect.
- As I said...
- The first thing that happens is that four moms...
Four moms were, like: "We are almost a little starstruck."
I didn't even... I hadn't even passed them.
Thank you so much. Menu.
- Thank you. Nice.
- Have a little look at it.
- Oh, how good to have some food.
- So yummy.
Oh my God, that was one cheesy pizza!
And gluten-free, to Alma's great joy.
Super yummy.
We have just gotten ready
at this center behind us.
There's a kitchen, a laundry room,
toilets, showers, and such.
And now we will go back
to our tent and sleep.
- And how will we sleep?
- Girl tent and boy tent.
- What?!
- Yes.
What was that voice?!
"I'm a girl."
No, but I'd love to sleep in a tent with Harry.
- And I'd love to sleep in a tent with Alma and Laurita.
- Yes.
- So, we'll have the one with three beds.
- Yep.
Oh, someone is driving by with loud music.
There are many greasers here.
Laura's, like: "What was that?"
Now we are here.
You're staying here.
- Good night, then!
- Good night!
- It's been a few days.
- And now Harry isn't here.
No.
Anyway, we slept in the tents.
How was it, Alma?
At first, it was really, really, really cold.
Then it got really, really, really, really, really hot.
Like it is to sleep in a tent.
Even when they're smaller.
In the morning, we got a really nice breakfast basket,
and I posted on Instagram stories where we were.
Then people started showing up.
- Very, very, very many people.
- Like a tidal wave.
In Tidaholm.
And I walked around in my underwear
and my hair was all messy.
It was very difficult to film anything more there,
because things kept happening.
Eventually, we had to move on. So...
We got, like, a little panicked.
Or, we were shocked. Like, God!
Yes, but everyone was really nice, it wasn't that.
It just got a little much.
- Yes.
And then we were going to other places
in Skaraborg, so... that was that.
Thank you for watching this video!
- Please leave a thumbs up, or down.
- Mostly thumbs up!
- Comment, ask questions and take care until next time.
- See you!
Bye-bye!