It smells awful.
Psych!
It's sour.
5 points.
I'm a little fart.
Yaaaaaay!
Hey, hey!
Today we are going to try...
Crazy candy!
YAY! "OUII!" (candy)
- Laura has already started.
- She's cheating.
Little cheater!
- But it's fine, she's only 2 years old.
- Yes, she's excused.
Here's the thing...
We often go to the store and see candy
that looks a little crazy and funny.
Yaaaaay, yaaay!
And then Alma and Harry asked if we can try crazy candy.
So, not from a particular country.
No, exactly. Just crazy candy.
- So now we have gathered...
- A bunch of crazy candy.
YAY, YAY, YAY!
- Let's start right away.
- YAY!
"Lamp Spray"
It's a candy spray...
with a light in the package.
Sour.
More.
- Very sour. Do you want to try it, Laura?
- No.
You don't want to try it?
- But it was good.
- I don't know, I've never understood liquid candy.
It's like squash concentrate
that hasn't been properly diluted.
There's something about it being a spray too.
It feels like you're spraying hairspray in your mouth.
You think?
- Do you want to try mine?
- Yes.
- My spray tastes like raspberry.
- But it's blue?
I know, but there's a raspberry on the package, so...
Yeah, it's raspberry.
This should taste like strawberry,
but it doesn't taste like strawberry. It tastes sour.
This one should taste like green apple.
You might notice a hint of green apple.
Do you also want to try it now, Laura?
How many points do you give it, from 1 to 5?
5.
- Or wait, 0 to 5.
- Yes.
- 5.
- 5?!
Me too. 5.
I'd buy this for Friday's coziness.
- What? Friday's coziness?
- Yes.
- Zero coziness factor with...
- I totally agree. Very un-cozy.
- Is this lamp for the coziness, then?
- No, but... Well, a little.
I give this 0 points, but it was a lamp
and I like cool stuff, so it gets 1 point for the lamp.
Oh, you changed your mind. You rounded up.
I give it 1 point.
Laura, how many points do you give it?
"Um." One.
One, one, one, one, one.
"Cotton Candy Buttered Popcorn Flavor"
It's cotton candy
with the taste of buttery popcorn.
- Such nasty texture.
- Are cotton candy in a chip bag a common thing?
- I don't know. "Made in the USA," it says here.
- Exciting. Okay.
- Let's try it.
- Let's try it. 1, 2, 3.
It really tastes like butter-flavored popcorn.
No.
How crazy!
- Laura doesn't seem to like it.
- No.
She's reaching for her candy deodorant.
- I think this was good.
- You like this?
It's something completely new for me.
Not my thing. Not my thing.
I mean... I'm shocked.
I don't know what I was expecting, but not this.
I probably would have bought this candy
if there was no other candy left in the store.
Not a very good store, in other words.
I think I'll give it 4.5.
4.5?!
Whoa.
I give it 1 point. Too messy.
I give it 1 point. I think it was really disgusting, but...
It tasted a little bit like popcorn.
- Mm, that's where the point came in.
- Yes.
I completely agree. I give it 3 points.
Way too messy for me.
Completely impossible to have in a home with a bunch of kids.
But, yeah, it tastes like it says it should taste.
- What do you give it, Laura?
- Are you eating on a wet wipe?
Eww! Yuck.
- Laura, how many points do you give it?
- It was quite similar.
Om-nom-nom! Yaaaay!
Okay. It sounds like 3 or 4 points.
- "Gango"?
- "Gingo!"
- "Gingo."
- What!
"Gingo" is "cinco". So, 5 points.
"Milka Mmmax Choco Jelly"
It's a chocolate bar filled with jelly pieces.
- Oh, this jelly is very rubbery.
- Mm.
- I haven't had any jelly yet.
- No, I only have crackling.
- Crackling?
- Me too. It's crackling in the mouth, like popping candy.
- Yes!
- Oh, it's filled with different things!
Yes, it crackles and pops in the mouth.
This was a little festive.
Do you think this is available in Sweden?
- No.
- Maybe at the store Normal.
- You think? Do they usually have Milka?
- Yes. But maybe not this kind.
Oh, this is kind of fun.
You guys at home...
We don't know which of these are available Sweden,
so you can comment below.
Good idea. Do that.
Do you hear how it crackles and pops?
- Sticky.
- Sticky? Yes, chocolate makes you sticky.
- "Uaua" sticky.
- Yes. Laura is sticky.
I like this candy.
I think it's festive and maybe fun to share with someone.
I give it 3 points because I didn't really like the jellybeans.
They were a bit hard.
I also give it 3 points.
Fun with the crackling. Unexpected.
- I give it 0 points.
- Oh! 0 points?
- Why's that?
- That's why. It was gross with the jello.
Oh. I thought it was really good.
It reminds me of when I was little and made candy in the freezer.
I melted chocolate and mixed it with
pick and mix candy.
I give it 4 points.
It was fun and festive.
"Baby Unicorn Dipper"
It's a dipper lollipop that you can open...
and then you dip it in the powder that's in here.
- It smells a bit suspicious.
- It smells awful.
Oh, Laura, you got a blue nose.
- Oh, it's the unicorn's hair.
- It just tastes like sugar.
- I can't even get it in the powder.
- It doesn't fit? Oh no.
- How are you supposed to dip it in the powder?
- Like this, look.
- Right.
- Oops.
No, what a horrible candy.
Wait! You can put some powder in this...
- Oh, smart. That's how you do it.
- In the cap.
- This is so disgusting.
- Laura, your unicorn has such big eyes. It's really cute.
It tastes like...
It tastes like Dextrosol.
- But this is more sour. It's sour.
- This tastes just like Dextrosol.
This isn't sour.
Look, mommy!
You're right! Now I recognize it.
It's Dextrosol.
It's not like Hockey powder. This is Dextrosol.
This is as much instant sugar as it gets.
Zerooo! Zerooo!
- I give it fiveee, fiveee!
- What?
- Do you give it 5?
- What? 5 points.
Psych!
- What do you really give it?
- "Psych" means the opposite. Zero!
- You don't like it either.
- Zerooo...
- Laura also went like...
"Trolli Jelly Eyeballs"
They come in a plastic bag
and look like eyes.
- There's something sour and runny inside!
- Oh, yuck.
Stop it.
Hey, you haven't even eaten yours!
- This is such Halloween candy.
- Yes!
You mean, "such gross Halloween candy"?
Yeah, it's a bit repulsive to eat.
- Why is it red?
- That's the blood.
Creepy.
I give this 2 points because I love Halloween.
I also give it 2 points, because it's a good Halloween treat
to give to kids who want to trick or treat.
- Eww. 0 points.
- "Eww", as he throws the eye.
I also give this 2 points.
Great packaging. Fun and perfect for Halloween.
- Crazy.
- Mm.
- How can you like this kind of thing?
- "Konkink."
"Konkink", says Laura. She wants to open another one.
I think that means she agrees with us.
"Mentos Fanta"
It's completely ordinary Mentos candies, that are orange.
- Wow!
- It really tastes like Fanta.
- Yes, it really does.
Put those eyes away now.
What does that in your mouth taste like?
Fanta without carbonation.
Was it good?
I think this tastes just like
regular orange-flavored Mentos.
No, it doesn't.
Therefore, I give this 0 points.
It's just a re-branding of an old product.
No, now you're negative. This tastes like Fanta.
I give it 3 points.
I give it 3 points, same as mommy.
I give it...
0 points.
- What?
- Zerooo!
You don't like it.
"Crazy Roll-On"
It's this little deodorant
that Laura has been sitting with.
I have Blue Raspberry flavor.
- Strawberry.
- Green Apple.
Laura has Green Apple,
and this is Blue Raspberry.
- Let's go!
- Yes!
- Such a quirky way to eat candy.
- You think?
Green Apple was so good.
Love this one.
Can I try it?
- So you two like these?
- Yes, I love them.
But it's a useless way to eat.
I also don't understand the roll-on thing.
It's like there were some deodorant bottles left over in the factory.
- And the noise is so unpleasant, like...
- Yes.
- Laura has a good technique.
- Mm. Although the bottle leaks if you turn it upside down.
- I think this is one that children like and adults just don't understand.
- No, exactly.
- You don't want yours?
- No, go ahead.
I give it... ZEROOO!
- Me too. 0 points.
- How could you?
- What?
- Yes.
I give it 5 points. 5, 5, 5.
- 5, 5, 5!
- 0, 0, 0!
- 5, 5, 5...
- 0, 0, 0...
- And do you give it?
- 0, 0!
- No, Laura!
- Three against two. It's a 0.
"Milka Oreo"
It's Milka chocolate with small Oreo cookies in it.
Laura is still playing with the eyeballs.
But this one was really good.
Everyone loves Oreo, right?
- No.
- What?!
I don't like Oreo.
I love Oreo, I love Milka. Perfectly mixed.
I've eaten this before. I love it.
- Mm-mm-mm.
- I think it tastes like dust.
- Dust?!
- You are not like the rest of us.
- You're a little fart.
- I'm a little fart. I'm a little fart.
- I give it 4 points.
I give it...
...5 points.
Five?
Oh my God.
I give this one 1 point.
- ONLY ONE?
- Yep!
"XXL Acid Gumetro"
It's some long sausage with... chewing gum!
- It's sour.
- Very sour.
Sour?
- Don't you feel it?
- No. Yes, now. It came late.
- Harry!
- Hey, no, no, no...
Oh God, how sour.
Here, you can have mine.
No.
- Horrible!
- I'm crying.
Horrible!
- Eww!
- Ouch, my eye.
Eww!
- You get sweaty eyelids from this candy.
- You get sweaty everywhere.
I give this chewing gum 3.5 points in terms of taste.
And I actually think this candy deserves crazy points
I give it 4 crazy points.
Yes, it was very crazy.
It gets only crazy points from me, 2 points. But 0 for the taste.
I give it, like, 4 crazy points, because it was pretty crazy.
It looked like Shrek poo.
And it was like...
The taste wasn't that good, so I give it 3 points.
- Mm. And Laura, what do you give it? Is it good to clean the toes with?
- Why is she putting it on her toes? Eww.
She's cleaning between her toes
with Alma's chewing gum over here.
What do you give it, Axel?
I give this 0 points.
But I give it 2 points for the packaging, so it gets 1 point.
"Boom Vampire Extra Sour"
They are small hard blue candies.
So hard.
Oh, it's so sour.
- Woho!
- Wohoho!
Oh, you're…
- It says "Mouth Painter."
- It turns your mouth blue.
- Really blue.
- No...
Mommy...
Oh, Laura.
- I give this one 0 points.
- What?!
- I didn't think it was fun.
- But it's crazy.
Yes, it was blue and it was very sour.
- Harry, how many points do you give it?
- I give it 500. Getting a blue tongue was super fun.
Yes. I give it 5 points. It was good, it was sour,
and I think it's fun that it stained my mouth.
I give it 3 points.
And you know what? This was our last candy
and the sun is setting outside.
Yes, so we have to wrap up and say…
Thank you for watching this video!
Please leave a thumbs up, or down.
Mostly thumbs up.
- Comment...
- Ask questions, and take care.
And subscribe!
Take care until next time!
- Bye-bye!
- Take care, bye-bye!