Hello Hello
Today is a sunny day.
It's warm and nice.
We thought we should put in our ...
Boat!
- Boat!
Your boat.
Your old hull, shoulder.
Yes.
This one is like an old abrasive patches.
It's so risky
But it works, and we haven't tested it since I bought it, so we have to test it.
It's about time.
- Yes!
We have driven to a supplementary ramp on the island where we have our summer house.
Here is the car.
Here is the boat.
You see
Yes.
- (Harry) No.
You look pretty good, I think.
It's a little light, so you get a little dazzled.
Here we also have a small treasure.
- (Harry) We will bring it.
(Axel) Oh, she seems to be bothered by the light.
- (Joanna) Yes.
(Harry) the steering wheel is steering
Everything you do the first time takes some time.
It becomes like a little "trial and error".
Do you know what "Trial and Error" means?
- No.
You try, you fail, you do it again.
You try, you do right hopefully - and so it will be good.
Yes.
It will be fine.
So there, check out.
It seems to float.
Oh, there lies my macaop bag
(Joanna) You and your sandwiches, so ... you love sandwiches.
Yes, yes, I do.
You also love sandwiches, but you must not eat it.
- No.
I have a hate love for sandwiches.
What happens if you eat sandwiches, then?
-Ehm ... Sprutti-Bang-Bang.
Because you can't tolerate wheat.
- No.
Jösses, so it flows.
That's a good sign.
Dad, you must not sit down!
- No, but I have to start the engine and see it goes.
But you can remove the macaop, okay?
- Okay.
(Joanna) Harry is mostly broken about her sandwiches.
- (Harry) sandwiches ...
This is pretty good, that we are like this.
Check out this little Donnan.
The life jacket is kind of larger than her.
(Alma) What a cute!
- (shoulder) So sweet!
(Harry) Oh, her arms!
They are gone.
- (Joanna) She seems to enjoy it, strangely enough.
It's like a main foot.
- Great!
Now Axel and the kids will go away with the boat.
I will take the car away for us and then they will pick me up on the bridge where we live.
Because this is a bit away on the island.
Okay, then we'll see you then, then
See you just as soon, I hope.
- Yeah!
I hope so too.
What should I do with the rope?
- We take it in when we come out a bit.
Don't get a motor stop now, because then Laura can be very hungry and angry.
Yes, we will try.
What happened now?
- We got a motor stop.
You are joking?
- No.
What are we going to do now?
- I do not know.
No, but ... you are joking?
- No, I'm not kidding.
We may be able to call someone who can help.
- Dad is kidding.
No, I'm not joking, that is.
It died.
It is newly tanked and newly served.
I've been on this boat for what three minutes?
I sat down.
Took a rice cake ...
And it died.
- Yes, and so the engine died.
But we can still go to Grandma and Grandpa, because they are over there.
Yes, we are quite close to Grandma and Grandpa's jetty.
- That was fortunate.
Or, well.
Not very close, huh?
- (Harry) Well.
I'll see if we can start again.
(The engine starts)
Yes!
Dad cheated us!
- No.
I'm not fooled.
No, he actually pressed "Start".
(The engine does not want to start properly)
(Joanna) What do you think happens, what is the problem?
I do not know.
It sounds almost like a fuel crane that is off, but ...
Still lucky this happened when I was on the boat, because I think of poor Laura.
(The engine buzzes a little more) Now something is happening.
So I have to sit and pump with the gas for me to have some power from the engine.
It is a sign that there is crap in the carburetor.
We did not end up in sea!
But it was close.
- We ended up at Grandma and Grandpa's jetty.
Yes so far we came today.
Is anyone craving a dip?
I!
- Me too!
1, 2, 3
Was it good?
- Great!
So there.
Now I have called and talked to a good boat meal ...
... and learned that this boat is a little special, so I've learned some tricks.
So now let's see if I get it started.
It started!
- No problem.
What was the "secret trick"?!
- That's you.
Old boat with lots of small peculiarities.
This was great now we drive!
(Joanna) and Laura are just here and soft.
- (Axel) She seems to be happy.
Yes, one for boat children.
- Lovely, after all.
When Alma was little we had a wooden boat.
She was always asleep in it.
Now we are in Vaxholm where we were going to check out a bit.
We have brought SOS the reclining part to Laura, but no trolley, so ... We can't go far.
No.
But we saw that there is a place ... there, so it must be where we go, simply.
Yes came again, the family!
Do you want to sit here, maybe?
- It will be just fine.
It is absolutely incredible that you managed to get the boat started again.
- Yes I know!
I thought, "Now we get bridge sail. There will be nothing more today."
- But it worked!
Are you not impressed with dad
(Alma) Well.
- (Harry) Nah.
Aren't you impressed?
- Nah.
It's just stupid.
Gosh
And this one, she just keeps sleeping.
I am impad of her
Good with ice cream.
So what a summer day it was.
Wonderfully.
Keep in the wooden rails there.
Now we are going back to Grandma and Grandpa's jetty, because we will actually put this boat there.
And ... there is someone who has come to Grandma and Grandpa now.
Frances.
- Yes!
Who is it then?
It's my cousin and ...
Bästis, huh?
- Yes.
Cousin and best friend.
When did you last meet her
A year ago.
A year ago she lives in Dubai, so this is a huge day after all!
Should we gas there?
YES!
We speed up.
- Quick!
The foot on the gas and just ...!
Oh, look!
It's the ice cream truck!
- The ice cream truck!
On a car ferry!
How fun.
- I don't think you can see, it's too far away.
Can we buy ice cream
No...
I see Frances.
- (Joanna) What happiness!
(Harry) Hello
Are you peppered?
- Yes.
Are you happy?
- mm.
As you have longed
Will I be able to be with grandma and grandpa for a little while
Obvious.
This is the first time they meet Laura as well.
- Right.
Hello!
- Hello!
Should I receive?
- Yes please.
(Frances) Hello!
- (Joanna) Hello, old man!
How big you are!
Who wants to hold
I!
- I also!
Can I test?
Hello, Laura.
Now it's been a few days ... full of play.
Hello
I stand on the edge and am falling out of the trampoline.
I would show these two cousins.
And someone else has come!
Hussein
Hello, Youtube!
- Hi, Hussein!
Hello!
Should I also jump?
- Yes!
Hope it does not break, because I have become heavier.
Hussein Hussein!
Hussein!
It's been a long time since you jumped with us!
I didn't jump yesterday either, so ... Hörrni, I have to be a little careful.
(Harry) No!
We can hold hands!
- Hello!
Shouldn't you brush it a bit?
I can brush.
- It's lots of junk ...
(Joanna) It's a great idea.
- (Harry) Hussein!
Beware!
Karate Kid!
(Hussein) I can do it.
- (Joanna) You can hold the edges of Hussein.
Check out this trick, mom!
- (Axel) What good!
Good now you ended up right at an edge, now you can stay there and hold up.
Frances, I have to ... you can keep the edge here.
(Harry) No, I want to stand here.
(Hussein) Good.
- (Axel) Good!
Check out how good you are.
(Joanna) What are you doing, Alma?
- I clean the hut.
(Harry) I think Hussein should become a photographer when he gets a job.
(Joanna) Hussein already has a job, Harry.
- Yes, at a school.
But why not become a photographer?
(Frances) What is his job?
- Yes, what is your job, Hussein?
My job I work at a school.
Hussein is a leisure leader.
So there
(Joanna) Nice!
- Thanks!
There are two more chairs.
But you ... - Yes?
It is a question that comes back on our channel every week.
What happens to your Youtube channel?
That's the question.
No but...
I actually made a video that I will post ... soon.
It is a video where I test dolls with my best friend.
Yes.
Alma has been peeled with dolls lately ... quite a lot.
When I edited the part where we are out with the boat ... then you see that you are pilling with a doll type all the time.
Pay attention to viewers have probably already seen that doll.
And you are not a doll game otherwise.
No, but I just realized it was ... fun, and that people seem to like dolls, so ...
Now I will test some dolls and toys on my channel in the future.
The whole thing with Alma having her own channel started by making videos for her class
During our first long journey.
For every country we visited she made a type of 5 minutes long video
For the class to watch, which was about that country.
It was very much appreciated and we realized that maybe more people wanted to see them,
So we posted them on their own Youtube channel for her.
Since then, it has not happened very much on that channel.
No.
She has tested L.O.L.
Surprise Dolls sometime.
This channel is completely ... depending on Alma's desire.
We do not control it and we do not encourage her to it either.
We have this channel.
Yes.
But then she got the feeling with her best friend UMA
A few days ago and recorded a video.
And then she thought, "I might continue to test toys".
And it fits on that channel and not on this one.
That's not what we want to do.
No.
So, now there is an answer to that question, because it has come quite a lot.
Yes, so if you like dolls, for example, you can go in and check out.
Or "Fidget Toys" I know she has talked about doing something with.
Yes exactly.
Then you can keep a little lookout on Alma's channel.
It's called "The Swedish Alma".
We get to tip about it.
Do you think viewers wonder where Laura is?
- Yes.
She is sleeping.
- As usual.
Our boat was not really to be trusted, so it is facing a total renovation.
That you should do.
That I should do.
- Don't mix us into it.
Sometime in the future.
But, yes ... it will come at a later date.
In the next video on the channel, both Hussein and Frances are included.
So keep an eye out
Yes
Thank you for watching this video
Feel free to leave a thumbs up, or down.
Most thumbs up
Comment, ask questions and have a great time and we will see you again soon.
Bye!
- See you in the next video!