Hello Hello!
We are in Hammarby Sjöstad in Stockholm, and what should we do?
- Bake!
- Yay!
A while ago we got an email from a guy named Albin.
His father is a baker and is called Magnus.
His bakery & pastry is there!
Here!
- They should teach us to bake.
- Hopefully something very miserable.
We will bake pastries and croissants.
- Yes!
I love croissants.
And pastry.
- It will be super good.
See what a lot of butter.
Below the camera is the butter that we will bake into the doughs.
- Is that the Croissants and that to the pastries?
- Yes exactly.
- What a lot of butter is needed for croissants.
- Is this a messy guy?
- Yes, he's super busy.
- You can sit on my shoulders and bake, maybe.
Here we will add the dough.
Then we will press some of these buttons, but not now!
Then the hand becomes pancake.
Any?
If you press it, it goes here and if you press it it goes to it.
This is what we will roll into the dough.
It's almost as much butter as dough, do you see?
- Yes.
- Feel it.
It's a bit elastic.
- It's hard.
- It's a bit like rubber.
Check!
Now it came out.
We will try to get it as long.
It should be as much dough at the bottom as on the top.
- Harry, do you want to help put on the butter?
- Yes.
- Nice!
- Good there.
High five!
- Now you got lots of butter ... - Okay.
Fold over it, Alma.
All the way.
Then you can pull a little in the butter ... or in the dough, sorry.
- ... so it's just like this, do you see?
- It is not possible to pull in butter.
You have made a sandwich!
No, it's no sandwich.
We make it layer of butter, dough, butter, dough.
- Stay there.
- Harry, do you want to press the second button?
Perfect.
Now we will do what you call "three -stroke" in bakery language.
This is one.
So this will be two, it is important that you dot almost right, and so it will be like this - three.
- Do you know why you do it?
- No.
In pastry and croissants there is layer of butter and dough.
Now we will have about 1044 layers of butter, dough, butter, dough ... so they get crispy and good.
- How big will they be?
- It depends on how big you make them.
What did you say?
- 1044 layers exactly?
- Stay here.
No Harry, absolutely not!
- May I count them?
- Yes, you have to do that when we eat them.
We have rolled so, and then we turn it in this direction, and we will do the same again.
- Who is going to drive now, then?
- Alma!
Alma, beware!
Now we must be careful so that we do not destroy the layers.
Okay Alma, then we press here.
- Pull a little in the dough too.
- Good.
A little more.
Get to know, do you have muscles here?
Yes, you had.
Then we do this, oh hi oh.
Harry.
So.
What happened now?
Place it there.
Oops!
- Place it straight and think about the layers.
- I'll see where Harry and Axel went.
How's it going?
Yes it is good, but we needed a little break and talk a little about that with listening.
It was a little difficult for Harry in there for a while.
I asked if he heard what Magnus said and then he just said "no".
There were some other sounds and machines and dough you could dress with, then so ... there was so much that happened.
- The machines were cool.
- Yes, they are cool.
- Harry has the ability to be overhead.
- Yes.
Then it is difficult for him to take in what others say.
Yes, and today Alma is also a little overhead, I would say.
Then it becomes super difficult to be a parent, but we do our best.
Yes.
It will be difficult to record a vlog in a good way and get good material.
And it will be very difficult to edit the material and make it so that you who are watching understand what we do.
That's why we went out to give Alma a little more space so she can join in and bake.
And it gets a little calmer.
- Now let's roll pastry!
- Yep.
Then I think we can do this with this one, that we cut up lengths.
- And then you roll it.
- Oh!
For example, you can do an eight by making an S first, turning them there, and turning it.
Then you have an eight.
- If we want an eight.
- If you want an eight.
If you don't want an eight, you can just spin it like a round ...
- I will do that.
- They look like macaroni.
- Fold the snibber under.
- I want to do that.
Good.
Now these are going to ferment for about an hour and a half.
Okay.
- Sad, huh?
- Yes.
- Then we have to sit and roll our thumbs.
- It's lucky that I have ice cream then, right?
Yes!
Albin will ask today's question when eating ice cream.
"What countries have Alma and Harry been in?"
Good question.
Do you remember?
- Jamaica.
- Malaysia.
- Greece.
- New Zealand.
Thailand.
Taiwan.
- Spain.
- Yes, just that.
And Cape Verde.
And Singapore.
There are a total of ten countries that Alma and Harry have been in, with Sweden.
Yes!
- What a good bill.
We have never counted ourselves.
- No, but I think it's actually true.
Move some Harry, so Alma comes out.
Here comes the Tuffe-Tuffe train!
TUT-TUT!
They crashed.
TUT-TUT-TUT!
Pang!
- In the middle of the cake.
- Stylish holes.
Move down your hand, Alma.
- So there.
- Oh!
Oh!
Well!
- What did you do?
- She threw a piece of chocolate!
- Did she eat a bit?
- Yes.
It is okay.
Do you remember, now we have done the three -stroke, the lighthouse and the three -stroke, right?
Check out what many layers, do you see?
Oh.
The best thing about pastry and when you rolled and so, do you know what to do then?
The best of all.
Oh.
It's crispy and then it melts ... mmm!
Do you want to taste?
Harry?
Oh!
- Beware my fingers.
- Yes.
Check out what nice layers, huh?
Three strokes, four -strokes and three strokes.
Perfect!
- Mmm!
- Albin?
- They are so good!
- Mm!
Beware the dental position.
Sinally good.
- Open the dental position.
- No.
- May I see the dental position?
- It's a horror movie now.
- Bye.
- Thanks and good bye.
- It was very nice.
- Thanks for coming!
You are welcome.
- Bye friend!
- Hello then, Harry.
- Bye!
Hello then, hey, hey then!
- The world's messiest recording.
- Yes but ... so, my God I just say.
Oh my God!
Fantastic nice people!
Albin, Urgent guy.
And Alma and Harry showed up from their absolute worst side.
Yes, they were completely impossible today.
It was like they pressed "Mute" when we went in and just didn't listen to us.
They are still so!
- Oh!
- I know.
Spin doors get stuck!
I have been pronounced.
- Nämen ... Alma.
- Are you a ninja?
- Stop it!
No, now it is enough.
- But, but, but ...
So.
Just stand here and listen to Magnus.
Harry, come here.
Harry, come.
Well, you wanted to go there.
It will be fine.
Do you know what to do now?
Are you with?
- Alma!
- Are you groaning?
Still, it feels great to show that we are not a perfect family.
Sometimes people ask, "Do you never argue?".
Yes, we are struggling.
Well, our children turn off.
Yes, we are messy.
Just like everyone else.
But you wish you could be it just in your loneliness and not when you go to record anything.
- I first come to the car!
- Yes that is good.
Run to the car you.
Thanks for watching this video!
Feel free to leave a thumbs up, or down.
Recommend, subscribe and have a great time until we see you next time.
Bye!