"Mommy, can we please buy
the Frozen ice cream?"
I'm so bitter.
Five!
- Balalaika! Hey, ho!
- Balalaika!
Hey, hey!
Today we will be trying ice cream!
Those who have followed our channel for a while
know that every year we try the new ice creams of the season.
Yes!
Here in Portugal,
GB Glace is called OLÁ.
- Olá!
- OLÁ's new ice creams are quite similar to GB's back in Sweden.
- Yes.
But not entirely. So, we will try the new ones in Portugal,
but many are the same as the new ones in Sweden.
Yes.
- Ready?
- YES!
Let's go!
"Frozen Snowflake Cone"
It looks like this.
- Well, mommy. Laura has played with yours.
- Yes, mine is beaten.
Laura didn't like yours.
Ice cream melts quickly here in Portugal,
so we have to start munching.
Oh, Laura really wants to munch.
- It feels pretty small.
- Can she start? Shall we start?
- Isn't it quite small?
- Really small.
- A super tiny ice cream.
- Let's go.
Oh, Laura...
- She loved it!
- She's going to be so dirty after this, I can feel it.
Can I also try it?
It's blueberry ice cream.
Super tasty.
Oh, Laura isn't in the frame.
Maybe that was just as well -
her table manners aren't very good.
I like the pre-taste, and I like the aftertaste,
so this one was actually very good.
How many points do you give it, from 1-5?
I give it a strong 3 points.
- I give it 3 points.
- I also give it 3 points.
- Daddy, you ate the whole thing.
- Yes. Yum!
I think Laura gives it 5 points.
I give it 2 points.
- Look how much Laura has eaten.
- I know. She's crazy about this one.
I feel this was a "little kid's ice cream".
Can I say that?
Yes. It's like one of those, when you're at daycare, you're just like:
"Mommy, can we please buy Frozen Snowflake Cone?"
- And it's the right size for a smaller child.
- Yes.
- Good taste.
"Solero Pineapple"
It's a popsicle,
and it looks like this.
This popsicle is not available in Sweden.
- Laura...
- You can't cheat! She had a sneaky little taste.
- Shall the rest of us try it?
- Yes.
- Very pineappley.
- Very, very pineappley.
I like it.
It says that the pineapple is from the Azores,
which is a Portuguese island group we would love to go to.
Right.
- Floppy.
- Yeah, it's a bit like jelly.
It's not a hard popsicle, like "Piggelin".
Yes, you like it.
I give it 3.5 points.
I think this is a really good ice cream,
but it's a bit of a shame it got floppy so quickly.
I give this ice cream 3 points.
It was all right.
Laura seems to love it.
Do you give it 4 or 5 points?
I really like it. 5 points.
The first 5-pointer of the day.
- If you don't count Pipita's 5 points to the snowflake cone.
- Oh, right! But does her points count?
- No.
- No, we make them up.
She seems to like all ice cream.
She's really taking it in, it's all over her body.
I give it 3 points.
"Magnum Almond Remix"
It looks like this.
It's dipped in white and brown chocolate.
Daddy, you said "white and brown chocolate".
Isn't all chocolate brown?
Yes, unless it's dark - which we call
"Old man's chocolate" - or white.
- Then what do you say?
- Milk chocolate?
What do you say?
Comment below!
They're so lame.
They're mocking me for saying "brown chocolate".
And also, leave a like
if you think it's called "brown chocolate"...
- No, then we won't get any likes!
- ...as a consolation to daddy.
Okay, leave a like if you DON'T think...
- Leave a like if you like the video. Nice and simple.
- Leave a like.
Leave a like anyway.
- Balalaika. Let's go!
- Balalaika! Hey, ho!
Balalaika!
- I'm just sucking on it.
- Why? It's delicious! Take a bite.
Oh, now I get it. The whole ice cream is dipped in white chocolate
and almond pieces, and then half the ice cream is dipped in...
- Brown...
- ...brown chocolate.
It tastes like "Mandelkubb" inside.
I've actually cheated.
I tried this on the beach one day. I love it!
"Mandelkubb" and white chocolate...
What do I live with?
It's amazing!
- The apple doesn't fall far from the tree.
- No. That's good, Laura.
Good taste.
What do you guys think?
I don't like it. I don't really like almonds,
so I don't like this one.
I give it 1 point.
- I think it's all right.
- 1 point? Oh.
- What do you give it?
- Zero.
- What?!
- Zero?!
Zero, zero, zero, zero, zero!
You're crazy! You're crazy!
Okay. I think this is a bit of a
"senior citizen's ice cream"...
- Thanks.
- ...but I give it 2 points.
Laura and I give it a very strong 5 points.
"Calippo Lime"
I think everyone knows
what this one looks like.
- Very limey.
- Mm.
- Great on a hot summer day.
- My hands!
- What is it?
- It's so cold on the hands.
- I like this one.
- They've frozen together. I can't move them.
The sugar has gone to their heads.
It happens so quickly. I was a little tired
before we started filming. Now I'm, like, ding-dong!
Ding-dong, indeed.
Or it's because...
- ♪ "Rena rama ding-dong..." ♪
- Oh, not that one.
♪ "Rena rama ding-dong" ♪
Oh, God.
Not only are you forced to watch The Melody Festival every year,
you also have to listen to those awful songs.
- Stop being so bitter.
- I'm so bitter.
They are great!
What do you think of the popsicle?
That's what we should talk about.
When I eat this popsicle, my tongue crumples up.
Kind of like I'm drinking something chemical.
But it feels like
it contains a lot of energy.
It feels like you're drinking something
that makes you, like, superfast.
Look at me! Zoom, zoom...
- "Zoom, zoom." What's he doing?
- They can't see you. He's lying on the floor and spinning around.
I give this popsicle 3.5 points.
I give it 2 points.
Laura gives it maybe... 3 points.
But...!
Put away my padel racket.
Alma, how many points?
I give it 2 points.
I also think it feels a bit chemical, if I may say so myself.
But, it's nice on a hot and sunny day.
- What are you doing?
- Come here and give points.
- Okay, sure.
- Hey, Zoom-o.
That can't be here, Laura will get it super dirty.
Bye-bye, rabbit.
Harry's points.
Zoom-zoom.
- To the camera.
- Zoom-zoom.
"Salted Caramel Brownie Peace Pop"
It's an ice cream on a stick
that looks like this.
Laura is coming to take it.
This is also a new ice cream
in Sweden this year.
- Exciting.
- Very exciting.
- Ready?
- Yes!
Let's go.
- Oh, that's a lot of flavor.
- It's very salty. Do you want to taste it?
Oh, there's so much in this one.
Yes, you like this one.
- It's almost like Arne's Salty Licorice.
- What?! It's not even similar to anything with salty licorice.
- Arne's Salty Licorice.
- What was that?
- I think it was a new ice cream last year.
- Arne's...
- Don't you remember when I, like, threw up?
- Oh, right. Uncle Arne.
- Here in Portugal, a salty licorice ice cream would never work.
- No.
One of GB Glace's news in Sweden is a licorice ice cream,
but no Portuguese would ever buy it.
- They don't eat licorice down here, they don't eat pick-and-mix...
- No.
They have a completely different
culture around sweets.
The caramel was very, very salty.
A little too salty.
When I bit into it, I almost got a shock
because it was so salty.
It feels like a strange mix.
Brownie and salted caramel, and ice cream too.
It was a lot in one.
A bit of everything.
A chicken has stepped on mine.
That's the peace sign, Harry...
that looks like a chicken foot.
I give this ice cream 2 points.
I think it was too much in one. It was a strange mix.
- I get it.
- I give it zero-superhero.
- Zero?!
- Scanner eyes.
- He doesn't like chocolate ice cream.
- No. That's his second zero today.
Harry doesn't like salted caramel.
I give it 4 points.
What does Laura give it?
Five!
- What's this?
- I spilled Calippo Lemon.
- You made the classic mistake and turned it upside down.
- Not lemon - lime. Calippo Lime. Not lemon.
- Don't do it. Never turn a Calippo upside down.
- No.
We have a Question of the Day.
Alma, are you listening? This one is for you.
Okay. Yep!
"Will Alma make a movie about Portugal?"
- YES, I will!
- Yes, she will! Pipito is with!
Yes, I will.
- You will?
- Yes!
- When will it be done?
- I don't really know, but it will come.
Keep an eye out on Alma's channel.
"Solero Barrinha Manga"
It looks like this.
"Barrinha" is Portuguese for "barbell".
- In Sweden, a new Sandwich ice cream has come out.
- A new flavor.
Yes, exactly.
This is Portugal's version of Sandwich.
Very difficult to eat,
because it doesn't have... the Sandwich bread.
Exactly.
It's not a sandwich, it's just the insides.
It's mango and vanilla ice cream.
This feels like an ice cream they've come up with last minute
to be able to fill up the sign with news.
It's an ice cream that's easy to make,
but completely impossible to eat.
The white vanilla melts faster
than the yellow mango, so it's completely...
It's very unclear why it's not on a stick.
It'll just turn into goo when you buy it,
so I don't think anyone will buy this.
- I like it. I give it a strong 3 points.
- A strong 3 points.
It took me a while to, like, figure out
if this is ice cream or if it's real mango.
- Oh, you think it was that mango-like?
- Mm.
Pipita is now demonstrating what it will look like
when people eat this ice cream in the summer.
It's going to be an orgy of ice cream goo.
Horrible.
I give it 1 point. A weak point.
I give it a strong 4 points. No...
- It's on your upper lip.
- 4 points. Not strong.
4 points?
I give it 0 points.
A very, very zero-y zero.
"Cornetto Rose"
It looks like a rose.
This is not a new ice cream in Sweden this season.
It says that it's "raspberry milkshake flavor".
So, it tastes like a raspberry milkshake.
Are you ready?
1, 2, 3!
- Good raspberry flavor.
- It's better than I thought. The "milkshake" scared me a little.
- Me too.
- No, Laura. What have you done?
When it said "milkshake",
I was sure I would give it 5 points.
That says something about
one's starting point, I guess.
Laura also likes it.
Oh, she's really munching on it.
She has come to a family that loves ice cream.
We are all ice cream lovers.
I love this ice cream!
This is the best one we've ever tried.
- Really?!
- 5 strong points.
- So, you think this one should come to Sweden?
- YES!
Yes. How many points?
Oh, wow! That's a lot.
- She held up her whole hand. 5 points from Laura.
- Yes, I think so. Was it the best ice cream?
Good, Laura! Good!
You have my taste. Good taste!
- I give it 3 points.
- I also give it 3 points.
3 points.
- This was the last new ice cream!
- Yes.
In summary, you could say that
Portugal has more fruity flavors than chocolate flavors.
- Yes. More than chocolate and soft serve and such.
- Exactly.
They don't have Cornetto Soft here in Portugal.
Not the new ones, at least.
- Or Cornetto Dragon.
- Right. I don't know if it's still available in Sweden either?
- No, but it's really good.
- Yes, you like it.
- Hope you guys liked this video.
- Yes! If you come to Portugal, you can always try these ice creams.
Thank you for watching this video!
- Please leave a thumbs up, or down.
- Mostly thumbs up!
Comment, ask questions
and take care until next time.
Bye-bye!