Hey.
- Hey.
- Where are we?
- We are in Isaberg, in Småland.
Yes.
- And what's behind you?
- Our house and daddy, who's packing his backpack.
Isaberg is a ski slope during winter, and during summer
this place offers lots of fun action-packed activities.
Really cool.
When we got here yesterday, this place was full of
mountain bikers. You can go to the top and bike down.
We're not doing that.
- I can't do that.
- I know.
If I bike really fast
I get so scared that I fall.
- What are we going to do now?
- Tree Top Adventure!
We are starting
our day up high.
- Camera mounting in progress.
- Yep. Thank you, Alma. How nice.
- Are you nervous?
- No.
- It's pretty high up.
- It's going to be really fun.
- They look so professional.
- Right?
They look like they are about to
chop down trees or work on power poles.
- Daddy, when will you put on your suit?
- In just a bit.
- We are ready!
- Yes!
Yeah, yeah,
I have the coolest suit, wow!
I got a green helmet because I have the biggest head
in the world, so now I really do look like a watermelon.
- Will we climb the ladder?
- Right? Just like a watermelon.
We will get instructions now, Harry.
You can't open both of these at the same time, so you'll
always be locked in with at least one. That's good, huh?
If you look at these you will see
which one is open and which one is locked.
The one that's like a C is open
and the one that's like a U is closed.
When one is open I can't open the other one, see?
So, you will always be secured up there.
The arrow to the magnet, and push.
Now that this one is locked,
the other one is open.
Push the button and pull it towards the wire.
There, now it's open.
Pull up and pull down,
pull up and pull down...
Oops, I accidentally hit the camera.
(Alma) Harry, stop.
- Oh, someone's a bit too excited.
- Yeah... we'll see how this goes.
Now Harry will try it.
Fasten yourself again.
- Here?
- Mm.
Okay.
Where's the little rope?
Here.
Watch out!
Watch out.
Do not do that
when we are on a real course.
- Do we know everything now?
- Yes.
- Are we ready for the first course?
- It's a little scary to go on our own.
- Yes, a little.
Now we should just know it.
From this low spot to up there, folks.
- Let's go!
Okay... this was kind of difficult.
- Oh, how fun. A sleigh.
- Yeah, indeed.
Alma is Santa Claus!
- Ready?
- Yes.
Go!
♪ Prince Ali!
Mighty is he! Ali Ababwa ♪
I feel like I'm too heavy
and will fall.
Help, help!
Now I'll jump
to the next one.
It's... semi difficult
to walk and film...
But, what don't we do so that
you guys at home can come along.
What did you think of the
Tree Top Adventure?
- Really fun!
- Perfect!
- Really fun.
- It was really fun. And really hot.
Extremely hot.
We had to go inside
and eat our lunch.
Swedes usually eat outside
when the weather's nice, but-
-it's almost too hot.
I know you can't say that, but...
Alma almost had sunstroke.
Now we'll try something we've never tried before.
I know I'm very excited, how about...
Me too!
- I'm very excited.
- Rodel!
Yes, rodel! Summer rodel.
The track is there, I'll turn the camera around.
There.
- Come on, friends.
- Let's run!
- Mommy, are we going in one?
- We'll sit one adult and one child per...
Okay, I want to sit with daddy.
Daddy is so kind.
- Do you want to sit with me?
- Okay.
- I'm also pretty kind.
- Yes.
You ride up there, then turn around
at the top and ride down.
It sort of looks like
a roller coaster.
The camera is mounted.
And we are ready.
- Buckle up.
- Oh, right.
- Hey.
- Have you done this before?
- No.
- Are you getting the buckle in? There you go.
- That feels very important.
- On the way up, you don't have to do anything.
- No.
- It's too tight.
- Oh, she's saying it's too tight.
Rather it's too tight
than too loose, Alma.
- There.
- Thank you.
So, you don't have to do anything
on the way up.
At the top, push the levers forward
to go full speed.
Hold them there.
If you want to brake, just release them a bit.
So, you decide the speed on the way down.
- We'll go full speed, right?
- Mm.
- Let's go.
- Thank you.
(Harry) Daddy!
(Alma) This will be exciting!
Daddy, get in.
- Alma, how high is it?
- How dare they ski all the way down there?
- Are you ready?
- Yes. Are you ready?
- I'm ready.
- Are you really sure?
- Yes.
- Are you really?
Are you really? Are you?
Full speed.
Here we go, Harry!
- Are you really ready?
- I'm ready.
Are you really?
"Forbidden to stop"
"Accelerate"
- The rodel was crazy fun.
- Super fun.
- In the curves, it felt like you'd fly out.
- Yes, it did.
So, there was also
a scary element to it.
There was one curve
I didn't dare to go full throttle in.
- Full speed.
- Yes, full speed. It was a little scary, actually.
- It's fun that there's so much action here. I get NZ vibes.
- Yeah, indeed! Rotorua vibes.
Yes! New Zealand was like this.
Lots of nature and lots of action things to do.
- The... swing.
- Yes, exactly.
And the ZORB ball.
- We're only trying a few things here, there are lots more.
- I'm riding a zip line, wieee...
- Golf, all these mountain bike tracks, and such.
- Yes, right.
This is the last stop on our Småland trip
that we are doing in collaboration with Visit Småland.
All our stops are on a link in the video description,
if you're curious about any of our stops in these 4 vlogs.
- Yes.
- Check it out, if you want to.
Check it out.
- "Yes."
- "Yes." "Check it out."
This is where we are staying.
Here is mom and dad's room.
Here is the living room.
- And an upside down Harry.
- Yeah.
Here's the kitchen, and...
Here's mine and Harry's room.
- Please excuse the mess, we are on vacation.
- Yes. Excuse us.
And our tech stuff has moved
from the bed to the kitchen table.
Sometimes it's like this.
Here comes the camera Christmas tree.
- That's fitting, because we are in a mountain hut.
- Yes, exactly.
Oh, right. This must've been
a mountain hut from the beginning.
Then this ski resort
was turned into a more summery place.
- They still ski here, when there's snow.
- Right, when there's snow.
It's a great resort, I must say. I like it.
It's nice that there's a lake nearby.
God, how nice.
It's super nice.
We are on this super cozy floating sauna.
Oh, that's bright.
It's still so hot outside.
It's like 6 PM.
In there is Alma, all cozy.
With a camera!
Will you jump in with it?
Oh, you splashed!
It was a bit cold on my feet...
It was a bit cold on my feet at the bottom.
Was it?
What a tricky face
you just made.
Oh, the castle face.
Show mommy.
This is what Gustav Vasa does.
(King of Sweden, 1523–1560)
- Can you add a picture of Gustav Vasa?
- Yes, I can.
Harry was super kind. We walked past the front desk,
and he said: "Daddy needs some snacks".
He knows exactly
how to charm me.
The chipsomaniac.
You have a weird shadow on your face.
Give me some Pringles.
Thanks.
- There are lots of people over on the beach.
- Indeed. Lots of families.
Now it'll be very good
to eat some food.
Harry and Axel got burgers.
Alma got...
- Potato pancake.
- Just like me.
Then you can go and play
in the really fun park right next to here.
Yay!
Harry, wait for me!
- I said no.
- You said no?
This is going to be scary.
I thought we could summarize Småland,
instead of answering a Question of the Day.
Yes. Beautiful, I think.
Very beautiful.
- Yes. Lots to do.
- So much to do.
Great for families.
And we say that from our heart.
Many lovely swimming lakes.
Lots of Swedish fika spots, everywhere.
They love Swedish fika and sugar!
We didn't film it much, but there are fika spots,
waffles, ice cream, pastries and candy everywhere.
Mixed with flea markets
and small towns.
And gnats.
Yeah, there's an extreme amount of gnats right now.
I'm trying to stand still but my body just wants to, like...
Thank you for watching this video!
Please leave a thumbs up, or down.
Leave comments, ask questions
and have a great summer. See you again soon!
Bye bye!