- She seems to like it!
- Yes!
That's Monster.
Tell me if it's scary.
Alma, I love you.
Hey, hey!
We are at Gröna Lund!
- We are all alone in the amusement park.
- All alone.
It's so cool.
It's so quiet, it's so calm.
- It's so...
- It's almost a bit mysterious.
It feels a little scary.
All the shutters are closed...
Oh, that little... thing.
It's completely empty,
and it's a little scary.
- No, it's super cool!
- Yes. This will be super fun.
The park will open in a bit,
and we will still be here and ride stuff.
Gröna Lund let us in before it opened,
so that we get to experience the park all alone.
- Remember this one?
- I do.
- It's like a ninja temple.
- No. It's The Ship.
- Oh, right.
- The haunted house.
- It's Laura's first time at "Grönan". She seems to like it!
- She really does!
You guys, we're not completely alone.
- Hey, hey!
We're not completely alone - he is here.
But only he.
He came from The Ship...
maybe he's a ghost.
Slingshots!
I've never ridden
this huge roller-coaster.
Jetline.
Alma, you can go on all the rides
now that you're over 140 cm. (4 ft. 7 in.)
Yes! I'm going to ride this one!
Here they're playing music.
- Do you get feeling?
- Yes.
- Are you dancing with the stroller?
- Yes. I'm trying.
Shall we dance, Pipita?
She's dancing with her pacifier.
She thinks that
the pacifier is more fun.
Here's what you get, bear.
- What's that sound?
- I don't know.
Was it... some kind of monster
that I have to shoot?
There!
This is Monster,
the new ride of 2021.
It's also our first ride of the day.
Mommy, it's coming!
Now, actually.
They're letting guests in now, and...
You, me, and Axel, behind the camera,
are going to ride it.
Harry! Come.
You're not allowed to ride Monster.
Can you take care of Laurita-Pipita?
Okay.
We enter through the exit.
Oh, there's an elevator here. Good.
It feels so secretive.
Yeah. Like an action...
- Oh, I think I'll take the stairs.
- Why?
It's so cramped. Is there room?
Okay, nice.
- Are you nervous, Alma?
- A little.
I feel that I know too little about Monster.
All I know is that it goes underground, and up, and...
- Oh, I thought you meant real monsters.
- No... Well, maybe that too.
- I was very surprised that it was so quiet.
- Yes.
Oh, wow! Look...
Oohweee...
- Hey!
- Welcome!
- Thank you!
- What a nice entrance!
You have to tell me if it's scary,
and if I would dare to ride it next year.
- We promise.
- Mm, promise.
Let's go!
- It feels scary to start with the worst one.
- But then you've done it.
- Yes, then I don't have to do it again.
- Everything else will feel like child's play.
- Yes. I am a child, though, so...
- That's true.
No, no, no... Now I don't want this.
I regret my decision.
It'll be fine, Alma.
- The floor is disappearing.
- Oh, the floor...
- Oh, what have we done?
- Stop it!
Why are we doing this?
- Why are we doing this, Alma?
- I don't know!
Alma, remember to
smile at the camera!
HELP!!!
That was so fun!
- I'm not warmed-up at all.
- It was so good!
My mouth...
I'm in shock!
- That one was a bit too much for my taste.
- It was so good!
- Yes!
- They love it.
I love it!
"I love you, Monster!"
- Do you think Harry will dare to ride it next year?
- Yes! Of course I will!
I actually think so, it's a really nice ride.
However, I don't think you'll be 140 cm. next year.
(4 ft. 7 in.)
- I'm convinced he will be.
- He's about 130 cm. now. (4 ft. 3 in.)
- 1 cm. per month. No problem.
- Everything for Monster!
- I recommend it. It was so nice!
- Yes, it was fun. Just a bit too much for my taste.
- You're a little nauseous.
- A little.
Now the park is open for guests.
Harry will get to decide what we'll do next.
To the Fun House, we go!
Okay. That'd be difficult with the stroller,
so I'll stay out here with Laura. You guys go alone.
- Okay!
- Let's go!
♪ I believe I can fly
I believe I can touch the sky ♪
You won!
Nice job!
It looks like a bazooka!
My hair after all the rides...
- Shall I help you?
- No, I'll have to look like this. They know I've been on rides.
We are having a snack.
Laura is drinking some milk,
and the kids are eating Harry's big win!
Show it off. How cool?!
A huge deal.
This is the first time
one in our family wins one of those.
- It's been my dream since I was a child.
- Mine too.
Harry, you've fulfilled
my and daddy's dream. Good job!
- Which ride was the most fun?
- Monster.
- The Broomstick.
The Monster Broomstick.
I like the Wild Mouse.
You just fly around, it's so jerky.
It's a classic ride
where you sit in a cart on top of the rails.
I think it's scary.
It feels like you're going to fall off.
It's finished, Laura.
Now it's empty.
All done.
She's like:
"What are you saying?"
I say that every time she's finished the bottle,
so that she understands.
Now we will ride the Tunnel of Love.
Laura might also get to ride it!
Oh, oh...
Oh, how exciting, Laura!
Wow... look.
Oops, they can barely see you.
Where are we going?
Look, Laura.
How does it feel, Laura?
Was it exciting?
Was it fun?
- Was it good?
- Yes.
- Laura fell asleep when we ate dinner.
- She got exhausted from the Tunnel of Love.
- Did she like it?
- Yes, indeed. I think so.
I think she fell very much in love with me.
I fell very much in love with her, at least.
Harry. Good thing we're not here
on Halloween, right? With Laura.
Pipita would be scared.
- You think so?
- Yes.
I definitely think so too.
It's so nice that we are here
when the weather is nicer, and it's a bit kinder.
Yes.
When we were in the Fun House, Harry was so scared
that there would be killer clowns in there.
No, that's only on Halloween.
Harry, you're at an amusement park
and can go on a bunch of rides...
That was pretty fun, though.
- I want to try the Giant Drop.
- Are you sure?
- Absolutely sure.
- Let's do it!
- Will you go on Tilt?
- Tilt? Oh! I've never done that one.
I mean...
Do I ride that one before...?
- Do you know what "tilt" means?
- You go up, and then it tilts you forward.
Scary! Do I dare?
I will not ride it, and you're too short, Harry.
Would you have wanted to ride it?
- Yes, of course!
- Are you kidding?
No.
Oh, somebody's waking up.
Did you take a little power nap?
Hello. Hi!
You two go,
we will wait down here.
...at 100 km/h. (62 mph)
- 100 km/h...
- Was that a joke?
...on the way down.
The way up is pretty slow and kind.
Was... was that a joke?
The worst part is that it will feel like
we are about to hit that little house.
- But look how beautiful it is.
- It's very nice.
They're going up now.
It's so high.
Can I get off?
Oh, dang. Oh, it's so high.
I don't remember it going this high.
Oh, no...
We are so high up now.
I wasn't prepared for this.
Alma, what have we done?
Alma, this wasn't fun at all.
Alma! Why did we do this?!
- I don't know!
- Alma, I love you.
I mean... the Giant Drop was so scary.
I'm still trembling. I'm shaking.
Was it worse than Monster?
Yes, it was actually worse than Monster.
Monster was fun, in a way. This one wasn't fun - just scary.
- It's just contempt for death.
- Adrenaline rush 2000.
Yes. But it's fun. I like it.
What a thing... "Gröna Lund" on weekdays.
Not a single ride had more than a 10 minute line.
No.
A hot tip.
They're open for a while longer.
Thank you for watching this video!
- Please leave a thumbs up, or down.
- Mostly thumbs up!
Comment, ask questions
and take care until next time.
- See you!
- Bye-bye!