Hello Hello!
Today we will make a challenge.
With candy versus food.
We have made Gummy vs Real Food twice before.
It is very popular, viewers often want us to do it again and again.
But this candy is not so easy to find.
The candy in today's Challenge bought me and Axel during our long journey.
- Should I tell you how it goes?
- Yes.
I am a waitress and I will serve you each plate.
On one it is sweets and on the other it is food.
It is as usual at home that decides who wins today's Challenge by commenting.
Alma, Harry, or maybe a shared first place?
- Or both?
- Yes exactly.
And corner, don't forget to push thumbs up if you think this video is fun.
Are you ready?
- Yes!
- Let's go!
- Mix, mix, mix ... - mix, mix, mix ...
- I am satisfied.
- No, I want to take it.
Okay then.
Mix, mix.
Wait wait.
1, 2, 3 ...
A real sausage!
Candy sausage.
Lol!
Ouch!
- It's really good.
- Yes ...
... Super Duper.
Although it is very good.
This tastes ... sausage.
This one tastes ... candy.
It actually tastes sweets.
- Are you ready?
- Mix, mix, mix ...
- I want it.
- No, but ... I want it.
- Yes, now I have it.
- No.
- Can you agree?
- It is mine.
- Yes.
- How kind of you, Harry.
- Wait a minute.
- Okay.
1, 2, 3 ...
- A real orange!
- The pretend orange!
- More precisely a candy orange.
- Yes, a candy orange.
God so tasty!
- Should the waitress help a little?
- Yes thank you.
So this is a chocolate orange.
That's a lot of parts.
They have to put them on the plate.
Yes, these are gaps.
Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh!
- Oh, wow.
Can I taste?
- Here, you get it.
- Thanks so much.
- I have lots more.
Tastes super good.
Alma, look.
They are the same.
- This one was the best.
- Yes I agree.
This was a very common orange ... that tastes common.
Yes.
- Bye.
Mix, mix, mix ...
- I want that!
- I want that.
1, 2, 3 ...
Candy can.
Nom, nom, nom ...
Can I taste?
- Can I taste?
- mm.
This is a hard club that tastes ...
... much like all clubs do.
This is a real monk.
It tastes super good, it tastes like ...
... a real monk.
I'm ready for the next one.
Bye.
- So it can go unless the hasp is on.
- Yes.
- You may be able to lift it that way.
It's fine.
- Yes.
It must be without bud.
You must not laugh when Harry gets his not bud.
I nip you in the toe.
- Was my monk best?
- Yes.
Mix, mix, mix ...
- I want that.
- No, I want it.
- Yes, okay.
- This time I think it's his turn to choose.
Yes exactly.
- And then you have to take them like that.
- Yes.
1, 2, 3 ...
Candy...
- Taco.
- Godistaco, delicious.
- Real taco.
Oh!
My taco just fell out.
- Can I taste?
- mm, here.
It is full of different things like tomatoes, such green things and these.
Rubber bears and everything.
I dropped mine.
I lost all the stuff for it, and now it has broken.
Mix, mix, mix ...
- I want that!
- I take it!
- I want that.
- Now it's probably Alma's turn to choose, huh?
- Yes.
1, 2, 3 ...
Candistoast.
- So, not candistoast - sandwich.
- This is toast?
I think it's like a toast.
- Can I taste?
- Yes.
Mine was disgusting.
This one was huge.
Thus, it tastes the rhinet Macka with sugar.
Very much sugar.
1 kilo of sugar.
I'm ready for the next one.
I'll save you, Mackis.
- I'm ready for the next one.
- I'll win.
Mix, mix, mix ...
- I want that.
- Yes.
1, 2, 3 ...
Mini french fries which are chewing gum.
Mine are quite ordinary french fries.
- I want to taste Harry's now.
- Okay.
Thanks.
- Thanks.
- I have chewing gum in my mouth.
I won.
Ew.
- Oh, what happened there?
- Alma's chewing gum was not good.
Wasn't the chewing gum good?
Well, but you yell and eat and munch.
Are you hungry?
- Yes.
- Yes, I expect it.
I thought we would take a question of the day.
Moabella wonders, "How's Alma's own channel going?"
- Super.
It actually goes super.
- It actually goes super, it exists!
- It exists.
- We have done it.
So far there are three videos there, and it will be more.
We are talking about it now in the corner if you are interested.
- Should you tell us what you do on the channel, then?
To date.
- I have...
You have to stop smoking in my ear, the viewers there at home will be crazy.
Just.
With closed mouth.
Good.
I talk about different countries and ... yes, their flag and their language and blah blah blah.
The videos are about the different countries we visited on the trip, the same countries where we bought this candy.
Yay!
- There will be something else on your channel later, huh?
- mm.
- You have recorded a slime video with Harry.
- Yes, when we mix a lot of slime that we bought.
Yes, so as Alma thinks is fun on that channel.
But this - The Swedish Family - is our main channel, this is the one we will continue to work most.
- mm.
- Are you full now?
- No.
- Do you want to eat more sweets and food?
- Yes.
- Then we continue.
- Yes!
Mix, mix, mix ...
- I want that!
- I want that.
1, 2, 3 ...
- I got a juice.
- And I got a candy evening.
- Are you a baby, Harry?
- Yes.
Goo goo ga ga, little baby.
- Oh!
- Can I taste?
- Yes.
Then I can eat up all yours, you will eat up all of mine.
- Harry's was the best, I think.
- Yes, though now you are also a baby.
- goo goo ga.
- GA GA GOO GOO.
GA GA GOO GOO GIGGI.
- GA GA GOO GOO GIGGI, GA GA.
- GA GA!
Mix, mix, mix ...
- I am satisfied.
1, 2, 3 ...
- A real pizza.
- Candy pizza.
Check out, how nice it is.
- Now it's not as nice anymore.
- No.
- So yes.
- Now it's fine.
Mmm.
My pizza was the best.
No, I actually think mine was the best.
You never tasted mine.
You have to taste mine.
Okay.
Do you feel the taste of the juicy pizza?
I just feel onions.
Mix, mix, mix ...
- I want that.
1, 2, 3 ...
A real watermelon.
A club for watermelon ...
... and it was made of candy.
- It can't bite.
- Do you want to taste mine, then I can taste yours?
Mine is nice, but it's a little hard.
I agree, but I actually thought mine was the best.
Yes.
Mix, mix, mix ...
- I want that.
- I want it.
- Are you happy?
- Yes.
1, 2, 3 ...
Those I remember!
We have tested those.
- Bean Boozled Challenge, do you remember?
- Yes.
I don't want to taste, no no.
Those are the spy.
- I don't know if these are as dangerous as the others.
- Taste.
Taste...
Okay, if I have to.
I have to spit.
It did not taste good.
Oh, what a disgust.
It was really good.
Never again.
It is better with regular popcorn.
- Hi, sweethearts.
- Hello!
- How did you have it?
- Great.
- Has it been fun?
- Yes.
It says "Buttered Popcorn Jelly Beans", so it is buttery popcorn-jelly beans.
- Do you dare to taste?
- No thanks.
- Joho!
You must.
- No.
- It looks like those who tasted the kiss or vomit.
- Vomit, huh?
Although these should taste good.
- Oh okay.
- We bought these in New Zealand.
Thanks for watching this video!
Feel free to leave a thumbs up, or down.
Write who of these two crunch balls who has won, ask questions and have a great time until we see you next time.
Bye!