God, what a fail!
It's just sunny outside.
Give it to me! Give them to me!
The mood went...
Alma is a little afraid of trains.
You have to respect that.
It says Uaua. (Laura)
- Does it say Laura?
- Yes.
- Let's see.
- Show it to mommy.
- No, it says Alma.
- It says Uaua!
Yes, okay.
She really wants this pink stamp
to be her stamp.
Uaua!
We are currently trying out a new camera.
Yes.
- A new camera.
- A new camera. Yes.
So if the image or audio is a little different,
then you know why.
This is what it looks like, the new camera.
It's so small.
And it's almost Christmas, you know,
so I'm wearing this.
- Hello.
- Hello! What are you doing?
I'm playing with my toys.
- We're testing out the new camera.
- Mhm.
- It's small, huh?
How are you?
Good.
You almost seem a little sad.
Nah.
- Are you sure?
- Mhm.
Could it be that you're a little angry
because you couldn't sit with the screen anymore?
A little.
Harry was playing Roblox
and then the screen time ran out.
And yeah, the mood went...
We are quite used to it
and I think many families are.
- What? Used to screen sickness?
- Yes. That kids get sad when you say no more screens.
Yes. Completely skewed dopamine levels.
I think that's very common.
- I think we should try to get out of the house.
- Yes.
- Mommy, give me the pacifier today!
- No.
- What are you yelling about, Laura?
- Uaua have the pacifier today!
No, there will be no pacifier today.
We are taking the pacifier fight.
NO, NOT THAT, MOMMY!
Uaua have the pacifier!
- No, no pacifier. Only when you're going to sleep.
- No! I don't want to sleep with it!
No.
Wrong way.
Yes! Okay, good.
It's green!
- Come, come, come!
- Otherwise, the doors will close.
NO, MY TURN THERE!
Alma is a little afraid of trains. You have to respect that.
She wanted you to get on quickly.
I was so scared.
Can't you help me?
Can't you hold my hand and hug me
and say that everything will be fine?
- Uaua have the stroller, then?
- No, no stroller now. You can have it when we get off.
- We'll count to one first.
- One station.
Does your fear of trains feel any better?
Well, not really.
It's still tough to travel by train.
Yes, I noticed that.
But I was wondering if it has improved after this semester.
A little better, because me and Harry have gone by train
to school sometimes...
Look, the shadow of the camera is right over your face.
Sorry for that.
But I know. And I thought about...
We filmed a morning routine where you took the train to school
in maybe September or October, and then you talked...
- Mommy!
- Hello! ...about your traffic phobia.
- Yes.
- We got a lot of super nice comments.
It was so nice. I mean...
It means so much that when I talk about something
that's difficult for me, that you dare to say that too.
Because I know it's hard to talk about.
- Can we buy ice cream and candy?
- Not right now. Alma is actually talking about something important.
Buy ice cream and candy...
So it really means a lot to me
that you chose to write so many nice comments, like...
"I'm afraid of that too,
and I feel this way, and I'm afraid of that."
I remember it so well, because you sat and read on my phone
and was almost in tears, comment after comment.
There were so many comments
so we didn't have time to answer them all, but we read them all.
We can take the opportunity to thank them now,
even though it's been...
A few months.
- Yes. Thank you for sharing.
- So nice of you, really. It means a lot.
- We probably haven't told you where we're going.
- No.
I've put on some clothes that I don't really care about
because we're actually going to buy a Christmas tree.
- Me too!
- You too. Yes. Although we're only going to buy one Christmas tree.
I want a Santa.
- A Christmas tree and a Santa. That's enough.
- That's enough!
- Is this the tree we're going to buy?
- No, I think it's way too big.
We can't take this on the train.
I think this is a European silver fir...
...which certainly holds up very well,
but I think it will cost a small fortune.
When we were here the other day, she had a bunch of Christmas trees.
That's why we went back here.
And now it only seems that the most expensive and finest one remains.
We'll have to ask her.
- She has a small store there, maybe she has more?
- Yes, exactly.
- Shall we check?
- Let's check.
(Portuguese)
- Hello, do you have other Christmas trees?
- I have that one, and one that's closed.
- There.
- Oh! Okay!
This is the only other Christmas tree they have.
It's a little depressing, it's sitting here in the backyard.
But it looks very big.
- Yes. Although it's easier to transport.
- It's much, much easier to transport.
- What do you think, Harry?
- I think it looks pretty good. I like tall Christmas trees.
But you're buying the tree in a poke.
You don't know what you'll get.
No, but I was expecting a much smaller one
than the two she has left, I can tell you that.
These have been left behind because they're so big.
No one has space for them.
- (Portuguese) Thank you.
- Thank you.
- What shall we do? Shall we buy a giant tree?
- I mean, yeah.
But how are we going to get it home?!
She says she can get someone to deliver it to our house,
but I mean...
It's unclear. We don't know.
Hey, you. Those two were just in the Christmas tree.
Why are you carrying them around?
Give it to me! Give them to me!
- "Give them to me"?
- God, how spoiled.
Chip 'n' Dale can stay here. They can't come home with us.
Portuguese Chip 'n' Dale.
- They come home with us.
- No, they can't come home with us.
They come home with us!
You're a good negotiator, Laura. But I don't know.
We have to discuss it with the rest of the family.
We got the tree delivered,
but not the same day we were there but the day after that.
And then another day passed
because it needed to get used to the indoor climate.
Yes.
And I needed to move some potted plants and such.
But now it's here and it's huge!
- It's huge.
- Yes.
And Alma and Harry have done their last day of school.
Yes.
- How does it feel?
- Good.
- Does it?
- Yes.
Very cool.
Now I see that you're looking at yourself on the screen.
Axel, help me so he doesn't see it.
Having a new camera...
Then I have to spin it around.
- Gosh! And then I'll do this.
- Yes.
But tomorrow you have graduation.
- I have to see myself.
- Oh, stop!
How do you feel, Alma?
It's a little sad and a little fun because it's the end of something,
but also the beginning of something else.
- Yes. It'll be your last day at this school.
- We'll kind of see how it turns out.
- Yes.
- We'll definitely see.
Where's Laura now?
Laura is at her crèche - her kindergarten - so...
And she probably hasn't even had a snack yet.
I know.
So we have some alone time without her.
Yippee!
- Are you happy about that?
- Yes, quite.
- She takes up quite a lot of space.
- Mhm. Quite.
- Okay, she takes up a lot of space.
- Lots of space.
We paid 80 euros for this tree.
That's a lot of money here in Portugal, but these trees
don't grow here naturally the same way they do up north.
- But how much does a Christmas tree cost in Sweden?
- Yes, how much does a Christmas tree cost in Sweden? I have no idea anymore.
- Comment below, or what?
- Yes, you could say that. Comment what a Christmas tree...
- Have we been robbed with our, like, SEK 900 tree?
- With home delivery. Yes, maybe. But it's worth it, for a little Christmas spirit.
Right, how is the Christmas spirit?
Alma, you're walking around in summer clothes.
I mean... it's so-so.
But I don't really think the Christmas spirit is snow.
Huh? Of course it is.
Well, snow is a big deal, and also that it's cold outside,
but the Christmas atmosphere is so much more.
- Are you feeling any Christmas spirit, Harry?
- No, not at all.
And why is that?
I mean... mostly because we're in a very hot country.
It's not even snowing. It's just sunny outside.
The sun is setting.
- Hello.
- Hello, hello!
Ta-da!
It's the Christmas tree, Laura.
- Gosh!
- Did you get shy now?
Hello... my friend! Did you get a little shy... in front of the tree?
Or what happened there?
God, what a fail.
We thought she would be surprised.
And happy.
- No.
- Weren't you happy when you saw the tree?
- Are you going to put your little Chip 'n' Dale in it?
We got one. Chip.
- Up in the tree.
- Shall we put it up there?
Yes.
You managed to negotiate for yourself a Chip
who lives in the tree.
- It's a little fun after all.
- Give it to me, then.
- "Give it to me, then."
- Oh, now you'll start picking them out.
You want to sit on my lap?
You're so funny.
You can look at it. There are many beautiful lights in the tree.
And lots of Christmas bulbs and presents and...
- What do you have there?
- Corn.
It's a new day again.
- And Alma and Harry are at graduation.
- Yes.
- We were not allowed to come.
- No. Sad, but that's how it can be sometimes.
And Laura is at kindergarten.
Every year, we get the same Question of the Day
from several people.
We already got it on Instagram, and that is:
"What will the children get for Christmas?"
Yes. We understand that it's exciting.
And since this video comes out the day before Christmas Eve,
we can show you-
-because then Alma and Harry
won't have time to sneak a peek.
No, exactly.
Laura doesn't really have the skills yet.
But we can start with her Christmas present from us.
A new "o bebê", which means "the baby."
Right.
And what happens when you pull out the pacifier?
No, this will be annoying.
- It can also talk a little.
- "Mommy. Mommy."
- It said "mommy." That's me. No, that's Laura!
- Yes.
- And... Would you like to show Harry's present?
- Yes, I can do that.
Harry is in a time of his life where he has to start
keeping track of just that - the time.
So that's why I bought him a watch.
This is a watch from Swatch.
The watch brand.
But it's a special edition
which has been released together with Omega.
So it resembles a classic Omega watch.
It has a timer and a regular clock,
so I hope he likes it.
I like it anyway.
If he won't use it…
It's one of those gifts that you really wanted.
I'd basically want this now, but yeah…
So, this is for him.
Alma has wanted a set like this
with rhinestones.
I don't know if you can see it through the plastic
but there are small crystals that you glue on...
In lots of different colors.
...on a phone case, bags, shoes, and so on.
Here's some applicator thing,
and here's a large pair of tweezers to go with it.
She's very excited about this, so yeah...
It will be interesting to see
what her shoes look like later.
- Yes. These were the three gifts we feel we can show.
- Yes.
- And now we're going to wrap them up.
- Yes, we will.
Once upon a time, I was very good at wrapping presents
because I worked as a clerk at NK, the department store.
But yeah, no longer.
- You've lost it a little.
- Oh, God. Are you kidding?
We had to take a gift-wrapping course,
we who worked at NK.
- So it would go fast or look nice?
- So it would look beautiful.
What kind of weird image is this?
You only see the bed.
- You're supposed to see the presents.
- Oh, gosh.
- We can raise it a little.
- Give me the tape.
Now there's a lot of complaining.
There we go. Nice.
Oh, the wall looks green, I think.
What do you guys at home think?
Does it look green or blue? It's blue.
There.
They don't have cards or names written on them.
No, that's true. Shall we do that?
Shucks!
They can guess and think about it.
They can sit here and dream away in the Christmas tree.
It's good.
This was a pretty slow vlog
that extended over several days.
Yes. I think it was quite nice for us
to make a vlog like this.
It's been quite a stressful and hectic fall.
Yes, indeed. There have been a lot of projects and travels
and all kinds of things that we've been up to.
You've had a lot at school too,
and with training and such.
- And I have written a book.
- Yes!
So good!
And the club and Kenya and, yeah.
Yes. So it felt right to just slow down before Christmas
and just go at a leisurely pace.
I started to wonder if it was this camera
that slowed us down a bit.
I don't know. What do you guys think?
Is it slow?
Please leave a comment about the audio,
the image, the camera, and...
- What you like and what you dislike.
- Yes, exactly.
And finally, we would like to wish everyone a...
MERRY CHRISTMAS!
Yep.
And of course, we'll see you before New Year's Eve.
Thank you for watching this video!
Please leave a thumbs up, or down.
Comment, ask questions
and take care until next time.
- See you!
- Bye-bye!