We are going home to him, we will eat with him, we will work with him and we will hang with him.
Just when I say it he rolls in.
- Hello!
- Mauri
- Tjena Mauri.
- Nice!
- The same, really.
Here we have billionaire Johan, who has 50 different companies -
-As in a short time, one of Sweden's richest people has become.
- Wait now, you are parked there?
- Yes, I thought we could be close to the boat club.
- But do you get it?
- It depends on who you ask.
- And why do we meet here?
- I usually have breakfast here.
- At the Royal Mot Boat Club?
- Yes, they have the world's best sandwiches.
- But should we go in and check out?
- I think so.
- Should we?
- Let's go.
This section is also in paid collaboration with Air Up.
- How is the situation with you then?
- It is good.
Is this with you?
- Could it have been worse?
- Yes actually. Heat day at work.
- Did you work today? It's early in the morning. You have been at work already.
How hard do you have to sit still?
- Quite difficult. At school it was hard.
At school I had problems. I had to go for a class ...
It's actually fun. I did an ADHD investigation.
It came to light that I'm just hyperactive.
It is very unusual as an adult to just be hyper.
Hello to you!