Today I will visit the ten strangest restaurants in Sweden.
We start with number ten and then we work up until we reach number one.
I can already say that that restaurant is at its very own level.
But we start here in Varberg with place number ten.
Hehehe
This is a restaurant run by robots
Then pat the robot on the forehead to send it back
Then it pulls!
It is so good.
Bye!
And now I will order via these plates.
Fried chicken, order.
And now it comes!
I have received my food.
And I've got my drink.
Bye!
But of course there is an ordinary, real person who is responsible for this.
Hello!
The man behind it!
- Tjena, serve, serve.
Welcome to my restaurant.
- You were one of the co -founders of the quiz fight and then sold it.
It feels very much like a guy who gets a little too much money and just, what should I do?
I start a robot restaurant!
- I must admit that is guilty that it is about what has been.
- What do your customers say?
- Most people are satisfied.
Especially children think it is fun with robots and stuff.
In the beginning, there were a lot of robots that just drove into should N.
On one of the test evenings, they pulled a frontal crash at full speed.
It slammed quite loudly and it spread a very strange atmosphere in here.
Like this, what the hell are we doing?
What is this?
- Is it not strange that I had not heard of this restaurant before we went out?
- Well, I also think it a little.
I had probably expected a little more noise and bong.
- And now you are sitting here with a robotic restaurant.
- Now I'm sitting here with an empty robot restaurant.
Just Mauri here.
- I guess you still destroyed a lot of capital and stuff like this?
- Ooouuuff !!
Hahaha
In fact, I think this is the worst business of my life, purely financially.
-Is that it?
- Yes, my God.
I will not be the break-ven here in a decade I think.
That's not why I did it.
- It was pure desire.
But imagine what a boring Sweden would be if we had no such as you.
I want to test this.
And then you do it.
I am passionate about having more guests.
- Thanks.
The next time you are in the hooks go to wonderful Henrik and his robots.
However, we are going to a restaurant that is strange in a completely different way.
It's time for the list number nine.
A very common Thai restaurant.
But according to about 30 different tips, they are likely to have Sweden's most angry owners.
I have sat on my hidden camera and will go in there and then we simply see what happens.
Hello!
Maybe a Pad Thai?
No.
According to the tips I have received, special orders are not appreciated here, so I gave it a try.
Can I get other noodles?
No but I love that you are honest.
I think it's fun.
No I don't want to argue.
We do...
It's a bit ... We're in the process of recording.
We have heard that you are sometimes a little annoyed at your customers.
What do you have to say to the camera?
Ahh ...
Huh ehh no ...
You don't feel good about stress?
But can you send out customers before they get the food if they are too hard?
It happens?
- Better ..
- Go
- Ahh
Hahaha.
Yes, fortunately, she was, like most people, really kind.
And honestly, we customers can actually be really hard sometimes.
Next restaurant, number eight on the list, is not so spectacular,
But on the other hand, there is a detail that I thought was so funny
That it was worth a few extra hours of travel to southern Norrland.
And this, my ladies and gentlemen, it's Hofors.
A small village with about 5,000 inhabitants.
And here there are really two large restaurants.
And the first restaurant in the village is called Mekong.
But if you walk about 100 meters in this direction you will find ...
Mekong 2!
I'm just...
They are only satisfied with Mekong 1 and Mekong 2.
I am so incredibly curious about how it could be this way.
I think we should find out now.
And invite Hofors to a little surprise.
But we start here at Mekong 1.
We have a bit that needs to be sorted out, I feel.
- How could you not come up with another name?
- I think it's Mekong.
It's a good name, nice.
Before, I had Mekong in Sandviken.
- Was your restaurant in Sandviken also called Mekong before?
- Mekong!
- You have to find a new name for your restaurants!
Everything can't eat Mekong, wine tach.
Now, of course, it was time to test Hoforsrundan.
With a dish on Mekong 1 and then Mekong 2.
- Exciting!
- Thanks!
- A little fun that you have french fries on the buffet?
- Former price.
!
- You are welcome!
- Are you getting rich in Mekong?
Or?
- Slightly.
It is okay.
- How rich do you get?
- Rich as rice.
- Rich as rice?
- Mekong 1 cleared.
- We go to Mekong 2.
- Mekong 2.
It's just over there.
- Yes, it's only ten minutes.
- Ten minutes?
How slow do you go there?
It's 100 meters there.
- Ten minutes it goes.
Walking.
Not far.
- I would say a minute about.
- One minutes.
It's a little quick.
Quick!
- Mekong 2!
- Welcome!
- Welcome to Mekong 2!
On Mekong 2 we each ate Vietnamese egg pancake.
After that I went on to the small cafe in the village.
Because I had arranged a surprise for Hofors.
- Ever since I was told that Hofors has Mekong 1 and Mekong 2,-
-I have known that they must have a Mekong 3.
And now, my ladies and gentlemen, it's time for the opening of Mekong 3 in Hofors.
I called you the other day and asked if you can imagine you change your name.
- We obviously felt that we hook up on what we need more Mekong in Hofors.
- It is noticed that it is also gathering a lot of people.
Hofors is like tagged at this inauguration.
- Really
- Trubadur ready?
- Yes!
- Personnel ready?
- Candy rain ready!
Audience ready?
Yeah yeah!
- Welcome to this big day in Hofor's history!
Today you will be world -unique!
Then the speech was given by the municipality's chairman Thomas Isaksson.
All good things are three!
And then we paid tribute to the Mekong Creator and Mekongarvatan.
- I love that name Mekong.
Then we got celebrated visit from the woman who is known in the village to almost look like Marianne Mörk.
- You really are almost Marianne dark.
- Yes, I've heard it before.
- An applause to Hofors Marianne Mörk!
- Are you ready?
- Yeah yeah!
- Then it's time to cut the tape
To Mekong 3!
- Oh damn what a lot of people!
- It's a folk party, it's a carnival atmosphere.
So there are so many people inside Mekong 3 right now.
Oh, think what I dreamed tonight.
Mauri called they are going to play a splash
We already have Mekong 1 and 2
What is it he thinks we should go on?
Yes, Hofors had finally got his Mekong 3.
And now my ladies and gentlemen are starting to approach the top of the list.
And I can promise that it will only be more remarkable.
First briefly mean that we live in tough economic times and therefore it is more important-
-Ever ever to keep track of their money.
If one is not an overpaid bad Youtuber who gets paid collaborations with Anyfin
For me it is quiet on that front but if we take you for example.
What's your name?
- David?
For you David, it is incredibly important to keep track of your finances.
We take David as an example so now we stand here at David's home.
Awesome guy, kind to his girlfriend, good at round pingy, all that.
But this TV, I happen to know, is purchased on installment.
Which is easily happened when buy now and pay then is so common.
Anyfin, they are on the consumers' side.
They do not want anyone to pay too much unnecessarily.
Therefore they can look at your finances and possibly provide an offer-
-As can lower your costs.
Anyfin does not publish any new loans or suggest more loan-
-Outan they want to help you lower your loan-
-So that you can become debt free faster.
So apply in the app today.
The link is in the description.
So, now I think you can get a better look at your finances.
Hoho!
- And now we are in Gothenburg, because here is Sweden's only restaurant-
-Out a single employee.
My ladies and gentlemen, a pizza machine!
Yay!
It's like no one here.
You can knock.
Hello!
Then it is really just to order a pizza.
Add.
Confirm.
Your pizza is cooked.
Do you want a receipt?
No.
It's like an ATM although it is like pizza that comes out instead of money.
Now it's this one.
Look!
It is delicious.
Now I dare not really say anything else when the CEO is there staring at me.
Yes, a card with a good visit, because we have to move on.
Around Sweden there are many strange mixtures of companies.
We have classics such as Börje's fish and asphalt, Kennet's kennel and kebab and Stenåsen's meat and weld.
In Ödeshög in Östergötland we find place 6, because here is just such a place.
- And then we stand here with ...
- Annelie.
- You have an expertise in two areas above all.
- delicacies and underwear.
Yes, it is a bit odd.
- Here is your store and here you see the care itself in the store.
- Yes, the underwear.
It's a bit crazy.
- Yes, it's a little crazy.
Okay, and what do they cost here?
- SEK 260.
How good you will be now.
- You feel almost flirted when you buy clothes by Anneli.
I take these now and a lunch of the day.
- You can hang with me down.
-Bowl.
- I know now that you can sell lingerie.
The question is, can Annelie cook?
- Yes, it's not safe.
-Not.
*Pling Plong*
- Now Annelie will sell on someone something.
How fast you are, Annelie!
She is so the sales suck.
- You have to hurry.
These are good and popular.
Yes, was it good so or should we have something more in here?
- And now she gets sold underwear, socks and potatoes what it seems.
- What should you have the potato?
You usually eat these?
Aha!
- But then we have to go and eat then?
- Yes, we go and eat.
- This was very nice.
- Yes, I agree.
Get here a little more often.
- Yes indeed.
We hope it tasted good and that you will enjoy your new underwear.
Speaking of strange mixtures, now we have gone in Helsingborg.
Here you have Humlan which is a mix of a life and a pub in the same.
Here we have...
Hey!
Here it is bar ...
And one meter there it is life.
- We are alone in Sweden with such a concept.
- But that mixture has never been heard.
- It doesn't exist.
- May I have a beer here?
- Jajamän, welcome.
- A beer.
- Jajamän, please.
- But it is still fascinating that he has mixed life and pub.
- mm.
- It's a genius that stands there.
- Then you don't pay any extra price either.
Then you pay the same price as in the grocery store.
- But then I go there.
Do you want to hang out to life?
Like here is the bar.
- Yes.
- This is where the grocery store begins.
- The grocery store, yes.
- Here is this princess cake that is so good.
And my beer I stand waiting there.
- Okay.
- Right over there.
It's very close.
- What are you laughing at?
- I think it's a bit charming.
- Here
Who should stop us?
- None.
- What should they do about it?
We do our thing.
- I eat princess cake and drink beer at the same time.
- No.
- And no one can stop me.
- Jajamän, please, please!
- Do you want?
Obvious.
- It will be perfect.
- You are welcome.
Yes, think that you can have it so good on Wednesday.
Oh, don't say!
Yes, it simply had to be so.
I stayed at Humlan and said goodbye to my photographer.
Then I realized that we have lots of restaurants left, so I shaped shame with a photographer to Malmö, where we find the list five.
Usually, restaurants are owned by one or two people
But Restaurant collective It is owned and operated by 50 different people
As everyone should be combined and take turns running the tavern.
- Welcome to the gang!
Hello Hello.
Welcome.
Hello.
- This is the gang that owns and runs the restaurant collective in Malmö.
And you are like the main responsible.
- Yes you could say that.
I came up with this snappy idea.
Everyone wants a restaurant and then we came in a way that you can ...
Instead of everyone opening each restaurant.
So we open one together.
One thought was also that we would vote one a week haha
- And tonight you are five who will work then.
A pilot, a doctor, a music producer, an architect and a saxophilist.
You are the one who runs this pub tonight.
Do you keep track of this?
- No.
- A little neighbor, a little neighbor.
- Here stands Thomas who is a pilot and you serve today.
- Yes.
- This is like a guy who doesn't really know what he is doing.
- Now comes food.
- Food in the door.
- I don't really know what I'm doing now.
So, but I don't know.
But I go out and ask who should have them here.
- So don't you do?
- No but...
Should you come along or?
- Yes.
- Okay, now we are with Patrik who has got some kitchen manager.
Yes, I drive a fish here.
- And you are a music producer in normal cases.
- No, it's totally crazy.
Then it should just be seen and seen so.
- No, I think it should ...
- Yes exactly.
What a lucky thing you are here!
- Yes.
- Then we'll just sprinkle on someone like this
And now the dish is ready.
Ready to be served.
- And I'll eat this one.
- Now the question is whether they are making good food too.
This is for real.
Great job.
Great.
Otherwise?
*Inaudible mumble*
Sorry, can you take it again?
I didn't really understand.
*Inaudible mumble*
- And the next place is here in Furulund in Skåne.
For here, a nudist café or naturist café is opened every Sunday.
And I have received an exclusive invitation through my newly -saved membership.
- Below then, the queue is underway to pay for the cafe.
Are you snuggling?
- Yes now we are snuggling!
- Hello Hello!
It is then Pia who is some kind of chairman of this initiative
It feels so exclusive to me to get in here
- Yes, it is for members of naturist associations mainly.
- What is it like to go to some kind of cafe completely naked?
How will it be?
- Since you bathe and baster too, it feels pretty natural-
-. to keep being naked.
- Then it's time for you and me to go and like ...?
- Then we go and dress up.
- Yes we should go and undress?
- Yes
- Are you a little scared?
- Yes a little.
Is it so wrong?
Now everything goes off.
Hello!
- Let's go.
- If you take your fig and then you go in.
- We'll do that.
- Damn.
I get so shocked every time I see a naked person now.
- Yes, okay.
But the corner of the gang then I explain the evening's Sunday café opened!
Coffee in charge today.
Thanks.
When I'm on a cafe, I don't usually see so many genders.
- No, no, but it's a little denser here.
- Do you feel uncomfortable?
- Absolutely not, I feel super comfortable here.
- Here's not a prestige.
You cannot see any class of society.
Everyone is good looking, everyone is beautiful.
- It's something beautiful about it.
-Absolutely.
Nudity is beautiful.
- So many nude pants in a row.
-Yes!
It is also such a strange feeling when it is even a photographer.
Now I will film you.
Waving if you are doing well.
You feel good.
-Bowl!
- Skåll!
Mm.
- Really nice.
After seeing enough of Scanian sex for a lifetime, I went to Stockholm for place three.
The black club at Södermalm is powered by Ulf, which is blind.
And he offers a restaurant experience where you are forced to eat in compact darkness.
- You run Sweden's only dark restaurant.
- That's how it is.
A restaurant where you don't actually see anything.
The idea is that I take you into my world.
I want to pepper people.
Don't let anything as mild as a little blindness stand in the way for you to have a good life.
- The wonderful thing is that everyone who runs the restaurant is also blind.
Can't you come in the whole gang?
-Yes we take in the world's best staff.
- Here we have the whole gang.
Yes.
- Here is the gang.
- However, the chef is not blind.
- No.
- Johan he sees.
BUU!
- Then we take one last applause and then we drive!
- Now we will be led here in the dark room.
Here it is.
- Now I step into your world as well.
- Yes, now we're going to change.
- Help me!
- hold me just like that
There you have a chair.
So you should sit on it.
You keep the backrest there.
Does it feel good?
- now it feels good
- How nice
- But I don't see much.
- No, but it's planned indeed.
-You feel very ...
I feel a little stupid.
This is really so strange.
Shall we take a bowl?
1, 2, 3.
Bowl.
- No, we can't find each other.
- Where are you?
- Now then?
Bowl!
- Yes, you can take your fork and then you look at you.
- Checking?
- Yes or.
- How the hell did you think I would check?
- Check with the fork.
- It's so strange not to know how much the portion is left.
Now I think I'm done.
Only my cameraman can know if I'm done.
- When you think you're done, then you're done.
- Then I decide that I'm done now.
But I still understand a little what you mean by that ...
So, just having a conversation is almost more present in this way.
- Yes, but there is also a lot that expresses that it is very nice to sit if one is not looked at.
- Here you cannot be judged for anything other than the one you are.
- Yes.
- Ulf always ends the evenings here with a musical number.
Life makes sense
Before we move on, let's still be impressed by Ulf and his gang who crush so many prejudices about the blind.
For this restaurant is top notch.
Realize that you are the best of you-
Now it's time for the list number two.
Disgusting Food Museum in Malmö.
And here I want to warn of offensive content, because what I will eat here is really good.
- And then we stand here with Andreas who owns Disgusting Food Museum where you only serve disgusting food.
- Disgusting if you are not used to it because what we think is good it is we think is disgusting.
It is very cultural.
We only bring things that people actually like.
- But how many of the guests here as well as you serve them?
How often does it happen?
- We'll see, 297 times.
We have a vomit counter over there.
- And now I'm going to eat several dishes here.
- Yes, we show up, absolutely.
- Yes, fun.
- Take a bit.
- It was totally okay.
- It sure is.
- It was crispy.
It tastes a bit like a creamy chicken type.
- Should we reveal what it is?
This is what you have just eaten.
It's a small veal.
- What are you sitting and doing?
What are we doing here?
- Eat and drink well, right?
Then we take the rest.
These bull penishes that you so well prepared earlier.
But we should have something to drink too, of course.
I think some mouse wine.
- These are 200 newborn hairless mice.
- Uhh you joke?
- Not at all.
- So it is medicine for asthma.
- So it's liquor and dead mice?
-Absolutely.
This was a clear liquid when we put it in.
So that the color you see is the color of mice
- But it's not dangerous then?
- No, no, it's not dangerous.
- Are you sure about this?
- Yes I have been drinking it before and I have not died.
- Unfortunately, I was saying.
- Hahahaha
- When you feel the scent you feel that yes it is dead mice.
-Absolutely.
That's a bit of the smell of ...
A little rotten meat.
- Your bastard!
Bowl!
- It's strange that I want to neutralize away the taste with peniches from a bull.
It was kind of good.
- Yes, but right?
- It was kind of good.
- There is nothing wrong with that.
- No!
Hahah
- This is what I would call Final Boss of drinks.
What does it smell like?
- Farm.
- Yes!
This is Kourin.
- Is it pure urine from a cow?
- Absolutely pure urine.
- Ah but vaf ...
In which country do you drink this?
- This is drinking in India.
It is part of Ayurvedic medicine.
- Three.
Two.
One.
- It's just like ... it tastes Bond ...
Not really my taste.
- I see it.
Then unfortunately you will rap some urine for the rest of the day.
We both will do that.
- Your fucking AS!
Should we thank you for today?
-No no no, we have one thing left.
- Get it then.
Okay, this one you see here-
-It's the stomach on a goat guy.
Then you cut out the whole stomach-
-and ties together the-
-And it leaves it.
- You know what?
Maybe I can just thank me today.
What the hell are you going to do about it?
Why am I sitting here with you?
You are not the boss of me.
It's so fun that when I suddenly realize, I don't have to do this.
It's so damn nice.
I'm leaving now.
- Mauri ...?
- I'm not palleting
- Yes, you can.
- I'm not doing it.
I can't cope this.
I drank that mouse.
- Yes yes, come.
- Mmm ... no.
Now you have seen almost everything, but there is still number one.
So now receive with cheers and Klang Sweden's strangest restaurant.
- Brilliant, thank you for today.
Now I'm going to Sweden's strangest restaurant.
So, number one.
Super nice, hello.
- This looks like a very ordinary student corridor, but there is an unusual difference.
It is that behind one of these doors, a restaurant business has been conducted.
For over 20 years.
In a student corridor.
- How often do you see a customer go here?
- You feel the scent.
And sometimes the door is open and down there.
- In here is the restaurant.
It is like in the midst of different student centers.
- Welcome to Flogsta Food Association!
- Thanks thanks!
Yes, here you have him, 72-year-old Staffan Alner,-
-As a few years ago, noticed when it came to light that he lived in a student corridor for over 40 years.
But there is thus more in this story,-
-For from that apartment he has also run a successful restaurant since the early 2000s.
- So you go in here.
- This is everything?
- Yes!
All.
- Where is the kitchen itself?
- Here for example.
Here and a little everywhere there are appliances.
- How many guests do you have here in one evening?
- Yes, then it can be from ten, twenty.
- So sometimes twenty people come one evening here?
- Yes kind of.
- Type?
- Yes of course.
- Obvious.
- Before Corona, there was often a bunch here and jaw and so a bunch was in the kitchen there waiting.
- Okay.
So you are like a popular restaurant in Uppsala?
- Because it is different from all other crap served here.
- What is this restaurant?
If you describe it in ten seconds.
- It is a place that will change the souls' nasty food culture.
It should be the strongest food in all of fucking Sweden.
That's my business idea.
- You sound almost angry when you say so.
- I hate Swedish food.
- It's a huge anger.
- Then I came to school.
Then it was discovered that the classmates for cat food streaming.
And I was shocked.
- You feel like one of the most unusual persons I've met.
- Thanks.
- You build up the excitement for your food.
- Yes of course.
- It is obvious.
- What is the right to get today?
- Tortilla.
- Staffan What do you do on the toilet?
- Guacamole.
- It's a sentence you've never heard before.
What do you do on the toilet?
Guacamole.
- This one has in hand when you go out and ask customers how it tastes.
- Four minutes.
- huh?
Is the timer connected?
Aha ...
- Obvious.
- So, Bon Appétit Monsieur.
- Thanks thanks.
A little sour beer.
- Yes, that's the only thing that fits spiced food.
- What about chili and that?
- Taste!
Mmm!
Oh!
- Is there any strength at all or?
- Yes, I want to mean that.
- Good.
- I get hiccups.
I get hiccups of strong food.
- I hope it is as far from Friday night as possible.
- So I have to say that this is delicious.
You are a talented cooking.
- Yes of course.
- albeit a very unusual cooking.
- It is important to go against the current.
- You can say that, if it has been your goal, then you have succeeded, Staffan.
- Yes.
- Should we bowl for it?
- Yes of course.
Yes, going against the current may not be such a stupid idea, after all.
Do you want to run a robot restaurant in Varberg?
Do it!
Do you feel about baptizing both your Thai buffets to Mekong?
Go for it!
Are you passionate about wearing underwear and restaurant in the same store?
No one will stop you.
And honestly, what are we really for land if there is not at least a 72-year-old Staffan-
-Or it cohesives Mexican food from his student center in Flogsta?
Should we go in or?