This morning, Victor asked if I wanted to be a rabbit on his birthday paintball.
So now we drive!
My name is Mauri Hermundsson.
Since I became Youtuber I have started getting lots of requests in my inbox.
But I always say no because I'm a coward.
Now, however, there will be a change in that.
This week I will open my inbox every day and accept the first thing that shows up.
What strange places will it lead me to?
What unexpected people will I meet?
And how far will I be prepared to go?
- Do you want to take Elin Olander to your wife?
This section is also in collaboration with Wolt.
But now we are running.
- Monday we have cleared.
Now we will accept something new.
And the first thing that appeared now is that a woman named Pirjo wants to show me Finland.
You receive such mail.
That is why we do this section.
I get so heavenly random mail.
She did not write her number, but I will look for it.
If you see this now, then that's what we do tomorrow.
It is early in the morning and now I will pick up Pirjo for today we will be traveling to Finland.
Is it Pirjo?
- My name is Pirjo.
- Mauri
- Who has been so stupid?
- Yes.
- Does it sound too damn good or?
- It's an old guy.
- Is it?
- No it suits you.
You look like a Mauri.
- Okay.
Against the boat!
- Against the boat!
- Now!
What fun to go on vacation with a strange guy.
Or guy or boy what are you called?
But I'll watch you.
There are cute girls in Åland.
Or boys.
You never know.
- If you can guess what do you think I'm most craving?
Boys or girls?
- Both.
Is it true?
- Is it true?
Hit me hand!
What is yours?
Yes, that's right.
- What are you looking for then?
- Just old men.
- Just old men?
- Yes, I think you might find someone.
I might find someone captain.
- You are craving the captain?
- You just never know, these nice hats and stuff.
Yes, and a little stomach and like this.
- Is it sexy?
- The old man should have some stomach.
- Not under 200 boilers?
300 kilos?
- No.
Where does the limit go?
- It's two and half.
- 250 kilos?
- But if he's big!
- You should suffocate when you are under him.
- or over.
- You should suffocate when you lie above him.
Then you are big.
- Who is the longest of us?
- I.
I have much more strength.
- Are you stronger?
- I can lift you.
- It's easier for me to lift you.
- Try
- It will look strange for all cars?
- No, it doesn't matter.
You should lift me.
- Don't I wave?
- I take everywhere on your body?
So!
So, don't!
Me too, me too!
- It's a lot of cars.
- Yes, we are going to the ramp.
Now I get a stomach ache.
Now I go under.
- Pirjo is very afraid of ramp.
Pirjo, it doesn't help you lie like that.
- Now we're in the middle.
Now brake, brake, brake.
- We are going to Åland and have fun.
My God, I hate them.
I hate these ramps.
- Goodbye Sweden!
- We will come back for a while.
We are going to Lilla Finland.
Now the captain talks to me.
Welcome Pirjo the boat.
You're fine.
- Now we have got hold of the captain.
You're not single, right?
- No.
- If you change your mind, honk.
Just honk here.
- Tuta if you become single during the journey.
So Pirjo knows about it.
- Great captain.
- Thanks.
- Thank you for your time.
- I think he looked a little so.
Too bad I'm married.
- Do you think so?
- I think that more was your imagination as well.
- No no no.
- He was craving or?
I think so.
If he was not married.
- But vase was what you said.
If he honks, then he will be single.
- Then he is single.
- You run up and get a small howling in the captain's cabin.
- Not the cab.
- No?
Where do you get your howl?
- What is sewing?
Pippa!
No, I'm not going to pip with him!
- How nice it was to dance a little.
- Yes, it was nice.
It was a real thing.
- You had a tutting, cructer.
- huh?
- You did this tutting, krruutsa.
You are such ... What do you say in Finland?
You are...
- Thank you, thank you, thank you.
- Thank you.
- Okay, so ice cream first?
- We take an ice cream.
Here are such cozy or do you see?
Very nice.
- Mauri.
- Hi, we're holding on to mine and recording right now.
- Okay, should I say a thing?
- Yes.
- Do you want a video idea?
- Come and work in an ICA store.
- Okay, Ica.
- Ica near the Enköping mountain.
- Okay, I'll think about it.
Have an awesome time.
Bye.
- I can't really say no to him.
I have to say yes to everything.
- This section is in paid collaboration with Volt.
Ahaaa.
Wolt is an app where you can order home food from restaurants near you.
The best thing about volts is that it frees up a lot of time for other fun in everyday life.
Let me demonstrate.
You open the app and then just choose and wreck what to eat.
Hamburger...
And since I do not need to cook now, I get time for lots of other fun.
I can wash wash.
I can clean.
You have time to bed in bed.
You can check the story of the ring the triology.
You can go to hockey in Mora.
You can go a little helicopter.
You can be in Greece.
And now the food is here.
And I've had so much fun.
And here we have it, all the way to the door.
And that's pretty accurate this much better life gets with volts.
And with the code assignment, all new users get SEK 100 discount on Wolt.
The link is in the description.
- I can't really say no to him.
I have to say yes to everything.
Work at ICA ...
- Call out!
- Excuse me!
What is the number to he who owns?
- 070
-070?
- 851
-851, but then we'll see you at ICA-Enköping then?
- Yes good bye!
- Then we drive the gang!
- Yes, come
- Go for it
- Yes.
- or?
- That's a great idea.
- Come on.
- Wow!
We will return to my trip with pirjo-
-For I will hang out a bit on Ica-Enköping-
-What may not be the most exciting thing to do in life.
But if you have sat in the boat, you get it in port.
- What do you think then?
- I don't know, you can sing to yourself.
If you like to sing.
- What do you sing then?
*Sings*
- Now it's time to try the cash register.
I'll do that with you, Ella.
Ella has been prao here for two days, which is more than me.
So now she will show me how the checkout works.
Then just wait for our first customer.
Don't they trust us?
-No I do not think.
- Then you say the prize that stands there.
–168.
- Crowns, they say.
- Far, kronor.
–And you say digital receipt there.
- Digital receipt there, please.
- So have a nice weekend.
-Have a nice weekend.
- Thanks for the help.
SEK 169.
- Then you say you want the receipt.
- Now I forgot it.
-Yes.
-San you say ... - nice evening.
- Nice weekend.
- Then you want the receipt.
- Yes, I forgot.
Ella, the hand on the heart, are you a little disappointed with me?
- Pytte, puddle, puddle, a little.
- Did you think I'd be a little better?
- A little better.
- How old are you really?
- I'm eleven?
- It's cool.
- And so you think there and there.
Great!
- Nice weekend.
- and digital receipt.
- Digi ... huh?
Digital receipt.
- Did she get a digital receipt?
- It says there.
- The little girl?
Does she have a digital receipt now?
- Yes.
She got it now anyway.
- Yes but thank you in Ella for the lesson.
- You are welcome.
- You were an incredible teacher.
And an incredible person.
Thanks.
What fun to meet you.
- Yes.
This by saying yes may not be so stupid anyway.
Otherwise, I would never have come to know the gang at ICA.
Then it was time to rand in tomorrow's challenge.
- I have a video idea.
You should meet my friend Niklas.
He is very nice and will have a gig in Färgelanda tomorrow.
We got in the car towards Färgelanda in Dalsland to meet this Niklas-
-As apparently, occasionally occurs at local associations.
- In here lives this Niklas.
Should we see where he is.
Niklas Gårdelid.
Hello!
- Good day!
- Hey!
- Welcome!
- Today we will be able to hang out with you at a gig in Färgelanda.
- Färgelanda is called it.
It is a small town up in Dalsland.
- We got this message yesterday and now we have to hang out with you.
We are very grateful for that.
- Yes, it was great that you wanted to do it.
- Have you ordered a rider there at ...
- Just it's careful now.
We get a choir and bread.
I think it is good.
- It's not just Red M & M's.
- No, that's bad about it.
Think co -workers are going on?
- Is she who drives us there?
- Exactly.
She will drive.
I feel it is stupid if I do.
- It can be a little dangerous.
If I get to choose, I will choose that she is happy to drive.
- I have a spontaneous sense of it.
- I have the box down here.
There is no AC in this car.
- It's no AC at all.
It is bad with it now.
- It's not like this luxury tour life.
- No, it's not.
You drive by car without ...
- AC to Färgelanda and gigs for a sausage ...
- You get a driver, absolutely.
But it's funny.
- How many people will be there?
- Today it will probably be a pretty small audience.
It's probably 25-30.
- Do they pay to get there?
- Yes, exactly they do.
- You are still an artist for whom you pay entry.
It feels a little luxurious.
- Yes, so it is.
Absolutely, yes, yes.
- How long have you been doing music?
- All my life really, but I started playing piano when I was two or three years old.
- Oh!
It feels like you have absolute hearing.
- Yes it is true.
- huh?
If I sing a tone, can you say which one it is?
- I think so.
*ton*
C sharp.
F
- Mwawawaw
- It was a C major stacked, roughly.
- Mi.
- A bess.
- Wooo.
- A diss, I mean.
- Wullalule?
- From Bess to C.
- Muwhululu?
- Ass to ESS.
- No, what is it tones?
- Yes, when we talk, there are also tones.
- And this one?
Mowuluhulu.
- Gess is up to ace about.
- God, I'm so good.
- Yes, I think.
- And now we are starting to approach Färgelanda.
This is going to be fun.
- Yes it will be really fun.
- Then we are there.
Can I help you?
- I will take it.
- Don't you lit him?
- This one then Niklas, Mohowolulo.
- F to C to D.
- Okay thanks.
- Here we are.
- Ajamensan.
- Sound we have, one two.
Yes, yes, yes.
- Then it is time to test the coffee range at the Cultural Association in Färgelanda.
- Yes it is.
- Incredibly exciting to taste.
Mm.
It was delicious.
- Yes, that was the point.
- Was it?
- I do what I can.
- OK, I understand.
- And is it something I'm good at that.
But that's not so much I'm good at.
I make a damn lot of stuff anyway.
- One thing you are good at, Janne.
- In other words?
- The mustache.
You've curled to them.
- Yes, but it will be ...
It will be Velcro.
- You have had big dreams.
- Yes, I usually have it.
- Yes, you usually have it.
- So that ... yes.
Yes?
So that...
- And then just start waiting for guests?
- Yes.
The...
We expect some to come.
- Yes we do.
- Hello, Hi, welcome!
- Thanks.
There was one and there was the other.
- Excuse me, does he try to plan?
Are you trying to schedule yourself?
Caught in the act.
Now he is not so cocky anymore.
- Three minutes left to Gig.
How does it feel?
-It feels good.
I am a bit nervous.
Then this humble guy-
- Sing on the small cultural association in Färgelanda.
And as he sang.
- So when I think of life that I got to live-
-and when I dream of days that I have left-
-So all the clear is my truth that will carry me-
-I know that you...
- Incredibly good job!
- Thank you, what fun to hear.
- During the break after I heard you, I ran out and contacted a music studio in Trollhättan.
And then I think we'll release a song with you when this section is released.
- Yes okay, that sounds exciting.
Yes okay, it would be fun.
- Here you have the cardan.
Go in and listen to this song today.
It is Niklas host.
- Hi, Mauri.
It is time to release my otter that I have taken care of for a year.
You are welcome to Finland.
There it is!
Finland.
And now we are here, in Finland.
And there lives Penilla and her otter.
I have never traveled so far for an otter.
Think if the otter opens.
They are dangerous.
I hardly know what an otter looks like.
- Hello!
- Pernilla.
- Mauri
- Nice.
- Nice
You emailed me and said you would release an otter.
Now we stand here and will release an otter.
How is it that?
- He was, about a year ago, very much.
He had just opened his eyes.
He was chased by a sea eagle in the middle of the open sea.
It was a Swedish family on a sailboat that saw this.
They dismissed the attack and waited for a mother to pick up her otter.
But there was never any mother.
They hoped him and called me.
He didn't even have teeth.
In the beginning I cut centimeter -sized salmon pieces that he kind of scarred in himself.
Let's see.
- There is an otter.
Check!
Hello!
You have not taught him-
-Table condition real?
- No.
He splashes fish juice on you.
Ouch.
- Your shoes will smell fish after this.
- No but otis.
Oh!
Otis!
How much do you love that little racker?
- With the whole heart and a little more.
It will be very heavy to let him go today.
- Why are you letting go of him?
The goal of wild rehabilitation is that the animal man rehabiliters-
-Always bring back to the wild.
- Now he will become an adult.
- Yes, for my baby.
- You baby?
I'm sorry.
-I know!
I can't cry now.
- He does not know that this is the last day you spend time with each other.
- I've told him.
- He doesn't understand that Pernilla.
This is your last day together.
Is there anything we can do that makes him extra happy?
- I don't know why I've never tested it, but I've heard that otters like eggs.
–What do it like more?
He'll get everything!
- Flow
Some gorm-cat food can.
- He should get a three course.
You fix tables, I fix food.
See you here in a quarter.
- Now you should enjoy your last meal together in life.
- are you going to kill us?
- Yes
- Now we almost have to make a lady and the air with this fish.
- There they have their last minutes together because now it is time to head towards the lake and release this outdoor forever.
- Otis has been quite stressed during the car ride but very capable.
He has nevertheless been relatively quiet.
You are very capable darling.
You are really good.
This is my last seconds with him.
Now you should swim in the lake.
You should swim in the lake.
There, there.
- Do you see what?
Yes but look!
- Do you swim honey?
Are you swimming now?
Otis, now you are just a small otter who doesn't understand what I say because you swim away.
But I want to say that anyway.
That I love you so much.
From the bottom of my heart.
And I will miss you.
So much.
And I will remember you.
For the rest of my life.
- Sorry what's going there?
- It's an ostrich.
- Why is there an ostrich there in the middle of everything here.
null
- We are back in Sweden.
The last email I've received is from a woman from Töreboda in Västergötland-
Who wants me to come down and take a picture with her sister child.
Damn!
- We are now in Töreboda in Västergötland soon after four hours in the car.
I'm here to take a picture with Marica's sister child.
It must be here.
God, what a strange thing.
It's like a huge space.
- Is it Marica?
- It's Marica!
- What is happening now?
- Now Håkan has been here and picked up the children in school.
- Why are they getting in that one?
-What is going on?
- It's how it works here as well.
-I do not understand anything.
Hello Hello.
- You get health.
Nice.
Hello Hello.
Mauri.
- Håkan
- Mauri
Hey.
Hello everyone.
What is the idea here?
- The idea was that you should come here and take a picture with the children.
- Right.
You seem very uninterested.
- Perfect.
- Lovely, the gang!
What do we do now?
- What do you want to do?
- I do not know.
I've been going here for a long time.
- There is a lot to do here.
- Can you just explain what this is?
- I usually say it's a small minitivoli.
We are like a single large family living here.
- As a collective type?
- We like life.
You only live once.
- How many people live in this farm in total?
- It's type 12 people, I think.
- 12 people?
- 13 we are probably with him above the garage there is one too.
- Caravans, tractors.
- Bouncy castles.
Here it will really be the runway for Håkan's flight then.
- Does Håkan have a flight?
What is this like?
A lot.
- Bouncy castles.
- Is that a slide?
–Wa?
- Jajemans.
- What are you doing here in the yard?
- We rent out bouncy castles, limousines,-
-party buses, cars, vehicles of all kinds.
We have taxi-business, the ground contract,-
-Excavators' service, rental of residents.
We have from popcorn machines, slush machines, table chairs for big events.
Rodeo bulls, tivoli operations, tractors, cross maps.
We have snow removal, shoot some paintball.
We also have the mini golf course further down.
Then we have our 10-man bike here.
No, now it is no longer possible.
During the press, there is a Viking ship.
- Of course it does.
- Yes, of course I do.
- What is this Marica?
- An old Porsche.
- Is it a bathtub on the Porschen?
- It's a bathtub on the Porschen.
It fits great there.
I went here in April and would visit.
Now it's September and I still haven't gone home.
- Is it true?
- No I love this place.
- You are stuck.
- I've been stuck here.
- My friends say you really found home.
I work with criminal justice and know a little grip and stuff.
- Then try.
Oh!
- Turn the wrist a little so with.
- Ouch ouch ouch
- Where are we going now?
- Now we take a little trip to Töreboda.
To the big city.
- You look with a lot of suction in my eyes at my photographer?
- Is he single?
- The photographer?
Yes.
You really look at my photographer all the time.
- Now Marica has started to pick up my photographer it feels like.
This is really a party bus.
- What should you have here?
- Here you should have a heel.
- Yes, my God, but it was nice this?
- Really.
It feels like there is something with you and my photographer in some way.
Yes, it might be a little irritating ...
- In?
- In the stomach.
- In the stomach?
What do you say about him?
- Yes he is a little delicious.
- Is that so?
- Yes haha.
- Are you just going to go and take a walk in Töreboda, and do I remain?
- I can do that.
If he wants to.
- Yes, yes, yes.
- Is it okey?
- Yes, it's great.
Nice to meet you, Marica.
- The same.
Great fun that you came.
- Thanks for today.
- Thanks.
Have a good one.
- The same.
That was fun.
Yes, we could kind of be something.
Somewhere we leave Töreboda and continue with this section.
Thanks.
Bye.
Now only the last challenge of the week remained, which would prove to be the toughest.
But first we will end my vacation in Åland with Pirjo.
- Now we are happy!
- Yes we are fine.
- How good are you on proverbs?
- What is proverb?
- Short test of Swedish proverbs with pirjo.
- Can you this ... Everyone feels you feel monkey, but not ...
Have you heard it?
- Everyone knows who monkey is.
Monkey does not feel ...
- There is this one ... When you are gone you want to go home a little.
- At home best, gone worst.
- It who laughs last ...
- Cry the least
- I've heard.
The one who laughs last, cries the least.
Wait, the one who congratulates first, crying last.
No not...
The one who congratulates, congratulations first cries last.
- Now we have found it.
- Now we will ride their subway.
- No, it goes to the harbor too, huh?
- No!
No no no no!
No no no!
- Do you see these masts?
What are their names?
- The masters, yes.
- It's very popular.
It's a tourist.
Old sailboat.
- It's just what they can show here in Åland.
Now you have seen it.
Applaud!
Now we can go home.
- That is all?
- That is all.
- Now it's flat.
Oh, how cute.
- Now it feels sweet.
Not nice, but sweet.
How would you spell nice?
- Sö t, sweet.
-  What do you say then?
I'm also shaky.
I'm totally ...
Where have you been?
I've been in the train.
- Do you know what we do?
We're going to Tivoli!
I'm first in line!
Hi, it!
Taksktor!
Now waves!
- That was fast.
Should we change machine?
I can't run.
- You have so much fun.
Run everything you have.
So I can walk at your pace.
- I run quickly.
- No, I walked at your pace.
- Did you do that?
- Check out.
Pirjo Pirjo.
Excavators!
- No no.
I get tamp.
- What do you get?
- Tamp!
I get tamp!
- Pirjo, this is where our trip ends together.
Two days in Finland.
Åland.
- Were you happy to be with me?
- I'm happy with you.
- I am also happy with you.
You're a wonderful guy.
- You're a wonderful girl.
- Ha!
Should we take a wrestling match too?
- I'm going to win.
- You do not.
I'll break your neck on you.
No!
No on you!
You have lost!
- I won?
- No!
But this was a great trip.
There are a lot of aunts in Sweden, but the question is if I have not found my new favorite in Pirjo.
So lively, so funny and so much yourself all the way out at your fingertips.
Now only the last challenge.
When I sat there an early Sunday morning, I was not prepared for how tricky it would be.
- I can't ... Can I even do this?
If she only knew what consequences this has for me and for this program.
- And for her.
- Hello?
What the hell?
- Do you understand what you have put to me?
- Oh no!
I didn't think you would call.
But the vaphase.
- We decided to get married the Sunday.
I booked church and priest while Angelica, as she turned out to be hot,-
-Started preparing mentally at home in Östersund.
She walked with me, introduced me to my new in-laws-
-And told the great news to his grandmother.
- Do you know who Mauri is?
- Yes.
- Who is it then?
- The red -haired guy I've seen on TV.
- Do you think he's good looking?
- Yes then.
- Are you sure?
- He is good enough.
- He is good at war.
- Yes.
- Yes, and now the day has come.
This is really strange.
I have a girlfriend as well.
It doesn't just feel good for any of us, I actually think.
- Fyfan what an annoying.
- It's not that often you get married without ever having met your bride in life as well.
Now she will come.
What have we done?
Hello!
Nice.
- Angelica.
- Mauri, nice.
And the viewers certainly think it's clear that we ...
It's just because we have to, so to speak.
But it feels very much for real.
- Yes very much.
I have friends and family coming.
-Do you have it?
- Yes!
- God, then ...
- Have you regretted it now?
- No no no!
After all, it will be a lot of paperwork if we are to divorce again.
It will be so much mecca for us.
- So we're just going to hold together?
- I thought more ...
- I understand what you meant.
- You seem great.
Angelica was there
You seem top.
You seem to be a top girl.
- You, Mauri.
-Thanks.
Thank you as hell.
-Here we go.
- How to keep ...
- I just take in.
- And so we go.
- mm.
- Please sit down.
Before God, we have gathered for marriage between you, Mauri and Angelica.
To enter into marriage is to say yes to each other.
To the love as a gift and task.
Another gift in love and if love comes through the music.
Please turn around.
- Thanks so much Oscar for that gift.
Now we are starting to approach the great moment when you finally have to say yes to each other.
Before God and in the presence of this congregation, I ask you Elin Angelica Olander.
Do you want to take Mauri Victor Leonardo Hermundsson to your husband and love him in need and desire?
- Yes!
Before God!
And in this congregation's presence, I ask you, Mauri Victor Leonardo Hermundsson.
Want to take Elin Angelica Olander to your wife and love her in need and desire?
And what happens here is hard to explain but it was like everything got a little too much and above all I already have a girlfriend.
- Yes ...
*Angelica Harlar*
- Was it a yes?
- Wouldn't you accept everything?
- I think you are absolutely wonderful and very funny and everything in every way.
But I may be thinking here but no longer.
This may be where it ends.
Is it okey?
- You have been noble before.
- And then you are left at the altar ...
But would it be okay if I understand the right that we stay there and we eat.
Wedding cake?
- But now I think then I put it down.
Or is it standing?
- Then you put it down.
- Oh.
- What are you talking about Bengt Olof?
What did you say?
- This was a bit surprising what happened today.
I'm a little surprised.
- But you, I'm with that.
Then we ate cake and tried to melt my betrayal jointly.
But Angelica seemed to take it easy and pleasing enough she already has a boyfriend so it seems calm.
Bengt Olof, in turn, refused the wedding cake but instead ate his onion jam.
- Jet on onion is very good.
- Is it?
- Yes absolutely.
- Oh, now you sit and eat jam.
- Yes.
Jet on onion is always jam.
Also on a September day.
It is exactly at the great insight about jam that we round off this program.
As we are so happy that we have done.
Then imagine what incredible experiences were hidden behind seemingly pretty boring messages.
Finnish aunts, educational children, pity troubadours, bushy otters, wonderful Western Goths and unforgettable memories.
Big thanks to Wolt!