But then there are some who have thought about a lot.
They live louder, strange, more beautiful and more remarkable than everyone else.
Welcome to seven accommodation that you have never seen before.
So, I have sent out a search Now just wait for tips for really cool housing.
Hello?
The highest apartment in Sweden.
We will, we will, we will, we will.
We have to pull.
Okay, we're heading to Malmö for our very first visit.
And we will do this as a top list, only up to number one.
But we start with number seven.
And what you will see now, it's probably something really extra.
And now we are finally here, my ladies and gentlemen.
At nothing less than ...
Turning Torso.
We are not going into any apartment. We are going into the highest apartment.
Not only in Turning Torso, but throughout Sweden.
Hello. There is no apartment in Sweden that is higher than where we are going now?
- No, there is not this is the highest.
- Oh, Satan, what a speed.
Hello! Are you living at the top of Sweden?
Oh my God! Are you kidding me?
We are so high up!
How do you best use this? What to do here?
- Takes a beer in front of the view?
- Do you do it?
- Yes! Do you want a beer?
Yes!
Welcome!
- What benefits do you get from living at the top of Sweden?
- It's damn good to say.
- To say to ...
- Just everyone.
- A cloudy shit day.
So you get up here and you see sun.
- So some rainy days you take the elevator up and then it is sun again.
And the clouds are below you.
- You can stand down here on the ground, see the sunset go down.
Run in, the elevator up and see it again.
YES!
Here we have the gym. If you look over to Denmark like that. Do you think ...
Fy damn, what much better we are than them.
- I don't want to stop before you.
- Hahahahaha
- Now William has fixed an incredibly exclusive access to the roof of Turning Torso.
Is it dangerous this?
- Oh oh oh!
- Oh, damn!
- You fucking jokes with me huh.
- It's really fucking loud.
- Here we sit well.
- Here we are damn good.
- Look there is my photographer.
- Hello!
When we are still at such a height, I felt it was time to call in-
-Sweden master in paper aircraft.
Welcome in, Filip Bergkvist!
I am Philip Bergqvist, 22 years old and am Swedish champion in paper aircraft-
-And even the top 20 in the world.
- Okay, each airplane, each throw, who is coming the longest?
1, 2, 3!
- Oh! It falls like a ... oh!
Oh, that one!
Oh! Oh!
Oh what it goes!
No! Is it coming now?
Yes! It landed on the roof!
The wind takes it!
- It's at ICA, in the square!
- It is still a highlight that my plan, because it did not look good, would come further than yours.
Then it's time for the Swedish Master.
Do your thing.
No, look what it sails!
- Oh damn!
- You are joking! Check!
- It's halfway to Helsingborg!
No, but are you kidding!
Check!
We have a winner!
Congratulations!
Now I'm going to move on.
- See you.
- Hey Hey hey!
- Then you take that way yes.
- Off, this actually feels scary.
- Then just climb down.
This is scary.
And while I am freeing up there, it is time for us to go towards the number six.
Which is...
We are heading towards Borlänge. And what we are going to it is no ordinary boat.
It is a guy who built a house that can go on the water.
Then we were there. This is what a house should not look like.
What kind of house? Hello!
Hello!
- Well!
- Nice. It's like I almost meet myself.
- You're a little longer and a little red hair.
- Yes exactly.
Then it's time to step on this bathboy.
- It is a kitchen, living room, dining room and so here is the lounge corner.
- How do you get electricity?
It's from the batteries. Crashed electric car.
Great.
- You have a washing machine?
With built -in dryer.
- It should not be the boat.
- No, it should be a house.
- It should be a nice apartment.
- Imagine this ... Come and sit down.
Yes, come.
To have this as a living room.
- That's how it is.
Is there any boat in the way? No.
- Just that, you control in parallel here.
It is a constantly ongoing-
-mindfuck to see a living room-
-Oka around like this on the lake.
What a small boat you have!
Superpathetic!
Hahaha, now you have to be nice Mauri!
- Now we're going to eat ice cream. Come and we eat ice cream.
- Oh, what are you doing? You're so heaven ...
Hello? You are so athletic!
- Send the ice cream.
- Oh, you're greedy.
- Yes, I want ice cream.
- You may not get any ice cream today.
- Then you must not be up here.
- No, okay, you get the ice cream.
- Summer and sun.
It's cozy.
- How much sunscreen do you need to use like this?
- So damn much.
- Then I came up with an idea.
Hi, it's Mauri.
- Yes, serve Mauri.
- My friend Billy Tang has a restaurant in Falun.
What happens if you order food delivery from him for a house that is in the lake?
So now Billy Tang was completely unknown to deliver food to your house that today stands in the middle of the lake.
- It's going to be great.
- Hey!
- Hi Billy!
This guy lives. His house is on sea.
- Well.
- And we want food delivery. I'm sorry.
- How should I come over here?
- It's a bit what you are here to solve. There may be some canoe there.
- What happens?
- That boat is too small.
Other problems. I can not swim.
It's so small.
Hey! Do you have a boat or?
Do you have a boat so you can drive?
Yes.
- Are you going to the houseboat?
- Yes.
- Why can't the houseboat just come here?
- Good question.
Mauri! Why can't you come here? Why do I have to get there?
- It looks like he's a little angry with us.
- But you look like he gets good help from others as well.
- I don't really know what is happening now.
- Look! Will the boat come!
Yes, no one can fool Billy you know!
I know exactly, you know.
Hello! Thousand thanks!
Thanks thanks thanks!
Hello!
Mauri I'm coming!
- Hi, Billy!
- Hello!
- Billy?
- Yes?
- Where are you going? We are here!
- Bye!
- Billy stop!
- We are going to Stockholm!
- No, you are not going to Stockholm!
Where are you going?
- Hello Hello!
Hello, serve! Thanks thanks thanks!
- Billy!
- Hahahaha!
- Hi! We'll dance!
- Shall we Dance?
- A beautiful girl!
Is she free?
- No, not free Billy!
- Cheers for the world's most difficult food delivery ever?
- Thank you for visiting Dalarna in Falun.
Thanks thanks thanks!
Oh Mr. Mauri!
Hahaha!
Okay, we're on our way to Örebro and a couple who apparently live in a fairly ordinary house.
But according to themselves, their downstairs should have something that no one else has.
- Okay, then we are there and I don't know what to expect for me.
The only thing I know is that in that house live a couple who really insisted on that-
-I should come here and see something. So we simply get to see what the hell is the question.
- Hello!
- Hello the gang!
- Welcome home to us!
- Oh, you were almost completely sync.
Most often now I have known where I am going, but you have not really wanted to say what it is.
- No, but it should be experienced.
- Exactly. It will be a surprise, without its equally I think.
Now I dare to hit the big drum!
- What the hell are you have then? You look so damn crazy.
- I think it's time.
- God, what an exciting.
- Then we drive then.
- Yeah.
- It feels annoying.
- Oh damn.
- Research shows that oxytocin, the love hormone is increasing in social contexts.
- This section is in paid collaboration with Lohmanders.
- Mauri! Focus now. In any case, it activates the parasympathetic nervous system.
As...
Well ...
What I am trying to say is that research shows that spending time with families and friends is the best thing you can do for your well -being.
And best is a joint dinner!
Come then we will practice sauce for real. Follow here!
Then we spent the evening practicing sauce,--
-The also the doctrine of creating memorable dinners together.
And we could do nothing but pay tribute to Professor Lohmander,-
-Not just for his outstanding research, but also for the sauces he offers.
Invite your friends at dinner you with and serve them.
Lohmander's new barbeque!
Oh, damn!
Are you kidding or?
Oh God!
It must be worth millions?
- Ah that's a lot, we can say.
- It is difficult to take in everything that is in here.
Can you show me?
Yes, that is a clock combined with a display.
Then we have the thick TV screens.
The proof that I won a Nintendo SM.
This is a Nintendo 8-bit. Here you have an old Vectrex.
You get a little enchanted, but wizard when you look.
- Do you become?
It's so damn much stuff.
Now I died again, Emilie ...
- ah then we put this down
- Would you say I'm unusually bad at Pac-Man?
- Gosh. Nah.
- Now you have to choose a character here.
- They are completely bare -breasted.
- Oops. It might be ...
- Why does David look so stressed that this was the first attitude?
Lots of bare -breasted women
Who played this last?
David!
- Here we have part of the Metroid collection.
We have also named our child after this heroine.
His name is Samus Aran. Our first guys had to find the Aran.
- Lufia is actually our daughter named after.
It is also one that is warm to us.
- You really love this.
- We really love video games. It was also as I said we met.
About 18 years ago.
- You feel like an absolutely perfect couple.
So because you are so similar in this.
- It was delightful.
- And with that, maybe I start to thank me here.
Because I have to return to the editorial staff.
No no no no. Mrs. Andersson. Mrs. Andersson!
I want to sell a subscription to you in the National Geographic magazine.
One second.
Hello?
Mauricio, we have a tip!
- We are heading towards Malmö, where you should see Sweden's perhaps least glamorous accommodation-
-Hos one of Skåne's absolute best characters.
And now we are in Malmö and he is not here.
He is and eats lunch in Skillingaryd unfortunately.
So I have to wait now for two hours about in Malmö.
Have you ever waited this long for something?
! Hello!
- Hey!
- Long time no see.
- We met so a year ago when we played in a program.
Then it is mostly about being the man who says ...
- I smoke myself as long as I think it's good.
- And if I had a bad thing, I quit.
- Yes, it's a hateful version of it today.
But what we didn't really talk about then ...
You are one of the few people in Sweden who do not have like an apartment, a townhouse or a villa.
It's nothing like that.
- Yes, but that's nothing. What the hell am I going to with you to?
- No what the hell is going to ...
- It's nothing fun.
- It's not so damn fun.
- No.
- You live instead.
Here. It's not a townhouse this.
- Why should you do like everyone else?
Do as you please.
- And this is what you want?
- Yes otherwise I would not have done it.
- No.
- Then I had done something else.
- And now I think you should show your home.
There it is!
Oh, soft and nice.
It is really just this picture we need to show.
There are not so many more rooms.
- No no, just a room.
With clothes and cigarettes.
Yes, yes, yes.
You must zoom in.
- Zoom in?
- The cigarettes
- We can ask me photographer and so maybe he is kind and he zooms in.
- So he zooms them in so that it seems.
- And just then you take a cig?
- Yes of course.
- It is obvious.
- I get so curious, how much is this worth?
And that's why I brought in a broker from Malmö.
So now I'm going to value your home.
- Yes, she can do it.
- Welcome in, Nicole Svensson!
- Hello!
- You smoke in here?
- Yes exactly.
- But smoke smell and tobacco, you can still find another clientele.
So now I'll just inventory a little here and such.
Good smart storage.
But I still thought it was a nice choice of materials.
And here you have your lounge corner.
- Just that, you see it as a lounge corner.
Yes, I see good material choices here.
Then he has slightly different materials together.
I also see that *mum * *mum *
It's a kyling stand.
It's good, smart storage.
- Do we have a collaboration?
- Yes, of course we have!
- Yes, what a wonderful!
- No, it turned green again.
- huh? Which?
- What a flow!
- Life smiles at you!
- Yes!
- Are you Sweden's freest person?
- It actually feels like you are.
Hehehehe!
Now we are at Ribbersborg.
- Here you usually sleep?
- Yes.
- This was no bad view.
- Could it be worse?
It can be.
But can it be better?
- Exactly. Maybe may I sleep with this?
- There will be no place. It gets a little bad place.
- Is there a heart room? - So there is one located on the floor.
- It is just to bed down. - Was this all the evening routine?
- This is not entirely uncomfortable. - Yes, it goes.
- This is no problem.
- No it goes.
- Now we are heading towards Östermalm in Stockholm where they have started a scientific housing experiment.
Researchers want to test how to fit more people on a smaller surface without impairing their quality of life.
Now we will simply go and see how this social experiment has gone.
And here is the place.
- Hello!
- Tjena, Mauri! -Hello!
- Is this somewhere else in Sweden? - No, this is quite new.
We are 52 people living here together.
It started a bit like a social experiment.
Resources were also given from different institutes.
- Now someone is coming home.
- Yes, here we have David.
- The situation?
- Yes that is good.
It is good.
Do you like well here too?
- It's absolutely fantastic.
- But can you walk around and look around?
- Absolutely.
- Are you with us now?
Are you in the gang?
- yes I simply hang with
- And here are these pods.
- These are four small huts, you might say.
- Oh.
In here you live?
- Surely it is a little vibe anyway?
- It's a bit vibe.
Here you still have a room.
- Yes.
- Here we have another room where we ... there are six people who share rooms.
This is probably the most minimalist, as well. The option available here.
-Hello! -Hello!
-Can you play? - Yes, I can do.
- The flower time is coming? - No, I can't.
Kind of like that.
Yes, otherwise I live here with my roommate Raj.
- Right.
- And here a lot of food is cooked.
What are you cooking?
Potato.
Potato?
And now everyone is at the table.
And this is some kind of fuck then type?
After all, we have all prepared and brought with us a right.
Right.
After all, I haven't brought anything with me ...
I can't run and buy something. Should I do it or?
Is there any restaurant?
Is there anything I can get really fast? What goes fastest!
- I'm doing raw beef now!
- A raw beef?
Oh it's done, it's done!
Thanks thanks thanks!
Bye!
Raw steak!
Everyone can watch.
Let it wander.
They took 300 bucks for that one.
- For real?
- Yes 300
- Hahaha
Did you buy raw beef for 300 bucks?
- What was I supposed to do?
Hello?
We are heading towards Vadstena in Östergötland.
There is a house that is built in a greenhouse.
It sounds really strange.
But it is such a sickly brilliant trick they have come up with.
This means that they have tropical heat at home with them year -round in Sweden.
And here it is a house in a greenhouse.
And now it's time to step in, my ladies and gentlemen.
I stand out. It's cold.
Soon I step into as well as a tropical climate.
I step into a new world as well.
Oh!
Oh, it's like flying to Mallorca in two seconds.
It's so nice in here. It's really strange.
Swedish cold. It's really another world in here.
Oh, there are people. Hello!
-Good morning. -Good morning. Do you live here, your fucking.
It feels like I'm in northern Italy. It really does.
There are some sitting and eating breakfast outdoors.
All of us others are just loosers compared to you.
- Yes, but weather in any case.
This spring there was half a meter of snow and we had 25-26 degrees in here.
So you can't complain.
- You have, like fucked with the whole system.
It is intended that you live in Sweden so you get a good welfare system and a functioning society.
But unfortunately it is cold.
You get a good welfare system and tropical heat all year.
- The heat rises so that we usually say that here is northern Italy.
And the higher up you get closer to Cyprus.
- Your sick bastard.
How hot is this?
- 29, 30.
- Oh!
- Here it got even warmer.
- Yes, it's hot now.
- It is very hot.
- I completely forgot that it is type 12 degrees outside.
In here it is 32 degrees.
I am getting sunbathing for real.
- Yes, we go down.
- Can we have shade?
- Yes of course. We go down to Italy. We fly to Italy.
- We are going to Italy instead.
But show me more. Show me everything.
Apricot, peaks, vines here, figs, Japanese misleads.
Here you have a mango and here you have my avocado tree.
- Is that there a lemon you have grown?
- Yes, it hangs on the tree too. Now the new is blooming, so it comes all the time.
- Look! Your very own lemon.
- Should you taste it?
- Yes please!
Bowl!
- It's like you've started a new land-
-in another country-
-It's almost the emotion-
-The bowl for you and you and for what you have done.
- Thanks! And funny that you are here.
- Fun to be here.
- I have a long time in my life a dream.
I have always dreamed of literally being allowed to throw stones in glass houses.
Yes!
- I am so tired of redheads who will do a thing that they are red -haired.
- I'm so tired of all Iranians that are so successful.
- It's stone in glass houses! Now it's stone in glass houses!
And now, my ladies and gentlemen, it's time for place number one.
And now we are soon in Knivsta for place number one for our Grande Finale.
Oh my God!
What a building!
Damn!
So check!
What is this?
It is one of the sickest you have seen.
Hello!
- Tjena, welcome.
- Mauri.
- Henry.
- Nice.
Yes, here he is. Henry.
Which a few years ago found a decline in a water tower no one wanted.
Then he rebuilt it completely and created Sweden's perhaps most spectacular accommodation.
- So, you live here?
- Up there.
After all, we have fixed this ourselves.
Yes, this was my toughest mission ever.
- I can imagine.
- Oh.
Oh oh oh.
- This is awesome.
- You live here?
- Exactly.
- But my God, how high we come.
This is the first of your three floors?
- The first of three floors, yes.
- And there you have a sauna, your bastard.
This is kind of a shovel department.
Here we have a sauna, bathroom.
- The next floor then?
It is so neat everything and so this view.
- Well, Mauri. Sit down. I'll show one thing.
- There comes a TV. It just slides up there in front of us.
Do you look a lot on Youtube?
No, but I've been looking at you. I am impressed.
- Is it true?
- If you sit there and press a button there.
- God!
- Where are you going now? Now you go around and have yourself ...
- Exactly, and then I can ...
- And here is a staircase if you do not want to take a lift here.
Oh oh oh.
- Then we have a small balcony here too.
This is how you can follow the sun.
- Can tourists sometimes come and foot and so?
- Yes, we have almost daily.
- You are a tourist attraction as well.
- Yes, it has become.
Just.
- If you were to sell this today, what's worth it?
It is very difficult to value.
- If I say 40 million?
- Yes we can think about it.
- It must be in those hooks.
- It is in those levels.
- Yes, it's more.
- But had we had it on a total contract with a larger construction company.
Then it had cost ...
Incredible money then.
- Mmm
- Here you have one ..
- A cold IPA after the sauna.
- Is it you and I who take a sauna and a little pool with an IPA in my hand?
- Just right!
- Is that what we should do now?
- Yes, the sauna is warm.
- This is not entirely wrong!
- No fuck then.
- Just enjoy.
- Not completely wrong.
- Cheers.
- Cheers. Nice, Mauri.
- Thank you for visiting us. Thank you for looking at us.
Subscribe to the channel with Mauri.
I have done it and it is absolutely wonderful.
I adore him.
- No stop!
Give you!
- But you have to get praise too.
- Yes, but I get embarrassed.