Everyone will at some point in their lives end up in a school, in a hospital,
elderly home or maybe even jail.
All four places have one thing in common.
You serve state food.
But does it really taste the same
How differs and above all where is the best
First out we will test the food at a Swedish hospital.
So I've booked Karo ....
Ah, I can help you
Shortcut to hospital
Fille I have already booked
Hello then, thanks asking
Hello
I would like to place an order on an ambulance
Good morning
Where are you hurt somewhere then
A little everywhere
Are you from Gävle
No
No, it sounded like that
This section is also in paid cooperation with oboy
What start on this day you
Where are we now
Now we are at Karolinska Hospital's emergency room.
It was just a little tricky way here you can say
We will start by undressing you
so that we can examine you properly
Okay
Here we'll probably take off and see if we don't need to plaster a little
Should we plaster
Yes, probably the whole bone thus
The whole leg
What have you been out for then
I would do a sketch.
Okay,
Yes it was a long way here.
But now it's time to test the food at a Swedish hospital.
Here we have Anette.
She works as a dietician at the hospital
And the menu that she and her colleagues have produced look so luxurious.
It feels like you're at a restaurant.
How can you afford this
After all, it is a very expensive to keep patients in the hospital.
So everything we can do to get patients prescribed is very important.
If you put money on good food like that
Can you kind of benefit them from people feeling better and can be printed faster.
Absolutely just like that
Damn
It is very important for you to heal and recover.
Lasagna Al Forno
Absolutely
You have deserts
Black currant sorbet
Päronglass, fruit salad, milk chocolate mousse, cheesecake, vanilla ice cream,
Coffee, chocolate cake, season pie,
Apple pie with vanilla sauce
Yeah like it, it gets pretty good
Something else
Ne but i like to drink because i think it's top service
The question is how to get there
Should you go bed or should you ride a wheelchair
Wheelchair sounds fun
What is maximum speed
Ojojojojoj
Is this max speed
No, it's not
Annette you can better
Wiii
I fly Annette
And here we have Cedric.
He is a chef.
I thought you should come with us into the kitchen and cook some jaw
You really checked out that I'm ready.
I don't feel ready
I think you feel a bit half -back if I am to be honest, but we are driving
Why did we do this
It feels unnecessarily complicated.
I could only go without plaster
Now you have been up in the ward and you were a little hungry
I got a little craving for this lasagna.
I could almost imagine it
I looked like such a guy
You feel a little cat Gustav
After all, there are several liters of bechamel you have there.
You knew it was bechamel, that's impressive
Do you think so
Then we start with a little bechamel in the bottom
So that not everything should get stuck
Then we go with Bolognese
Now we will have some cheese on this then it will be in the oven.
Yes
Buh
Aah
It feels more like you're at a restaurant while sitting
And check the menu.
Fun that you say it because that's a bit of the idea.
For many, it is the highlight of the day just because you have happened to something.
There is probably nothing that allows one to eat good food here as well
Then we try to do as we want it ourselves.
Yes, now we have finished all layers
And now pushed into the oven.
Buh
Aah
I love the reaction which is a “uh” back
And there the lasagna is ready
No
No there it is inside
When the food is done, it is packed into boxes and cooled down.
When an order comes in, then the food is sent off to the correct department
And there it comes with a robot.
A robot.
Oh now comes
Hop
Is called it
Then we put the food in here
And now drive this to your department
Now it is gassing it here
You are allowed to tread on a little
Takes that elevator up to your department.
What a good
Right
Now it's just that you should go up and receive it and eat.
Thanks for the help
Thank you
I waved goodbye to cedric while the food was shipped to the department
Where it was heated and served, which means we have the first contribution of the competition.
How does the hospital stand against school, senior housing and prison
We'll see that now.
And this lasang that has now been heated we will be able to enjoy together with
a real patient in the hospital
named Rolf which I just met which is very nice, faster
Faster
I'm joking
Tjena Rolf
Hello
Hi welcome
God was good
Yes they have good food here
Do they have it
Yes then, when I first came to the hospital
So I took a picture of the menu and sent to the family in the United States.
Sometimes you should be happy to live in Sweden
For the most part so I am
Bon Apetite
Non apetite on yourself
How come you are here
I came in October for a cancer surgery
Has it gone well.
It has gone well.
Swedish healthcare is wonderful
And what should you do when you are done
with this treatment completely
I'll be happy pensioner.
Sounds nice.
Yes, you become like that you
Take advantage of life more in some way when you have received such a diagnosis
It may be a cliche
But the moment that is most important, as long as one has the ability
Appreciating, it comes a little natural in some way.
But sure, one will enjoy the day
and you are lucky
So you can plan for the future.
How did it taste
I think it tasted very good
It is well balanced
Just like you
Right
And so are wet wipes
It is because you are here I think
Is that true, you have not received before
Oh oh oh
Then you get luxury to it yourself with wet napkin
Juste there is a lot of liquor on this one
It stings along the lips
I'm really an idiot huh
Jauauuououh
No
It is not useful with ...
What did you do
We'll score here, what would you say
One to five
Four
A clear four.
I fully agree with you
The hospital gets a four.
Then it was just saying hello to Rolf
Before I finally got to take off the plaster I carried all day
Do you want to bring the home as a souvenir.
The good indeed
Okay, the first rating of the competition is awarded, but we have more challengers.
Soon the elderly and the prison will show what they are going for
But first of all school food.
And that's why we stand here with Sandro who is a student
At the Sverker School in Uppsala
Yes
Hello
But what would you say about Swedish school food in 2024
How does it stand
Can we see the big analysis
It's hard for you maybe
What does analysis mean
Yes it is hard maybe
But like it is good
Yes, the school food is good
You don't freeze, you
Yes
Why didn't you say anything.
I thought we were going to talk in there but it wasn't so
When it really didn't.
Should we go in or
No, we can talk if needed
Sandro you should not suffer.
Ooh
Did it go well
Yes it went well
Thank you for checking the situation.
We go here so it's not so icy
Do you miss any lesson in now
Yeah, but I would rather do this
And then it's time to show us the kitchen
Yes, the kitchen
Hey
Mauri
Welcome
And thus this young man has taken us to the finish.
We are at the kitchen
and now
Should we meet Jelica who is partly a wonderful person
But above all, she is the chef at school.
Good pat
Hello and welcome
No we can take over from the beginning
You are already wonderful
I was just going
They are filming now
No god be embarrassing
Oh no they have already started
Oh my good, what this got crazy
But we take it from the beginning.
We'll take it over
And now we stand here with Jelica
You are a chef at SVERERS School
Yes, hello and welcome to the Sverker School's
Dining room and kitchen
Thanks
I am responsible chef
My home is here at Sverker School's kitchen
Would you say it is good food at Sverkerskolan
I think the food is excellent
And then I think you should accompany me to the kitchen and see how it goes
Well then we take the step to the kitchen
Then we take the step to the kitchen
come along
Before I run in.
I have a very fast thing
Can I only get a minute.
Yep, it is going well
Today
We visit various institutions that have always been there.
Healthcare, school, elderly care.
I would like to take the opportunity to pay tribute to another
Swedish institution
Oboyen
As this section is in paid
in cooperation with.
Do you hear the sound, the sound of the spoon that mixes an oboy
Almost like a melody
Yes, it's really just a spoon that mixes oboy
But also a sound that, like sounding through us for generations.
The sounding after sports training, ringing scents.
The sounding after school trips
The sound that continues today.
That said, a Swedish institution.
And one thing you can forget is how much you can do with oboy
Everyone has it in their pantry
Here, for example, we have some really crispy
Popcorn cookies that take less than a quarter to throw together.
Or as my friend Max taught me when we were little milk, cornflakes and oboy on top.
Or an ordinary oboy.
When winter wines the coldest, there is always oboy there
And it stands for security, joy and adventure.
But basically it is simply a glass of chocolate milk that is
Very, very good.
Well then we take the step to the kitchen
Then we take the step to the kitchen
come along
Should we greet my friends here.
Absolutely.
Are all here friends
Everyone is my friends.
Buddy number 1
Buddy number 1, abbe
Abbe, serve
Lena
Buddy number
Everyone is number one.
Buddy number 1, Lena
And here Abbe is fixing pulled pork
Then we have Lena here.
She is about to take up chicken fajitas
Here we have one to buddy
Therese
Here she a good boss
She is a good boss
I can imagine it.
And now we are
Arriving in the serving
Do you have soup too
And so we have freshly baked bread here too.
You are so incredibly ambitious.
Still, think what an important difference you make for society with your job.
Thank you
Now I get embarrassed
Do you become embarrassed
Why do you get embarrassed
You serve food for hundreds of children every day
It's not just me, it's all my friends.
But can you feel this in here.
Yes I can
That you make a difference
When they come and say thank you for the food, then you get warm in the heart.
It gets hot in the heart
Then it gets hot in the heart
Will you continue to work on this
Yes Yes.
When I came to Sweden, I worked as a maid and that
Was my first job right here at this school.
You started at this school as a maid.
And then so
I always looked in as I walked here in the corridor past
I thought it was very exciting and interesting here in the kitchen.
So you could literally go past that door over there.
Yes, that door over there.
And then I look in here.
It smelled good.
You got hungry when working.
Then you wanted to.
Maybe I'll invest in that profession.
Yes, and that's it.
And now I'm standing here.
And I'm a chef.
What a thing
What a lucky thing you came to Sweden
Really
And make such good food here at Sverker School
Thanks
What happens now
Lowering down the food, preparing out in serving
Then the staff should have their rest itself
And since it's Friday today.
So every Friday we find some fun play
VA
If you want to join it, you have to do it.
If we want
Me and now
My friends will have our Friday night.
We will do two teams.
The game is about building pyramid with
Spaghetti.
Do you play like this every Friday
Every Friday
God what a good thing
Friends, now we start with two teams.
Team their, team abbe
Clear, finished, start.
It feels a bit like being the best in test.
That you and I are David and Babben.
I'm like a long red -haired David Sundin and you, like Bosnian Bab
That stands here and monitors the tests
Yes, now it's only 30 seconds left.
3, 2, 1
Drop, release, release, release
Release Lena
Lena you hold
Teams its, team their won
Lena, you take on this loss
No, I absolutely don't
Don't be sad Lena.
I offer some coffee.
Who has cooked
It's the chef.
They are very good
Thanks so much thanks!
The coffee tastes good
Oh cappuchino is my favorite.
She really wants to wait for her coffee for after dinner
But she's good at
May you reveal
The food is ready so I think I
Should go and meet some students and eat eating school food with them.
Do you think you can win the competition
Yes, I actually think so.
Do you have a winning skull, do you want to win against them
Obviously I want to win.
And the food today we will eat with Signe and Otto.
Yes.
Will you win this or
yes, I think so
I hope at least the school will win
Hope Sverkerskolan is now delivering
One two Three.
It's like good flavors
It tastes kind of like restaurant food a little
Fresh
Yeah fresh is it after all
Eaten and clear.
We are now rating each institution, every public meal.
What would you rate on the food
Then i say 5 then
You say five, five dots
Five out of five
Signe
Yes, also five
You give fives
Yes, it was very good.
But I still think, if I have to be fair because it is still competition.
I would put a four
It feels fair
Yes, that sounds good.
Do you know who is the chef in here
No
You haven't met her
Wouldn't it be fun if you just went in and thanked her for making such good food.
I think she would be very happy.
I think it is very appreciated that you
as well as prepare food for us and that it likes to put down your own time
To work with this to make food for this school.
Thank you for cooking
The heart does this a little extra
While wanting to just, yeah
So that's why it became
You were kind of happy to say that because you appreciate it so much.
That she, like cooking the food we eat
And in the middle of this fine we leave Uppsala.
It was an honor to meet you
Thanks.
I move on.
Bye.
There will be four out of five in grades to the school as well.
Which thus goes up in split first place with the hospital.
Soon we will see if Sweden's largest prisons serve better food than this.
But first of all, we will test the food in elderly care.
So I went to a dementia residence outside Stockholm
And that's why we stand here at Mälar Backen's care and care accommodation with you Stefan
Thank you good day
Did you say please
Yes yes, a reminder so I know who I am
Today is also fat day.
Yes my wife said I had a name day.
Said your wife that you had a name day
Fettis
But I'll be able to come in and test the food today
Good luck
Are you ready
Jajamensan.
To what tones do we and this day drive?
Now it is summer now it is sun now it is koskit in the pasture.
Then how does it continue
No, I dare not
It gets worse
Yes
And now we stand here with Tobias.
Jajemen
You are a chef here.
That's right.
What is on the menu today
Today we have fish piccata with tomato sauce.
Semlor for dessert
Because it's fat day
Just
My wife told me this morning.
Today is the name day.
And then I said, "What is it"
And she just: "It's Fatty Day"
It was fun.
But I think you and me,
Jajemän
We start cooking.
I like
F*ck yeah
Oh yeah
So if you just take a fish and give a little like this.
It becomes like a giggle as well.
How many portions of food do you make in a day
About 900 in total
Oh damn
Okay, what happens now
I thought we might do some bran.
Semlor
Pretty good job huh
Really
You are so persuasive
It will be great
You just make it worse.
Now only the cream is left.
Have never had as bad self -confidence as when I cook in front of you
Like you're about to start crying because it's so ugly
No, really not
And there
There yes
Take a holiday
Can i do it
It is good thus
Is it good or
MMH
Yeah that's good
Can you say something persuasive
Can you make me believe in something
It is delicious, it is absolutely
Thousand thanks
I was good.
Very capable
I think it was great.
Then it is finally time to see how the elderly care can handle
In this competition.
Are you tagged
You can say that definitely.
Should we stop talking now and eat instead
God huh you have become cocky since imorses
Sure I have become
Cheers
The table we sit at we call bb because it is the best table
The craziest sits there
Are you as a gang of own you 3
Yes it has become it
Are you like coolest on the place type
Feel honored
You are.
Yes, we think so ourselves.
Yes, you think so.
I see it on you.
After all, I was never the cool gang when I went to high school.
This is like my establishment.
It must be a tricky disease dementia
Not for us
I don't think you notice so much yourself, but there are others who notice and point out
The name you don't remember, we talked about that
Namen that i have forgotten
Is it a painful insight in any way.
No
It's not anywhere,
However, for our relatives, it is probably a painful illness
Yes maybe it is more painful for the relatives than for one's self
So it actually
That was good.
Yes, delicious.
Should we take in the dessert
Semla, Semla, Semla
Is no one here that hears us
It is so depressed that no one comes in
Semla, Semla, Semla
God was good it is with bran.
Sure it's that
Absolutely wonderfully good
Okay the gang, final grade then.
What do you say 1 to 5
If 5 is at most then I take a 5
-—-—-
I take the five -man too then
Takes all five
Four and a half then
I would probably put and that's a good rating but I put a third
Oh
But what is well good
No that is not it
Are you not satisfied
You get what you want.
What are you going to do about the thing Stefan
It's my program.
It's the only thing I feel I would like to do now
As you are the cool gang
Can't we
Cool us down a bit
What did you say
Shall we cool down a bit
Sounds that like a plan
Yes, so we kept going and cool down.
Threw snowballs on passersby, mucked quarrels
with each other, made cool greetings and finally
A farewell.
And so we only have one visit left.
Kumlaanstalten outside Örebro
Where we will meet the officer Sofia.
Behind these walls that are most guarded throughout Sweden
Almost no visitor gets access.
But we, we may come in
On one of the more exclusive visits to Swedish Youtube history you can say
Absolutely
Or in Swedish television history
Not many people have seen the inside.
It's at that level.
Should be incredibly fun.
Is there anyone who sees us
Here is someone who sees every step you take
Okay now we're soon inside
Hello
Who am I talking to
Tjena Jens
Can I come in
You have.
You have now demonstrated your power Jens.
Can you just let us in it's cold.
Who wins the best in test
What a world we are on our way and step in.
Should you also be visited
As soon as I go out and go in again.
Exactly the same system as at airports.
Now you are on your way into the part where all administrative staff work.
Then we will go into the real prison.
As a person, you have a very exciting story.
You fled to Sweden from Congo about 30 years ago.
Soon 34
And then you have made a rocket career within the Prison Service
And now head of Sweden's largest institution.
Would not describe my career as a rocket
It must be said like a rocket
But we are here to test food today on a prison.
How good is the food?
Very good.
The punishment itself is that they are with us here and will serve their sentence.
Then we also have to take care of them.
Make sure they do not return to crime.
Thus, to maintain a decent standard of living in here.
Reduce the risk of committing new crimes and they will very safely.
Very safe
Thousand thanks
Then I was led towards the prison itself
through quantities of doors, gates, corridors and locks
Until I ended up in a department that was just renovated this day.
And here is literally there
The prisoners at Sweden's largest security prison live.
Yeah not there because it's a cleaning scrub
Yeah okay but there
And here is like a cell.
Yes absolutely.
That's how it looks
Is this like everything
Yes, here for 12 hours
No not so fun.
Is this toilet no.
Yes
it's not fun.
No, it's a boring and tough environment they may be in
There is no dance on roses.
How long would I survive in this environment
I have a quarter of a quarter in me.
It depends on which department you sit on.
I would not sit in this department it feels like
maybe not really but i know where you could sit
We have another department
A small fog
Yes a little so
And what we are in.
It is a special department in a way you can say for it.
Here you cook the food yourself
Do you have a knife and stuff.
It is stuck and is stuck properly
If you are here at the same time and talk to someone, then you stand a bit away.
Now my photographer is lucky that he is on the right side.
Here it takes a stop.
Here comes some prisoners, big and strong he was on the left
They are quite bitty some of them here
They will not cure me against it I can say
But most are right okay
They are.
They are fun to have and do with
What is it like to work close to them
In my case, I feel that I meet the person, not the crime.
I have to be able to go in
And meet them as an individual and talk to them to make a difference.
I hope you can do anyway
A small, put a small seed of new thinking or rethink.
Here I do not want to again and encourage you can find these little points where you show
That you can see them as people, as people and then you make a difference.
But thank you very much for the round
Now I'm going to the large kitchen where all the food is made.
Hope it tastes.
Thanks
It is green
It's green now
So now we can go in without any prisoners that we meet
They live here right and left.
Exciting
Strange, why do you have scooters.
Can you get you can get
Can definitely get to test.
Now is really literally in prison.
On a scooter.
Is there anyone who would hurt me if they got the chance
Yes absolutely
Is that so
No.
I do not think so
Then we arrive at this department.
Called Tsyd
But now I go straight into the department.
Yes
Yes, but we go in.
They are certainly great most.
Safe.
Now there were some inmates who saw me
Mauri, Mauri, Mauri, Mauri
Hello Hello
Oh now they try to get out
I have been noisy so well received somewhere in my life
Hello then, hello then, hello then
Oops that was strange
But we will go on because now we will see how they make the food to 70% of the entire Kumla
And then we have come to Kumla's main kitchen.
Here the food is made to 500 inmates every day.
And he who makes the food his name is Robin.
This is what I look like.
Thanks.
You thank you for looking like that.
It is still a complainant self -confidence.
Thank you I see it like this.
If people at home imagine some of the most serious criminals
The last 20 years so it is most likely that you have ever cooked the food to them
That's right
Didn't sit down Rakhmat here
Good question.
Maybe you may not say that
No
Now it's done with some rice
What a smooth sound
It is because we can hear and be happy.
So just fiddle
But that is so solemn
Now the rice is ready.
Run a lunch with steak paneng today
Oh it gets a little thai
Now you just go
You have to turn this here.
It feels like it's not you who really decides here.
There is a matriarchate in here
in the kitchen at the facility and here the woman is who
is it you who is really responsible for the Paneng Grytan
Well, yes, yes
Coconut milk, coconut milk
Coconut milk
But is it you who have got Kumla now to start serving
More Thai food
Yes
Fun anyway
Yes i think funny
Packing
We pick up friends, come all together.
Pling pling
They will help us.
Pling pling gasket
Yes here, Thailand too
He little guy
You get like your lunch box here.
Really reminds you have been shopping at Thai kiosk
and how many grams
She lost interest
Does she always have this much energy iaf
Yes
always.
You have gone to Thailand before too
I watched.
You think I should go to Thailand
No sorry, i mean before
But I've been to Thailand.
Joooo please.
I don't remember please I'm dear now
Are you a girlfriend
How old are you
-—-—-
It is not a girlfriend's age
Jooo
I think you're young.
Thank you thanks thank you
This is finished food, soon time to drive to them
And this is then the food that I should eat today
Try taste.
If not, don't talk to me.
Will call you.
Is it not good then you may call
Do you know what I really feel.
I will miss you
Me too
Are you tired of me
No, a little
Bye
1, 2, 3
Cape Khun Krap
When I say Cape Khun Krap
If I count
1, 2, 3
When I say Cape Khun Krap, Cape Khun Krap
Look
1, 2, 3
Cape Khun Krap
Yes good
Last in the competition is thus prison the food.
Will it be able to beat the hospital and school
We'll see that now.
Cheers for a Swedish prison meal 2024.
Thanks so much
This is delicious Robin
So this is a delicious thai stew
Lum pie has done well
Lum pie she is, she is my queen, type
I love her boundless
My queen
You may borrow her if you want.
Oh
What funny that you react
No she is my queen
The punishment is already to sit here on Kumla.
The food can still be very good
I think
It would be strange if you chefs strained you to make bad food,
Yes but it feels a little wrong
is there a limit and you feel like this
Oh, now it was too good we are still a prison.
So i salt in a little extra then
Nothing like that or
Ne
Okay, final grade on this.
I would say that in this context this is up and nos
on a four.
So I may have to go home and think about who is the best.
Prison, school and hospitals thus all land on a 4
But who wins we return to just right
What else do you do in life when you don't cook food to prisoners
Then I take care of my two kids at home and then I am doing some music.
VA
Can Spelalite troubadour and such
Are you a singer
Yes some
What are you?
You understand what this will have to lead to.
I hope you realize
Ne, not sowing singing
I think I read now that you have to sing
No
It won't happen or
There is not a chance.
And in the midst of this wonderful little moment at the prison yard
So it was time for me to decide a winner
And I can say that it was difficult for all the chefs we have met deserves their own tribute
They don't have any magnificent wages.
Many people hardly think that they exist.
Yet they stand out and day in and fight with small budgets
To in their way illuminate the existence of children, pensioners and sick.
But it is a competition and the one that eventually draws
I let the longest straw be surprised by two friends.
Congratulations
But wait it is me
In the big Sweden
Of all the meals that are cooked and that we have won.
Feels huge.
Like having received a Nobel Prize.
I would like to encourage everyone with this one
The benefit to donate a coin to the Child Cancer Foundation.
And of course we will give our profit to the Child Cancer Foundation.