After thousands of tips and a solid research work-
-Have I put together a top three list of the most extreme cases of spokenness.
You should meet the whole trio today.
We start at Södermalm in Stockholm, because here 19-year-old Elliot lives with mom and dad at home.
He has never ever contributed with work in the home-
-And even though he has a job, he really lives on his parents.
- Then we stand here with Erika. You are the mother of our first guest.
It's early in the morning. Why are you and I stand here now?
- We have to wake him. I wake him every morning.
- And your husband he prepares breakfast.
It is going on as a small operation here.
- Well, but it flows on. He is my little prince.
- He's your little prince. Then we step in then.
- Elliot?
The baby, now you get to wake up.
Elliot Hörru, were you tired?
- My name is Elliot, I am 19 years old and turn 20 in a few months.
I would describe myself as very spoiled.
Gets serviced and curled at home.
Do nothing at home.
But I enjoy it.
- Never has anyone made such a tired and let go of this program.
- My dad prepares breakfast for me every day.
So it is served in the kitchen when I go up.
It feels like ... I'm almost a little sooty on you.
That you only get to paw here and as a 20-year-old get the whole breakfast served.
- Now you would like me. -Gladly.
- And I understand that.
- What would have happened if this one was not here?
- Then we have a problem. Then we have a very big problem.
First of all, it is ...
- Then we have a ...