Have you seen this movie?
A young, healthy and well -trained woman has got Corona and become Assjuk.
It's scary. Corona is not dangerous if you are not old and sick.
Someone has written that it is an old movie that warns of smoking.
-You might have found a scam there. -Shey, fake?
-Many doubted the movie. -Is that fake or not?
Journalists Åsa Larsson and Jack Werner started the Viral reviewer.
Today, they run the source criticism, Sweden's national team in source criticism.
Now, together with Edwin, they do Källkoll Corona.
Before we look at the woman, we should have it clearly and clearly-
-At Corona, Covid-19, worst affects those who are older.
It is the clear picture from everywhere.
If you are over 40, you suffer worse.
But in the news feed, which comes from all over the world-
-We also hear about what stands out.
This spoke the state epidemiologist Anders Tegnell Om-
-To a press conference.
When one has a disease that in a short time affects a million human-
-The all diseases will have odd events.
This brings us back to the woman on the movie.
This was a two-child mother from the UK who became inserted
-And then turned out to have covid-19.
I'm on intensive. I can't breathe without this one.
She described it as having glass in her lungs.
She became very scared and wanted to tell about it to her friends.
This movie was then spread throughout the world.
Everyone was quite stressed by it.
Then people began to comment. "This is fake."
"It's an old anti-smoking film." Maybe because she said like this:
You who smoke, put away the cigarettes.
You need your lungs.