My "babes", here are my "sidekicks" Åsa and Jack, who do their thing.
Now we will have advertising. The sweater is from ---, and the shoes are from ---.
And this face is "all natural, babe".
We will hear next time. Kiss!
-Ope to see you in a good mood. -Yes, I'm a comet.
-Is that is burning? -A celestial body in space in the dark?
"Whatever!" What you nerd nerds about will not "get me down".
-What are you doing? -We come on "Källkolls" tagline.
No problem! "'Källkoll' - Slayer of fake news."
It's "catchy", maybe.
Or: "'Källkoll' - Bad News for fake news."
-We have a problem with fake news. -I know, Åsa.
No, not like that. The concept is kasst.
When it began to be used, it meant something.
Then it meant that a fake site publishes something completely invented.
It was the electoral movement in the United States in 2016.
After that, the concept has begun to mean pretty much anything.
It is used for rumors, propaganda, poor journalism, misunderstanding.
-Everything can be described as fake news. -It is a very specific concept.
People say fake news, so you don't know what they mean.
It's almost like a belligerent: "What you said is fake news."
Or: "You are fake news."
It sounds like something we can do in the program. All kinds of fake news.
-Good idea, but first some coffee! -Or energy drink! Just wait.
Honey, your favorite star makes uninhibited advertising, but for you over 16.
If you want to party or plug all night, you should drink ---.
It solves all your problems. You are "Perfect, beautiful, amazing"!
We will go through all the fake transmitters once and for all, "right"?
Have you been cheated on social media?
Yes, you get cheated everywhere. It may be a friend who lurks one.
Then people can fool you into clicking on a link that will take you to a page.
Most often so ...! Sometimes it looks shady.
Usually you do not have money so you can't be fooled!
When I was a kid, they said: "If you follow me, you are in a competition."
Or: "You get free products if you write this." But it's false.
You go on it when you are small.
I probably haven't been fooled, but if you get cheated you don't know it.
No. I am careful what I buy and what I trust.
Do you remember the freight ship that got stuck in the Suez Canal for several days?
-Yes. -It was exposed to fake news.
Egypt's first female sea captain-
—the falsely accused of Suez channel blocking-
-trot that she worked on a ship far from the scene of the accident
It was a campaign. She had figured in an article-
-If she was Egypt's first female sea captain.
Then some changed it:
"Egypt's first female sea captain has caused the chaos in the Suez Canal."
But she had nothing to do with the disaster. She was far from there.
Sometimes you easily realize that it is wrong.
Sometimes it is much more difficult. More often it is more difficult.
Often things are mushy and not a hundred percent true or false.
One may ascertain that all that is wrong-
-Don't come from a man who has lied.
Sometimes it's not even wrong.
-What do you mean? -Covid situation in the United States for example.
In an open society, people can testify to what they have been through.
When Pandemin swept across the countryside in the United States, it looked like this:
You said that even when hospitals are over-loaded with covid patients-
-do they come in, are seriously ill, tickle after spirit-
-And they still don't think they got covid.
Yes, the hardest thing to see is that people are looking for other causes.
They want a magical answer, and they don't think covid exists.
-This got stuck with me strongly. -But?
But, then it turned out that this picture was not obvious.
A reporter had contacted other hospitals in that area-
-And heard with emergency nurses who did not share this picture.
This does not mean that the nurse is lying.
The reporter who called around may not get hold of those who saw the same thing.
Different nurses see different parts of reality. Hence the problem.
How representative is a testimony?
That a person is involved in something does not have to say what the whole looks like.
After all, a testimony can color a very many picture of the truth.
One has to ask how common and representative phenomenon is?
Just. Much like "Tafsar Day" which was a few weeks ago.
It was alleged that there were calls in social media, on tiktok-
-"Challenges" that guys would paw on girls on the big "pawing day".
It seems to start with the police warned of "Tafsardag".
The big spread of "Tafsardag" came late.
It's disgusting.
It's good if parents talk to their children about it.
This is the problem:
When it spread in all media, there were no first -hand sources.
When many young people are asked if they heard it, it is likely that they heard about it-
-For the police, newspapers, the school has talked about it.
One has to weigh the balance between worrying or warning of something-
-What is a phenomenon for real.
We talked about that in previous programs. There is a risk of a "copy cat" effect.
When someone does stupidity or it is talked about it-
-Tris it to inspire people to do stupidity.
Was it a joke from the beginning? Would just a few idiots do it?
Was it big or small? We do not know that about "Tafsardag".
We must be clear that abuse must be reported to the police.
If things happen at people's schools, they should tell you about it.
If we pick it up.
It happens that such stories start with that an individual person-
-Have have been involved in something, tells about it, and it gets huge spread.
That it is not a celebrity, or scam in the background ...
It really happens and then it can be anything from truth to rumors ...
-... to misunderstanding to jokes. -And the individual stories ...
... can then be picked up and reached by those who have a purpose.
They can screw it, add things-
-and even omit stuff that is relevant-
-As to make a point of it. It becomes political propaganda.
In India there are cases where rumors have led to lynching.
This is fired by contradictions between people groups.
When someone has something to gain on it purely political-
-Then you can expect them to look for individual examples-
-To get this point.
It doesn't just have to be political actors or groups-
-What may be states that want to promote their own purposes.
On Russian state television last month, AstraZenecas vaccine-
-When an APVaccine and is portrayed as dangerous.
A study from the United States says the same Russian troll-
— which is suspected to have affected the election result in 2016-
-Have tried to fire on a debate about how safe vaccines are.
Sometimes even states use magic factories and armies of bottoms.
Very sci-fi!
The origin of the concept of "troll" is someone who just wants to joke-
-And a debate to derail at fun, as well.
But with magic factories it is about states wanting to promote their own sake-
-And they want to get into other countries' internal debates and perhaps influence.
When a person comes to the magic factory-
-They get a list of topics that the factory is working on.
Which event has happened and what is to be written about it-
-And what feeling the troll should evoke in the audience.
Hello? Hello! Yes, it goes amazing!
Yes, I'll do more just right away. You have a new thing? A cream?
Yes, send it over! Certainly! Kiss!
Money, money, money!
But must it be someone who does it for the money, right?
There are many who do it. For example, fake sites.
Those who only find stuff. "The original fake news."
After all, we have not had so many of that in Sweden.
This is Veles.
As a 22-year-old, I earned more than some do for a lifetime.
And these are the people behind it.
It is a huge industry and a huge network.
We create fake profiles so that we can reach more people.
There is a strategy here.
But we have some satirical sites that want to make some kind of satirical score-
-and that can therefore find or exaggerate.
They may also have the purpose of making money.
You do this by having these little boxes with Google Ads-
-And then you get money through traffic.
Then we also have the viral sites.
Those who are looking to get articles very scattered and viral.
They pick up the most engaging news.
Sometimes they can just write them straight off a news site.
They also do not care that what they write should be just right.
No ... here we have old favorites like "Mikropopcorn is fatal!"
"Chips are fatal!"
Are you sent by the snack lobby, right?
No, but these pages have a tendency to pick up study-
-What says something is dangerous in very high doses when really ...
It is not dangerous if you stick to the daily intake.
Then we have the fraudsters who find different types of scams-
-To access personal data.
A man called my mom. He said he called from the Public Health Authority-
-And had found her through infection tracking.
He would send mouth guard-
-And she just needed to verify that she is she.
Fraudsters try to find weaknesses.
They are looking for man who does not know they exist.
They try to get over personal information, money.
This can happen in many different ways. They can send sms, messenger-
-dm, anyway!
I'll do a thing, but that's something you should include in your channel.
-Absolutely! It has eighteen followers now! -Wow ...
There are many different types of false content on the web.
All to what is intentionally wrong for things that are not.
Here are all types of senders to this content.
We ourselves.
We do as we have always done. We talk, joking, lie, misunderstand-
-and all this can get viral.
Fake sites.
Fake sites find their articles straight up and down.
Their purpose is to amuse and sometimes make money.
Viral sites.
Viral sites are like fake sites, but they take their material from reality.
They cut and borrow things from the web that they think should spread.
The goal is to get traffic in and then make money on traffic.
Fraudsters.
Fraudsters are looking for our money and personal data.
Personal data can be used for different things-
-As to order cards or stuff in other people's names.
Ideologically motivated.
It may be those who create and spread political propaganda.
It is not always wrong, but it may be busted-
-Or so something has been omitted to make a political point.
Foreign influence.
It is when states sit behind the fake accounts and pull the threads.
The goal is to promote their own purposes-
-And sometimes disturb or influence the debate in other countries.
You can release your pores and put yourself in focus with ---!
You don't have particles in the eyes-
-and unnecessary cascade effects around the temples. Best of all?
No Corona!
No, but ... I can't say it helps against Corona!
I don't feel amazing perfectly beautiful with this cream.
My safaris, you deserve better! I jump off my advertising contract.
Good moral compass, Edwin!
Think of all the money you had earned! But you stayed on the narrow road.
-Perfect! -Yes ... Yes, it felt good indeed.
Swedish text: C. Fröderberg/N. Lie Iyuno Media Group for UR