Corona ...
... is not just illness.
It is power play and big politics.
Countries and holders who want to win at the expense of others.
Åsa Larsson and Jack Werner started the "Viral Reviewer".
They run the source criticism - Sweden's national team in source criticism.
Now they and Edwin Safari do "Källkoll Corona".
Russia and China, for example.
Serbian President kissed China's flag when Chinese doctors flew in.
And Russia sent the auxiliary package to Italy with "From Russia with Love".
There is more behind the sudden kindness.
With Trump as president of the United States, relations with the EU have deteriorated-
-So to the extent that Angela Merkel and Trump didn't even shook hands.
Can you shake hands?
Mr. President? Can you shake hands?
China has seen an opening when things are going badly between the US and the EU.
And Russia has a rather crunchy relationship with the EU.
So it may seem like Russia and China beating on big-
- But it may not.
The magazine La Stampa received the information-
-If 80 % of Russia's aid broadcast was meaningless.
All help from Russia or China is not meaningless.
And that does not mean that the US and the EU do not do things just "for show".
But it shows that what the countries do have to do with politics.
For example, when I do this.
But no!
Speaking of your extreme self-goodness, Jack-
-The I have seen some debate about Sweden's strategy.
So the rest of the world thinks we are crazy.
We can look at it, so I'll explain.
The politicians found in all countries-
-Want to prove to be actionable to their voters.
They want to be able to show what they did so that voters vote for them.
But Sweden has different things that come into play. Sweden has...
... perhaps the most fragile minority government.
In several countries, such as England, the political leaders have ...
They govern the majority of Parliament. They can run over the opponents.
They cannot do the Swedish government.
Then it is that Sweden has independent offices.
-Agencies. -Just.
The intention is that the government should not in and poke in what they do.
This is not the case in all other countries.
Each section contains educational material at Urplay.se.
Search "Källkoll Corona" and select "Pedagogical Material".
Click on the worksheet.
So here's a little neighbor.
The government has various advisers who are directors general for authorities.
They give advice and recommendations and then the government should weigh everything together.
Then it can be a bit like this.
We say that the medicine here says:
"Lock them in each cave until September."
-Typically medical. -Sen maybe the economist says:
"No, then there will be financial crash."
Then the government must decide what to do.
They have listened to their advisors quite a lot.
They must stand for it before Parliament. They respond to the elected officials.
Now the government has listened particularly much to the Public Health Authority-
-As is responsible for this particular area.
They have been given quite a lot of responsibility.
They are not only responsible for infection protection, that there will be less infection-
-Or also for us to feel better in the long term.
That we should feel better mentally, that children should not be deprived of their school-
-That women should not end up quarantine with violent men.
We will feel good in ten years and not just when the Coronapandemia is over.
Sweden does both as other countries and definitely not as other countries.
It can open up that other countries may think of things about Sweden.
It may be more about the fact that they want to appear less crazy.
As Trump did when he said Sweden suffers severely in the Corona crisis.
Sweden suffers very difficult.
Sweden makes this "flock".
Sweden's Foreign Minister opposed.
I'm not going to review Trump, but he has a factual error.
We do not have a strategy that is based on flock immunity.
State epidemiologist Anders Tegnell did not agree.
After all, all countries suffer during this.
Trump has a history of drastic statements about Sweden.
“Last Night in Sweden”
But it became a photo exhibition of it.
Sweden is often picked up as an example in other countries' debate.
They think we are extreme. It can be immigration.
They can see us as a socialist and feminist paradise-
-And show pictures of latte dads. Some like it, others don't.
There are many fathers walking around with strollers.
What they are not interested in is the nuanced image of Sweden.
And speaking of shades, I just want to say that when Trump made the statement-
-I have I for myself that Sweden had Sweden 750 cases per million
-While the United States had 1,200 cases, something like that.
But now you do just that. Goes in and defends Sweden against the United States.
It is not possible to know who has the worst, because everyone has it piss.
The situation develops and the figures are unreliable.
No one can test their entire population-
-And you have to test at the right time. It's just opinions.
It is very easy to go into this spin and think we and them.
It is so easy to become indent-
-And stand and think it's like a international match.
That's what politics does sometimes. Distract from the important.
Distracts is exactly what your conversation has done from what I should do.
Let's see. Yes!
Girl, whatever!
Texting: Stina Hedin www.btistudios.com