Have you thought about how you have been able to grow 1-1.5 meters since you were born?
Or why are you not like your siblings even though you have the same parents?
Two thoughts with one and the same answer: cell division.
Celler's life is a few months and the body has to fill with new ones.
This is done by cells cloning and creating copies of themselves.
The process is called cell division and there are two types:
Meios, when germ cells divide to sig-
-And mitosis, which is when more common cells in the body clone.
To understand why they differ-
-Th we go through what distinguishes germ cells from ordinary cells-
-and briefly explain the DNA chromosomes.
Each chromosome is packed with DNA sequences on long threads.
These chromosomes are sitting in par-
-Ach contains the same information, the same genes and the same characteristics.
In a regular cell, our DNA consists of 46 chromosomes
-But in a germ cell there are only 23 chromosomes.
The difference in the amount of chromosomes affects how cell division is done.
When a regular cell should split, when a mitosis is to be shown
-Ad the process of coping DNA.
The cell gets a double set of its 46 DNA chromosomes.
The organelles, cell components, are also doubled.
When cell division is to be done, organelles-
-To the two daughter cells and DNA migrate into the cell halves.
After that, the cell membrane closes and two new, identical cells have been created.
They have exactly as many and similar chromosomes as the mother cell.
It is thanks to the mitosis that you grow 1-1.5 meters since you are born.
Then the split goes faster and more cells are created than those who die.
Germ cells have only half as much DNA as a regular cell-
-No 23 chromosomes.
In the ovaries or testicles there are cells that are diploid.
They have 46 chromosomes, but are not included in the reproduction system.
They are there to create germ cells with 23 chromosomes.
MEIOS sharing of germ cells is initially weighed as in the mitosis.
Organelles and DNA double and divide into two daughter cells.
But 46 chromosomes are too many. Therefore, another split-
-So that the chromosome number ends up at 23.
In this last phase, when two daughter cells become four-
-Ships what makes each individual unique, a so -called cross -cutting.
Chromosome changes change and create new combinations of inheritance-
-And this way creates an endless variety of germ cells, all unique.
When the egg with its 23 unique chromosomes is fertilized by a sperm-
-Of as well with their 23 unique, they will together form 46 chromosomes
-What becomes your genetic mass and a mixture.
If you are not a one -egg twin, you have your own inheritance not like anyone else's.
That is why siblings may not be the same at all, despite the same parents.
Swedish text: Gabriella Eseland Iyuno Media Group for UR