We often imagine antiquity in a single color-
-But it didn't look.
We have a picture of white antiquity.
That sculptures and architecture were white, but it was painted.
Antiquity is more colorful and dirtier.
All the statues we are used to seeing this looked like this.
Painted, gold -clad and often dirty.
Antiquity is seen as the starting point for our modern history-
-And is a time when much we have today takes shape.
Everything from democracy and religion to philosophy and architecture.
So what happened under the colorful antique-
-and what was it like to live then?
Early European history can be divided into three eras.
This is the first: antiquity.
It consists of a Greek and a Roman part.
It begins when Greek city states have its first Olympic gaming
-And ends when the Empire in Rome is set aside.
It is now our time count begins - year 0-
-But we are far from the beginning of man.
Rome's dictator Julius Caesar has the same length of time to today-
-As the completion of the pyramids in Egypt.
We start with the Greek antiquity.
Greece is divided into city states.
They are independent and consist of a city with surrounding landscapes.
Most are farmers.
If they are self -governing - why are we talking about a Greece?
Greeks see themselves as a people, regardless of where they bor-
-And everyone speaks and writes in Greek.
They also share the same god-
-And every four years, Olympic games are held to honor them.
Religion was polytheistic, with many gods.
They had different special functions and work areas, you might say.
This is this gang: Zeus, Athena, Poseidon, Apollon, Aphrodite, etc.
Although much holds the city states together, much else separates them.
They have their own laws and political systems.
In addition, they are constantly at war with each other.
Two arch enemies are the leading city states Athens and Sparta.
We take a closer look at them.
First Athens.
Athens has its heyday during the 400s before our time-
-And here the idea of democracy is born.
It is a long political process where one is trying to find medium-
-Ee to take power from the rich aristocratic family heads-
-and distribute it to more.
This is solved by giving all citizens voting rights.
The parenthesis is that only free, Athenian men are counted as citizens.
In Athens, women, foreigners and slaves also lived.
They had no right of voting or the right to speak in this system.
It is a democratic principle, but not a democracy like today.
Elections were not seen as a democratic institution, because they could be influenced.
The lot was the democratic way to choose people.
With it comes rights and obligations.
If you are drawn forward, you are obliged to take your responsibility.
If you are drawn into the council, you need to be able to convince the free Athenian men.
You both need good ideas and be a skilled speaker.
Many philosophers were also a teacher of rhetoric.
There is a small bonus in the system.
A politician you dislike can get a land -defeated with 6,000 votes.
It is seen as a protection for democracy.
While Athens focuses on democracy, life in Sparta looks different.
It is one of the few monarchies in Greece-
-But above all the view of society and the war distinguishes them.
The collective went before-
-And the whole community was organized according to the best of the state.
Citizens were some kind of warrior.
War characterizes the entire life of the Spartans, and they conquer land.
You should always be ready for battle, and loss is nothing that is accepted.
Boys are raised by the state and do military service until they are thirty.
For people in Sparta, the state and the collective are at the center.
One should live a sparse life.
One would live spartan.
You looked down at material wealth, so you would live poor.
The city states differ, but nothing unites as an external enemy.
One of these has the city states in the east: the Persian Empire.
The Persians are an arch enemy of the Greek world.
Athens and Sparta are side by side against the Persians in several wars.
At Thermopyle, Greece goes on a loss, and you dream of revenge.
When Alexander the Great inherits power in the Greek Kingdom of Macedonia-
-he thinks revenge.
He leaves on an expedition east and is successful.
He conquers the entire Persian kingdom.
Finally he reigns over today's Greece, Turkey-
-Iran, Iraq, Egypt, Afghanistan and India.
He dies young, probably after heavy alcohol consumption.
He seems to have been driven by eagerness.
A willingness to lower the world.
After his death, the kingdom falls apart to the small kingdoms again.
However, the expansion leads to Hellenism.
It is the mixture between the Greek and the eastern.
A typical such mixture is the coin here.
A side in Greek and one in Persian style.
When it is not war - what is it like in the ancient world?
It was a wonderful period if you were an aristocratic man.
Then they had great fun.
The majority are not free men and do not have great fun.
Slaves have no rights, and often married women away when they are twelve.
The marriage was mainly something man in
-A social and economic reasons.
Love did not matter that much.
The goal was to breed the heirs-
-So you got married heterosexually.
Then you could have other relationships-
-When we might be described as gay or bisexual.
So you didn't think then.
There are strong ideals and norms-
-Dore if you are a woman or a man, free or slave.
A man should be strong and have control.
One had control over one's body, their feelings and lustar-
-And even over others.
After all, they controlled your wife, their children and their slaves.
The woman should be everything the man is not: passive and without control.
A slave has no norms or ideals, because it is not seen as a human being.
This is included in part two - the Roman antiquity.
For a long time, the Greek and Roman antiquity coexist.
From the beginning, Rome is a city state, but here you have other ambitions.
This with independent city states is nothing to the Romans.
They will build an empire with Rome in the center.
Rome puts areas underneath, and after three wars they conquer Carthage.
You are at the center of the Mediterranean world and an established superpower.
Now nothing can stop the Romans.
The Mediterranean starts to be called "Our Sea"-
-And you control areas up to today's United Kingdom.
In addition to the Greek areas, they also take their gods.
They get new, Roman names.
Hello then, Zeus.
Welcome, Jupiter.
But for the people in conquered areas - what happens to them?
How does the life change to belong to the Roman Empire?
A principle is that Rome does not interfere in local affairs-
-or the religious life.
You let people speak the language they speak.
In the eastern part you still speak Greek.
You are relatively open and take in citizens from parts of the Roman Empire.
In the end, all men can become citizens.
Some may get full citizenship and others without voting rights.
The Romans call their politics to disintegrate and rule.
Different conditions to different areas-
-makes it harder for them to come together against Rome.
Those who are given voting rights must go the long way to Rome.
This is where the Republic is governed.
Here is the Senate, an advisory body with the wealthiest men of the kingdom.
The officials ensure that the decisions are enforced.
They are selected two and two for one year at the time-
-To avoid getting too much power.
The two most important officials - the consuls - lead the kingdom in war.
Then there are people's congregations.
In those who appoint officials, all male citizens are allowed to vote.
In the Republic of Rome, big cities grow in
-But wherever you live, it gets carbon black as soon as the sun goes down.
Here is a Roman oil lamp - the only light you have except the sun.
You must have many, and it was one of the most common objects.
They are manufactured on running bands in workshops around the kingdom.
The workshops were named after the owner.
The names were printed on the bottom, so you knew where the lamp came from.
It was one of the first objects that were mass -produced.
It is also true that these brands are pirated.
Much of the workforce is slaves, and most are conquered on the battlefields.
Something the Romans may be that war-
-And here is one of the foremost generals: Julius Caesar.
He dreams of more power and a greater role than is allowed in the system.
Caesar is chosen as a consul, but you cannot be re -elected.
His position is not quite in the system.
How does he solve it?
By force.
He trains towards Rome, and that leads to power struggle and civil war.
In the end, Caesar stands in the capital with the sign "Veni, Vidi, Vici".
"I came I saw I conquered."
Caesar is proclaimed dictator.
First in one year, then ten and finally life.
Now "dictator" gets a negative tone.
It would have been something you could be chosen in a crisis situation.
If both the consuls fall, someone must control Rome.
Then you can choose a dictator of a maximum of six months, but not for a lifetime.
Therefore, Caesar becomes less popular and ultimately murdered by senators.
Then the empire takes over.
Rome is governed by an emperor, and everyone gets the title Augustus.
Now follows a period of 200 years of peace.
Much we recognize now is established: monuments, bridges and aqueducts.
For the Romans, life is quite comfortable, but all good has an end.
It crackles in the joints, and the Roman Empire is in crisis.
The Conquest War has subsided, and they gave all the slaves.
The governing bodies are forced to raise the tax, which deteriorates for farmers.
A new religion emerges: Christianity.
Christians refuse to worship the gods of Rome
-The Christianity is banned and the Christians are persecuted.
But with Emperor Constantine, everything changes.
Constantine perhaps expects the potential of Christianity
-Som something that can hold together the now rather fragmentary empire.
By the end of the 300s, other religious expressions are banned
-and Christianity is state religion.
Now everyone is forced to release the Roman gods and worship the Christian.
Konstantin prohibits crucifixion, the Peter's Church funds in Rom-
-And makes Sunday work -free.
But not even that can hold the kingdom together.
Power moved to Constantinople - today's ottanbul-
-And that city is getting bigger and more powerful than Rome.
The Great Empire is split into two: Västrom and Östrom.
Östrom grows strongly and later becomes the Byzantine Empire-
-As lives on for a thousand years.
For Västrom things go worse, and the last emperor loses power.
It is said that antiquity ends in 476, when the last emperor is set aside.
We have found that.
The question is whether anyone who lived in 476 noticed any difference 477.
That an era was over - probably not.
There was probably no giant difference-
-But antiquity has been symbolized a wonderful time with philosophy and knowledge.
We have read the philosophers.
They do not tell how they exploit women and slave-
-and how others are treated.
We only got this ideal image from those who were doing well.
The second picture we have had to dig out.
The democratic heritage has been given a great place, and it has often been idealized.
Not least Greek democracy, but it wasn't always.
Only in the 1850s began the ancient democracy-
-Ses as a political role model.
Before that, democracy was regarded as a mob.
The idea of a Roman Empire power has inspired rulers.
Napoleon, Mussolini and Hitler used Roman symbols.
From the first democratic steps in Greece to the military empire in Rome.
In ancient times, different types of rule and view of power may take place.
Whatever you want to legitimize, you can often find it in antiquity.
Almost like a sandbox of experiences.
Swedish texture: Per Lundgren Iyuno-Di Group for UR