Coronavirus! Teens make Corona attacks on old people. Or?
The police dissolved a party yesterday ...
... coughed and spit on food and then tried to steal beer.
Two young men are visible on the surveillance images ...
Åsa Larsson and Jack Werner started the "Viral Reviewer".
They run the source criticism - Sweden's national team in source criticism.
Now they do and edwin "Källkoll Corona"
It is a damn way, but there is more behind the story.
-But first: Social distancing. -Shole.
There are coronary parties. Young people drive with the elderly by coughing them.
On March 20, Markus held Söder-
-Whots are ministerial president of Bavaria, a press conference.
There he told me that it was young people who had "corona parties"-
-And coughed on the elderly and shouted "Corona" because it was fun.
It became a news in Germany, then in Europe, then in Sweden.
-I'm nothing in Sweden too? -Yes. They uploaded a Youtube clip.
They coughed on people and said "Corona".
It was a prank attempt. Not many people agreed that it was fun.
And on March 30, Eslöv Municipality posted a Facebook post-
-If young people coughed on the elderly.
That post also became a news.
The Youtube prank is easy to know if it happened, it's just watching.
Now they have removed the clip, but it was there.
As far as Germany and Eslöv are concerned, it is more difficult.
How many were there that coughed and were coughed?
-Welcome to the police gear. -I am called Åsa and is a journalist.
We have checked it. We first talked to Germany, or tried.
It went like that, but they basically said ...
The police had received "A Smaller Number of Violations".
-"A Small number of violations". -We have talked to Eslöv.
It seems that it is smaller than it seems.
The police have no reports on this.
They had no reports that it would occur to a large extent.
Then we have asked different grocery stores if it has happened there.
Nobody said it had happened right there.
Then we asked Eslöv's operations manager who told the newspapers.
Finally she said it was about an event in a store-
-There older people had taken offense what some young people had done.
She wants to point out that this is not a trend among a lot of young people.
Okay. But there are so few who do. Why is it big news?
It's provocative. We get to know the days long how to behave.
And when someone doesn't do, it provokes.
When something provokes, it is happy to be a way to show what you must not do.
And disturbing themselves on young people is a folk sport since ancient times.
-Do you remember the clown hysteria 2016? -Yes, who can forget it?
After seeing something like this ...
-When the police in South Carolina ... reports of threatening clowns ...
As it spread, I think this is also spread. There is a similarity.
Wait. You should explain a little clearer.
My great pleasure. If you think like this:
It starts when someone gets the idea to cough on an old man and say "Corona"-
-Or when there is a rumor about the idea.
Somewhere in the world, some of the world's seven billion inhabitants do it.
It is an event that may be noticed.
There may be a rumor. And then people learn that it has happened.
Then maybe someone will be inspired, for example in Bayern.
Then Minister President Markus Söder takes it up at a press conference-
-As a lot of people reach.
Then someone gets an idea to do a prank on youtube-
-As many people look at, so it gets even greater spread.
Then someone in Eslöv gets for themselves ... You understand where we are going.
There are four events that have been noticed-
-So that so many people have heard about it.
It has only happened four times but when more and more hears about it-
-Maybe someone new gets the same idea and that's why we stand here talking about it.
It has not happened exactly four times, but probably few times-
-And the attention has become so great.
Maybe you should make extra clear that it is a terribly bad idea.
I have a tip for everyone. Do not cough on the elderly.
But remember that news reporting picks up the deviating-
-And what is different and then it gets so big.
Plus this with who does it. There may be young people in town.
Events may be obtained in number but still get a lot of attention.
Empty barrels that noise loudly.
And there is a clear right way to behave and a wrong way.
And then the little things that are wrong can be huge news.
They are like banknoting stories, stories about how we should not do-
-So that's a message. -A Message.
It is a abusive idea to prank cough on people. Don't hell not.
But only a few do it and get huge attention.
And stories that provoke we like to spread and share.
That is why they are lifted like this.
So I should not cough on people, as that person does on me.
-How good are you doing? -shit -bad. Don't.
Here comes the bacilli.
See you on Monday!
Texting Stina Hedin www.btistudios.com