Before the year 1450, virtually all books are made by hand.
One writes by the works words for word-
-Side for page and chapter for chapter.
Most often it is monks that do it and it can take a year to get a book.
This means, in addition to cramps in the hands, that books are rare and expensive.
It is said that the King of Portugal in 1400 has only nine books.
He is not close to filling a bookshelf.
But after years of attempts inventing the German Johannes Gutenberg-
-A technology for printing books.
He uses loose lead types that can be joined into text lines.
Now books from rare go to mass -produced.
The art of letterpress was an invention that changed the whole story-
-and and humanity's way of being.
Texts and ideas can spread on a new way-
-In the period called the Renaissance.
It is a time when you look both back and forward.
What did you write and read at the time-
-Then literature suddenly could reach many more.
The Renaissance is a period that can be difficult to put on a timeline-
-But it takes over after the Middle Ages and continues until the end of the 17th century.
"Renaissance" means "rebirth" and one rediscovered the ideal of antiquity-
-When you thought had been forgotten during the dark Middle Ages.
Renaissance is a restoration or look back to the ever-
-In this case to antiquity.
You want to return to what you thought of as the cradle of civilization.
You not only rediscover the old one but also discover new things.
Europeans are going for them new parts of the world-
-while you conquer and colonize-
-And you look out for the first time into space.
However, the discoveries do not protect against illness.