When Karin Boye is found dead behind a stone in Alingsås in April 1941-
-Have one of our most prominent poets and writers gone out of time.
She goes from writing emotional and vulnerable poems-
-To dystopian social depictions.
But how are it, and what did her lyrics bottom in?
"Yes, of course it hurts" and "in motion"-
-Is two of Karin Boye's most loved and known poems.
"The saturated day, it's never the biggest. The best day ..."
It is precisely mainly for her poems that we remember her.
But a few years before she dies, 40 years old-
-she gives out a novel that makes people amazed.
A science fiction novel with dystopian element-
-If a future surveillance society. "Kallocain."
It was so controversial that it was banned in several countries.
Kallocain caught a lot of appearance when it came out.
A very surprising, interesting leap in her literary development.
Karin Boye was born in 1900 in Gothenburg in an upper middle class home.
The family then moves to Huddinge in Stockholm.
She spends lots of time reading and writing.
As a ten year old, she has started writing poetry and short novels.
After attending girls' school at high school-
-Moves Karin to Uppsala to go to university.
A male -dominated environment where female students are unusual.
Karin gets her eyes on how unequal women are treated in teaching.
She had been staying in girl environments, so this with inequality-
-In how boys and girls were treated would not have been a matter for her.
Now she came to a very male -dominated environment.
One in many ways conservative environment-
-There the girls, the student shoes were something unusual.
Some thought they were intrusion into that environment.
After all, it sharpened her gaze for injustice in society.
An idea is raised at Karin at the university.
She has written extensively since she was little-
-And now wants to start sharing their texts with more.
She gathered her best old poems and went to Bonniers publisher-
-To Karl Otto Bonnier and asked if she could be published.
After only a few weeks they heard from them and said, "Yes, you are accepted."
So she was 21 years old. It was something very unique then.
The debut book "Cloud" is a collection of poems about a young man's pondering.
About life, about God, about his own future.
Suddenly she became a celebrity in Uppsala, a literary celebrity-
-So then she got into these author gangs.
Then she became more politically radicalized too.
With feminism she had discovered the injustices between men and women-
-and it was the next logical step to detect the injustices between class-
-and between different countries.
Interest in politics and how people in other countries had it-
-Growing with Karin and she started traveling.
Among other things, she goes to the then Soviet Union and is struck by the oppression.
1932 she travels to Berlin, the year before Hitler takes power-
-and sees how Nazism begins to permeate society-
-But then without understanding the seriousness, as for so many others.
She is curious and observes. Fascination mixed with fear-
-What is visible in her texts.
But the trip down to Germany she not only did for the sake of travel.
Her real reason was to get help.
She had wrestled with her sexuality and attraction to women.
Something she tried to push away, as homosexuality was seen as immoral-
-classed as a disease and was criminal.
She wanted to cure herself from it, so she would not be drawn with it.
Then the method of the time was to go into psychoanalysis.
But instead of, as she calls it, "being cured"-
-She is recommended to live out her desires.
"Purple that page instead. Try to live gay."
Then she did. She was out on "Dambars" there.
In the letters home, she talks about her forbidden love relationships.
Maybe it was the fear of having its secret revealed-
-and the feeling of being supervised-
-which it was the first seed of the novel "Kallocain". That and Kafka.
It is very clear that she was inspired by the outside world-
-But for Karin, the big thing was that she read Kafka.
This horror mood and feeling that the world is incomprehensible and evil.
She took it with her.
Kallocain is very interesting literary history-
-Stheft it is a fairly early, in Swedish context, dystopia.
In the subtitle of Kallocain it says "a story from the 21st century".
Kallocain takes place in a future community-
-Where several totalitarian states dominate the earth.
The main character is called Leo Kall.
He is a chemist who is loyal to the future despotic society.
He invents a truth drug that he calls Kallocain.
Leo cold, the narrator, is a scientific man, so it's a pretty dry prose.
I am an insignificant cell in the state organism.
But there are other elements as well. They eventually show up-
-Recomy when he interviews people with Kallocainet's help-
-The you hear other thoughts, much more emotionally, lyrical language.
But even the dialogues he agrees with wife Linda has a different language.
And the poetic language could sound like this:
Then one should remember that this with truth-
-and to be able to maintain a personal reserve-
-We something very deep for her, to do with her homosexuality.
In a future society of truth drug-
-Can not keep your innermost sexual and private.
It was something that scared her very much.
When "Kallocain" comes out, it becomes popular in Sweden.
In Norway and Denmark, which are under Nazi occupation, it is banned.
The consequence is that it is pirated and spread anyway.
There was a possibility that it could have gained even greater spread.
There were thoughts of translating it and releasing it in the United States.
Karin Boye was familiar with Gunnar Myrdal, who was a researcher in the United States.
He would bring the book with him.
But he was overweight on the flight and had to leave the books at home.
It was that random story that made it not come there-
-And the right person was not spoken.
I don't know if they sent it, but there was nothing with translation.
But in that case, it had arrived a few years before George Orwell's 1984.
But if the surveillance community was relevant in the 40-
-Is it no less relevant today.
In many ways, Karin Boye's depictions were before her time.
All these small cramped spaces that people live in, in the underground.
Police eyes and police ears, even the bed room is guarded by the state-
-So that you know that it is bred children, that is, future soldiers.
So Kallocain is not just a novel about surveillance technology and sow-
-What is a novel about closing women's life opportunities.
And there is probably something that has become more and more relevant over the years.
And Karin Boye still inspires contemporary writers and poets-
-When Athena Farrokhzad, who named her latest book after the poem "In Motion".
In the beginning when I met her I probably considered her like this-
-Reding, existential, tormented the poet.
But as I got older, I realized that she addressed urgent questions-
-Not only the existential, without political circumstances in the contemporary.
The years before Karin dies, it seems that she is in balance.
But an unanswered love gets in the way.
In despair she ends up in old habits.
She had a pattern throughout her life with staged suicide attempts-
-The time arranged so she could manage, be found, be saved.
But this April night in 1941 no one sees she leaving the house-
-and no one who can save her.
Her life gets a dramatic and abrupt end.
The suicide was a mistake, a classic cry for help that failed.
This life force has been lost.
It is important to come back to this living Karin Boye.
Yes, it hurts when buds are lacking.
Why else would spring hesitate?
Why would all our hot longing be tied in the frozen bitter pale?
After all, the casing was the bud all winter.
Texting: Elin CSisar www.btistudios.com