Okay, Edwin, we'll pick you up when you're done at the Social Media Agency.
Perfect Beautiful Amazing Digital Media AB? They are fantastic.
-Oh thank you! Thanks! -Absolutely.
What do they want you to do?
I'll just be my amazing self.
They have been very clear.
They are impressed with how natural the fab I am.
What are you going to do then?
A commercial collaboration? Should you say things for money?
Probably, but is it not wrong to make some money?
No, but it may be good if your followers know if you tip about something-
-Sore you like it or because you get money for it.
If you want to be a free voice-
-Is it important that there is a limit when you are-
-And when you get paid to say something.
We talk a little about the role of money in the modern media landscape.
-Sure, but late. Now I have to go. -Okay! Call if you need anything.
Ah okay.
They don't seem to have it olyxis.
It was something completely different from the old news editor.
It has not been so good for the news magazines lately.
Otherwise it used to be, Åsa!
Then the newspapers were so lonely about the advertising money.
If the shoe store in Flen wanted to put in an ad they had no other choice-
-An to do it in the local news magazine.
People subscribed to the newspaper for they wanted to know what happened-
-And then they saw the ads.
You? I didn't know that T-liquor was good for so much.
Today when companies want to advertise ... My God, what there are competitors!
There are social media companies, search engines, influencers.
And damn and his aunt, my God ...
The money that went to do journalism-
-and to make media owners happy now go largely to large tech companies-
-When Facebook or Google.
It's Edwin. - Hello Hello! Do you already miss us?
Nah. They think I'm a superstar and want to make a sponsorship collaboration-
-So I need help with some questions.
Sponsor, you say. Mm ...
We just talked about the declining numbers for old newspapers-
-Sitizing new rising tech companies.
There are social media profiles that flourish at the expense of old media.
There is reason to talk about it, the old and the new world.
Do not worry. I bring you into the new world. You become my advisors.
-Hurray. -So it is not enough for you?
Are you too nice to be advertising -financed?
No, almost all media is commercial.
It has been journalists for a long time.
With the exception of public service, SVT, SR, UR-
-As paid with tax money, not through business.
-There the state controls the content. -No! It does the editors!
As on all media it is the responsible publisher-
-which is a special role on an editorial ...
It can be sentenced to prison for what is published.
That person is often quite nippy that everything is getting right.
But in the media houses, someone sits on the money and it decides well?
Well, it determines some things, but not over the content.
Then there are in the new world a couple of new kinds of media owners-
-What do not understand that journalists must be independent of the owners.
It has stormed some around the news site Bulletin.
They have not respected editorial integrity.
They have exerted pressure on the responsible publisher.
It was intended as some kind of new, large newspaper project.
Sweden's New York Times. Known opinion writers had been recruited.
Then it passed three months, and then the world's conflict arose-
-And many of the famous writers pulled. They had had enough!
The conflict was between the editorial staff and the owner.
The owners may not agree, but the conflict was nevertheless.
I have to go back now.
Can you notice if something is sneaky advertising on social media?
Yes, if they write that, often recurring: "Test this!"
"I got this home, and that's the best I've tested!"
It is difficult if it is a sneak advertising because you should not notice.
You can watch a video and so have someone set up nocco bottles or something-
-Giantfint in the background. They say nothing, but you see it.
Or that they have a sweater on and you see adidas. After all, it is visible.
That they talk about their own companies without saying that it is advertising.
Subscriptions and advertising is not the only way-
-Financing journalism. They can make money through Swish.
Via Patreon, that you get money directly from your readers.
It is made by podcasts, game makers, so why not journalism?
-It gets just as good for that. -The risk is in itself ...
When you get money for each individual job, the risk is that you just do job-
-As you know that readers react to when it is linked to the money.
This also plays a role in the fake world.
I interviewed a guy who had a fake page.
I asked why there were so many stories about immigration.
He said it gave him traffic. Angry clicks provide traffic.
People get into the page where he has ads and it gives him money.
That "clickbaita" is something that is done on the entire board.
This is done by serious media in the same way as on the fake sites.
Oh, it's Edwin! - Hello Hello! How is it going?
It's going superb! We talk about agreements and sponsors, but ...
Are there any rules? I have some vague memory of talking about it.
Absolutely. This is how it says in the rules of the game for journalists:
"Make sure that journalism and advertising cannot be mixed together."
-No you should not receive gifts. -Just. This applies to journalists.
One should not receive gifts, presents or other-
-"which makes it possible to question one's role"-
-"As a standalone, independent, independent journalist".
There must be examples of journalists who have done so. Or?
Yes. So it is, unfortunately.
But I'm not a journalist. It's a heavenly talk about journalists!
No, but you want credibility to your readers, followers, viewers?
If you are going to advertise, you will have to mark it out clearly.
The Consumer Agency did some review of fifty influencers in the area-
-And found some flaws.
Views are protected by freedom of expression-
-But if you advertise, the Marketing Act applies.
Then you need to clearly mark your post marketing something.
Okay! I say "in collaboration with" ...
And remember that "in collaboration with" does not act as advertising marking.
Ah! What should I say then?
You can send a signal and hear with them at the Consumer Agency directly.
Yes!
My name is Charlotte Söderlund and I work as a lawyer at the Consumer Agency.
One can mark up posts in social media-
-for example. By using an explicit marking-
-If the post contains advertising, and that you place the marking-
-Clear and prominent. It is also important to remember-
-The social media channels can both contain personal opinions-
-and advertising. Personal views are protected by freedom of expression-
-But it doesn't advertise. As a follower one should be able to choose-
-Do not continue reading a post containing advertising-
-To advertising basically has a purpose to influence us.
We have conducted a review of some fifty influencers posts.
We have seen that there is a great risk that there is post-
-Which contains hidden marketing, which is not allowed.
Several of the posts have sometimes had a advertising marker-
-But the marking has not proven to be sufficient.
It may have been too small or hidden.
The important thing in an advertising marking is that it becomes clear to followers-
-Th the influencer has been paid to publish the post-
-And the advertising marking is clearly visible. It is e.g. not enough-
-To use the advertising marking "in collaboration with".
The Court has considered it not to say in a sufficiently clear way-
-That the influencer has been paid.
In the past, advertising was a little more straight.
For the teeth well, you should buy pepsodent
-No remember ... -Pepsodent!
Right?
Thanks, Sture. And thank you, please Marabou ...
... for the new milk chocolate.
Nowadays it is a little more mixed forms, if you say so.
Suddenly an ad looks like an article on a news site-
-or so you have put in something there-
-To look like the editorial staff has written it.
"Native Advertising, Advertorials, Branded Content ..."
There are a lot of English expressions in this world.
It is in different ways advertising, and not independent journalism.
It should look like journalism because people are so tired of advertising-
-So that they instead make it look like journalism.
Therefore, maybe everyone does not print this so superbly.
But you must not do so. Hidden marketing is prohibited.
It should be clear to readers and viewers that it is advertising.
Some influencers have gone there. Most recently Therése Lindgren-
-With a million followers on Instagram.
She was convicted that she had not clearly noticed enough that it was advertising.
In the new media landscape of influencers and youtubers, etc.-
-To some advertising that risks being addressed to people who are unauthorized.
Surely it was a pretty big campaign for that just recently?
17 consumer organizations in Europe have written a report-
-To show several examples that there is hidden advertising in the app.
In France, laws have been enacted around influencers.
As of April, French influencers risks up to five years in prison
-If they use their children for financial purposes on social media.
There has been a discussion about that in Sweden as well.
How is it okay to show pictures of their children in social media?
Me and the pearl - Alex, my husband - we have discussed-
-and have come to the conclusion that we do not want our son Elvis-
-Do join our social media anymore.
Some are actively trying to become influencers too-
— because of getting up to a follow-up that makes them current-
-For "sponsored collaborations", etc., and they scares no means.
On Facebook and Instagram there have been large "shark groups"-
-Where you have boosted each other with followers. They have said:
"Here's my account. Follow me!" And so they have been laid and followed.
Then you have, like divided everyone's followers into a large pot.
It's not exactly the same thing as someone shows genuine interest-
-Alt if there are real people who have pressed the Like button.
No, exactly. Advertisers who want to cooperate with influencers-
-As interested in REACH which is authentic, for real.
They want to reach out to real people. They may not be completely satisfied-
-If it's some kind of divided shock.
Now then? Hello!
-Otherwise, we're ready. I'm safe! -Oh really? Oh, congratulations!
-We drive away and pick you up, then. -Okay!
When we talk about Källkoll it is important to know-
-If a message is genuine or not.
In some cases, the sender is simply not independent.
It can be about money.
Editorial integrity is important. There are rules for journalists-
-To their independence cannot be questioned.
In the rules of the game for press, radio and television, there are rules against text advertising:
Something that looks to come from the editor-
-But really is a message that someone has paid for.
In social media it is difficult to determine-
-What are sponsored messages and not.
But the rules are clear: one must not be fooled in advertising-
-And you must not be fooled about who is behind the advertising.