When you listen to music-
-Tare your heart rhythm to the pace of music.
The music can touch in the same way that the human hand can touch us.
Scientists try to understand how music affects our body and brain-
-To improve our health.
My name is Eva Bojner Horwitz-
-And I work here as a professor of music and health.
At the Royal Academy of Music, the research team collaborates with Karolinska-
-to understand how the music affects us-
-And what benefit the music plays.
We are interested in the effects of the music.
We want to understand how to buffer against different types of stress reactions-
-But also see what we can strengthen.
How is the body affected by different genres, tempo, rhythm, pulse?
What the researchers have been able to show through various experiments-
-Is that the body and brain are like a tuning fork.
The music not only puts our emotions rocking.
It also triggers a number of biological reactions in the body.
Pulse, respiratory rate, hormones ...
Even the bowel movements are affected.
It is very interesting with these study-
-Where we see that after operational procedures, at the awakening ...
The patients who have been allowed to choose which music they want to wake up to-
-can get an increased activity of oxytocin, a calm and ro-rush-
-Imme with those patients who have not been listened to music.
Music can calm but also stimulate blood circulation.
Good for avoiding complications during surgery.
It stimulates the brain at e.g. Dementia and stroke.
When the music meets ear-
-and reaching the brain's sorting center, thalamus-
-There the signals go two roads.
The first one quickly goes down to the reaction part, amygdala.
That part of the brain belongs to the limbic system.
It is usually called the emotional brain.
Amygdala controls the autonomic nervous system.
Music can raise pulse and alertness and set the body to activity-
-Or so the music can send signals that lower heart rate and heartbeat.
Signals that have been found early in human development.
In the cave we need to pay attention to life -threatening sounds.
But also the fire, the heat, the touch that creates peace and quiet.
The second way goes slow-
-And leads up to the cerebral cortex and frontal lobe.
There, the music is interpreted by reason.
The music is linked to memories and deeper feelings.
Here the reward system may activate-
-We signal substances such as dopamine that give strong, positive emotions.
And oxytocin that provides calm and quiet feelings.
This is intricate.
There is no music that everyone responds to, the same way.
The impact of music can give many kinds of physical reactions.
The researchers have just begun to understand the mechanisms behind the influence of music.
Next step: Map how the music can be used to diagnose health.
What is exciting is that our bodies give us pre-signals.
There are orchestras in our bodies that we can tone to, read ...
We might be able to read warning signals on stress much earlier-
-Do that we train ourselves in music listening.
Swedish texture: Petra Vancea Iyuno for UR