Sweden's history between the 16th and 19th centuries is divided into four eras.
This is the third - the time of freedom.
During the time of freedom, one goes from a system where the king determines-
-To a system where more people can participate, and more and more people want to participate.
During the time of freedom, Sweden takes a few stacked steps towards democracy.
It is usually counted from Karl XII's death to Gustav III's coup.
What happened during the time of freedom?
What was it like to live during the 18th century when more people get something to say about?
To understand the time of freedom, we must understand what it was like before it started.
The first decades of the 18th century, the last part of the Great Power Time ...
There are few occasions when it has been worse to live in Sweden.
During the great power, Sweden grew, but now most is lost.
The country is poor, and a large part of the population has died in war.
Karl XII has been shot in Norway.
He could not get married and have some children who could inherit the throne.
It has been plague and famine.
Ever since the Middle Ages, Sweden has been ruled by powerful kings
-But now many want a change.
Weaving war after war does not maintain the country.
Time for New Times. And how do you get it with a new form of government?
The time of freedom begins with the new form of government in January 1719.
Karl XII died just two months before.
It was planned for this, so when the king dies, the plans are put into action.
A form of government is more exciting than it sounds, because the balance of power changes.
The monarchy is abolished and Sweden will now be governed by the Council and the Riksdag.
But was there no royal descendant that protested?
When Karl XII died, there were two options:
Ulrika Eleonora and Karl Fredrik.
The succession question was not decided-
-So it was now about which player would be the fastest on the ball.
The fastest is the acid Ulrika Eleonora.
Although she did not want to rule with limited power.
The National Council persuades her that it looks better out-
-If Parliament chooses her.
Then there will be no trouble about the throne.
Ulrika Eleonora agrees to this, but the first parliament says is:
We must have a new form of government that she has to relate to.
She is in a form of hostage situation and can only accept it.
We still have her copy of the form of government with notes.
She never accepted this reconciled position.
But despite the queen's sour notes, the time of freedom can begin.
During the time of freedom, we did not say "now we live in the time of freedom".
On the other hand, it was said that you lived in the freest constitution.
People were satisfied and said it could not have been better written by angels.
It was illegal to talk badly about the new form of government.
It is now super-famous Voltaire describes Sweden, little Sweden-
-like the freest country in the world.
The one who stood back for the country to be free - Ulrika Eleonora-
-Sit only one year on the throne.
Next to him, the queen has a man, her husband, Fredrik of Essen.
Here, they both keep on the helm as a parable of controlling Sweden.
After all, Fredriks and Ulrika Eleonora's plan was that they would cooperate.
However, this does not agree with this, and the Queen chooses to abdicate.
Fredrik becomes Fredrik I.
It is during his reign that royal name stamps are introduced.
There are stamps with the king's signature.
Documents can be signed by the king without being present.
The stamp has sometimes been seen as a metaphor for the entire freedom time.
The stamps are highlighted as symbols of how weak royal power has been.
But you needed the king's signature.
We say the kings were weak and powerless at that time.
But we compare with previous kings.
It is undoubtedly that they are the most powerful politicians at that time.
This is another of the most powerful politicians - Arvid Horn.
He is the office president-
-And leads the work of the Council, the government of the time, which now governs the country.
He wanted the kingdom to be restored.
Without war, one would rebuild the kingdom and gain financial stability.
Sweden is starting to be led as a more democratic country.
Two political groups are emerging after headgear.
The hats and hats were the origin of what then becomes parties.
You can see them as two networks that mobilized for different polls.
Who was a bit unclear.
-How do the dawn democracy look like? -Riksdag was a state of the stand.
So it was priests, citizens, farmers and nobility who had their own parliament.
Every stand has a vote, but it's not so democratic.
Many belong to no stand-
-And the stands represent different part of the population.
Each stand had its own room.
Delegations of noblemen went to the priests and shared them their decisions.
"Thanks so much," says the priests, and then they do the same in turn.
But outside these premises, people often stood waiting.
Where the farmer met, there was a staircase that was often full of people.
They stood listening to the decisions that were made.
The 18th century day is quite messy. People are loud and sometimes unsuccessful.
Parliamentary representatives receive no salary, but may support themselves elsewhere.
Corruption was quite common.
That you received bribes or that you embezzled money from the Treasury.
It is easy to keep track of who is who in the Swedish position society.
They sit in different buildings.
But outside it becomes increasingly trickier.
It was important for everyone how to stand in the social hierarchy.
If you are out walking in any city in the country-
-Is it important to be able to read if you or someone else should step away.
Is based on the social hierarchy of society in that you were born in a certain stance-
-If it is possible to read which it is.
But also what position you have within that position. Preferably on hold.
During the time of freedom, it becomes more difficult as people start to be able to buy new things.
Some groups begin to make more money and the availability of cheap goods is increasing.
For example, cotton fabrics with prints that look fine without being expensive.
It is perceived as something problematic that can turn to the social order.
It is seen as dangerous that the lower stands dress like something they are not.
In order not to be chaos, the social hierarchy must be regulated by law.
It will be abundance regulations-
-which regulates who is allowed to use what types of goods.
To keep on the hierarchies, but also to promote Swedish goods.
If you are born in the peasantry, you must not by law carry silk.
People can be mistaken for your stand.
Citizens can be fined if they carry a guard. Only the nobility must do that.
You are not allowed to dress over your stand.
Those who are at the bottom of the hierarchy come to trial for such crimes.
Especially maids. And the fine is soaring.
Social mobility does not exist in the Swedish Sweden's Sweden-
-But the country has begun to scratch from the chaos in the early 18th century.
Sweden has a popular form of government, a dawn democracy
-And has not been fought for a long time.
Surely that is the top? No, the hats dream of revenge in Russia.
The lead leader Arvid Horn is dismissed, and Sweden is attacking Russia.
Now the country will be restored, but it will be a real failure.
The war lasts for two years, Sweden wins nothing, and Russia takes Finland.
To get it back, Sweden must agree on concessions.
At this time, Ulrika Eleonora has died childless.
Sweden had no follower.
The Russian Empress said that if one chose her relative Adolf Fredrik-
-Ad it improve the terms of peace.
Russia wants an ally on the throne. It annoys the valley farmers.
They start carpentry together things that are not only used for agriculture.
Here we have a nail club - a fairly simple weapon.
But it is, nonetheless, deadly.
The special thing about the weapon is that it is probably one of the 1084 bar weapons-
-Whith was seized from Dalalmogen when they traveled down to Stockholm-
-In what is called the Great Dald dance.
During the time of freedom, as it should be possible for the votes of the people to hear-
-SKs the Great Daldans, also called the Dalreworking, 1743.
Fifth-thousand ripped down guards wander to the capital-
-To "jerk the wig" by the gentlemen in Stockholm.
They are upset over the expensive, unnecessary war, trade restrictions-
-And Russia's involvement in the choice of throne followers.
They train all the way to Stockholm.
But it will mostly be a tumult
-White ends with dead fellows and over 3,000 captured rebellioners.
When Fredrik dies, Adolf takes over Fredrik the throne, to the dismay of the Dalkarls.
The king's wife is called Lovisa Ulrika.
That she was something to count on synthesis early.
Here is a small gold box.
If you open it, you can see an object that looks like a weight paper.
It is Lovisa Ulrika's fetal membrane, that is, victory hood as it is called.
Previously, it was considered a sign of future happiness.
It was thought that the princess could carry this as a bracelet.
Sweden's "Power Couple" is not satisfied with its back position.
In order to strengthen their power, they decide to implement a coup d'état.
The coup attempt was not well thought out.
The king gets sick, and the whole thing is revealed early.
They arrest the insurgents, and they are executed before the eyes of the royal couple.
Lovisa Ulrika's foster membrane did not work as a happiness amulet at that time.
Sweden is at the forefront when it comes to art, culture and science.
A science academy is formed, and an early industrialization occurs.
Sweden hooks on the colonization trends that exist among the countries in Europe.
Through the East India Company we get a trading route all the way to China.
Life for ordinary people is slowly improving.
For example, parishes begin to take care of their poor.
But on a level it does not happen much.
People are quite free, at least when it comes to religion.
Religion is central to people's lives.
It is the one that explains and legitimizes the entire position society.
Now a house interview, a kind of religious hearing, is held by the priest.
When it comes to house interviews, they have several functions.
The church is a propaganda apparatus through which the state can get its message out.
The second is like the gossip center.
The church keeps track of who people lie with, are married to and have children with.
The third function is like school. At a house interview, a priest goes home to people.
You interrogate the family and the service people in Luther's little catechism.
You should know what is right and wrong.
This leads to people becoming more literate than in many other places.
Then it is fun if people can read what they want.
They know when Sweden introduces the world's first freedom of the press.
The Freedom of Pressure Regulation comes in 1766, and what you must not write about is:
One must not criticize the royal power, the religion or the form of government.
Otherwise, you have to debate and write anything.
It is extensively debated. The hats and hats are often on a collision course.
The notifications of election fraud are many.
In the midst of all this, Adolf Fredrik dies.
It has often been claimed that he ate to death on bran.
The meal consisted of, among other things, bran, which was a kind of wheat bread.
But he ate too much and had a heart attack.
It had nothing to do with the bran.
Adolf Fredrik's son Gustav III crowned.
He is the first heir to the throne born in Sweden for a long time.
His father and Fredrik I came to Sweden as adults.
Gustav III tries to create order in the Swedish Parliament-
-But now the election fraud beats the ceiling.
In the election 1771, then we arrive at the last parliamentary period of freedom
-Had it was hard to agree on who would be allowed to vote in the presidential election.
In the bourgeoisie, this speech valet-
-So pass that there was a blood white.
They were struck at the ballot box about who would stop in banknotes and not.
Corruption, electoral fraud and fights inside the Riksdag.
In this chaos, Gustav III sees an opportunity to take back power.
He plans a coup d'état, and he doesn't get sick as his father.
The coup is also better planned.
In August 1772 he succeeds with the help of officers locking in government-
-And force them to agree to a new form of government that gives the king power.
Gustav III's coup effectively ends the time of freedom.
We are back where we started, with a strong royal power and a weak parliament.
You have seen in different ways in freedom.
It is either the freest period Sweden had.
Others say this was the most corrupt time in Swedish history.
This is also Finland's history, since the country was then part of the kingdom.
Several hundred years later, in 1936, Finland praises a person from the time of freedom.
A politician who was born in Finland.
Finland was now free from Russia-
-and there was wear and tear between citizens and communists-
-S and a constant threat from Russia.
Here is a Finnish stamp where you have portrayed Arvid Horn.
To choose this compromise, peace-loving Arvid Horn-
— on the stamp
-Is both to point out that we should be able to agree in the country-
-But also to go back to the fact that we have been part of Sweden.
We may be able to get support in Sweden if Russia will attack us.
Which they do three years later.
Although Gustav III turns back very-
-There is something that is gaining momentum that exists today - democracy.
Even though few were allowed to vote, that the election fraud has never been so great-
-and that people were locked up in a predetermined stance-
-found an ambition to let the people decide.
We not only see that more people are allowed to join, but that more people want to join.
There you see that it is a movement that is starting to move forward.
Swedish Setting: Elin Dahlqvist Iyuno-Di Group for UR