Blue owl explains the world to you.
Review - Ethics and Morality - What is Ethics and Morality?
What will you learn? In this short and simple review you will find out the following:
What ethics is for something.
You will learn the difference between ethics and morals.
You will find out what ethics are used for.
As well as learn names on some ethical models.
What does ethics mean?
The word ethics comes from the beginning from Greek.
Ethics means about: "custom" or "habit".
Ethics is about what is right and wrong.
Ethics is used in philosophy. It's a way of thinking.
Ethics is also used in religious science, ie research on religion.
What is the difference between ethics and morals?
Simply explained, you can say that morality is the same as action, ie what you do.
Simply explained, you can say that ethics are the same as one's thoughts on what is right and wrong.
Thinking about what is right and wrong is ethics.
When you do something that can be perceived as right or wrong, it is morality.
A person's morality can come from the person's ethics. But since we are human beings, we are not always well thought out.
We are very much controlled by emotions. Therefore, there can be a big difference between what a person considers to be right and wrong and what it actually does.
Sometimes the words ethics and morality are used as synonyms. It is not really, but some mix the concepts.
You may try to keep track of yourself, but be prepared that everyone does not have as good control as you.
What do religion and ethics have to do with each other?
All religions have elements of ethics.
There are thoughts in religions about what is considered right and wrong.
Some people interpret that it is God who determines ethics, ie what is right and wrong.
Other people interpret that it is man who decides on ethics.
Why is there ethics?
Ethics exists to be able to think systematically about right and wrong.
You should have a system to think.
A method is used.
In philosophy, systematic thoughts about right and errors are called ethical model.
We will pick up some ethical models soon.
You can use ethics for thought experiments and think about how to act in different situations.
You can then try different solutions and more easily understand the different choices you can make.
You can also show various problems that can arise as a result of one's choice.
Examples of the most common ethical models.
If you want to know more, there are reviews that explain each model for themselves. See the description for links.
Consequence ethics that deal with the consequences of an action.
Duties that are about what duty thus obligation you have to act.
Sensory law ethics that deal with what intention one had with their actions.
Grave ethics that are about what characteristics you have.
No man uses only one ethic model in his everyday life.
In an everyday situation, it is common for us to argue if it argues based on the different models
Although we are not aware of what they are called.
It is common for arguments for the same action from different models.
It may also be that in some situations you use more arguments from a single model.
Thank you for looking at the clip. I hope you learned something new.
If you have it, don't forget to press like.
You can also subscribe to find out when new clips will come.
Or look at one of the other clips that are available so you learn something more.
Thank you for choosing to watch. Bye!