[Music]
Katarina Bjelke, Director General of the Swedish Research Council 3 00: 00: 11,000 -> 00: 00: 10,114 [what contributes to high quality in research?]
We see that more long -term support for high quality research means that the researchers dare to invest / think new and take risks.
This, in turn, increases the opportunities to make groundbreaking discoveries, and contributes to the knowledge base needed to meet the major societal challenges.
Of course, there are other things that strengthen the quality of research.
For example, it is assessed in competition, international cooperation, gender equality and that researchers collaborate with relevant groups in society.
[How can Sweden become better at attracting, recruiting and retaining prominent researchers?]
Sweden we need to be better at creating research environments that maintain high international quality.
These strong environments \ hkan attract the foremost researchers, both from Sweden and other countries, who want to pursue research and make a career.
If we are to be able to recruit and maintain the foremost researchers, attractive career paths and attractive employment conditions are required.
Postgraduate education is also important to invest in, both for research development and renewal and for the provision of skills not only within the academy but in society in general. 13 00: 01: 44,000 -> 00: 00: 47,900 [how can we ensure long -term prioritization and financing of research infrastructure?]
We need to develop a better model for how we manage the priority and financing of research infrastructure in the long term.
Sweden needs to increase the exchange of the investments we make in the major international research infrastructures where we are a member,-
As ESS and CERN, for example by using more researchers using them or that we are given the opportunity to contribute to the technological development of them.
Increased costs for membership in international research infrastructures must not be made at the expense of our national infrastructure.
[How can we promote the freedom of research, a good research culture and strengthen confidence in research?]
Academic freedom and that there is a strong confidence in research is crucial to a democratic and strong society.
Here, a good research culture is basic, with a living discussion on ethical issues - it also strengthens the quality of research.
In this context, it is also important that there are good conditions to be able to reach out with scientific knowledge.
A world that rests on scientific knowledge is a wiser world.