[Footsteps]
Hi Sten, it’s the Swedish Research Council.
We’d like to come inside and chat a bit about your research.
[Local politics]
The interesting thing about local politics
is that it’s about people making
their local authority their own.
Where you start figuring out:
“OK, what shall we do about our society?”
We can’t wait for the government to do things
or for aid agencies to give us things.
We must solve these problems.
And that’s an important part.
[Sten Hagberg does research into local politics]
In this way, I find it interesting to see how politics becomes real for everyday people.
That is: healthcare, other care and schools.
What we often talk about in Swedish election debates.
On the whole, it’s the same type of
basic needs that citizens have
that are brought up in local politics.
[But if politics isn’t delivering?]
There’s a long tradition of
rising up against power.
When power goes too far.
In Burkina Faso in 2014,
the president wanted to manipulate the constitution
and stay in power for life, more or less.
And then, the first ones to rise up and
really take over, were the women.
A group of between five and ten thousand women
went out demonstrating with spatulas and brooms.
The “spatula uprising” or “la Marche des Spatules”
it was called.
They went out, shouting “Dégage Blaise! Dégage!"
Or “Remove from power! Go away!”
And that’s what is so interesting.
That in this power, you often talk
about the “angry young men”.
You often talk about these violent risings.
But in actual fact, we are seeing women’s ability to organise themselves – and of course also men
organising – in the determined organisational work.
That is a key that we often ignore.
[Are popular risings part of democracy?]
Popular risings are part of democratisation processes.
Or can be, we should perhaps say.
Therefore they also become a means; that when people
see that they cannot have influence in any other way.
So it is very positive when people mobilise themselves.
In Burkina, as from this mobilisation, they have always avoided violence,
avoided attacking people
and those in power in this way.
And that is very important.
That means it’s civil disobedience. They are peaceful demonstrations.
So they are definitely part of the democratic process.
[What is needed for local politics to be successful?]
One factor is very important with the local processes in Burkina Faso and other countries.
That is that people organise themselves.
They organise themselves in civil society and in organisations, in political parties, and in various ways.
That is, they organise themselves to create change.
These organisations, they don’t primarily follow religious or ethnic lines.
Instead, they are organised around an issue, a problem.
And this might be a development organisation in the
municipality, or something.
This is an important process, because you are not creating a “them” and an “us” in this type of organisation.
And this, in turn, leads to something of a paradox.
Those rather dry-as-dust municipal council meetings that I think most of us associate with,
those sub-committees and boards and whatever that we think of when we hear the words
“local politics”. They are, after all, the very core of democracy.
This is where we create the opportunities to live together. They are where the decisions are made
that can lead to us improving our society.
[Uppsala]