- Today we're gonna have a boat day, Mickis!
- Yeah, how sweet?
- Really nice, the current weather is so hot.
- Who shouted?
- You've learned to pronounce "R".
- Say "R".
- Rrr.
- King!
- You're so good.
- Today we're gonna hang on a boat with Emelie, Johan and Stella.
- Let's see if they're home.
- Emelie and Johan have renovated the house.
- Let's go inside to see how far they've come.
- Let's go in and take a look.
- You don't have to get awkward, Johan, damn it.
- Now we're ready. We've got a little tour, but will come back here and record when it's all done.
- Here you get a preview, oh my god.
- Above it all, Mickis, the conservatory!
- I love this.
- Magical.
- Hey Stella.
- Hey, what's happening?
- It's time to go to the boat.
- Captain Mickis, are you gonna steer the boat?
- If I'm allowed.
- "Give me!"
- When did you start to speak English?
- You're doing this so damn good.
- It was nothing!
- Really fine!
- Well, it looks good.
- Yes, I think so too.
- And how you drove through the channels!
- I had a good flow today. I could feel it from the beginning.
- Are you full and satisfied?
- Life, and a glas of rose wine, later on.
- Mickis, we have to get a boat!
- Yes, we have to!
- The thing is that I'd like a big boat.
- Let's sell the house.
- This is life. Days like this make me so happy. Don't you think so?
- Yes. I think so too. It's the calmness.
-  The calmness.
- For me who comes from Tärnaby, this is sort of the same. Like when you're up in the mountains out in the nature.
- Really? I love that as well. I'm getting flashbacks from when I rode boats all summer.
- It's amazing. We have to get a boat. But as said, then I'd like a big one, which we absolutely can't afford.
- And none of us can drive it either.
- Anyway, the situation is a bit stressed, I'm going back to meet Anderstam and Sverre.
- Yes, we've got some problems.
- Not so much problems, but we have to redo some drawings, so they can make some new measurements...
...to also make sure that the transfer from Rafald to Sverre will be correct.
- But first we're about to go out and sunbathing. Then you can go home and work with the house.
- I might get one more glass of rose wine.
- Really!
- I got some feeling. It's nice weather and still feels like vacation. Don't you agree?
- I agree to a 100%!
- Are you gonna drive later on?
- Yes!
- Alright!
- Now it's time to swim.
- Now it's time to swim, and to just embrace this, all the way back.
- Sometimes it's nice to just check out from life. That's what I'm feeling.
...to live some, before you get back to reality.
- Here we have the boat.
- Their boat is a perfect sized one.
- And Johan and Emelie are also perfect. They are awesome.
- You are perfect.
- You are!
- This part of the vlog is in collaboration with Once Upon.
- So let's start of with sharing our code, we've got for you.
- It's "MICHAELAJENS25" and will give you a 25% discount.
- You know how addicted I am to this app.
- Well, it can be a bit scary sometimes when you use it for such a long time.
- Yes I know, but it's so fun. You can really do your own photo books...
...where you can add your text beside the picture, or under the picture, and make your own story.
- I've been writing the books for our children in first person.
- It's pretty fun, to write down "Here is when I lost my first tooth", and so on.
- And now I've done a new book from this summer. Summer 2022.
- Before I start off showing the book, I'll show how easy it is to use the app.
- Here we have all my books collected.
- Here we enter the book, my most recent book.
- Here.
- And all books will be saved here. If I something happens with the book I've ordered, I can order it again.
- So, here we have all pictures. It's really simple to add.
- I can choose the layout all by myself, as well as adding a text on the side.
- And then you'll get a finished book sent home. And the delivery is really quick.
- And the book will come like this, but you can choose format. If you prefer softer book, or a hard book...
...and I've chosen a hard book with matte silk paper, so it feels luxurious, and this is our result.
- The pictures are getting so good, and I think the quality is awesome.
- And it's really fun to have as a memory.
- Fine, most people have all pictures on their phone or computer, but it's really nice to have it in a physical shape as well.
- It's fun to watch, and also something you can have in the house for visitors to look at.
- And I'm making books on the children each of every year. It's so worth it.
- It's fun with photo albums.
- I'm happy you're doing this.
- Yes me too, I've talked about this for such a long time. As soon as you start, you realize how easy it is.
- You just add the pictures. They will come in order from when you took the picture.
- It makes it easy to find pictures from every month.
- Especially when you're doing a book like this, and might want to follow the pictures from July to August...
...which is created automatically, even though you can choose which order you'd like.
- Anyway, the chronological makes it easier.
- Awesome! And remember, if you don't have a picture, it did never happen.
- Exactly!
- For example: the snake bite. It's something to remember.
- Palma!
- I'm looking forward to make more books. I've started to make our "House book", as I've showed earlier.
- What's really great about Once Upon, is that you can start, and then add material until it's done.
- Easy and good.
- Now we will get a bunch of these books at home. How fun?
- Awesome, Mickis!
- Alright, so don't forget the code: "MICHAELAJENS25" to get a 25% discount.
- It's valid for a week, from today.
- Who wants to join me?
- Who's with me? Are all kids gonna join?
- They are so cowardly and wants Jens to be in the water when the enter, just like me. I hate to jump in by myself.
- Let's go!
- What's your reaction?
- Oh no I lost my swimming trunks, they're gone.
- I just jumped.
- Watch out, Valle!
- "Laddel".
- That was nice. Now it's your turn, Mickis!
- No!
- First swim of the year?
- Have I been bathing some? Yes, once.
- So you will get in?
- We have to record this.
- Can I push you?
- No, you can not. Then we're getting divorced. 100%!
- So you really want to get a divorce?!
- Mickis is about to go into the water, so you have to move a bit.
- The old lady is about to go into the water.
- If no ones laughing there is no one in the neighbourhood.
- The old lady is half way into the water.
- This is so cold. Why are we doing this?
- What's nice with it?
- It's the feeling you get afterwards.That's the whole point.
- Nice!
- Wooho!
- Don't hang there!
- Stella, get off me.
- This will end up with me drowning you.
- Hanging on Stella.
- I won't dive in, I'll jump.
- No, dive!
- It's fun if I'll end up doing a belly flop.
- Go mom, go!
- How do I even dive?
- Come on, it's like riding a bike.
- You're awesome!
- The lactic acid is all over, right?
- You know, my distances were like, 200 meters, 100 meters.
- For how long period did you swim?
- A long time.
- Her name is Mickan.
- How's it going, Valle?
- Jump up here, behind me.
- Turn in that direction.
- A bit more. Even more, so you'll come up straight.
- Happy.
- A really happy guy.
- Emelie, this day has been so good.
- Yes, fantastic!
- A big thank's for this day!
- Yes, indeed. What a day!
- We're just gonna finish.
- Why are you filming when we're away?Are you gonna publish this or what?
- Maybe we will!
- This is not gonna give you money.
- This is 100% a Delér gene.
- And I'll be like:
- I have so many videos on you dancing.
- What?
- Yes, a lot!
- From Palma?
- From everywhere, Mickis.
- Have you had a good day today?
- Fantastic!
- Indeed.
- Magical.
- Thank you for watching this episode. Next time we're back by the house.
- And by then we're hoping that the interior walls are up.
- Yeah, I really hope so.
- And maybe we can go trough what happened.
- Sure!
- I missed the meeting today.
- Yes, we should have been back by four o'clock, but it turned out differently.
- But it will be fine anyway.
- Sverre and Anderstam will solve it.
- It was worth it, because this way was magical. Fantastic!
- Indeed!
- Take care everybody!
- See you next week!
- Bye!