It started well with a general fascination for older buildings, old houses.
I went to a building maintenance training, ended up with a tile stove maker
And a little on that road it was.
My most common mission is to redo an existing stove.
"Setting" means to tear and wall.
A little nice, I think, to work with tiled stoves
It is probably partly the contrasts.
It's pretty heavy, dirty and tiring -
But it will be such an incredibly beautiful end product.
The tile stove itself can last for hundreds of years
Then you have to change it and replace the brick inside.
A life span between the turnover of between 30 and 100 years.
It depends terribly on how it is fired.
Glaze is extremely permanent, so the colors are the same since they were created.
I think such details are nice.
I think the tile stove professional will live on.
I don't see that it would change.
It is rather greater demand now than it has been a few decades.
People realize the value in having a heat source
That makes you basically independent of the outside world.
Once you have received in clay use in all joints
So you go on and mushrooms to it all.
Removes superfluous.
When I am going to join an oven, I start by scratching the joints from old joint
And I do that with a regular break knife, or some thin blade.
It is important that you do not break sideways, because then the glaze can danger.
Without pulling straight, along the joints.
The texture of the joint should be a little creamy.
Pretty firm, but not too hard.
Now I join this oven with a mixture of just chalk and water.
Realize about your oven is something that you can advantageously do yourself.
And how often one does it is entirely up to each
But preferably when the fire season is complete, you have a nice oven all summer -
And this fall.
So there, it was good.
The funniest little part is to be done with an oven.
Because it is so incredibly satisfying to see the pre -joined oven in front of it.
Take that last photo, and see how damn nice it was.
I like that very much.
To be done.