Gary G is back again to build some fat ass beats
'97 - 2023 forever king of the streets
Cruisin' round in something fat I threw together from scrap
With all my shooters finally out from the penitentiary
I don't fuck with EPA-dunk, smoke them like I smoke my skunk
Keep them inside of my trunk, mix some lean and take a sip
Got my plug Freddy Ferrick always by my side
Dealing scrap and dealing bars, my brother makes it shine
Me ang Gary G, we head home, roll up five
I'm the hood's Kanye West, and Mulle, Sweden's Eminem
Pull up with some shawties, it is sesh and conversation
But my opps better watch out or they will receive a grenade
Your pathetic life I'll make sure to delete
Cut your body parts and sell them on Tradera
Patrolling the hood with Mulle my homie
Darn it. Sasha is gone and got lost again.
When Gary rolls them, he rolls them really fat
Rollin out and roll along with Tramadol and Ketamine
Five-O pullin up, yeah they think that they are tough
Just they wait until they get to meet my boxer Bouncer
When Gary rolls them, he rolls them really fat
Got so many spare parts on my junkyard, gotta search it
Wallah shawty, come on here and shake that junk of yours
I never leave the house without an automatic rifle
I used to search for gadgets from the morning until dusk
Nowadays I'm in competition with Elon Musk
Started from the bottom, built my car and boat and house
You can call me "Mr. Pest Control" 'cuz I get so much pussy
Cruisin around with my clique and if I spot a cute chick, then I've always got a gimmick that can get her on my dick
Erm, drip check?
Blue bib overalls and black hat
"Looking Good" as we say in America
When Gary rolls them, he rolls them really fat
Got so many bitches that I got visit from PETA
The government wants me in prison for good
The ladies, they say: "nicely built, baller ride"
When Gary rolls them, he rolls them really fat
Always been a G ever since "Building Cars" left its BETA
If they're coming after you then start to fucking shoot
Gary Gadget will teach you to build AK47s
I got bands stacked to the ceiling, we're building capital
Got a new burner from Dana Digital
Mia Minardi is my Insta DMs
Hello Gary, don't you wanna come over to my place?
We take Adderall and Molly, mixing Xanax with coke
Injecting everything, every widget and thingamajig
Never worried on street, whatever I carry
With some of lean in the the doubly cup, we'll arrange a juice party
Whacked a fucking plug, but I don't feel no remorse
Chilling with a shorty up in Ferrous Field
The dirt road is too muddy, you need a better set of tires
Deal so much gasoline that you can call me OPEC
Sippin on a Norrlands Guld and you know we keep it lit
Or we'll build yet another gadget, and sip on that moonshine
Move however I want, I don't care about the odds
'Cuz you know I rep Djupforsen