The social anthropologist Edvard Westermarck
was one of the first scholars from
Finland who had an international career.
He became widely known for
his research on marriage,
morality and religion, at a time when there
was great interest in Darwinism and race theory.
During his career, Westermarck served as
professor in philosophy both at
University of Helsinki and
Åbo Akademi University in Turku, Finland.
He was appointed the first Rector
of the newly founded
Åbo Akademi University in 1918.
However, his impact and networks did not
evolve from this northern part of Europe only,
but also from northern Africa and
the United Kingdom.
He held the position of professor in
sociology at London School of Economics
and Politics for 24 years,
and lived and worked
in Morocco regularly for
more than half his life.
Professor Westermarck was a pioneer in the ways
in which he conducted his field research,
and he is said to have lacked the “colonial
attitude” of some of his fellow researchers.\h
Through his research, Westermarck influenced a
whole generation of scholars from around the world.
Many of his students became internationally
known social anthropologists.
His importance as a researcher, teacher,
and friend is evident through the documents
he left behind.
Westermarck rose to fame with the
publication of his first magnum opus
”The History of Human Marriage”, from 1891.\h
“The Origin and Development of
Moral Ideas” was published in 1906.
The manuscripts for both books are found
here at the Archive Collections at
Åbo Akademi University Library.
Welcome to the Åbo Akademi University Library
and the Archive Collections of Edvard Westermarck.
We are very proud to house them
since more than sixty years:
letters, manuscripts, pictures and more.
Westermarck kept the drafts of many of his
books, speeches and lectures,
and it seems that he was a bit of a perfectionist,
judging from all the corrections found in the text.
Westermarck also left a
collection of 7500 letters,
carefully catalogued here at
Åbo Akademi University Library.
His letter collection includes
correspondence with some of the
most renowned anthropologists of his time.
Westermarck’s collection of letters reveals the
vastness of the research network he created.
It also illuminates the development of
social anthropology of the time –
including some of the academic disputes.
The letter collection also includes a large number
of letters from friends and family in Finland,
including letters from his sister Helena
Westermarck who was a well-known writer,
artist, and women’s rights activist.
"Dear miss Dawson, thank you very much indeed
for your kind letters, and please forgive me
for not writing to you before.
When in Morocco, I lost at least a month by
having to revise the translation of my
“Memories” and have been struggling
hard to get my “Moorish Proverbs”
ready for the printers.
Yet I could not manage it during the busy
time in England, and am now on my way
back to Morocco, where I hope to complete
the revision of the typescript and
to read the proofs so that the book
can be published in the autumn.\h
I was very pleased with my seminars this year.
We discussed questions relating to the family,
marriage, and kindred subjects.
Malinowski read the first paper,
or rather gave the first address,
for he did it without any notes.
Baron Meyendorff spoke of the
Soviet law of marriage, and
other gentlemen of the Oedipus
complex and so on.
Last week I had seminars on two
days in succession, which ended with
a tea party for twenty persons.
I never had a more satisfactory
term at the school."
Edvard Westermarck’s large collection of photographs
contains some pictures of Westermarck in his
professional and home settings in both Finland and England,
but the majority of the pictures are from Morocco.
Photograpy was one of the main
methods Westermarck used by
in his extensive fieldwork in Morocco.
These pictures give an excellent presentation
of the conditions of field research in the late
19th and the early 20th century.
Westermarck focused his field research
on the customs and beliefs in Morocco,
and he wrote several books on the subject.
One of his main interests was “baraka”,
which is a concept of holiness.
In his fieldwork, Westermarck wanted to be
able to get his information directly from
his informants, and therefore he learnt
Arabic and also studied one of the
Amazigh dialects, Shilha or Tashelhit.
The notes from his language studies
are stored in the archives.
Westermarck had a longtime friend and
research assistant in Morocco
named Shereef Abdessalam el Bakkali.
El Bakkali helped him learn Arabic, and was also
his assistant in the field research.
In Westermarck’s absence, el Bakkali
took care of Westermarck’s beloved
Villa Tusculum outside Tangier.
As a unique feature, Westermarck’s archive
collection includes el Bakkali’s letters to Westermarck.
El Bakkali’s work helping
Westermarck map the local
traditions in Morocco earned him
the Order of the White Rose of Finland.
Westermarck was one of the key figures
behind the Pro Finlandia cultural petition
also known as the European Address in 1899.
His archives are also a source of
information about Finnish university history
from both Åbo Akademi University
and the University of Helsinki.
One of the folders contains Westermarck’s
documentation about the Åland islands dispute,
which was presented to the League of Nations in 1921.\h
He was also an avid defender of
women’s, children’s, and gay rights.
The significance of Westermarck’s research
for the development of moral theory and
social anthropology cannot be denied.\h
His personal as well as national history
helped shape him into
the researcher he was, and his
contributions to science
are of great value for researchers still today.
Through digitization we can greatly improve
the accessibility of this
outstanding collection across the globe.
We hope it will shed light on the histories
of Morocco, and of social anthropology
and also benefit researchers in linguistics,
philosophy and evolutionary psychology.