I'll be the last swimming guys, I'll be the last swimming.
I am back on my steel horse.
On the way to Head in Nacka.
There I will meet with Per, and Dennis who works there.
As well as my team when it comes to Swimrun, Lisa.
We drove Ötillö last fall together.
Yes what we are going to do is simply to test some costumes.
Tips for you to buy your first costume, but also check out some news for 2016.
May be good for those who want to supplement or update your equipment.
So, hang on
Hi, fun to see you.
The same.
Hello.
Well all good?
How are you
It is nice.
Nice
My name is Dennis and I work with PR and marketing for CBM products.
And CBM products have Head as a brand in the Nordic countries.
And so, of course, my heart lies in open water swimming and swimrun.
After all, we see a huge potential in an extremely fast growing sport.
Yes, there we have Limited Edition Ångalopp's pants.
Cool.
After all, they are made for a little warmer race like the Ångaloppet.
Yes.
But even considering that swimrun is growing so much in Europe,
And there will be new races in Spain, Italy, Greece, it is one in California, Australia.
Then you do not want to run in a full suit.
So then we have produced this, and it is just like the race costume.
It is 6 mm floating panel on.
You can combine with a linen, if you would like to.
And not run with bare torso or sports bra, or what you have under.
Well, welcome.
Thanks, Per.
Dennis
Oh, sponsors and stuff.
Limited Edition as well.
It is an honor to take on them here, I get them here
This is the new one.
After all, it is like a race at the top.
Yes.
But as a rough at the bottom.
Right.
Just to increase flexibility and that it is much easier to run in.
And it has no floating panels
After all, it has been in demand by many a faster costume.
Easier to run in, nothing unnecessary.
We have no zipper at the back either.
No.
As we had before.
In order to.
There are many who say, I, among other things, when I drive.
I never open behind.
I just open up.
So we have shortened the zipper a bit.
So this one will be super fast.
You have run a lot of swimrun, but you are also good in open water.
So it would be a little fun to hear about your Morocco trip, it was a slightly different swim adventure.
Yes.
What did you do there
We swam 25km in four days.
Then there were people from all over the world, and then it really was, all variants of equipment.
Wet suits, hats, some drove without every day.
It was 17 degrees in the water, so I thought it was too cold to swim without
But I was jealous of those who had like this.
Tank Top.
I thought it was too cold to drive completely without a swimsuit.
One day we got away late, African time ...
Then it was tide, and waves.
We chased buoy, the other kite surf.
What are they doing?
This is much more fun.
Should we try.
We test the new one, it seems cool.
Aero.
Yes
It sits piggy.
Yes, and what I have thought has been difficult.
It is that they should sit well around the trunk.
I've probably never tried anyone sitting so well around the trunk.
There was no problem with it being a zipper.
Would you keep it, or would you cut how does it feel in the knee joint?
Yes, now it does not feel like it is as important to cut it.
I don't think it would be a problem at all to keep it.
No.
It is almost as if you could keep it just so as not to be stiff about the knees.
So when one gets cold
I think, I haven't put it in the wrong direction huh
No, because you have the whistle here.
It's too small
Yes.
You can see that here because it is not possible.
It goes up by itself.
You're too big over the chest.
Jump in the other.
Yes.
It will work.
Then only, you run with the glasses on
Yes.
Yeah, yes but you know we hunt hundreds.
Yes God.
Then I understand why people aim to get in pants and such.
I've never understood it.
It is just to buy a size larger.
So shit, you look like Superman.
Yes, but I'm superman too.
It might work well that one
It may work well.
Now Börje and Ragge get nervous.
I think they get really nervous.
Sitting in Japan and biting your nails.
I have to send a little video greeting to them.
Earn Simon and Ragge, Perra here at Head.
You ski and I charge for the Ångaloppet.
These are priorities, there are priorities.
Yes, but it sits nicely, how does it feel
It feels good.
Between the branch and shoulders, it is not tight
No.
Because even though it feels claustrophobic now, it should.
It releases, it goes out half a size when you get into water.
And then you open up when you run.
Yes exactly.
Who do you drive with
I drive with Erik Olsson, my old swimmer.
Okay.
He has been a little stronger like that maybe.
Not this year.
No, not this year.
We'll see, I think he's a little nervous now.
I think he is sitting and looking at every episode and just, Satan.
Per looks fast, Per looks fast.
Thanks Dennis, nice.
Thank you Lisa for coming and modeling a bit.
Cool with the logo.
Limited Edition.
Yes, yes, yes ...
I will walk around them here in the office.
Around the clock.
Yes.
Sleeps in them.
Anna just, it smells like skunk.
You just.
I don't take them off