- It's fun because you get to plug with your friends. - Exactly!
- You hang out all day. That's wonderful! - Yes, amazing!
- For me it was very good when I started plugging.
I was not thrown into any stress, but it was a very nice start.
Got to do group work in the beginning so you got to know each other and help,
to get started with the plug. So it was very nice.
- I hadn't plugged in for a while when I was going to start,
So I was a little happy about what it would be like.
But it is in a completely different way at the university than high school I think.
You plug much more together, hang out all day on campus.
Fuck together. It will be an everyday life in a different way.
I think it was beyond expectation. Fun to plug as well.
- I was also scared when I had just started university.
I also felt that in high school you got help from the teacher.
The teacher knew who all the students were.
You had been told that at the university, the teachers have so many that you are as a figure for them.
I was really scared and thought how should I get my help.
But it is not at all! Really not at all.
Here you get help from friends, people in your class because everyone plugs the same thing.
The teacher. Just send out an email and you will receive an answer.
- Once the teacher asked if I had read the course literature.
And I had not bought the book. Then I had to borrow her course literature book.
To have. Then I returned it after the exam.
Then I felt that these teachers really care about us.
- We have the opportunity to choose a semester to plug abroad.
It's so fun that you can get that chance!
To actually get to study and be in another country and see what it is.
- For example, I would like to plug in the US and that's how the plan looks right now.
You can also plug in Europe so I have also been thinking about Marseille.
- I am studying for the medical program and unlike many other education in Sweden,
So we are a pretty small class.
I think that has really been great.
It is very good cohesion between the classes, but also for other classes.
We also have our own campus, which is Supernice because you meet your friends every day.
It is also close to the teachers and tiles so you can easily go and knock on the door,
and ask about something.
- I really would have gone to Vietnam now, but because of the pandemic it was not so.
But then our program has possible to adjust when you can go abroad.
Then I have only postponed that semester so I will be able to go abroad later.
So I didn't miss my chance to go abroad.
- What good to do so! - Great!
- Education General should not be that you come and this is the knowledge, receive the knowledge.
Without it, it should be that the lecturer tells stories and that they themselves have experience,
And inspires one so that you come home and want to open the course books.
You long to learn more and think "what cool" this topic is.
You don't get it out of everything. Of course, there are boring courses.
Feels like there is a lot of things like that, that the teachers are really passionate about what they do.
- Do you only meet people who read to a lawyer?
- No, we get to meet criminologists, forensic and socio -economists.
I think that's fucking fun!
As a lawyer, you are often part of a larger network, whether it is at a company or within the state.
So then it is good to understand how you work in this chain.
- We have it included in the studies as well, this particular proximity to real life.
With companies that come and present, you get the opportunity to ask questions,
And talk to people from working life.
- Yes, it is often that companies come and give in lectures and tell us what it is like.
Maybe sometimes they are looking for, so you can search for something alongside the school.
- That's perfect!
Being done here and having a job, I really think you will have.