Hello everyone and welcome to this section of Oru Talks -
Here at ... from Örebro University.
My name is Anna-Karin and I have ...
... today with me Sofi Oskarsson. Welcome Sofi.
Thanks! - How's it going?
It is good. - Who are you?
Who am I? Sofi Oskarsson as I said.
I am a doctoral student here at Örebro University I -
Criminology, although I have been in psychology in the past -
Then I am on Wednesday's doctoral student in criminology. It's great fun.
Fun! Congratulations on it. - Thanks!
Before we start, we have to talk a little about that -
This is not your first live broadcast this week?
No, that's right.
Without? - My other.
Which one was the first? - Yesterday I was on TV4 News Morning -
And got to talk a little about my research, -
Which was great fun. - Yes I understand that. Exciting.
Of course, I also saw it and I think that in TV contexts -
so is four minutes for quite some time, but when to talk about -
This type of research so it felt like a short while, -
Which also felt great that we had this today -
Where we talk a little more about your research.
Yes exactly. - Tell us about your study that you have.
Low resting heart rate and the risk of relapse in crime.
Yes ... I published an article earlier this year -
which is about low resting heart rate increasing the risk -
For relapse in crime, just as you mentioned.
And this in itself, low resting heart rate, ie the session between low resting hearts -
And crime is nothing new, -
Without it, we have known for a long time for many years.
But it's not quite as much studied at just -
Low resting heart rate and relapse in crime.
So I felt this is probably the next step to -
Know a little more about resting heart rate in relation to kimiminality -
And how we can think about this.
Just that, it's a register study. - Yes exactly.
Yes, and how does a register study work?
A register study works like ...
We have many different registers in Sweden,
Among other things in Sweden, but there are also registers in -
Many other Nordic countries, which is a fantastic asset ...
... for research context -
And above all, epidemiological studies.
But in my case I have looked at the pattern register, -
which contains those that have patterned.
And during the pattern you measure, among other things, resting hearts -
And blood pressure and ... lots of different things.
But resting heart rate is one thing you measure there.
And by linking it to the criminal record -
So we can look at resting heart rate in relation to crime.
Right. How many have you looked at?
How big is the ground?
We look at all men who have been convicted of at least one crime.
That was the starting point. And which of those who patterned -
And who have registered the rest of rest in the pattern register.
And a little over 400,000 men are included in this study.
There are very many. - There are very many.
And what is low resting heart rate?
What do you define as a low resting heart rate?
Yes, then ...
As you have done before in register studies -
When you look at resting heart rate is that you let data control -
With how to divide into categories.
But as it has fallen out, we look at -
Those who have the lowest resting heart rate and then you are somewhere -
between 35 and 60 beats per minute.
And then compared to those who have high resting hearts -
And then you are up to 85 to 140-145 beats per minute.
Right. Then I also think spontaneously that you have taken into account -
These well -trained people. I heard that ...
On TV4 yesterday, they referred to Gunde Svan. He's - after all -
Known for its low resting pulse, but ...
... These are factors that you have counted on then?
Yes exactly. Because we know that affects, just as you say.
The same thing as length and weight can also affect what we have for resting heart rate.
So you put it into the analysis and adjust for.
So we have thought about that. - Right. Now you said "we", -
who are we"? Because it is not you who did the study yourself?
No, I have a collaboration with many other researchers, -
which can be found here at Örebro University, my supervisors.
And also at the Karolinska Institute in Stockholm, but also in the USA -
in Florida and Upenn. - Right.
It is exciting that it is an international cooperation as well.
What ... is it as big ...
... Impact even in the US and in these other places where you have ...
... where you have your partners?
It was actually a colleague from Upenn -
that encouraged me to talk about this and make a press release, -
that "these are interesting research results", -
Because they had been on him to make a press release.
So it has been noticed there too.
To what extent I do not know. - No, exactly.
But you ... before this talk we talked before a little neighbor -
And then we talked about something called physiopsy ...
... psychophysiological responses! It is a whole new concept for me.
Can you tell us a little what it is for something, -
Because I think we need to clarify that for our viewers -
before we go into the connection. - Exactly.
Yes, but psychophysiology ...
... is such a word that you easily stumble on when to pronounce.
Psychophysiology can be said to be the interaction between -
What happens around us, our brain and our body.
I usually exemplify this with that -
If anyone loses anything in the floor that we are not prepared for, -
And it melts loudly, then comes our brain -
automatically orientate us against the sound. We will register the event -
And then we will also be affected in our body by this.
We are afraid that there is something we have not prepared for.
So we might start to sweat a little in our hands. The pulse might go up a bit -
And we react physiologically to what is happening outside us.
- Right. It can be said to be psychophysiology.
So the joint between the brain, body and what is happening around us.
Right. And how is this related to your study?
Vilacule is a psychophysiological ... a psychophysiological measure.
We think that resting heart rate ...
When we talk about resting hearts, you might think of that -
“I lie and rest, we measure the pulse.
I am calm and at home in my sofa. ” -
Or "I lie in bed and just take it easy".
So it is not really with the resting heart rate -
As we think about it in a research context, -
But then we think about it as a situation there ...
... the person who gets his heart rate measured -
is perhaps in a hospital environment or in a pattern environment -
Or in a lab environment, or wherever you are.
An environment that is not at home. Someone else measures the pulse on one.
So it's a pretty strange situation in many ways.
So that's why we think that then you should react a little -
On this stimuli that is around us, that we become ...
... maybe nervous or that we think it's unpleasant -
Or yes, a little stressed you are theoretically in such a situation.
So that is why it is then thought that the people who have low resting hearts -
Despite such a context, the ability to keep the nerves in check.
You are not quite as influenced by what is happening around one.
And there would then be a connection between the low resting heart rate -
And the risk of falling into crime? - Exactly.
What would that connection look like?
Yes, as I said we have studied ... or "we" ...
Other researchers have studied low resting heart rate in relation to crime for a long time.
But usually you do it in a controlled lab environment, -
which makes it a lot of time -
And so that is behind such a study, so there are quite a few people -
which participates in such a study.
So the first study that was published -
on a much larger selection in the pattern register.
It was published in 2015 and was the first large -scale study to be ...
... studied this association.
Then you saw that low resting heart rate actually increases the risk of crime -
And now also relapse for crime.
And then you may wonder why it is so.
Yes, that was my next question! Why is it like that?
Why is it like that? A small background was needed ...
But it is good. - Yes, - -
Although it is so well studied, we still know very little about -
The mechanisms behind this association.
But there are two main tracks, theoretical main tracks, -
As one usually talks about when one -
Talking about precisely the association between low resting heart rate and crime.
It is either a theory that is about fear -
And that you then ... So you have a low resting heart rate -
So maybe you are not as afraid of -
The consequences that one's actions can have. One is not really afraid, -
"If I do this then maybe it will be like this".
You don't have it ...
You are not afraid of it, but you think it will solve enough.
It's been a way to look at this.
The second way that one has thought about is about that -
If you have low resting heart rate and it is regulated by the autonomic nervous system -
And there is something that happens automatically in our body.
We don't have to think about us ...
... have a pulse, but it is there. The body takes care of it itself.
If you then have a low resting heart then you may have -
A little imbalance in the body, that you feel ...
I don't know if "discomfort" is the correct word -
But there is no really good equivalent in Swedish that -
Talk about it in a different way.
You feel that you have some discomfort in the body, -
You are a little restless maybe.
Not always, but in some situations, -
And you feel that you need to look out and search for some form of kick -
So that you get stimulated and get this one ...
... level in the body to a more optimal level -
Where you feel that "now it feels good".
So it's been another way to look at it.
One is either scared ... or you are not afraid -
The consequences rather, you are not afraid.
Or you seek stimulation through kicks ...
... where crime is one thing you think you can do.
While we are still in that with looking for a kick in some way ...
Because one had also seen that low resting hearts -
is common in other types of professions or in other persons that are not -
criminals, without any other risk ... - yes, but exactly, -
And it may mean that this theory that you are looking for stimulation and kicks -
Feels a little more ... maybe it's wherever we should ...
In the circles we should think, just because ...
I have seen that one has written about -
low resting heart rate in people who work as bomb dear, -
A very specific occupation. But there may also require that you have -
the ability to keep your nerves under control.
One cannot go into a situation where one should disarm a bomb -
and think about the consequences and fear them that way, -
Without you having to calm down.
The same thing as ...
... people jumping parachute or bungy jump -
or is doing extreme sports ...
... also has a low resting heart rate. Not all of course, but it occurs.
Exactly, and then you have taught me that it is called prosocial behavior.
Right? When you do something good about it, -
Instead of anti -social behavior such as crime would be in that case.
Exactly, I think it could be.
But that's how I've speculated on this.
And prosocial is, as you say, you might be involved in -
activities that are not harmful to anyone else, -
Without looking for kicks in a more socially accepted manner, -
While anti -social behavior is more about crime -
and to make bus.
Could one imagine sitting in a live broadcast -
Is a prosocial behavior to seek a kick?
Yes, but maybe. - Based on my own feeling ...
It may sound a bit simplified to say that low resting hearts have a connection -
with relapse in crime. There must be other factors as well -
which records for that recidivism risk.
How do you look at it and how do the thoughts go there?
Yes, but it is very important to bring in -
The thoughts and reasoning about this, that although we see that -
It is an increased risk if you have a low resting heart rate, -
So it is not the only thing, so we have not discovered "The Holy Grail", - -
Without you need to look at other things too.
But as I have reasoned about this -
Is that we know ...
We can assess the relapse of crime with what we have now, -
thus with the risk assessment instruments available -
and the risk factors we know from previous research -
Increases the risk of relapse in crime.
But what can we add as ...
... makes us better at risk assessing?
Can we bring in another type of measure, -
some other type of risk factor that can add something -
Beyond what we already know? That has been my thought about this.
And so I think, it will too ...
Thus, the care of those who -
Sitting detained today. Could it be a part of -
The preventive care for them?
Thus, long -term, yes, and had one asked some of -
My co -authors for this article they had said "yes, absolutely".
I ... I don't really know.
But it is not a completely foreign thought that we -
maybe eventually bring resting pulse as part of -
the assessment for relapse, -
Just because it is quite specific with low resting hearts, -
Too low resting heart rate is associated with antisocial behavior, -
While high resting heart rate is assisted with many other things.
So it is not as specific with high resting heart rate as it is with low resting heart rate.
Therefore, it becomes an appealing factor to include in the equation.
And it is also relatively easy to measure, -
It is not invasive in any way, but it is ...
One can count the pulse in a very simple way -
And it also makes it appealing.
Yes, just because then my next question also becomes: What do we do now?
What do you do now with this knowledge and with this one -
The discovery, so to speak? What is the next step in this?
Yes, the next step, what I am doing and do, that I am curious about ...
Now we know that this applies to men, -
And most studies have been predominantly on men -
Just because we know that men are over -represented in -
Crime statistics, we have a hard time coming out.
But there are also indications that low resting hearts -
Can also increase the risk of committing crimes in women.
So I really want to continue to investigate it -
and see if we see similar associations -
between resting and crime in women.
Or does it differ in any way?
But theoretically, it shouldn't, but ...
And what we know since previous research should look about the same.
But we also know that women have a higher resting heart rate on average -
than men have, and this is already seen ...
... when the kids are young. So at the age of three -
So you can see that girls have about six beats per minute, -
higher pulse than boys have.
And this has been a way to think about ...
Could it be one of the explanations for why men commit more crime -
than women because they have a lower resting heart rate?
I'll just say that, that you have to ask questions in the chat here -
To Sofi if you come on something during the way.
Now we have talked for about a quarter.
But I also think it is important to study such studies -
And this kind of research will benefit society in some way.
And this might be a huge question to one like you, -
But where do you see this taking us, say in 10 years, -
What have we done to this study and this type of research then?
Yes, so as I would describe psychophysiological research, -
So I would say that it is primarily basic research.
Basic research is ...
... a type of research where we ...
... maybe find out one of the building blocks as to why -
Some commit crimes and others do not, -
and maybe not primarily research results -
Who comes out in practice and does something fantastic upset there.
But basic research should also lead to other research -
that is more practically laid and who also answer questions -
That gives us guidance on how we can work with this in practice.
So a hope is, of course, that we know more -
About low resting heart rate and crime.
What is it in what we can use in practice?
Is there anything we can use in practice?
Does it make us better at risk assessing relapses in crime?
Just. We will see if we have received any questions in the chat. We have not received that.
If we move on ... We also talked about this with bio feedback.
If we get back to it, because we talked about too -
If you can train your resting heart rate ...
... and keep it in check.
When I have lectured on psychophysiology for students, I usually ...
To understand what is happening in a lab environment, -
So I usually talk about, and this is my supervisor who has taught me ...
One can talk about lie detector tests, because everyone knows what it is -
from American television series and movies.
So you can think about it that it is a bit so it works.
We measure hand sweat and pulse in situations there -
People are exposed to different things to see how they react.
And then you can, you have noticed, exercise.
Although this autonomous nervous system works independently -
and low resting heart rate is part of the autonomous nervous system, -
So you can still learn to control this a little neighbor.
And those in Navy Seals in the United States for example are very -
Hardly teased to be able to regulate their responses in the body.
And there is also a line of research that trades bio feedback -
which is also applied in practice in different ways, -
Where you can follow your responses to different stimuli in real time.
For example, if one has anxiety or phobias -
So maybe in a lab environment you will be exposed to what you are afraid of -
While seeing how to react in the body, -
and then by practicing handling the feeling and reaction in the body -
So you can learn to control this a little neighbor.
So it's definitely an appealing thought.
Could this be something that can be applied to resting heart rate and crime?
I don't know, but ... - But maybe you know in a few years.
In 10 years we may know a little more. - Yes, but exactly.
But if I'm sitting at home now watching this call -
And I have low resting hearts, I need to be afraid that I -
will commit any crimes, right?
No I do not think so.
This with the association between low pulse and crime -
Is at group level. And i usually see -
When I talk about this for students, that many are sneaking down -
And take the pulse of themselves while I talk.
But no, it's not at the individual level, but we see it at group level -
And of course, many have low resting hearts -
that will never commit crimes.
Maybe you are looking for some other type of kick, possibly, -
But it is not that one will commit crimes -
Just because you have a low resting heart rate. - No, just that.
Very important to mention. - Yes, but it is very important.
I think that, just as you say, you directly -
checks their own resting heart rate or pulse at this time.
Is there anything more that you want to add this -
As you think we have not touched on during this call, -
Which would like to tell us and our viewers?
So I could talk about this for a very long time, but ...
No, but I feel pretty satisfied. I think we have touched it -
which is essential and important to bring their from this ...
... I think. - Yes, what fun.
Big thanks for coming here today, Sofi.
And we will see you again in a new section of Oru Talks here in the future.
Have a good one!