We find some genes that increase the risk of psychopathy.
And we see that the genes especially in combination if you are exposed to the growing environment.
Then it seems that the gene really poses a risk.
This is the series about crime.
Where we seriously talk about crime.
It is important that we give nuanced images of crime.
Instead of what happens in your information flows every day.
My name is Henrik Andershed and I am a professor of criminology and psychology at Örebro University.
These are the other sections of this series on crime.
And we will continue to talk about psychopathy and why you develop psychopathy.
The question of whether it is inheritance or environment has been interested in researchers for quite a number of years now.
And you have studied this in slightly different ways.
The short answer is: It seems to be inheritance and the environment.
Not inheritance or environment.
However, it may look different for different people who develop psychopathy.
You who listened to me last time
Heard that I was talking about primary and secondary psychopathy.
And there is some support for and theories about
Primary and secondary psychopathy.
The primary has more of inheritance and secondary has more of social influence.
You have studied this with inheritance and the environment in slightly different ways.
Among other things, one has compared one-egg and two-egg twins.
Twin research can be called it.
One -egg twins are our natural clones.
They have similarity in DNA.
They have the same heritage you can say.
Because one -egg twins are more equal than two -egg twins
Then we interpret as that there is something that is hereditary behind psychopathy.
We measure psychopathy at twin 1 and twin 2 in one -egg twins.
And twin 1 and twin 2 in two -egg twins.
And then we are happy to study thousands of such twin pairs.
And then we see that one -egg twins are more similar in psychopathic features than two -egg twins.
Then it does not answer the question:
What is hereditary then? How does it work?
How does it work that we actually see something hereditary behind psychopathy?
We no longer believe that it is about a psychopath.
Possibly there are many genes in combination
that affects the development of brain.
Which affects how the brain works even in adulthood.
After all, the brain is the organs of thought and personality.
And of course we have a genetic impact on how our brain is affected.
Therefore, it is not so strange to see that we could of course have hereditary effects
on how we develop personality.
Maybe you have ever thought that you are quite similar to your mom or dad in behavior?
It can of course also be due to social influence.
Of course, we have also started to look at the DNA string.
Look at genes.
And look for genes that have to do with psychopathy.
We are no longer looking for the individual psychopath gene.
We don't think it exists.
It is probably about many genes.
We find some genes that increase the risk of psychopathy.
And we see that those genes, especially in combination if one is exposed to
in the environment in growing up.
For example, violence in the home and so on.
Then it seems that the gene really poses a risk.
Thus, gene and environmental interaction.
One can thus have the genetic risk but have such a positive environment
So you may not develop psychopathy.
We still keep that too likely.
That it can also work that way.
You can usually see these traits very early in life.
There is research from us here at Örebro University
which shows that we can measure these features as early as three years of age.
This does not mean that these people at the age of three have psychopathy.
It is not at all what the researchers want to say with it.
But you can measure deficiency in empathy. One can measure impulsivity.
You can measure voltage -seeking, need for change.
You can also measure if you start to lie a little more studied in school age.
So quite early in life we can measure these personality traits.
Now many research is conducting and wants to find out: Where does this go?
Which of these children show these features will develop psychopathy early?
And who don't.
A qualified guess is that all children who exhibit lack of empathy
At the age of three, it will definitely not develop psychopathy.
It will certainly be due to environmental factors and other factors during upbringing
Which will control it in different directions.
Here we do not have all the answers yet.
But when asked how early we can see this type of personality trait, we can see it very early.
And we can also see that the personality traits seem to be problematic.
This is important at an early age.
That is,: when we measure lack of empathy at the age of three
so can we see that it is related to aggressiveness and threatening behavior
3-6 years of age.
This indicates that it is a type of empathy and personality trait that is not so good.
How is this really about psychopathy and crime?
Do all psychopaths commit crimes?
It is clear in the research that you have these personality traits,
That you have this whole syndrome that we call psychopathy.
It seems to increase the risk of crime.
Especially for violent crime, it seems.
It also seems to increase the risk of relapse in crime after stay.
You have already been convicted and make their time at an institution.
So there is generally a higher risk for a person with psychopathy to return to crime.
Than people who do not have psychopathy.
To nuance that a little more, you can say that it is also
so here that those who exhibit these psychopathic traits
and showed previous crime.
In studies, that group often has a very high risk of crime and relapse in crime.
However, these psychopathic traits but not so much earlier crimes are presented.
Maybe not almost any previous crime at all.
Then the risk of crime is not very height.
It is an interesting nuance in the relationship psychopathy and crime.
Many researchers have been interested in the brain and psychopathy.
We have received some answers but also quite a few question marks.
One of the brain that we put in relationship and connection with psychopathy
It is how the forehead lobes that sit at the front work.
Worse function of the forehead lobes has been set in relation to increased risk of psychopathy.
And also the temporal lobes, that is, the temples.
Then there are some structures inside the brain
For example, amygdala that regulates anger and fear.
Anger and fear are important concepts in relation to psychopathy.
Many who have psychopathy are quite fearless and get anger outbreak.
And there is a connection between amygdala and psychopathy according to most studies.
In Corpus Callosum that communicates the structure between the brain halves
There we have also seen some abnormalities
in people with psychopathy.
But this is hard to understand.
Because we get quite weak relationships.
There is no strong relationship between how the brain is structured
That is, the size of different things in the brain and function in the brain.
We can actually film into the brain with magnetic resonance cameras.
We can expose people to tests.
It can look at a screen while filming into the brain
and see where in the brain beam we have the most activity
When the person looks at something that, for example, is sad.
So far, we are not completely wise to what we see.
We look pretty weak and diffuse relationships.
Maybe it is that our measuring instruments do not really keep up.
We may have to have better technology.
We can conclude that there are some relationships.
But there are many people with psychopathy who do not have a clear deviant brain.
A brain that looks perfectly normal.
What it is now. For our brains look quite different.
But within a normal range in terms of dimensions and function.
That person can still show psychopathy.
So the possible myth that the brain must look completely different in a psychopath
We have not confirmed it in research so far.
I have met individuals in the Prison Service who in adulthood suffered serious frontal lobe injuries.
And describes a life before and a life after.
It indicates at least in some people
so may frontal lobe function be the basis for the type of personal trait
which is part of psychopathy, such as impulsivity. Not being able to inhibit and control themselves.
There are other diagnoses and mental deviations
which people can show that can be perceived as similar.
One can see, for example, that Asperger's and Autism and parts of the problems
which is about shielding yourself from others.
Exhibits what can be perceived as unemployment to others.
There may be anger outbreaks and impulsivity as part of
They also syndrome.
You can interpret that as a psychopathic personality.
But maybe the foundation of it is something else.
And of course it is important to be aware of.
Especially when we talk about how to handle it.
And how to diagnose it right and what treatment is required.
General one can say about people with psychopathy and their crime
that it tends quite rarely, just like criminals in general,
To be quite versatile.
Rather than specialized.
I think many people believe based on the media image that many who commit crimes
are very specialized and niche.
We see many serial killers in TV series and movies.
Serial killer is a disappearance of people who commit crimes.
It is a very small group that certainly stands for a lot of misery.
People with psychopathy are quite versatile in their crime.
They commit both violent crimes, property crimes, fraud and financial crimes.
It is the typical statistical image of a person with psychopathy
rather than being very specialized in something.
How is it psychopathy in connection with abuse?
A person with psychopathy who also abuses alcohol.
What does that mean?
Here we have some answers.
And those answers tell us that it often entails an increased risk of crime.
But we also see that with quite a few other mental disorders.
We know schizophrenia as an example.
Schizophrenia itself is not a very high risk of violent crime.
But when it comes together with alcohol abuse
Then it becomes a rather proper increased risk.
It seems that mental deviations and problems with abuse.
There is something in the combination that one can logically understand
that increases the risk of crime and different types of crime
Quite a lot.
So in short, you can say that psychopathy and abuse are a rather problematic combination.
And unfortunately, it is not uncommon.
We see that it correlates significantly.
Quite a few people with psychopathy also show abuse.
But not everyone.
Thank you for being with us today.
Like if you think what we do is good.
Feel free to comment.
And don't forget to subscribe, of course.
I think it is important for all citizens to meet a more nuanced image.
Otherwise, maybe we will be scared unnecessarily.
To be affected by crime.
We may lose confidence in the legal system.
Due to the distorted reporting of crime.
Have you thought that you have a role in preventing crime?
You can have a role. I can have a role.
It is not just the police who have that role.
Together we can create a safer society.
This series is about it.