- Yes, but we drive! - Let's go!
- My name is Sebastian. - My name is Emma.
We will answer questions about the psychology program.
If you want to learn more about other people.
Why people do certain things for example.
And also learn more about yourself.
- as with all health care, if one has an interest in,
Helping others, the psychology role is a very good way to do it.
It is very wide and you can divide it into different parts.
Some are different perspectives to look at man and psychology.
An example of this may be what happens in the brain during childhood and adolescence.
- Then it is very much about how different substances in the brain affect us.
And what happens in the brain, for example, when we feel good or are sad.
- What happens to an individual when they are in groups or different group processes.
- Then it is about a scientific method and how we can absorb the research that is done.
And how we can use the results of research studies to,
Understand man both now during the studies and then in professional life.
- Then we learn a lot about different professional skills such as,
Call methodology - How to talk to a client during treatment,
And how to work in an ethical way. - mm.
A lot of focus is on trying to work health promotion.
Counteract ill health before it even has occurred.
- The first two years are a bit more basic knowledge of psychology,
Different perspectives on man and psychology.
- Then it becomes more and more practically directed.
So we have to apply what we learned earlier in the program.
- The last two years, years four and five, is the deepening of the knowledge.
Then we can also start receiving our own patients here at the university.
- Do you look forward to it?
- Yes, it is a little dreaded delight.
Because it is very exciting to receive their own patients for the first time,
But it's a little scary because it's a responsibility.
- Mm, absolutely! - What do you think?
- Yes I feel ready, but it's a little scary.
At semester 6 we have VFU, business-placed training, ie internship.
It is for 15 weeks.
I thought it was pretty nice,
Because then I could really get into the company I was at.
So that you can follow people and processes a little longer.
- The point of VFU is that we should use what we have learned in practice.
- What did you have to do on your internship?
- I was at child and youth rehabilitation.
Which most people do not know if they have not been there.
What we did was offer support efforts to children and adolescents,
Who needed it for various reasons.
I gave information about different diagnoses to children,
carried out some play observations, when observing children when playing,
To see where they are in terms of development.
Then I also had some support calls.
You just did your internship, what did you have to do?
- I worked at a company that offers psychological tests for companies for recruitment purposes.
What I did the most was trying to educate HR managers and HR staff,
In how to use psychological tests
And how to create a fair recruitment process with the help of the tests.
After the training you have quite a few choices of workplaces that you can apply for.
It depends a little on what you feel you have become interested in.
For example, you can work in primary care, at a health center.
Where you might be the first contact with someone who has started to feel bad,
Or that has a certain problem that they want to get help with.
Then you can also work at a school for example.
Where you work more preventively with staff and students to create a better school environment.
- Then you can also work with recruitment processes,
to develop recruitment processes.
You can also work in the Prison and Probation Service with both treatment and risk assessment.
- Then you can research too. - Yes you can do that.
- If you have become very interested in something specific.
- Then you can open your own too, which is not uncommon to do.
Yes, I can say that I have probably changed a number of times.
And I'll probably change a number of times.
But right now I feel most craving for primary care, health center.
To be the first person that people meet.
Also occupational health care. To help people who may be exhausted,
Who needs support to get back into work.
Can also imagine opening my own, in the long run maybe.
- Open my own I think would be great fun! - Yes.
- A little more later maybe.
I have been in a lot on groups and organizations,
Think it would be something I would like to test.
Then I think you might get tired of it in the long run,
And then maybe I want to do something else too.
You get to see a little, but right now I feel maybe group development,
or a little more to help organizations to streamline,
And make their workplace better for their employees.
When you start at the university, there is one thing called the introduction.
There are a lot of different activities indoors and outdoors, different kinds of activities.
Where you get to meet people from other courses and programs.
Meet new people.
- I thought the introduction was a very good way when you come from outside,
And don't know anyone or keep track of town.
It was a great way to get friends quickly,
And also to learn a little about orienting yourself in the city.
- Then the psychology program has some special days at the beginning of the program as well.
- Exactly, the first two weeks we have what we call conference days.
Then you really get to know your class very quickly and effectively.
It was also a lot of fun!
- Then you can get involved in other ways as well.
I have been a leader at the campus gym, as it is called.
I have been a volleyball leader there and play volleyball several times a week.
It has been a lot of fun!
Then it is also the various corps sections that organize lots of stuff.
We have a corps section Sobra that organizes activities.
There you can find something that you think is fun.
If it is to be outdoors and do stuff or,
If there are different parties and stuff.
There is something for everyone it feels like!
- It is a great way to create community outside the class as well.
More programming. - Yes.
- Then we have Superego too!
It is the psychology students' own section, or what to say.
They also organize activities over the semesters on the psychology program.