Everyone had understood what had happened -
- And then they saw me when I was relieved, so everyone in the whole hall started laughing.
It was so embarrassing! People still remember me today on the union. "It's you!"
Nice that everyone feels ready with their plug.
- Is this one on? - Do I have a look in my nose?
- No, do I have? - Yes a little. You have...
Have I?! Oh my God!
Sit down!
Welcome to the premiere of them calls us students!
Here we will address everything possible about student life.
You will be asked questions, and we will answer everything that belongs.
Yes, and we will share our stories.
Remember to comment and like this clip, and subscribe to the channel!
I was very, very nervous, that is.
I remember getting an apartment about 2-3 weeks before school started.
So about mid -August.
I had never been to Örebro before, so the first time I went here was when I would pick up the keys -
- To my apartment.
And just the idea that I would be in a whole new city, I don't know a single person there ...
Will I make friends? Will I get to know people really?
I had no idea, because I hardly knew I would start plugging.
- No ... - It was a bit at that level.
I sent in via late registration and didn't think about it anymore. It was like this:
"I live in Gothenburg. Plug in Örebro, it probably won't happen. I won't come in."
Thursday before everything starts: "Hello! You have come in via late registration for the program in Örebro.
- How fun! - Well, and when do I start? "On Monday." So that...
- * Laughter * - so ...
I was very annoying, I know.
I would jump on the medical program and book my life for 5½ years, as well.
So it was a bit like this: "But God, what have I given up on?"
And how will this be?
At the same time, it was very cool too, because for the first time you would jump on an education -
- That would lead to what you wanted to be the rest of your life.
So I call my mom in the evening. "I think I'll move to Örebro."
And she just: "Well ... when then?"
"In three days."
"Okay, where is Örebro?"
"I'll google, wait a bit!"
I have zero sense of geography, so I'm starting to google.
- "Yes, but it's easy to get there!" - "Yeah. Where are you going to live?"
Yes, that's the next good question too ...
I took a sabbatical to be able to digest everything and recover from high school.
- It's pretty ... especially if you go in for grades - yes, of course.
I didn't invest so much on the college exam. You can get in through that too.
And then it became that you ...
I didn't feel ready to get into the studies again. - No, I understand.
I needed to get some other kind of experience. So I worked at McDonald's and turned burgers.
- I still have scars on my hands today. - Oh my God.
- So, I was the worst. Although I always arrived on time! - Good experience, anyway.
In high school it is a bit so that you read because you have to. But now it was an active choice.
"Shit, this I want to read!"
How old were you?
- I was such a thing - "one like that ..."
- Who jumped at once. So I was 19 years old when I started here.
Once the introduction and school started, everything went very fast.
I got very comfortable in the hall.
I knew I was going to study, because I just come from high school.
- Yes exactly. - I took the student this summer, and I already knew -
- That I wanted to continue because I want to be finished earlier, later.
I had been here the year before and checked in, because I saw Örebro as a suitable candidate.
It was close, but I still wanted to test my wings and move to a new city.
- But still not too far from the parents. - No, of course.
It was the first time. I had lived at home for 19 years before moving here.
So it was a big step to start living yourself. Have your own accommodation, wash, cook.
I remember how I stood at home and practiced frying mom Scan's meatballs to be ready.
For the introduction I could catch up.
First I was very anti-Örebro. Now this sounds very cliché -
- But it was really like this when we had a syo-call. The study guide said: "But Örebro, then?"
I said no, and she asked why not. And I don't know, I've never been there.
I was just so set to Stockholm and Uppsala, because ... no, I don't really know why.
I come from Stockholm, and it was an obvious choice for me not to plug in Stockholm.
I really got tired of Stockholm after the student. I took the student last summer, and for me-
- It was just to plug somewhere else.
I applied for the law program in all cities that are available, and so I ended up in Örebro by chance.
For me, moving here is the best choice I've made.
I came here on such a day where you can see a little ... what is it called?
- Recruitment day? - Yes, a little bit like that. You have to go to lectures.
I thought it looked great. Then I fixed housing and came here.
I was really very uncertain about what I wanted to be.
Then I thought: Biology, it's pretty fun. Work with people, it's fun. I guess.
Can be.
I hadn't done it before. I had only worked at ICA. But I thought it could be good.
It felt like a good goal. When I came in, I thought I was driving on this!
On the first day of intro you will be divided into your group, and then you made friends from day one.
When you went, I knew some friends who had moved with me.
But I still wanted to know new people. Then we ended up in different groups, and it can feel a little scary.
Day two and three it felt completely natural and clear.
- It was super fun for the first few days. - Yes, but really. That's what is so good.
Everyone is in the same seat, and everyone just: "Give me friends! I want to find someone to hold in!"
- During the introduction, there are activities every night. - Yes it is.
How was it possible to combine it with the plug? Did you do with what you would and also go on activities?
- Did you have to make priorities? - Of course. It is always the school to prioritize first.
In terms of school, it was not so much for me in the beginning.
There were some introductions. You had to go through what law is and how to read a law book.
Since I read law in high school, I already had the pillars.
So for me it was quite easy to combine with the introduction. But it can be different for everyone -
- Depending on the conditions you have before.
- Then I have to be a little mom to you here then! - Yes, okay then. Gladly!
No, but I would say that everything resolves.
- Don't forget to have fun. - I haven't forgotten that, I can say.
Unfortunately, I was one of those who was not so much on the introduction.
I wanted to go in a lot for school. I felt it was coming like a bang.
In the MSc program, they want to test during the first few weeks.
They push on with lots of scientific articles and literature. You should still manage four years.
I didn't go so much on the introduction, because it was a lot to read.
Everyone is a little lost. Everyone is in the same situation.
But then I think it was very easy to find people in the class.
I had a huge trip. The second day I sat down with some that I am spending time with right now.
It was just "Tjena! What is your name? You seem funny. You will hold on to!"
This is going to be good! I thought it was super fun.
But it is on all these things in addition to the lectures that get the chance to network.
- Yes, that's it. - Just go and sit in any association house.
- Or go to the corps. That we talked about before. - So, for real. You can go to the corps yourself.
- Yes indeed! - Yes.
Then I got the opportunity to be a sponsor. It is true that everyone ... you know that too.
You can seek to become a sponsor and be part of the introduction and arrange it.
So I did that a year later. After all, it wasn't too late to get to know new people.
- Did it feel better after you became a sponsor? - Yes exactly. Since then, my network has increased a lot.
But otherwise. Do you have any housewife tips?
So, I am the worst housewife in the world.
We talked here before about food, tacos, and to wash and hold on.
I just felt that: My God, I've lived for a long time now.
I still haven't gone up in rank from sausage stroganoff. I'm still there.
- I understand. - the best I know is when you don't have to cook -
- And you can eat roasted sandwiches for dinner. - Yes, but I also know it.
My favorite food is just sandwiches.
It's so simple, it's just buying bread, butter and optional toppings
- It's kind of better than anything. - I know!
Prio one is to pass the studies.
After all, that is the reason why you are in the city and plug in at Örebro University.
- It's for the sake of studies. - Yes.
But to cope with e.g. The MSc Program which is four years old -
- Then it is still important to have good people who support if you have a bad day.
And even that you can help others when they have a bad day.
Where do you find yourself?
What do you focus on? Or do you think you have a balance between the social and the plug and all that?
I've had a hard time for it for periods.
I have been very active in associations at the same time as we had a lot in school.
It was different stuff. It was a party on the weekends, and here and there.
And it was fun. I liked to do it.
But I also think that maybe you should do it for a period.
Then maybe you back down and focus a little more on school
So that you can still breathe a little too.
- There was a lot of sausage and meatballs in the beginning. - No, so there will be a lot of tacos.
I still have my taco-streak in eleven days.
I have talked to many at the university, but no one has come up for eleven days.
It was for lunch and supper, and sometimes even breakfast.
It was crazy. My stomach became chaos after eleven days.
- We had 10 seminars every day. - 10 seminars?!
- Two weeks on the rake. - Every day?!
- No ... - And then it went two weeks and then we had ten more seminars.
- What? How do you come up with then? - You don't.
But how long were these seminars if you had 10 a day?
- No, not 10 a day. - Well!
Do not misunderstand me! Thus, 10 days in a row. One seminar per day. Did you think I meant ...?
- I thought you meant 10 seminars a day! - No no no!
Right. It's one of my horrible memories.
One of the first lessons when I had just moved here from Linköping.
- You know the feeling when you lose your phone? - A little mini-heart attack?
Yes exactly. In other words, I had my credentials there, bank cards ... - in other words?
I had been to the toilet during the break.
I remember I had put my mobile on the sink. I do not know why.
When I got back to the lecture room, it started again.
It had been 10 minutes. You have a routine that you feel the pocket if the phone is there.
And so I feel that, shit, I don't have my phone on me.
- Okay, my bank card ... I'll shop afterwards. - You should live.
I want to be able to come home.
Shit, I put it in the toilet.
- So I just get up. I sat in the middle of an auditorium. - You just stand up?
Yes, in panic I get up very fast. Everyone looks at me and wonders what's going on.
The lecturer also looks at me and wonders what is happening. Does anyone have died, kind of?
I'm just running out. "Excuse me, excuse, let go of me!"
Goes from the middle towards the edge and out of the hall.
The toilet was free, so when I get to it I see that nothing is there.
I'm panicing. I go in and my heart thumps like a thousand. I am sweating. I'm panicing.
It is laptop you have at the lectures. It was not collapsed.
I don't know why I folded it together. I was so disappointed and sad.
- Then I see that my mobile is behind it. - No!
Everyone had understood what had happened. When they saw how relieved I was, everyone in the whole hall began to laugh.
It was so embarrassing! People still remember me today on the union.
"It is you! It is you who dropped the phone and are so customer!"
Yes it's me. Theo, nice to meet.
Remember to comment and like this clip, and subscribe to the channel!
You can also follow us on Instagram below.