Testing One Two Three.
I have to test it.
It's actually a good question.
The student yes ...
It's just driving.
My name is Tilda.
I plug in a civil engineer, industrial economics.
My name is Daniel.
I plug language, rhetoric and communicative leadership at Örebro University.
My name is Erika.
I am studying at Örebro University.
I plug in subject teachers in sports and history.
My name is Rojan.
I am studying the law program at Örebro University.
Ever since I was a kid I have had a dream of becoming a defense lawyer.
And that was also why I chose
The finance program with a focus on law at the upper secondary school.
I have always thought that math is very funny,
Which made me read nature in high school.
I studied community with a focus on behavioral science in high school.
Just because I felt that width was something that was useful to me.
In high school I joined the technology program.
The reason why I chose the technology program
Was because I had a plan to become an engineer.
That said, I sit here and plug the subject teacher program right now.
So it wasn't exactly an engineer.
After the student I had many interests,
But also no idea what I wanted to do in the future.
So it took me three years before I applied to the university.
After I took the student, I chose to take a year,
To work and travel and so on.
But it ended with three years.
I needed three years to find what I wanted to do and what I wanted to search.
During these three years I did like so many others.
I traveled through Australia and Asia
And also had to settle in Norway and work there for a while,
Before I applied to the university.
Because I knew I wanted to keep up with law in the future,
But also that I thought that law was the most interesting in high school,
So I chose to apply to the university right after high school.
And once I came in, I thought that
It had just been worth continuing to study.
I also saw it as an advantage
that I would be done with the plug as soon as possible
If I started studying immediately after high school.
At the end of high school so I planned to go to the USA
And work as au pair.
But at the same time I was looking for some different education at the university
To really have a back up plan if the United States would not go through.
And it didn't either.
For starters, I applied to the police college.
But it wasn't quite as I had imagined.
So then I start to think about instead.
Then I thought some profession that would be to work with people,
And then the teaching profession was the first thing I came to think of.
And that is really the biggest reason why I am studying subject teachers today.
What I got stuck for in the program was mainly communication.
I have an interest in both talking and a great interest in writing.
The engineering courses interested me a little extra
when they were very wide and had many opportunities after graduation.
Industrial Economics I chose to
I didn't really have any special interest in technology,
Without wanted to learn a little about a lot,
Which is exactly what we do on our program.
In the future, I know I want to try
reach out to as many people as possible,
Whether it is through inspiration
or communication in either speech or text.
It may sound clumsy, but I want to make a difference in people's lives.
So that's why I would prefer to work in the judiciary,
For example, in criminal cases.
In the future, I would like to work abroad,
in Swedish schools around the world.
As a trait so I would like to aim to
be that teacher that one remembers
and the teacher who sees everyone, who listens to everyone,
And that makes the students achieve their goals.
In the future I dream of getting a job
at a company where I can grow and develop as an engineer,
and also be involved in developing
A technical solution that can change society.
So the conclusion of this was to dare to search and dare to test
To see if you find an education that suits yourself.