- Hello! My name is Jael. - My name is Sebastian.
- We will answer some questions about the medical program.
- Here we go!
- I think you should plug in the medical program,
For above all, two reasons.
Partly if one is genuinely interested in the human body,
And to understand how it works.
And if you have an interest in helping people.
Because that's what we do in the medical role.
- I like to have both the theoretical
And practical elements in their everyday lives.
And to have a job that is both exciting and varied after graduation.
During the program you learn how the body works from top to toe.
Then you learn about the most common diseases that affect the body.
Then you have to be out at the clinics and learn how to practically treat the diseases.
- Then we have another very important part we learn.
Much about patient contact and how to meet patients.
How to make patients feel safe, that we listen to them,
And that in our role we are there to help them.
You have to be out already from the first semester.
But then it is very short that you are out, just a few days.
Then you are out in primary care, ie at a health center.
Then from semester three you can start to be out in the hospital a little shorter periods.
In semester seven, the majority of the time is in practice.
- I experienced it as good that you got to be out on internship early, already during semester one.
So you got to know what it is like to be a doctor and see how it works in practice.
- I agree with you. It was a bit uncomfortable at first.
Or you didn't really know what you were doing there and it was very nervous.
What I think is fun about the practice because you feel that the longer I come,
The more confident in that role you become.
It is a very fun development I think.
We read everything in blocks.
You have a theme you read that is constantly returning.
I think that is very good.
Because when you start the program, there is a lot that is new.
A little difficult to understand and put things in context. Very new words and such.
Then you notice with the course of time that there will be things that come back.
I very much like to learn things in depth.
I like that it is being built all the time and that there will be a lot of aha experiences.
It will be like puzzle pieces that are put in place.
- I like that we have some PBL in Örebro, which means problem -based learning.
Which is to sit in a group of about eight people.
You get a case for each week that you then go through.
So you get some time to collect some information.
Then you discuss this in groups to solve the disease,
Which you may have read about during that week.
It is nice to get some interruptions from just sitting and reading in the books.
Sit with your friends in a group and discuss these issues as well.
New for this year is that the medical program is six years instead of five and a half years.
Which means that after graduation, you do a basic service that is one year.
- After that you specialize. It's about five years.
Then you can work at a health center, the hospital, private or research.
- You can say that every organ in the body has its own specialty, ie its own doctor.
Like, for example, the heart that is cardiology.
After graduation, I want to work with a surgery specialty.
Preferably where you get the opportunity to work a little pre-hospital.
I was at the ambulance helicopter a few weeks ago and looked.
There I would like to work in the future.
- For those who do not know, what does pre-hospital mean?
- Pre-hospital means working outside the hospital's walls.
As with an ambulance for example.
- I wish I was as safe as you,
But I actually don't really know what I want to do.
I was very much in surgery when I started the program.
But there is a lot that is fun so I have a little trouble deciding.
- I think that is very nice that we have such a long program.
That you have time to change many times along the way.
Student life in Örebro begins with three weeks of introduction.
Where you get to know new people.
I thought it was great, because I'm not from Örebro from the beginning,
Getting to know new people.
- I'm from Örebro from the beginning so I may not have been as involved in student life.
But I've been on some stuff.
I know that MFÖ, which is the medical association Örebro,
They arrange a lot of stuff for medical students.
What is so fun about it is that there will be very good community over the semesters.
You get to know both elderly courses and those who go younger semesters.
Then you can get a lot of help and tips from elderly courses,
Which I think has been superb.
- Exactly! I also think MFÖ has been great to be involved in.
That arranges slightly different sessions and we have pub rounds,
Where there is the opportunity to get to know other people on the program.