Are you ready to sit and talk a little?
Always ready!
Are you ready?
The program is called language rhetoric and communicative leadership,
So it's really the three parts that permeate everything.
Then it is language where we read courses in both Swedish and English.
rhetoric that is both written and verbal communication.
And then we have communicative leadership that is very much developed in all different courses.
We really learn what good communication means.
Term five is completely optional.
Then you can choose partly study abroad, an optional course or an internship.
You can work with a lot of examples as a communicator, you can coach or write speech.
It is very much because the program is so wide
And have so many different components that you fit a lot afterwards.
I am very attracted to the leadership bit.
And I want to work with some kind of education.
I've always had a dream of being involved in influencing and inspiring people.
So I have not decided any form of education since in which industry.
It is a very warm climate here at Örebro University,
I would say that is the reason why you find the belonging to university
And that you feel at home.
University is a little outside the city center
Which means that when you are at university you are really with students and get that feeling.
Then you can get into town and do activities there as well.
Are you interested in communication,
want to understand how people communicate between each other
And how you reach out in the best way?
Then you should read the language, rhetoric and communicative leadership.