- How's it going? - Good!
- Then we drive then! - Yes!
- My name is Muna! - My name is Adelina!
- We'll answer any questions,
- About the basic teacher program grades 4-6.
I chose the program to,
I substituted at a school.
I enjoyed the children very well there and in the classroom.
- Same here. I also substituted at a school.
I immediately felt that this is right for me.
I was a little lost there for a while and didn't know what to do.
Then when I started working at school, I felt that this feels good.
- I would say that you should read the program if you enjoy children,
Enjoy a school environment and teaching.
You learn the basic building blocks of pedagogy,
Thus, the learning.
We learn that it is important to create relationships with their students.
To be able to teach and reach them.
- Then we go through the three core subjects that are math, Swedish and English.
The Swede and English are quite similar.
Then there is a lot of grammar and phonetics,
meaning language sound. How to pronounce certain words.
And some children's literature.
On the mat there is a lot about the usual calculations.
You learn the theory behind the core subjects.
The practice, too, how to teach it.
- The education is four years, ie eight semesters.
The first course we start with is called educational science core, UVK I.
There we learn about the learning theories and what they mean.
Then we learn how to create relationships with the students in the classroom.
Then we go more into the core subjects, mathematics, Swedish and English.
Then we are divided into either SO or NO. What was it you chose then?
- I chose NO because I think it's much more fun.
This includes biology, chemistry, physics, technology and ends with man and sustainable development.
What did you choose? - I chose so.
This includes SO didactics, ie the art of teaching so.
Then also includes religion, history and together social science and geography.
You have business -based training, VFU, several times during the program.
The first time is already the first semester when you have five weeks of VFU.
How did you experience that period?
- Well, I thought it was nice to come out in practice.
To combine what we have read with the practice.
- Yes I agree.
Then we also got to follow our supervisor.
See how they planned and taught different subjects.
We got to know the students and test what it was like to teach themselves.
How did you think it was? - I thought it was great fun!
To teach for these students, get to know them and create relationships.
- I agree with.
It was fun to stand in front of a class and feel how it really felt for real.
- After graduation, you can apply for teacher identification at the National Agency for Education.
- We become authorized to teach middle school, ie grades 4-6.
We also become eligible in grade 3.
What do you want to do after graduation?
- I probably want to work for a few years so I get experience.
After that, I think I will read on and research.
- How about you?
- Yes, but I probably think like you.
I want to go out into working life and accompany a class from four to six.
It feels exciting!
Then maybe I want to continue to teach a university class.
So a class like ours.
- It's very funny!
I have moved here from Linköping to Örebro.
In the beginning, I felt very small here on big campus.
Eventually you will find new friends and people in the class you can keep up with.
We usually be here on campus.
Sometimes we have a snack, we spend time with each other and we also plug together together.
How do you experience student life?
- I, just like you, have moved here, but I moved from Leksand.
I chose to get involved in the Corax Union section.
We fix with sessions and other activities.
With that, I get to know people from other programs too,
Which is very fun I think.
I very much appreciate student life!