Also, do not forget to sign up for your exams.
You have to do that.
It was something I missed.
Hello and welcome to a new section of them call us students.
My name is Dana and with me today I have Indy.
And today we will go through:
Things that can be good to know as a new student.
A little practical stuff like this right in the beginning.
We will talk a little about student services.
We'll talk about what Blackboard is. It will persecute you throughout the education.
And much much more. So hang with it.
But first and foremost, we just want to welcome you all to Örebro University.
I think, or we think, this will be a fun time for you.
At least it has been for us.
Hope you will be happy.
And hope you will find your place here.
It will go great. I think so.
As a new student, it is good to know some stuff.
And we were going to go through now.
But Indy, how much should you actually study at the university?
The idea is really that you should plug in 40 hours a week.
So it really becomes like a full -time job.
But it differs quite a lot.
Partly from different programs I can imagine.
And then week to week how much you have.
Then it is some responsibility too.
That you learn what you need to be able to.
As Indy says, you have easy things for different things.
And then you can feel:
I may have to spend a little more time on this course.
Or that I feel that I can handle this without spending those 40 hours.
Exactly, and some weeks maybe you have more.
And then maybe you spend 45 hours.
And one other week maybe you spend 5 hours.
If you are a little lazy.
Ok Dana so we have this student services.
What is it really?
That can be said is the heart of the plug.
That's where everything is.
There you can look at the syllabus and see study results.
This is where you sign up for the exam.
Where you get their scanning exams since after the exam
So you see your answers.
This is also where you get in touch with teachers and staff at the school.
If you have any questions or concerns.
So everything like this is important and substantially happening there.
It may be good to check what you have placed for e-mail address there.
For information from the university being sent to that email.
And sometimes these are pretty important things.
So it can be a good thing to look up like this in the beginning.
And don't forget to sign up for your exams.
Because you have to do that.
Because it was something I missed.
About a month before, you can see that the exam has been scheduled.
And you also see your schedules that are constantly updated.
And so we have this blackboard that I mentioned in the beginning.
What is that?
Blackboard is where all material is posted.
All the tasks that the teachers publish.
There is more focus on the courses you read.
On Blackboard there is more focus on the courses.
So every course you read has its own page on Blackboard.
Where teachers put up stuff that you said, lectures and other things.
Information to be submitted is also submitted to Blackboard.
And sometimes like this in the beginning, it can feel a bit bondy with the studies.
That you do not really find your study technique.
It may be difficult to get into the fact that you have your own responsibility.
And then there is very good support you can get from the university.
There are usually many good free lectures
For example, as the university organizes study technology and stress management.
Which can be good to check if you feel you need it.
When you start at the university, it is no wonder that you do not know how it goes.
You can easily feel stress that you feel that you do not keep up.
But you have to get into it to learn.
For example, if you have dyslexia, there is something called Funka.
Which can help you with very good tools in your studies.
For example, you can get programs that read texts.
So you don't have to read it yourself.
So you get help with your studies if you feel you need it.
And when you start plugging here you get one here.
A university card.
And you use this to access the university's premises on campus, among other things.
You use it to borrow books at the University Library.
And more how to get one like this can be found at www.oru.se which is the university's website.
And something else that is really good when you are in the university area
So you have access to free wifi.
The WiFi is called Eduroam and how to connect on it is on the university's website.
The good thing about Eduroam is that there are slightly different places around the world.
Because when I was in Spain once, Eduroam appeared.
As a new student, it can be difficult to find on campus.
Then you can either ask some on campus or download an app called Maze Map.
And there can enter the hall you are going to, the app shows where to go somewhere.
Supersmid really.
For me who does not read on big campus but on campus usö
which is away at the hospital.
But it is also inside the Maze Map.
So that's good. They have got with everything.
And this also applies to you who are going to study on Campus Grythyttan.
But Indy where do you usually sit and plug?
I am such a real library plugger.
I can't plug in at home.
I get so distracted. One goes type and throws the garbage
Put on News Morning and then you lose it completely.
So I usually plug in the bible.
But the university is very plug -friendly.
There are a lot of places where you sit.
Different benches, tables and group rooms.
Actually, there are dedicated plug sites in all buildings on campus.
As it is intended to sit and plug in.
Either yourself or in group.
So it's super smooth.
Then in the middle of the city there is also something called Congrego.
And it is also a small building that is dedicated to Örebro University.
And there you can also sit and plug.
Then depending on what you are on for a plug humor.
So there are a few different types of plug racks.
For example, if you want to sit in a group and talk a little.
If you want to "latch plug" a little.
Then you can sit at some table in a corridor only.
Then in the library there are also quiet reading places.
If you are easily disrupted and there it should also be completely silent.
So you really get to a good study environment.
Then there are slightly different group rooms on campus that you can book.
We the university's website.
And it is super smooth for group work and the like.
If you want to sit in your own room and be undisturbed.
And did you know that you can go abroad and plug in a semester.
So -called exchange studies.
I think Örebro University has collaboration with type 150 different
University around the world.
So they have established contact with different universities in the world.
And there are great opportunities for those who want to plug abroad to plug
At the very place you want.
And have you been thinking about plugging abroad
so it is good to be a little set already now
on how to go about it and check out a bit.
This requires some preliminary work.
But there is no stress either.
For it comes, among other things, information evenings for those who want to study abroad.
For you as a student at Örebro University, there are lots of free activities.
Which is organized by the university.
Like, for example, various lectures by writers, politicians and so on.
As you are super interesting to go on simply.
And so there are concerts.
Which the School of Music organizes that you can go on.
Which is super nice.
And information about when such lectures take place continuously
on Örebro University's website, on message boards and in social media.
So you won't miss it if you hang out on campus or look in your smartphones.
And do you as a new student have questions and concerns, which you have certainly
And it's perfectly understandable.
So you can ask basically anyone.
Those who are older for example. Or your teachers.
Or your sews.
Then there is also the student center.
You can basically ask anyone and you will be led to the right person.
And don't be afraid to ask questions. For everyone is here to help you.
And it will be much easier if you have all the information.
Ok corner! Hope you have received answers to some questions that you might have.
Again, congratulations to your admission here.
And hope to see you.
Bye! Bye!