- Are you nervous? - Yes, a little neighbor but it will be fun!
- Yes, it will go well!
- Hello! My name is Felicia and plugs the subject teacher program,
with a focus on sports and health, and English.
I plug in semester eight.
- My name is Jhat and I also plug the subject teacher program.
My subjects are sports and health, and history. Semester eight.
I chose to plug the subject teacher program,
because when I went to high school I had
A great relationship with my mentors and teachers.
Somewhere I felt I wanted to emulate that relationship,
And work with students that way.
That's what mainly drove me to choose this program.
I don't know what it was like for you?
- I also chose this program because I wanted to work with young people.
Enjoy that relationship.
Then I chose sports as first topic,
Because I have always loved sports.
The subject teacher program is a program that you plug for five years.
It corresponds to ten semesters.
The specializations you choose depend on which topics you want to read.
- I have sports and health as first subject and history as second subject.
I read sports in four semesters and history for three semesters.
Then there is pedagogy in between too.
During the program, I gain a deeper knowledge of my subjects.
For me, it's sports and history.
If I take history as an example, I get a deeper knowledge of historical events,
And year. But also how I teach them to the students.
- Then we have a lot of pedagogy in teaching as well.
Where we learn about relationship creation with students, which is incredibly important.
And so we gain even more knowledge about how to teach to the students so they understand.
Because they need to keep up when we stand up there and talk.
During the program, you can take part in a lot of practice.
As it is called here, VFU, business -based education.
Where you get to the schools and test on what it is like to be a teacher.
- There you have to be out already the first semester. - Yes!
- It is good. Then you get to know quite directly if you are right out or not.
- mm.
- Then it is scattered, as Felicia said, throughout the education.
Where you can do different things within your subjects.
- You really get to taste what it feels like to be a teacher.
During the semester you get more and more responsibility during practice.
- After graduation, you become authorized to work within the upper secondary school,
But also within the high school.
So it's not just high school that applies.
- Pretty! And in addition to high school and high school, you can work in other businesses,
Where teachers are needed, such as Komvux.
Teacher education is a little wider than you think.
After graduation, I always thought I want to work at a high school.
But during the course of education and where I tested at VFU at high schools,
I feel it attracts a lot.
Especially high school with a focus on sports, because that is what I am very passionate about.
What do you feel?
- I feel a bit the same, that I would like to get out to a high school directly.
But another fun thing would be to first come out at a high school,
And then work upwards towards a high school.
So you get to meet many different students of different ages,
And gain experience that way.
And develop their work with as much scope as possible.
- We have both moved to Örebro to study at Örebro University.
What I love is the warm climate, you feel really welcomed.
Especially when we have a very long introduction.
Where as a new student you can find different events together with other students.
Get to know new friends and stuff.
Then I love that campus and center are very close to each other.
Just take the bike between!
It is very nice with Örebro I think.
- Then it is very section -driven.
It is also, as Felicia said, the warm, very family friendly.
So it's something positive.
Then we both who plug in the subject teacher program, also
Because there are many different orientations,
So you meet many different people during these five years.
As you get to know, friends join and create relationships.
It's been the best for me!