Here in Örebro it is easy for you as a student to get a home.
Many students choose to live in the university area, close to campus.
Here there are several different student housing, in mixed sizes
Depending on how you want to live.
You can, among other things, live in corridor with shared kitchen and living room,
in a collective or in a separate apartment.
There are both student apartments but also ordinary rental properties
Around Örebro.
This is how it may seem to live in one near campus.
In this student housing lives Isabelle,
Like all her neighbors, stay here because they are plugging in the university.
This is her second student apartment during her time as a student in Örebro.
The apartment is at 25 square meters
And Isabelle pays about SEK 4,900 in monthly rent.
What she likes best about her apartment is that it is so close to the university,
But also for gym and grocery stores.
If you prefer to live more centrally
Of course, it is also possible to live near the town.
In this rental apartment lives Eva, which originally comes from Örebro
But who still wanted to find something of its own.
The apartment is 42 square meters
And costs about SEK 5,000 in monthly rent.
Eva likes the proximity to the pulse and being able to go to town in just minutes
And therefore enjoy the area very well.
If you instead want to live in an area that is constantly growing and developing
So the southern barn bed is the place for you.
Here are modern buildings and many different types of accommodation to choose from.
Here Jacob lives with his partner Sofie
Both moved here from Stockholm when they started plugging.
Their apartment is a third of 65 square meters
And costs about SEK 8,400 a month.
What Jacob likes best with the area is the tranquility and proximity to nature.
As you understand, there are several different ways
Living as a student in Örebro.
But how have the students gone about getting these apartments?
Here are some tips on how to get hold of a home
before or at the beginning of your studies.
You can stand in a residential queue
At, among other things, the municipal housing company Öbo
or with other private landlords.
In Örebro it is free to stand in a residential queue,
and you can queue up before you seek education,
So do it now.
Some private landlords do not use a queuing system
Without it, it is important to be first come, first served with a statement of interest.
On Örebro Municipality's website there is a list of all private landlords.
If you would probably not find any apartment in time until the course starts
So Öbo has a so -called housing guarantee.
This means that you who fail to find any apartment
may receive a time -limited agreement
So that you have somewhere to live during the first semester of your studies.
Read more about how the housing guarantee works at obo.se.
Now you have got a little better control over
What it is like to live as a student in Örebro.
Welcome here!