Look at this park.
Many feel insecure here in the evening.
What do you think of the lighting in this park?
Is it a good lighting?
This is the series about crime
Where we nuance your picture of crime.
The picture of crime you and I get in our media flows every day.
What does it mean to work crime prevention?
What requirements should we place on the police, the municipality and other collaboration actors?
How do I as a citizen think they should work?
What do I think as a researcher?
Look at this park.
We have some problems in this park.
Many people feel insecure in this park in the evening.
What do you think of the lighting in this park?
Is it a good lighting?
Will it be a good even light?
Or does it rather create a wall of darkness?
Where the light cones end.
This is probably not such a good light design in a park.
Because we really have a wall of darkness.
The problem is that it is not a physical wall.
Without it, people can actually stand without being seen.
Because we work knowledge -based and systematically
we look at reported crimes and
We get reports in other ways from here.
And there is suspicion of drug store in the dark here.
In general, this route does not feel so inviting.
We don't get people here.
We would like to get an even flow of people who create security.
There are tall bush cakes here on the right side that create insecurity.
One can wonder if there is anyone behind the bush?
Now we have analyzed and mapped the problems.
There are many people who feel insecure in this park.
And we also see this drug crime.
Or at least suspicions of drug crime.
Now we analyze this that is the next step in the systematic way of working.
What is this because of?
Why do many feel insecure?
Is it the defective lighting and light design?
We are not just about it.
It's not just common sense.
Without we also look at research.
We also hit the knowledge.
That is why it is called knowledge -based work.
What does the research say about this?
Is it that lighting can make people insecure?
So defective or certain type of lighting?
In this case, we might be supported by it.
Can the high bush create insecurity and uncertainty?
Can darkness facilitate drug sales?
Now we do this analysis.
Before we put in an effort.
Now we are planning efforts on analysis grounds.
We try to access the causes.
Now we are also thinking about:
Now we believe that improving the lighting gives a security -creating effect.
We believe it will reduce drug crime in this park.
And now again we turn into research:
Are there evaluations that have tested this before?
Is there research that shows that improved lighting gives changes?
Now we are planning for efforts.
Improve lighting.
Change the bush.
We are doing quite a large intervention in this park.
In this next picture.
So we look after the efforts.
We have rebuilt this park quite a lot.
Now you see that the lighting is completely different.
We have even lighting that spreads lighting throughout the park.
This is the same time of day as the last picture.
But the lighting has done wonders with how we can see each other.
There are really no dark spots in this park at all.
Look at the bush and the height of the bush.
No one can hide with ease behind these bush.
We have an inviting park that invites you to spontaneous activities.
A slightly wider route where we can do things.
And we have benches that invite people.
Benches can certainly be a problem.
There you have to think about how to design benches.
Maybe so that you design so you can't sleep on the benches.
There are techniques for that.
When making such a situational effort.
That you change the environment.
Then we always have to think about this with redistribution.
And spread.
That is, do we move on the problems?
Has drug crime, which we see has decreased drastically.
Now that we have made this change in the park, we get much fewer reports of insecurity in the park in the evening.
We see that drug crime has almost disappeared from the scene.
Then we have to ask ourselves: Has the crime moved on?
Has it been printed to surrounding areas?
What we do now we are also following up and studying neighborhoods all around.
After the effort in the park.
Has the problems with drug traffic increased around?
Then we have support that we only pushed the crime away from the scene.
The spread effect means a good effect in the park but also all around.
We will not always move on crime.
It partly depends on what kind of problem it is.
What kind of crime it is.
Now that we have made the efforts and made this change.
This is what the park looks like when we have rebuilt it.
Then we follow up.
Because in our municipality we work systematically.
We map, analyze and follow up.
After all, we map all the time.
We follow the crime and other reports we receive.
And we see now: before we made this change.
So we had so much reports of insecurity.
And suspicion of drug crime.
And actually drug crime.
Now that we have made this change, we have followed the incident reporting and crime
A number of months and see that we have been given a fairly large reduction in crime.
We follow up and create knowledge about what works and not.
Of course, it is appropriate to compare with another park.
Which may have similar problems.
To see if the same problems do not change because they do not rebuild the park.
And see if we get a change when we rebuild the park.
That we have a control area.
Then we get an even stronger reliability.
If we do well in our follow -ups.
I think we should all ask ourselves:
Regarding this with working systematically and knowledge -based.
How do you work in my municipality?
How do you work in your municipality?
If you work in the municipality with the police and other cooperation actors.
So I think you should ask the question:
Do we work systematically and knowledge -based?
Why don't we?
I think we should make demands to work that way.
There is much to indicate that we will be more efficient then.
Must also think about what the alternative is?
Would it be that we work unsystematic?
And don't listen to knowledge?
And don't follow up on what we do?
It's worth thinking about.
We can not only be driven by common sense and logic.
It will sometimes lead us wrong.
Therefore, it is so important to look at what research also says.
It is also generally one of the big reasons why we have research.
That we have some kind of facts we can lean on.
Thank you for being with us today.
Like if you think what we do is good.
Feel free to comment.
And feel free to come up with suggestions on what to talk about the series.
And don't forget to subscribe.