- Have you ever clocked yourself when you cycle between town and school?
- Yes, it's ten minutes you usually say.
- Ten minutes no matter what direction you are going.
- It's like a big city in a small town.
- Mm!
- There is all university life and student life linked to it.
There is a real city supply.
Close to nature.
But I don't have to take the bus anywhere really.
- I was given the opportunity to greet a friend here.
- Okay!
- I had to come here and test on student life.
Feel the city and the city vibes like that.
After that, I felt I wanted to move to Örebro.
Then, of course, it was a security that I knew a person before who plugged here.
- I understand that.
- It's nice to have it.
At the same time, I know that even though I had not had it, I would have had a great welcome.
For my absolute closest friends today is not, that person is still a close friend,
But it is not the person I plug with.
- My friends had heard so much about Örebro
About student life, how welded and welcoming the city is.
Then it was like this, it sounds pretty good.
That's why I chose Örebro.
- Klara and I know each other since before.
You started plugging a little before me.
Me and another friend have been and greeted you a couple of times before we started plugging here.
We thought it was a lot of fun.
Got to go to a nightclub in Örebro City.
Very funny!
We got to meet your friends.
Great fun!
We had to live three people in one.
- An experience!
- It's just that planning.
At home, it was required to check bus times and train times.
Here's just jumping on the bike and it takes ten minutes!
- Pretty!
But also another thing.
Just the proximity and agility to get home to Stockholm,
I think is a great advantage with Örebro.
The train I think takes a maximum of two hours.
- And there are often trains.
- Yes!
So it's easy to get home a weekend or a day.
- I had lived in Australia for two years before.
I would move home to Sweden.
I felt I didn't want to move home to mom and dad.
I heard rumors and thought Örebro, easier to get a home.
So I thought I move there.
Also that it is close, but also that I knew in Stockholm, I have the family there,
I have friends there.
I am already established.
Thought it's probably the same for most people there.
Örebro I have heard, as you say, is a student city.
People move there and they don't know anyone there.
Then it becomes forced out.
It will be this student life where everyone wants to get to know each other.
- I applied for all medical programs in Sweden and entered Örebro.
- Correct!
- That's why it became Örebro.
- Congratulations!
- It was as good as any.
- How good!
- I haven't bought bus tickets since I moved here.
- boast, boast, boast.
Haha, no but it's really nice as well.
- Yes, I have saved money on it because it is so cheap.
- How do you get around, do you cycle?
- No, or ...
My bike is either twisted or gone, or not as much away as ...
When I moved it was winter and I am not super sharp at cycling.
I thought I won't cycle right now.
So I leave this and pick it up soon.
Then they tore that house!
Did they tore the bike?
Maybe maybe not.
Does anyone have turned the bike?
Is it left?
Maybe maybe not.
- You haven't checked?
- So I may have a bike.
But I do not use it, but I drive a lot of electrical kick bike or walk.
I think that works great for me.
- It is much easier to be spontaneous and get to this everyday hang.
Which otherwise can be quite difficult to get.
- Yes indeed.
- It will be difficult with planning.
You should go long distances in Stockholm.
Here you and I live five to ten minutes apart by bike.
- Yes, and it is not close with Örebromät measured.
- No, then we still live a bit from each other.
- Yes exactly.
Like different area codes, so to speak.
- Really!
- That you want to be social, you want to go and meet and start talking to people.
You start hanging out on everyday evenings and just "we should go home and play cards" or whatever type.
- Yes, it gets so spontaneous and so fun!
- It's so close too, student life.
Type everyone lives at the university so it really becomes this community.
- It's so fun!
Me and my friends talked about this the other day.
You have your family in your hometown, but then you have created your own family here in Örebro.