Hello and welcome to Örebro University!
At Örebro University, more than 15,000 students are divided into three campus areas.
Main Campus Örebro, Campus USÖ and Campus Grythyttan.
Right now we are on the main campus.
The main campus is the biggest campus and this is where most students are.
There are all twelve buildings here
And during the tour you will visit these buildings plus Campus Grythyttan and Campus USÖ.
Join us and discover the university!
Welcome to Novahuset.
Here, the School of Business has its premises.
Most people you find here plug the economy with different orientations.
In the Novahuset we have our largest hall which can accommodate just over 500 people, Aula Nova.
But here at the university we are not just sitting and plugging all day, student life is so much more.
You meet new friends and have a lot of fun together.
A house to have fun in, it sounds like the corps.
Join us and I'll show you it!
Here we have the Kårhuset and that could be called the students' own houses.
Here there are café and study places in the days and some evenings there are also pub and nightclub.
Welcome to the longhouse!
And just as the name reveals, this house is very long.
If you want to go in length throughout the longhouse, it is 325 meters long.
Here in the longhouse that can be seen as the university center we find students from all programs.
And now I'm going to show you the forum house!
Then we were there here in the Forumhuset!
In the Forumhuset we find mainly students who read programs in the humanities.
It may be that you read, for example, to become a political scientist or a staff scientist.
Here in the Forumhuset we also find media center that I have right here behind me.
Here are students in the film program and my program Media, Communication and PR primarily.
For here we have different editing and recording rooms.
The Forum House is actually together with another house, Prismahuset.
Instead, in Prismahuset we find students who read medical programs.
But that's all I had to say.
Now I pass you on to the School of Music.
The School of Music is for the students who are studying in music and theater.
Next to the Music University is a building called Bilbergska.
It is for students who study for science subjects.
But now we will go to the gymnastics and sports houses.
Right now we are at the Gymnastics and Sports House.
This is one of the oldest buildings here on campus.
Those who plug here usually plug in sports within Sports Management, the coach program
or teacher orientation sport.
This is everything for me, the next stop is the library!
Now we are outside Örebro University Library.
At the University Library there are over 300,000 different books.
In addition to borrowing books, you can also sit and plug with your friends
And then there is also the study workshop Lyktan where students can get help with their writing technology.
Now we are in our robot lab, which is located in Teknikhuset.
In Teknikhuset we find our engineering students.
In the lab, a lot of research is being done.
We are researching, among other things, robots and AI technology.
It was everything from Örebro University's main campus.
Now it's time to move on to Campus USÖ.
This is Campus USÖ.
Campus USÖ is located next to the University Hospital and it is a campus for us who plug in doctors.
At Campus USÖ we have our own library which is mainly focused on medicine.
Something that I think is great that is here is a clinical training center.
There we can practice various practical elements like listening to heart and lungs.
You learn so much more than what is in the books.
Hello and welcome to Campus Grythyttan, to the Restaurant and Hotel Academy.
One of Sweden's foremost education in meals and hosting.
And it is a very unique environment to plug in.
Everyone who plugs here is seen in their spare time very much and learns from each other, where everything is about food and drink.
That was everything for us, hey then!
Now we are back to where we started the tour.
I hope you thought there was fun!
Bye!