- Let's go!
- Yes!
I was not sure what I wanted to work with in the future and therefore I thought,
System science was a good choice because you can work with a lot of different things.
I chose the program because I always had an interest in computers and IT,
As well as working with people.
This was a good mix of both.
When you plug system science, you do not educate yourself as a profession, but to an industry,
Where you can work with different things.
Such as requirements analysts, programmers or business analysts,
or UX designer or project manager.
I was unsure and wanted a breadth with my studies.
Therefore chose to study the master's program in informatics.
I probably want to start working right away.
Initially, perhaps as a programmer and later project manager or reached.
What most people think about system science is programming and database management,
But system science is so much more.
You also read a lot of UX design and requirements management.
It is also about learning the connection between IT and man.
During a semester, you have the opportunity to do internships or system development projects at a company.
Which can be good for making contacts.
Yes, but you don't have to be out at a company.
You can do your own project just like me.
I made a mobile application.
I think student life is good and there are a lot of things you can get involved in.
For example, one can get involved in union sections, sesame is ours, be sponsor, holding an introduction,
Keep in sessions, sit on the board and be responsible for various events.
You can also get involved in many other non -profit associations at Örebro University.
For example, if you are interested in football, theater or similar.
Do you want to enter a future industry and to have easy jobs?
Do you want to work with problem solving and people's use of IT systems?
Then you should apply for the system science program at Örebro University.
- Then we were ready now!
- Lovely!