LiU Impact Factory is our investment in social innovations
There we recruit teams that have sustainable ideas,
based on the global goals.
During the program we give them among other things
offices, colleagues and skills.
When we make a program that has a clear direction toward
the global goals and we noticed that we got in
A brand new type of idea carrier in our systems.
So we really broadened at the university through this.
We develop Mathetopia, which is game -based teaching material
which shows students the purpose of math and
its areas of application in reality.
It is based on a series of research findings and we
using us of 3D visualization for increased understanding and
Clear connection to mathematics.
Broad look is a non -profit association, which works for more votes
and perspective, which is usually not allowed to be heard in public
the conversation, should arrive.
We are currently running a project called Listening Post Norrköping
where we try to develop methods for journalists to more easily come
In contact with new arrivals and others who have an immigrant background.
So that it will be easier for them to include them in their
Everyday reporting.
We have two offices that we offer members of the LiU Impact Factory.
We have an office at Kårallen on Campus Valla,
Where you sit in the middle of the student world.
The majority of our team consists of students and sitting on
Kårallen gives us an opportunity to find the skills that we
Need among students and researchers.
And so we have an office at Coffice in Norrköping,
which is part of Norrköping Science Park.
Coffice has also been a very inspiring
context, where we have had to meet other people
who has the ambition to do their own thing.
For two people like me and Mattias, who have also had
that ambition, but not had that experience, then it is
Great to be surrounded by like -minded people.
This is a project that I think all universities
should offer their students who work with social innovation.
Impact Factory has expanded our contact network and contributed
Valuable knowledge of how we can meet our challenges.
For us, Impact Factory has mainly been an environment
where we can look at our ideas and our commitment
As something one should invest in as a job
And I don't know where could have received that perspective otherwise.
Social innovations may sound new now, but it will
Become part of the new normal in the future.