My name is Alexander.
I am currently reading year three at Linköping University.
Student life is absolutely fantastic.
Then I would say that the education is absolutely fantastic.
Precisely because our professors and doctoral students want us to burn for it as well,
That way, they feel for the subject.
We get the opportunity to build an artificial intelligence
to Starcraft II.
And it is really cool, because then you are divided into a group,
And there I was responsible for the exploration of the map.
How much risk it is that it dies somewhere and
So it looks up a good road that it considers to be quite short.
For us, this is the way of developing and exploring
The methods available, in a fun way.
After 10,000 rounds, it began to improve.
It wins 80% of times instead of 40%.
Yes, as a civil engineer you are very flexible.
What we mainly learn is how to pick up information very quickly.
In today's society, many software programmers are needed, because we are moving towards a more digitized society.
There are plenty of jobs afterwards.
And if you do not want to work within Sweden, there are opportunities to get abroad as well.
Today so that I chose software technology,
Because that is really the education I want to read, given the content and focus area.
Once you are in the middle of it, then almost wish it was longer.
For the years go so fast.