Does it feel good?
Do you feel ready?
Before now?
After all, there are three principals who want to come here and talk to me.
Well, you just have to interview them?
It's an interview.
Well!
I thought I was called to the headmaster.
Well, no, no.
They come here and you talk to them.
It is quiet.
Yeah.
Today we continue the journey towards your high school choice.
Today we are going to cave in program selection and school choices
And how to find out what is right for you.
I have invited principals and high school students who will help us with this.
Warm welcome here Caroline and Viggo.
You work as a principal.
How come you became?
I work as assistant principal
And five years ago received about an offer of a principal service.
And chose to jump on it because I think it is extremely inspiring to get
Join the youth's journey towards adulthood.
To be involved and influence.
You go second in high school.
What program do you go?
The plumbing and real estate program.
How come you chose plumbing and real estate?
Yes it was in nine.
Then I didn't really know what to go but then I found out that it is easy to get a job.
After the plumbing and real estate program.
And you get to work very practically.
But that is also theory.
So that was the right profession.
Sounds like a good choice after all.
Do you have any tips that you usually give students to make their high school choice?
I think there is such a large selection and that it is important to
Start from their interests or an area that you are curious about.
And don't get into the trap of choosing what your friends choose.
Find out as much as possible about
The schools that offer an education because it is the environment and atmosphere, the school's teachers.
It is of great importance for what you get for feeling.
I think you should go on a nice feeling you get.
Really, good tips!
There are any benefits to choosing a practical education.
Yes it absolutely does.
If you enjoy working practically, it is a good education.
Being able to alternate both theory and practice.
Try the profession in working life.
Get contacts and experiences that often also lead to jobs.
You will go out on APL later this year for the first time.
How do you think about it?
We had no kind of practice out in the field in one but now in second
Then we get to know what the environment is.
We learn how it is for real, to be out and work with the profession we will work with.
Great opportunity to test at the high school already.
Are there any prejudices against practical education, Caroline?
Yes but there is.
One prejudice is that if you go for a practical education, you cannot read further at college and university.
Which one can.
Another prejudice is that girls should not choose a vocational education in, for example, construction and plumbing.
Which, of course, you should, because it has nothing to do with your gender.
A third prejudice is that vocational education is not for students who are study -motivated but students who are tired.
That's not true either.
You should go out on practice a lot during your education and the industry places demands on our young people.
Good prejudice and myths to punch holes.
Is there anything that is not what you believed in high school?
Well, with the plumbing profession, you can think that there are very shabby premises and tools and stuff there.
Maybe some prejudice against the plumbing installers.
But these are clean premises, they were newly built when we arrived.
We got new tools this week.
It is pure pipes, everything is recycled when we use it.
Thank you very much for being here and answered my questions today.
Thank you for coming.
Warmly welcome the lottery here and Frida.
After all, you work as principal, Lotten.
What is the most fun thing about your job?
There are many things that are fun with my job but I feel enough to
What is really fantastic about the job is to not only work with the students' learning
Without many young people today want to do something more you want to change the world.
I think Greta Thunberg is an incredibly good example of that.
So being able to participate and enable students to give students a platform for their commitment,
I think that's really, really fun.
To catch it and make sure they have the opportunity to develop it.
To simply improve the world.
The small project.
I understand that.
How fun.
And Frida, you go in second to high school.
What program do you go?
I read Sam behavior.
Why did you just choose that program?
I chose it because I am very interested in the orientation courses that exist.
That is: sociology, philosophy, psychology.
How people work.
Why they work that way.
How do you think you should think about your high school choice?
I think you should start from a little what you are really good at.
That's part.
And what you think is fun.
And it usually is connected.
Just as Frida is about looking at what it is for in -depth courses and thinking about it.
But then of course you should think about what conditions you want to get in the future.
What do you want to bring with you when you take the student.
That is the goal of high school time.
That after the student is ready for the next step in life.
What is it like to study the community program?
I think it's very fun.
You can, as I said, learn a lot about how people work.
Which is something I and my friends bring home too.
We can tell our parents that:
Oh now you used that method and now you did so there.
You learn a lot that is good both now and in the future.
Things you can use all your life.
Are there any benefits to choosing a more classic, theoretical program?
There are many benefits I think.
The most obvious is that one is ready to seek
University and college after the student.
You have with you in a degree that provides the opportunity for further studies and what we work with.
This is what Frida and the rest of the students should move on.
But then it is also that you are obviously challenged academically and theoretically.
If you think it is fun, you should of course choose a theoretical program in high school.
Are there any prejudices?
I don't think there are so many prejudices specifically against the theoretical programs.
I don't experience that.
But on the other hand, there are prejudices about the various individual programs perhaps.
It is thought that the finance program is this way and financial students are this way.
And nature students are this way.
You look in a certain way.
There are prejudice about that.
However, I think there may be a common misconception.
It is thought that the technology program looks the same at all schools and so on.
There are greater differences within one and the same program against what it does between the programs.
My technology students who attend technology -technology for example and become an environmental engineer,
They have a lot in common with our nature students and read quite similar courses.
So there the difference is greater to other technology students who may read information and media technology.
So I think you should be very aware of when applying for high school as year 9.
Is it something that you didn't think it would be in high school?
No I wouldn't say that something came as a great shock.
Then I think many people have some expectations that if you go for a cooperation, for example, that
"Wow we will learn about psychopaths and criminology" and all that fun directly.
But what you may forget that it takes a lot of background learning first.
You have to learn a lot about the backgrounds in the various subjects.
And it may well be good to be prepared for it.
So that you do not come and so you are completely disappointed.
It will come to an end, but you have to start with the background.
The first lesson may not be the most fun.
It comes a little further.
Well, how nice.
Thank you very much for answering my questions.
Thanks.
Warm welcome here Petter and Elin.
Fun to have you here.
You work as a principal.
How did you become the headmaster of a creative school?
Working with young people is absolutely fantastic, seeing them grow.
But working with creative young people is so wonderful because they have a little extra energy.
One may look the bloom
And get this creative as they create stuff.
It is absolutely wonderful to see it happen in reality.
I really understand that.
Here we also have a creative youth with us today.
You go in the third now which program do you read?
I go the aesthetic line with a focus on photo and film.
Fun.
Why did you just choose that?
For me, it was important to be creative.
But also to go for a college preparation line so that I could choose what I wanted to do.
What kind of questions do you usually get from students who want to start with you?
You often get very specific questions.
And sometimes a little more general.
But general is about what kind of students it is, what does the schedule look like and such things.
But then it is very very specific.
The creative professions are often linked to the industry that is aimed at.
It is very much about equipment for example.
What computers do you have, do you have Wacom plates?
What software is used and such things.
This is what is important for many students.
Great to hear that they are in control of it then even before they start.
Yes indeed.
And it is often because they have a special interest and want to continue with it.
They want to develop even more within them.
So we have to have a fairly high standard and quality
In order for the students to be satisfied with the equipment and what they meet in school later.
How would you say that a regular week at school looks like?
For me, it may be due to the schedule.
Shorter lessons to more theoretical lessons and theoretical subjects.
Then we have the long lessons for more creative so that you really get time to do things.
And then so on the breaks there may be people sitting in the hall
and playing games.
I always sit with my friends and play cards before my lessons.
So it is usually very fun and have good energy in the hall.
It actually sounds really fun.
Are there any common prejudices against a creative education.
Absolutely.
After all, we have prejudices about the types of students that are estates.
It is a classic.
And then I usually say that everyone is different, after all,
And you can be yourself in creative education.
So it doesn't matter who you are.
Everyone is welcome.
And then we have it with college preparation.
Is it a college preparation to go to an aesthetic program?
That's it.
All the aesthetic programs are college preparatory.
Most aesthetic schools also offer the courses you need for special permits.
It can be important for the students to bring with you if you want to be specifically late.
Are these knowledge really applicable in reality?
What do I become if I am good at keeping up with 3D models or maybe game graphics.
Should you niche so narrow already when you are so young?
Then I usually say that these knowledge is applicable even after school.
I have companies that contact me and ask "Can't your students come to us and make 3D models?"
Because it is an important knowledge to have also against other industries other than just the gaming industry.
It can be architectural firms.
Tech companies that are doing AR and that want you to be able to do such things simply.
Cool, you learn to be prepared for change and to learn new things.
Really, being able to use your creative qualities makes it easier to be flexible and enter into new contexts.
Cool.
Is there anything that is not as you thought it would be before you started high school?
Firstly, I thought the teachers would be more strict and strict in a way.
There are teachers who say no one will be able to handle my course.
Like it's a good thing to say.
But the teachers on the aesthetic line are very understanding.
They often have the same interests as the students.
I go photo and movie.
Many of my photo and film teachers have worked in photography themselves.
Then they have an interest in it and it makes a difference.
They are as enthusiastic as one is.
They are also very kind with submissions and they give a second chance so to speak.
So that you can really succeed in being able to take the student and everything like that.
I had not expected that from school simply.
How fun.
Think it is exciting to take part in their
Stories from their previous working life as well.
Yes exactly.
Big thanks for being with us today and answering my questions.
Thanks.
We will pick up the lottery and Viggo again to run a moment we call true or false.
Do everyone feel ready?
YES!
Great!
I will say a statement and then you must be true or false.
Just as you think.
First.
The high school choice is crucial to your entire future.
Quickly false.
Only guys read technology.
Same again, false, exactly.
After all, it has absolutely nothing to do with what gender you have.
You can fit into any school.
You agree again.
True you say.
How do you think Petter?
When choosing high school, you quite often choose a specific school or a specific education.
So then there are very often students who in some way have the same starting position as you.
So it's very easy to fit in there.
Then at school we have a responsibility to make sure
that the students land nicely into their education to develop as well as possible.
Next.
It is best to choose what their friends choose.
False.
How do you think Elin?
I had a buddy group in elementary school as many others have.
But I was the only one who chose the aesthetic even though we all liked the aesthetic.
They wanted to aim for something else.
But I felt I wanted to do something that is important to me.
And it is very important because otherwise you will only have three years that you have no commitment to.
So do what is most important to you.
You get new friends.
Exactly.
It is also important.
What you learn in high school is not relevant in ten years.
Here we have slightly different answers, exciting.
How do you think the lot?
I think that high school above all teaches one to learn things.
Hopefully learning a lifelong learning.
Whether you go further college or university studies or if you go out directly in working life as some others do.
So you have learned and gained the capacity to get into the next step and then develop and learn things.
How do you think Viggo?
I think much of these SO subjects and NO subjects, religion and history.
It is something that you might just plug in for a test.
Then you forget it.
It does not feel like we will use it in the future.
It is better to focus on what has to do with the profession.
Maybe sometime in a quiz so you can get a question from the lessons.
It's fun to go to high school.
Nice that everyone agrees here.
What do you think Elin.
Why is it fun to go to high school.
It depends a lot on which school you choose.
So it is fun to take interest over something you want to take interest over.
When elementary school in very wide
over subjects and so on and trying to teach an everything,
So you really have to focus on something in high school.
It can be very engaging and it becomes much more fun to learn some stuff.
I agree with it was great fun to go to high school.
Thousand thanks!
Well done all.
Thanks!
Big thanks to today's participants.
As you can see, it is best to start from what you want to get a good and fun high school time.
To be able to compare different programs or schools is to visit an open house a good tip.
Under prevailing circumstances, several schools offer a digital version instead.
Check out the websites for the schools that you are interested in.
Thanks for today!
It is really good to go to an open house because you get a really good picture of the school.
The premises, where it lies, how to get there.
And especially to meet other students who go to school and teachers.
I was at several open houses where I got to see different schools and how it is at different high schools.
Test on a student for a day.
And then you get to feel.
I was at several open houses.
If you go to school you are interested in, you get a better feeling for it.
And you can feel whether it is right for me or not.