Should you choose high school?
Shit how much you have to keep track of program, merit value and lots of dates.
But you can be calm, I Aliyah, in 9 short sections will find out everything you need to know.
Today we start from scratch, how does a high school choice go?
What's your name?
- My name is Melinda and I work as a study and career counselor.
What does a study and career counselor do?
- We help with everything related to study and work.
Both if you already know what you want, but you also have no idea what you want to do.
When should you make your application to high school?
When it comes to making their high school application, the admission opens in January.
Then the date, what you need to relate to and how the application itself goes to look different.
Therefore, it is important to check with the study and career counselor at their elementary school and the upper secondary school for your particular municipality what applies.
Are there different school forms you can choose from?
You can choose between a municipal school, a free school or a school with national recruiting intake.
What does the last thing you said mean?
National recruiting intake, which means that you can apply for this school no matter where in the country you live.
If you are looking for a municipal school outside your home municipality, it is important that you check that you have the right to be first adopted, or if you will be adopted as a reserve regardless of your credit value.
If you apply for a free school or a school with a national recruiting intake, you have the right to be first adopted regardless of which municipality you live in.
What was the hardest thing about the high school choice?
Which line I would go, what school.
Everything was very difficult, everything was pure chaos for me!
I thought it was very busy that I would quit the school I went to, because I have attended that elementary school all my life.
But then I got tips from friends.
What was the hardest thing when choosing high school?
I would say above all it was probably the choice of schools, because there are many options to choose from.
You have to weigh in things like the route and above all what lines there are, you still want to try to have someone you know at school since before.
What can be important to consider when making your application?
The most important thing is to think about which program and focus you are most interested in.
And how you want to prioritize these choices in their application.
Then it is also important to have several alternatives in your application because there can be great competition for the places on a program, so you are not standing without a high school place.
Some programs also include reading a modern language.
Then it is important to consider whether you want to continue with the language you read in elementary school or if you want to read a new language.
This can have different impacts on your credit value if you search for high school.
There are aesthetic programs and sports education that have slightly different admission tests.
These can look very different, so it is important to check what applies to the particular school you are interested in.
If you want to apply for a gymnasium, what to think about then?
There are 3 different options, they are called RIG, NIU and Liu.
When it comes to RIG and NIU, you need to make two different applications at different times.
You make an application for the sport itself and an application for the national high school program.
So to get a place you need to be accepted both on the sport and the program.
How can an application for the sport go to?
It may look very different depending on which school and sport.
Therefore, it is important to check what applies to the particular school you are interested in but also check with the sports association.
Thank you so much for wanting to be involved in answering all the questions!
Thank you for being involved, it has been great to talk to you.
The most difficult thing was probably if I had chosen the right direction, I think, I was not entirely sure whether I would be happy or not.
But hairdresser is really a really open program with lots of social people.
One step closer to high school, nice!