He can take over the Wagner Group after Prigozjin's death.
And Ukrainian drone attacks deep into Russia.
New images show a rare insight into Mariupol.
What does life look like behind the Russian occupation?
A classic trick used at Stalin era when moving whole people.
This is the war of the week -
- As every week, the latest news development in the Ukraine War deepens.
Here, Ukrainian drones fly over the Russian city of Smolensk -
- Cirka 30 miles from the Ukrainian border.
Ukraine has recently invested in drone attacks on various goals in Russia.
Many drones are built on your own.
It is its own production.
The most important thing for the allies is -
- You don't use weapons that come from the Allies.
This is because Russia should not be able to say: "Now NATO shoots Russia."
It could lead to an escalation in the war.
We move to the front, where there have been news in recent weeks -
- From the parts where Ukraine previously had success.
If you zoom out, it looks like it is pretty still at the front.
At the same time, we have known that this is an offensive that will take a long time.
It cannot be compared to previous offensives-
- There you quickly regain, for example.
The chermen or the charkiv region.
Here Russia has had months of preparation for themselves -
- To build up their line of defense.
Along the eastern parts of the front -
- If Russian forces have been on the offensive lately.
SVT's team visited a mobile health center near the front during the week.
We hear that the Russians have increased the pressure here.
The Ukrainians are pressed over here in the east.
But the pressure is also hard here - at the small mobile health center.
Everything works perfectly until the Russian terror begins again.
/EXPLOSION/
New films show a rare insight from Mariupol-
–As totally destroyed by Russian forces earlier during the war -
- And now annexed by Russia.
It is almost impossible to trust the material that comes from the Russian side.
It is selected propaganda material that is for us to get -
—The picture of a now flourishing city that is being rebuilt -
- And where all the inhabitants are happy with life - especially life in Russia.
Of course, we have started working according to Russian norms, and adopted Russian law.
Now everything is completely different.
The pictures see lots of newly built residential areas -
- But also several bombed houses.
And everywhere, Russian flags hang.
An important thing that is forgotten is that the city is actually almost emptied of its residents.
It is said that 350,000 people have left the city of just under 0.5 million.
Instead, people have been moved in.
You make population movements in Russia.
It is an old trick where you move people from other parts of Russia -
–And this way, the city splits.
A classic trick used at Stalin era when moving whole people.
Much of what is going on in the occupied areas -
- Remember about the great terror during the staline period.
Both in the way you interrogate and execute dissent -
- But also the big population movements.
The reason why the films from Mariupol were released right now is no coincidence.
The material was published on September 30 -
- On the anniversary of the illegal annexation of the Ukrainian regions -
- Luhansk, Donetsk, Zaporizjzja and Chenler.
This is what it looked like in Moscow the same day -
—When the anniversary, which in Russia is now referred to as the reunification day -
- Fired with pomp and standing.
It is symbolically important.
It is a way to show that you have had success in the war.
The whole war has been bought about -
—To one should liberate the Russian -speaking population of Ukraine -
- From "The Nazi rule", which is called Zelenskyj and his government.
This will be a clear picture that you want to show -
— That you celebrate in these "reunited cities", as one calls them -
- To show that people are satisfied and that they have succeeded in the war.
When the Proske Robert Fico proclaimed victorious in Slovakia's Val-
- Ringed the alarm bells in Brussels.
During the election, Fico has promised to strangle the support for Ukraine -
- And improve relationships with Russia.
Much indicates that Russia has affected the election and worked hard for it.
Several analysts have highlighted that the hard tone from Slovakia -
- Not so much for Ukraine.
I do not think so.
There is probably a deep unity political -
—That you have to resist Russia and support Ukraine -
- For the war not to expand and also affect their own countries.
However, I believe that dissatisfaction can lead to an increased split -
- A polarization in these countries, especially in Eastern Europe.
Ukrainian politicians have collapsed after Elon Musk published this meme.
President Zelenskyj's head has been cut together with the text:
"When five minutes have passed and you have not asked for a billion dollars in support."
An image previously shared by several Prorey accounts.
Musk has suddenly been given a big role.
Partly when it came to the fact that he had affected the attack against Crimea last year
- What made the Ukrainians furious.
And now that he is sending out this type of message on X, f.d.
Twitter-
- They get a huge spread.
Musk has almost 160 million followers.
Compared to a Russian troll, he reaches out to many more.
If he then chooses a Prorean rhetoric, it can have enormous consequences.
Late Wagnergruppen's rebellion in June and after the leader Prigozjin's death -
- If the Wagner Group's future has been unclear.
But now more and more tasks are spreading that means -
- That Prigozjin's son, Pavel Prigozjin, must have taken command of the group.
25-year-old Pavel has lived a secret-full life in the shadow of his father-
- And there are therefore almost no public pictures of him.
The challenges for Pavel Prigozjin are several.
On the one hand, the Kremlin must accept him as a leader -
–And here you have clearly shown that you would prefer that Wagner enters -
- In the regular Russian troops and is not left as a private army.
Then Pavel Prigozjin must also be accepted by the Wagner Soldiers -
- That has been very loyal to his father Jevgenij.
They are called the "chefs".
A strong authority is required from Pavel's side -
- To be able to take over the role after his father.
Texting: SVT Language & Accessibility Swedish Television AB 2023