Hey!
Tjena and welcome again.
Now it's been a while.
Yes now it has been a few months.
In terms of design, it is finished and assembled.
Now it is the most small adjustments and brackets to be done.
In a few days it will be disassembled completely.
Then I start with the frame and arrange it and it should be foiled.
Then it should be picked up and foiled, painted and polished.
-The should have no color huh?
No.
Everything that is in aluminum should be polished.
It will probably go to some autosol.
If it becomes autosol, I have tried slightly different means but have not decided yet.
-What are there for other means?
It has come a lot new to aluminum.
Autosol has come with 2 new ones and I have only tested one so far.
There is one that is only for aluminum and should test it with.
There are other means that you use that act as a wax.
There are 2-3 different brands on the market but I have not been able to try anything yet.
-There's happened to some time since last time.
Yes rims and tires are in place and so did the whole car.
The tires I have offended myself down here.
I bought iron so I could squeeze them.
Both front and rear tires have inner hose and I get punctured along the road ...
... then spare wheels are not enough, but you have to change the inner hose.
And then I have to know if it is possible to push the tire or not and I have practiced all 4 tires.
-And now the grill is ready.
Yes, I have roughly polished to see all the bumps.
If you feel like this, it feels uneven.
I will smooth more but now I know what is visible and not visible.
I have made some covers to sit on the inside of the frame.
These are these.
-And you have pressed this?
Yes and it should sit 2 screwed here.
It is to cover the ugly.
The plastic foil goes around the edge here.
Because I will foil the frame ...
... it is difficult to foil the inside and get it neat.
Then it is enough if I form up to the edge.
Then cover the cover.
-Is the engines ready?
No it just sits ...
... the crankshaft in so they are empty internally.
I have finished all the covers.
-Yeah, they're done.
Yes on both sides.
Look what a good thing!
There will be some inspection hatches.
It will be polished and painted with cast paint.
It should look like you see the engine block.
-What are you holding up?
It's an old whistle I've had lying to a motorcycle.
It must be cut and extended.
Or I take an old trombone.
After all, they are so long and are supposed to sit here.
-How should you be able to squeeze it?
There must be 2 plates that squeeze and be regulated with a pedal inside the car.
-Hahaha!
-Ope!
Then I get an electric whistle as a complement.
A truck driver I think does not hear this.
-The inspection doors are they riveted or screwed?
They are screwed.
There are small screws here.
Then you come in ... I'll have ..
I can't fit the oil filter because it sits here normally.
I have a help frame that holds the engines together.
Filter is placed here behind instead.
If you want to change filters, you can remove the cover.
Behind this hatch you see the joint between the engines.
Even when setting the ignition on the engines.
Distributers are behind here.
-How often will you use this?
I drive as much as the other cars, it is 600 miles a year
-Oops.
If it doesn't work, I put it in a barn where no one can see it.
It should work otherwise it is not fun.
It is pointless to have a car standing.
I want to be able to drive to Stockholm, Norrtälje on a meeting and home.
-What are you putting on now?
These are the oil filling pipes.
It's a bit tight.
It will be the first and second engine and here you fill the oil.
So I don't have to remove the entire valve cover.
When I change oil I will have a small gap here.
Where I can stick down a vacuum hose and soak up the oil.
Also put an oil stick in.
-Will the cooler hose leave?
These brass pipes that will be taped with black fabric tape and sit so.
And an angle in here.
I don't want the blue silicone so I tape so it looks like an old fabric hose.
-Hard system is clear.
Yes it is fully welded and suspended.
It is not silent but sits with feathers.
-Yes that yes.
It is stretched so that it can move.
Stainless steel has the ability to widen when it is hot and cold.
I think it bursts if I have it silent screwed.
It is easy to just loosen the springs and be able to loosen the entire exhaust system.
And three carburetors and they were not last.
Yes 3 pcs.
Original carburetor that has been renovated.
Almost everything on the inside is new.
The screws are also new in stainless steel.
I have rationalized away the choke.
This is never used in Sweden in the summer.
I never drive in the winter with this car.
-How should you be able to get carburetors to be sync?
They do not have to be synced because the carburetor in the middle feeds both engines.
Both engines have the same structure and the same compression and camshafts.
That carburetor controls both engines.
During normal driving, only the carburetor in the middle is connected.
When you gas on when overtaking, the other carburetors open.
There will be an exchange here.
It is also own manufacturing.
-Everything is well made on this one.
I can adjust here when I want the other carburetors to open.
If I want them to open earlier, I can move the pin there.
Then it opens already here.
The most important thing is that when driving at 100-110km/h that the carburetor is set correctly.
It is own implementation here.
It is a piece of leather that I have shrunk.
I got the funnel -shaped and squeezed it between two trays.
And made this brass ring so it gets air tight.
It is the details that do it.
-It really is.
If you want to be won I have made a gap here.
There should be a cable in this hole that is controlled with a lever from the inside.
And it opens that way.
-Of course!
We'll see if it works because it can leak a little.
There will be stainless steel feathers.
These are just ordinary Biltema feathers.
-In terms of body it is clear.
Yes doors and seats are cut.
I have done grid templates and most of the fitting is done.
-What is it for boxes?
-It's not going to be glass?
Well there will be slats.
That I will cut myself.
As I have to cast them into the frame before I sit there.
That's because I've done the template so I know it fits then.
Later on, the lamps are finished with 50 mm lens effort from an MC.
It is whole and dipped beam and is mounted with 2 screws so you can adjust.
Never have to adjust the lantern, but you do it internally.
And there is an LED strip as parking light.
-How does it look at the back?
For last time, "we" or you because I have nothing to do with this building.
We can take inside.
I have finished the partition towards the foam.
The chairs are cut and fitted.
What is missing is attachment and screw them.
Pedals and pedal racks are also completed.
And the steering wheel I have fully welded so it should hold.
Is there a wooden floor in here?
Yes.
I should not use this floor, but I have only used it as a template.
Just so I know how the pedals will end up and how the seat should sit.
Exactly the accelerator, it is important to have the right support against the foot.
If you want to drive for 5-6 hours, it will be difficult if you have the wrong driving position.
Right now, the accelerator is straight above the cardan tunnel.
Yes, but usually you sit a little oblique with your foot.
Here the heel ends up and if you brake you just move over the foot.
It doesn't get that far on the pedal.
There is no oil in but this one is connected.
And here is full gas.
-When will it get there?
I'll just buy a regular tachometer that I attach to the back.
And a pointer from a mora clock ...
... a little bigger as an arrow and old numbers as it was on watches before scaled up to 6.
And some lamps at the bottom for charging temp etc.
Should you have any speedometer?
No, there will be GPS instead.
I don't need any speedometer in this car.
And GPS you have with you so I can drive after it.
-The steering wheel was a boat knob did you say?
It is fully welded in the joints.
It was badly done for a boat you do not have to make an effort when you swing.
Now I have fully welded it for safety.
The whole steering wheel is in aluminum.
Since then I have made the decor in brass.
-I haven't seen any name on it.
It's going on and should ... would cast first ...
... and put on the back but I have regretted it.
It will be in the valve cover instead.
It will be written here.
So you only use plain salt water.
Mask and switch on a car battery.
Plus here and minus you dip in the water.
Here it has become a good edge.
It's only 20 minutes.
It is a very significant edge.
The text should be polished but the frame around.
-What should it be hot?
Uh, Decimo Segundo.
It's Portuguese.
In the past, they always named their cars in the United States.
It was Spanish or Portuguese.
Decimo Segundo means twelve.
It seems more complicated than it is.
Those who translate it on the mobile will probably be snooped.
Back here I have made all the moldings.
And where the light and a fuel cap should sit.
The tank is mounted right below.
-And all the moldings are tuned?
Yes but they are loose so far but know that they fit.
I have made the suspension to the rear exhaust system that is suspended with 2 feathers.
And there is thermal insulation in between.
Stainless steel moves a lot so it can't be fixed so it can slip a little.
It was sick near the wheel.
Yes it should be corrected.
I have to put a spacer in between so I get the wheel 1.5 cm.
It does not get that hot as it is silencer insulation.
So it insulates the heat with.
What is left to construct is a handbrake.
I have not decided yet and I will have a foot brake or a long lever.
It's good to have an emergency brake.
-Now I'll wage further we'll be visible again soon.
We'll do that.
Bye!
Hello!