-What is it for a car?
It is a Ferrari F40 replica of a 1988 model.
The whole car I have done myself.
I have done everything you see.
-Hello!
Hello, welcome back.
-I'm ready for section 2?
Yeah, then we drive.
Here you have the first F40'n made.
And pictures of when Ferrari tests the F40'n in wind tunnel and runs it.
This is the first car is the only one with five gills.
The other F40 has only four gills.
This car was standing at the Ferrari Museum long before a famous person had to take it.
-This is no Ferrari F40 that you have.
No, you should be clear about it.
There are people who can look oblique then.
This is one F40 and it is built as I want it.
Then there is always someone who has opinions.
I like this car and I have done the one I want it and it is a tribute to the F40.
The chassis I have made my own pipe frame but how I want to keep it for myself.
I don't want to share it.
I can show a picture of it but nothing more.
-When people understand what does a Ferrari F40 cost?
Prices have gone up like all other cars, but you will probably have to pay 10-13 million.
-All have 10-13 million at the bank?
Well, all car mechanics have at home.
-Refls, tires & brakes?
There I have chosen Oz-racing rims 18 ”.
Before I changed brakes, I had 17 "rims that looked like the original rims.
But those rims did not fit when I changed brakes.
-Where where the brake caliper too big?
Yes exactly.
Then I bought 3-divided 18 "split rims.
I did the rims so they seem to have center bolt.
Center bolt has F40 original.
These are these rims I want but in 18 "and I will try to find a couple but need to save money first.
This is from a drag racing car that I bought.
Brake discs are Wilwood and JFZ brake caliper.
There is a large 4-piston brake caliper.
The brake disc is 330x32 so there are thick slices.
It is my own hub that I built.
I have used A-arms as a link arms both up and down.
Then there are adjustable coilovers front and rear I have fixed dampers.
This is the Porsche 928 brake caliper and then a Skoda Octavia RS brake caliper for the handbrake.
There is no handbom on the car otherwise and this brake caliper fits well.
Brake discs are from VW Passat from 2010. Slices are 317x21 mm and fit well at the back of the car.
It is a damn fun to get everything together.
It should fit and look good and work.
A lot of time is spent on what to use for parts and how it should fit together.
The drive shaft rear consists of 3 different parts from 3 different cars.
When you build with different parts it becomes difficult.
-You have made all the boxes for yourself.
It's not glass panes?
No it is 4 mm lexan plastic with splitter film.
It's like a real box but in plastic.
-Do you have scored the plastic yourself?
Yes I have done it with angle grinder and sanded.
-With angle grinding, does not melt the plastic?
Yes it does but then you have to cut inside and grind.
-Is the windshield also in lexan plastic?
Yes it is also in plastic and so did the original.
I think the original got a glass pane in 1992 but is not sure.
I first had a Porsche 928 engine but it didn't fit so well with the gearbox.
I threw it out and put in an Audi A8 V8 of 4.2 liters instead.
I have worked at Audi for 17 years and it is a good engine.
So I decided to use one.
I know the engines and aluminum V8an weighs a bit.
It became much easier to fit in with the gearbox.
I built my own flywheel and clutch.
-Where did you find this engine?
I bought it from a crashed car in Stockholm.
I know it worked when I picked it up.
I have gone through the engine and painted some covers.
The engine is silver in the middle but it does not fit here so I repainted it.
T04 turbo aggregates below.
Both turbo go to the Weastegat who sits here.
I have rebuilt gas dampers for other stuff.
The air to Intercoolers comes from the inner screens.
Race cats are sitting on.
The exhaust system is just under a meter.
-Hold people opinions that you have chosen a German engine?
Well, there is both and the main thing that it is V8 and double turbo I think.
-Had you built a chassis for a Porsche Motor?
Yes I had.
I had built the chassis at the back for the Porsche 928 engine.
I turned the whole chassis into this engine.
Then I rebuilt the entire rear wagon.
It is the engine that has been in since the inspection.
I haven't done anything with the car since then.
-Where do you get hold of all parts?
You can order because.
The cats are from KL-racing.
I had oil cooler from another car in the garage that I did not use.
Turbo I bought new ones.
Intercoolers I bought new ones from KL-racing.
The hoses come from Do88.
These are Santo hoses that I bought here in locally.
These clamps are not optimal if you have higher charging pressure.
-How much do you charge?
0.5 bar and that's nothing.
It's a fun machine.
-What does the engine have for performance?
I do not know.
I have not tried the engine too full.
The idea is not to be the fastest.
It should go and drive with it.
I should not be the fastest and operate around on a track.
It should hold and I drive hard it just breaks.
The plan is to drive without having to screw.
The hardest thing has been to make the gear control.
Wires that will steer the backdrop forwards that will match a 6 -switched box with back.
I think it's been the hardest on the whole car.
There are many holes in the body that air goes through.
Here air comes in through the hose that will cool down the turbo.
The warm air goes out through the grid at the back.
-Yeah, the warm air comes out here.
This is original Ferrari F40 taillight that I ordered from England.
I have made the frames around the lights and the whole frame with grilles with.
-What does the rear light cost?
They cost 5000 SEK/piece.
-You're joking!!
It was worth it but now they are cheaper.
Think you can buy them for SEK 3000/piece.
Or used online but mine are new.
5000 SEK /piece !!
It is SEK 20,000 for all 4.
All parts have made the car quite expensive.
-5000 SEK / piece is completely crazy!
Everything is so incredibly expensive.
A rear window costs SEK 56,000 so I can't afford it so I had to do one myself.
Side mirrors Original costs SEK 26,000.
-WAVA NOW, COST SUCH A RUTA 56,000 !! ??
Yes, these are really strange prices.
I made a template in masonite that I have spaced up to see how big the holes should be ...
... on the real box.
I have since cut up holes and glued.
Because I couldn't afford to buy the real box.
It didn't take that long to do.
It took me a couple of hours without any trouble.
I really want to redo it because I'm not really happy.
It must be so until further notice so I get done with the car.
These mirrors come from Corvette C5.
The original is a little more straight but these are good.
The car is 2 meters wide and I look back with these which is the idea.
-It is also very low.
Yes, the total height is 112 cm from the ground.
I have weighed it on a race because I want the weight distribution front and rear and per wheel.
And be able to weigh in for the springs.
The car weighs without oil in the engine, no fuel and no person in the car weighs 1082 kg.
I think that is good.
-To be a sheet car, it's great.
Everyone thinks sheet metal is very heavy but it is not.
If it is just sheet metal and nothing else it does not weigh that much.
-How thick sheet have you used?
It is 0.8 and then it is 2 mm in the bottom of the car.
It is thicker on the bottom because you do not want something to happen.
-Why is it called plate lady?
When I had it exhibited at the Elmia fair ...
... so there were so many who had their own reg signs.
To see the difference between my car and a real car online.
I wanted something so I put Plåtlady there because the car is made in sheet metal and Lady is red.
I want to be own with something and there is only one F40 in the world that is in sheet metal.
I have chosen to do it just why it goes.
It doesn't have to be in plastic.
Another thing that a F40 must have is the recessed emblem in the wing.
I have cut out and put a plate behind and then drove with a Dremel and it took a couple of hours.
-Ferrari red learn the car to be?
Yes it is lacquered in Ferraris red.
-The weird would be otherwise.
Yes that's true.
Now the car is just lacquered.
When I had the car at the Elmia fair a few years ago.
I mounted it and pulled on color to see what it would look like.
Then the varnish would be for a few years so the car to move a bit.
Now you can grind it out and paint it as it should be with varnish and clear varnish.
I don't have that now.
Now it's just varnish.
In the coming year it will be sanded and varnished so that it will be perfect.
-When can you see this on the road?
Yes, it is partly inspected.
It is SRFO inspected but there is run and sound test left.
It is ready to be inspected now.
It should be done in 2 steps.
One step is to check the chassis that it looks like a car.
Step 2 is run & sound sample so that it works like a car on the road.
That is what is left.
Then you go to the car testing and rules inspections.
-There are many who want you to start the car.
-But then you have to wait, right.
Well then you have to wait until spring.
-Then I'll have to come back.
-It's not weather outside.
No, it's cold and snow outside so I don't want to back out.
-I have to make a return visit instead.
Nice that we look forward to.
-I can say that you can say.
-Fantastic, 1000-thanks because you took the time.
Thank you for yourself for coming and thank you everyone who is watching.
-See you later!