We are a whole bunch of Brooklyn Choppers who are playing and playing.
Go home to Foppa and check out.
He has strange stuff so it's worth a visit.
-Tjena, Douglas.
Hello Peter.
-Here there were stuff.
Do you think?
A little crowded I can agree.
-But fun stuff.
Yes, I think so.
However, not my wife.
-What's that?
It is basically an HD engine and a frame in titanium so it should be lightweight and two pulse dick engines.
The same type of pulse dough engines as Hitler's V-missiles during the Second World War with these are scaled down.
-What do you get such an idea?
On the internet there is a lot but ...
... there are a couple of guys who call themselves black hole racing.
They run with a large pulse -cutting scooter at Speed Weekend in Årsunda every winter.
Those guys inspired me to build my own pulse dots.
-Do you drive with this?
This summer it has been resting because the thought burst.
It just can't run because it pulls about 8 liters of gasoline per minute.
So I'm not going that far.
-Haha, understands that it costs a lot to drive.
-It's decent exhaust.
Well, those who have been behind can certify how bad it sounds.
It over 180 dB and it is absolutely unbearable.
It is not possible to stand there even with hearing protection.
I'll fix the order for the summer.
Thinking about mounting it down because it is quite a potent Harley engine to just have as a drag bike.
Then I can use the pulse dick engines for something else.
But I haven't decided yet.
It is quite complicated, you have to be at least 2 in order to start it.
Then it is a little dangerous.
There are 4 high pressure pumps that can handle 230 liters were flowing.
But if any gasoline management burst, it will be a disaster.
I was lucky when the tank burst.
The idea is below the spreaders.
Had it splashing up gasoline on glowing pipes it could have been a fireball.
The temperature increases about 100 degrees per second.
And when it starts, you have to go right away.
The pulse dirt engine can be up to 10-15 seconds.
I have protective plates, but I can't sit as wide as possible.
The plate is so close to the pipes so the heat is not against so long.
When you stop gas, you have to move your feet from the footpegs.
Otherwise, the heat goes through the leather stand.
-You also has a bike that is a little special.
This?
Yes it is a smaller pulse seating than the motorcycle.
This one goes 35 km/h.
It's fun to go on.
-Haha, lovely tube.
-It's a classic 70s limp bike.
Yes an old boy bike.
-How often do you use it?
On festive occasions.
Does it also draw a lot of soup?
It is so small so it is not so dangerous.
You can run about 2 minutes on 2 liters of gasoline.
This is the economic vehicle.
It sounds most bad and does not go so fast.
-What are you in there?
I have a jet grill.
It is probably Sweden's fastest grill.
This is what it looks like.
You screw it on appropriate ground.
It takes about 30 seconds before it is red.
After 1 minute it is white.
Then you have to spin the sausage quickly.
Then it's done.
We tried to grill marshmallows but it became very bad.
They all started burning.
Sugar burns well we noticed.
If you want a quick grill, this is the one you should have.
It is environmentally friendly and goes on gas.
That's probably the only advantage.
-You have snowed in on Jet.
Yes, it goes fast and sounds fun.
-How often do you use the grill?
That's when the whole Brooklyn Choppers is out at events.
This is fast food, for real!
It gets the surface first but then the sausage must remain to be finished on the inside.
I would not grill pork on the grill.
Shall we go into the other room?
-Do you have more things?
Now you have missed the coffee maker.
-Do you have a coffee maker.
In this you make 30 cups of coffee in 3 minutes.
-Haha, jet coffee.
This one also sounds a lot even when it is so small.
In this coffee pot you see ..
... this is the body and this jet engine.
Simple!
We eat and drink coffee fast.
Great!
Thanks so much.
Thanks!
-Bye.
-And we'll see you in the next section.
Yeah!