When there is a lot to show on this building now.
Looking forward to showing all Kalle Duck Secrets.
I'm going to build a camper and do it with a different approach.
Like to be a little inventor and generally crazy
So I've gone all in on crazy ideas.
Hello Hello!
Hi Douglas!
How's it going?
Now it's good.
It was heavy a week ago.
Then I was pretty stressed.
The heat that has been here has not made it easier.
I am so happy that it is overcast now I can say.
It is almost thunder in the air so that it is now possible to breathe.
Now it is working and now I am almost done.
It's nice.
Almost finished you say.
Yes!
What does that mean?
Deadline and the budget I have withdrawn on this project,
But it usually belongs.
May 1 was set like my soft deadline and now it's last June.
So one week to approximately need me.
Then I'm done to go.
I would say i'm 90 % ready another week, say 95 % finished
And the last thing I do during the journey so that a week, ten days
Something is the plan.
Then I stick.
But have you slept in it yet?
Well, it's now that everything happens.
I have built the last week, ten days that
I have done surface layers on it.
It's Thursday today and on Monday I was
And also inspected it.
It is now that everything happens.
Wonderful congratulations!
Thanks!
It's nice to have that bit over.
I have set a deadline for myself that was not.
About any real reason.
Not just because I want to push myself.
It has been good and spurring.
But now, now that I pass on May 1st and that it was June 1st
so there are very many who have been on me
And it has become a stress feeling.
I knew you would miss this deadline
from the first day.
I also.
It was far too much work.
But the hat off!
You have done a fantastic job!
Even though I haven't seen it see it on the inside yet.
I'm so damn curious.
I have closed again and do not want to show anything.
I want to watch the reaction video to it.
But before we go in and look so, so some stuff has happened.
On the one hand, you have no pressure left.
No, the letters are gone.
On this page I have a few left on the other side.
It has been by far the most boring on the entire building.
There are two colors on a light blue, dark blue and the dark blue.
The sticker surface has crackled in the sun so you can pick square millimeters by hand.
With the nails do not go at all.
Doesn't it work with razor blades either?
No.
The problem is not that they are stuck.
The problem is that it is so brittle.
It crackles.
It is five times five square millimeters pieces that one gets away regardless
What technology you use.
But I have tried with razor blades I tried with chemically dissolve rubber pulleys,
As you grind away and everything works and everything takes exactly the same time.
It doesn't matter what technology I use one
and half an hour per letter to get it away
And I have no patience.
Is there so much else you need to do so it's an eternal job
that never ends.
Besides now that I've removed it, the cabinet is so matte of oxide
And behind it so you have stickers that are bright
And it is not possible to remove.
I have tried polish clay, I have done everything possible.
It ends with me having bought color and I come and paint.
Look what geeky!
Fy phase what bold!
Each battery has its own information display
to show the charge status on it.
So it's 14 kilowatt hours like a Nissan Leaf in battery capacity
Sisåd is 4-5 times as much as you usually have normal.
You have 2500 watts on the roof, which is also three times
More than people usually have.
There is an excess of energy.
That was the idea from the beginning.
And I thought it was so fun to drive it up there.
It was great fun!
130 kilos weigh the batteries and hydrome pistons
Draws 150 kilos each, they pallets.
The spoiler is left to plastic.
But that wasn't that the Star-Link would sit in it?
I have also slaughtered it.
The Star Link is motor controlled on a 3-foot.
But when I remove that mechanism, it's just Parabol itself
The surface I saved.
The one in turn is only five inches thick and as I will fold into the spoiler
So it gets fixed in horizontal position.
So it is simplified and.
Wondering how many people in the world are like butcher Star-Link?
I can say that surprisingly many on youtube
Have I learned a lot.
They start to go in and solder about components and so on
So that people can geek down in all subjects.
On this page I have.
I have an electric bike in the garage for longer tours
And then my plan is that when I get somewhere in Europe
Then I take the scooter and raise what to ask.
This is Durk aluminum that I have powdered.
It could not agree but mounted there an hour ago.
I have it down here too.
On the underside of the box.
It is like a design thing that you should have the dark
Because it is the same as it is on the back of the dock.
And you have fixed new hub caps as well.
They came there yesterday.
Big difference for a small money.
It does a lot for freshness and the whole.
There you have the key.
A and B are on the key.
Yes.
Remote control.
It is not possible to sneak with that opener anyway.
No, it's a winch for a quad bike.
It is very strong and works great, but it is definitely not quiet.
The quality is not the best on it.
Then it is the disadvantage that it sits on the back of the bed,
So it's basically a drum that sits on a wall only.
It has been silent it has been quieter.
When you are at some campsite we'll go five in the morning
and wake half the neighborhood.
They have to take that.
The floor here on the door is art material called Eva.
Eva plastic or Eva rubber.
It is a substitute for teak
which is endangered and you have to devastate it longer.
Used on large luxury hunts and so on.
Has this type of material instead of the teak.
It's soft to go on.
It is soft and it is not slippery when it is wet.
It's easy to keep clean.
You can even take it if it has been given color on dirt.
On it you can take sandpaper and sandpaper away the dirt.
It is superbly good material.
It is certainly very expensive material?
No, it is mainly 3m double -sided tape that comes on a roll
Just buy a 70 wide I think it was three meters long roll
As you roll out it just self -adhesive.
It was very simple and smooth.
In the garage I want to try to squeeze in some features even when I sit outside.
I will be jawing.
Also fold down we have a kitchen table where you have a seat.
Again, it is 95 % clearly what is left to do
will do during the journey.
One of the examples is that the underside of the table,
What you see now is done.
But I will make the surface of the table in burnt wood.
Same as I have on the kitchen table inside the car as well,
So I will do it during the journey.
The first part is that you sit and take one berred together with someone
and then because I am about to tinker and stuff
And need to fix so you have to have a workbench too.
So then you can do so that you continue to pull it out.
Here I will have hanging off the tools and putting a screwdriver.
So here it is like a workbench and because there I have storage.
It is four and a half meters of box that I have the opportunity
to have storage in.
One -third of the kitchen floor I use all the way to
to almost all the way to the back wall.
This is an electric bike.
Yes, it is an almost legal electric bike.
It is just over 250 watts, rather EU mop in performance,
But it is really easy to carry.
It is collapsible, but I do not need to fold it in the middle.
It is a detachable rule.
What is the range of things like this?
I have tested it without treading and it does somewhere around 50 km/h
So it is about five miles reach.
Not so much bike left of it.
Think it will cycle something?
Or will you just slide around.
The tramps are only symbolic.
I have three transport opportunities and the truck is one.
If you are in a small town small town, it can be crowded and booky.
I have the electric bike for long excursions, the scooter for short quick travel
Around different purposes with them.
But you have a regular interior door for the front door.
Inner door because I have the back tilp to fold
So it is technically speaking in, it is inside.
Welcome Tom My Crib!
Here it was cold!
I have on the AC so it gets cold
Don't know what to start somewhere.
Where do you want to start?
We can start with planning.
Everything that is from waist height down and down is micro, concrete,
Concrete on the cabinets.
It is a girl in Värnamo who has started a company
Who has helped me with that bit.
It's so looks like concrete, it feels like concrete.
It is a concrete although you apply as color.
It is also flexible and you can paint around round corners
And everything.
I love concrete so it's really cool to have it on all the cabinets
Then all horizontal surfaces, powder coated sheet,
Everything up to every 3D cork I am happy with it creates.
Without it, it is a very soft sound in here.
So the feeling now is a bit biased
But the feeling you come in is more apartment than a camper.
One of the reasons for everything taking such time
Is that everything is handmade.
I have not bought ready -made cabinets for there are no cabinets
Which is in line with the dimensions I wanted.
Everything from doors to cabinets.
The body and everything is handmade by me and it is an immense time.
Two pieces in the kitchen that are from IKEA.
That's the only thing that is bought.
Every gadget in here I have done to get what I want it.
Is it difficult to get it on film should you have an outdoor feeling indoors?
After all, it is Moldak's modules that are LED panels with high resolution photo
In front that creates a feeling of skylights.
In the peripheral vision you get a volume feel.
But it is still just a common lighting.
The reason I have this is of course
Because I have covered the entire roof with solar panels.
There is no square centimeter to squeeze into a window.
And you have no window anywhere.
Without I have this outside the truck so we have
A campsite where we are standing now and this is my window out.
It is a bit strange that the surveillance over the toilets is right now.
It's just random.
Parked is no coincidence but the problem.
I want the lake view, but it's busy
Of a lot of German motorhomes so there was no place for me.
I had to stand somewhere else
And then I end up in front of the toilet.
This is so when you are fifth on the ball.
Do you think of a good 140 wide in the box that I had
on previously a 120 bed.
So what has happened while I have lived in the box
is that I have learned very much from what works
and not working and it has made me have 120 bed in the box
When I discovered that 140 works.
I think it would be too crowded in the corridor, but
It will be just fine.
A wider bed and so I have removed ten centimeters
on the shower instead of a 90 wide.
Has an 80 wide.
It is good enough.
This in turn means I have ten centimeters
Wider kitchen counter.
So when I have lived in the box I have adjusted the drawing
So it has worked great.
Saw it on Youtube that the submarines have red light
Not to ruin the darkness so I did the same.
Now I extinguish here.
Then I have red led lights in two places
In the camper when you need to go to Pinka at night.
But the red light you find.
The fake wall I built expands 150 millimeters
and a side effect of it is that it looks like the air heat pump
is penetrated into the corner.
The invert to the solar panels get hot
and therefore I have a cooling directly from the AC
to an inverter that cools down the entire plant
So they cooperate.
In winter I have run air air heat pump with heat
So I have heat as well as any and the same thing now in the summer
Who cools just as well.
I am more than satisfied.
It is almost the best on the entire building is the air heat pump.
The one in turn generates condensation water that I fill
and uses for drinking everyday.
Then we have the closet, what keeps it 95 % finished
And should be painted and clear.
So I do that on the journey.
So there's nothing I care about now,
Without it, I take it a rainy day in Poland when I can't try
To tinker with something.
However, we have.
This is the bathroom.
Should there be burglary here, no one finds the bathroom.
No, but you have no shower in the ceiling but you run with hand shower.
Then I have a loose shower curtain that you pull for.
The shower is pretty special because it is a hybrid solution.
When I shower I pull out in the closet,
Pulls out the refrigerator so I have room and can shower.
Now it was a strange sound.
This was a strange error.
Is good when you start driving around with that extraction fan.
The propeller blades are gone.
It's just the engine.
Where have the propellers gone?
Interesting.
Yes, it is a prototype.
The shower is a hybrid solution.
It has been an exciting adventure.
I have been very popular at Electric company so I took help
of they tear their hair in despair.
So what we have done now is a PLC programmed shower.
It has the opportunity to set both the time and the temperature exactly
Like I want it.
You have three buttons where the first one is the filling,
The other is the shower sequence.
The third is the emptying sequence
So I want 17 seconds filling
to get two and a half liters of water.
If I set it with the right temperature, PLC is programmed and is quite unusual.
But it feels okay to shower that type of power center next door.
There are more who have said it.
The electricity company calls it the death shower.
They do not like 230 near the shower.
I think is messy.
No, I'm not worried about that, but the closest are the buttons.
Partly low volts and they are rubber -clad.
Then I will set a wall, an openable wall in front of the power center
So you stand and spray on it for something to happen.
You have to avoid that.
You can't go to the toilet unless you pull out the refrigerator.
Well, I have actually learned from this
That it is actually more space than you think.
I actually don't think I will pull out the fridge
As often as I had planned.
However, the wardrobe bit will of course go back and forth.
It is, as I said, that it works great.
And the need for the toilet in this is behind it.
Because it is the extra job to pull it out.
I don't think you care about that.
Especially not when you are in a hurry.
Then you have to prioritize other things.
This is my toothbrush and toothpaste and to make
themselves in order in the morning.
So there you have that part.
Directly left in the sink, you should wash and all this.
So this will be my bathroom.
Bathroom, separate toilet separately.
That's what I have to do now during the week.
The kitchen counter.
The kitchen counter is the same.
Powder coated black sheet metal that is cut out for water and so on.
I got it today 3 hours ago so it remains in the car now.
Haven't been able to carry it yet.
But it is the final thing is related to the entire kitchen department
So it will be tomorrow's job the kitchen table that I talked about is burnt wood.
Powder coated steel sheet in the center and then you have the outer edge
with burnt wood.
For me, the bed and the tables are.
The two fixed points that I do not want to compromise with.
So therefore a large table and it is an extremely stable table.
It in turn means that when I work that way.
Folds the screen.
Folds it out.
How can you sit and youtuba there?
Here I will sit and cut when I have more time.
Looking forward.
How did it go for you to film during this project?
I have accumulated a lot of material and I have consciously chosen
Not to cut anything and not post anything
because it has been so intensely in the building
That I did not simply have come.
Without now as I go away, I grab the bit
And bet on Youtube your career.
I will share the link here too for now when I release this
so you are out traveling and have it cozy and stuff like that
And then you probably produce lots of materials too.
Yeah, I've started to put out material on it
and it is while I built the box so that the next change on the channel
Become the building of the motorhome and then change.
Another change later on will be more a travel related youtube channel
so the channel is the same, but the content will shift some neighborly dependent
on the fact that there are different phases of the trip.
Can you see you get angry and so there?
So I get angry.
I have cut away everything like everything works on the first attempt,
As it always does in reality.
Where will be the first trip by the way?
Exotic.
Umeå!
I'll be north and say goodbye and say goodbye to family and friends
And then I pull Norway south, down in Europe.
But I thought like this when you leave Sweden now,
Which you do soon and is away when you come back,
Then I want to know how it went, how you have been
And worked and how you met people and stuff.
So please feel free to contact me then
So we do a follow -up to it.
Preferably because it may be interesting to see how the stuff holds together
And if it has become as I imagined.
I am extremely impressed!
Hat off!
Thanks!
And good luck!
Great to be able to follow this, really.
It has been an interesting project and I have received very
Very new friends on the journey.
Very very curious people.
It's been fun.
Hello Motor Nerds!
Here is a short update.
I am in the northern Netherlands.
I have driven through Sweden a bit through Norway
And then through Denmark and passed Germany recently.
Have just found a motorhome in the middle of the central town.
It has been mixed results.
I have sabotaged a lot of things.
Things have been broken, I have had to rebuild and change
And that's part of the test process.
But on the whole it was very successful.
The difficult thing about the building I have discovered is to build just.
Some things are oversized and others are under -dimensioned.
And so it can be.
But I am very pleased.
We'll see if there will be more updates, but have gone!