-Now i am back!
We will be able to follow this entire project.
Until Elmia it is intended.
Yes.
-The car should be ready at Easter, huh?
And Easter is since next year thank goodness.
It is the end of April so there are many months left.
It has happened a little neighbor since last time.
Yes some.
I have to get the body ready.
I've started here.
These plates and this door are done.
The foundation is clear but it must be directed.
It is a bit wavy after the English wheel.
It should be directed and smoothed out with armored file before starting to grind.
I have also made the moldings that will sit over the joints.
It's a front list, here.
I have had to shape it a bit because the convertible to lie against.
So I've had to lower it a bit.
This list is measured adapted.
It sits so tight so it can hardly be removed.
There is a screw bracket at the forefront.
So you attach it there and also to the back.
The strip is attached like this and then it is angled in place at the forefront.
From the beginning, this is a Volvo Amazon List.
As I have been directed because it has been bent in all directions.
Then I have heated the strip and stretch it out so it becomes completely straight.
Then you have to weld this one so it has something to attach in.
It can be tricky as it is thin material in stainless steel.
It goes well if you are careful.
It is the same type of strip but I have narrowed it so it gets pointed.
And got another shape at the bottom.
I have done this because the joint is much more pointed.
Then there had been air in between.
Now I have made the list a little narrower.
The width up here is the same.
The strip then becomes narrower all the way down.
It sits well and it is a good fit.
-Very good fit!
-How have you got all this?
Long nights hahah..or late evenings.
-It must be more than 4 hours a day?
On weekends it gets more, it can be ...
... up to 24 hours on a weekend.
It all depends on how many other activities I have to go on.
-You have dressed the entire rear!
Well it went better than expected actually.
-This was paper last time I was here?
Yes it was cardboard.
Since then I have finished the inner frame.
I finished it only then the painting I frame.
Then you template the frame and cut a plate.
It will be a long plate.
This plate has been elected in one piece.
And here is the cormorant.
It is not so easy when you are alone and should roll such a long plate in the English wheel.
Do not have friends who show up here?
Yes, but they don't like to work.
They are mostly here to watch.
-It's like me then ... yes.
You reinforce by adding an angle profile at the whole frame.
I attach the plate with welding bars so I get stiffness in the plate so I can roll the plate back and forth.
When I start rolling the plate, it becomes stiffer.
Then everything should be fitted.
Everything is hand -knocked around all falsaries.
It is not possible to do with a machine so it is the hammer that applies.
-What job!
-The difficult is to make two equal sides.
Making one is easier but the other must be equal.
I do not build this body that other car builders do.
They build fish skeletons in wood with wooden boards and then shape the plate after that.
Then you can oppose the plate and check that it fits.
I don't like working with wood ...
Then I would rather do this and template until it gets right.
It may take longer but it doesn't matter.
Then I do not have to make a skeleton in wood.
Then must have pretty good eye measurements.
It was a carpenter who once said ...
... a little oblique is not easy as long as you don't see it.
Should it be that it differs a few millimeters here and there it does not matter if no one sees it.
It has nothing to do with the construction if it gets a little wrong.
I think that is a little charming because then you see that it is handmade.
Should you collide with this car, you have to make the parts because they cannot be purchased.
The lock to the door sits here on the inside.
It's sitting here.
Now there is a spring here but it will not be needed when there is a rubber list here.
Then the door springs automatically.
Possibly there will be gas pistons or if there is to be a lock in a fixed position.
It works amazingly well.
-Shelt crazy what a job!
There is a lot of millimeter fit.
-This you have done this too.
Yes it is the bottom plate against the frame
Since the frame swings like this, it would have been difficult to get to the line.
If this line had continued down.
Then I thought it was nicer to put in a bit and get a straight line.
Which is consistent with this line.
Then there are 5 of these that reinforce.
All the way down.
We have previously seen a template in cardboard.
These are made of stainless steel and I have welded the end together.
I will glue screws on the back.
Which is worn into the holes and screwed up.
Here on the edge, a friend has made small brass hats coming ...
... glued so it looks like a brass knit.
Much like this but the others are too small for my lathe.
They are made in an automatic lap instead.
In the next stage it is ...
... the doors and torpedo.
The torpedo is just a basic construction so far.
Here, reinforcement beams should be put down like this.
So we a possible crash with a deer, moose or a passenger car.
So it should be a support up here.
So it can be folded down.
And don't go along so you sit safely.
For the doors I have made a template.
I will knock the plate around.
So I get a swing that goes together with the torpedo something here.
The plate from the torpedo will be curved and then the plates meet about here.
The door will follow the line and then down.
The other plate will be in line with the door.
The shape continues up in the dashboard all the way away to the other door.
The entire rounding on the torpedo will be hand -knocked.
I have made a special tool.
I squeeze it on the plate and knock around.
I have grooved it so it attaches to the plate and does not slip away.
The length I have adapting so you can make a turn without it getting angular.
We do this instead.
Attach this one.
That's how.
Then you have to knock the last one.
Also bend with a pliers.
Then you get the right round and then you have to move the pliers each after.
Then it will be the same rounding all the way.
It will be bent a little so it goes in all the way.
Then it becomes a soft line all the way.
-How thick is the aluminum?
2 millimeters.
It is semi -hard aluminum.
I don't want too soft for then ...
... then there will be no hardness in it and then it widens too much.
-Now we have a sound that made a comeback.
Now it sounds again.
The fluorescent lamp also wants to be included in film.
Yes the fluorescent lamp lives its own life in the garage.
-Yes it is quiet then it starts to crack.
When it comes to the interior, I have made a chair to begin with.
To see what can fit.
It is a prototype to be cut down so it becomes easier to step in and out.
Then make one to a chair.
This is the padding that will be used.
It will not look like this but will be in black leather.
Even leather here that will go around the edge.
A little of the aluminum will be visible because I want to share the raw material left.
A wall will be manufactured behind the chairs.
And the wall will swing as much as the body.
Here there will be a couple of speakers.
If it is possible to hear over the main but we will see.
I hope the car gets quiet anyway.
In the middle there should be a podium for the gear lever.
-Should the gear lever be high or low?
It gets very low.
It is a control from a boat.
It is probably from the 1920s.
I don't really know what it has been, but some kind of control for a boat.
This control should be gear lever.
-It will be an automatic box, huh?
The second slider will be to open and close the exhaust control.
And it should sit here.
I will not do anything about this.
It should look old.
However, I will make a cover here.
I'll try to get hold of a rug.
And it should be rough in the material.
A bit like a doormat.
A copy of the front lamps.
-Yes have we seen but what should they sit?
They should sit here.
It will be in between the moldings.
Then I will also put a reflex.
Have not decided if it should be lowered.
Make a recess and get this in.
Or if I hang reflex underneath.
We'll see how I do.
-Where are you thinking of putting the tank?
It may be under this sheet metal.
Then it will be built so that it will follow this line.
The idea should follow this line below the frame.
You should not see that it is a tank but that it should look like the body continues under.
-Is the thought from side to side?
Yes it goes inside the frame.
And the idea will extend here.
-Where should the fuel cap sit?
It will sit here.
It will be an old model with a quick opening.
-How big is the idea?
About 67 liters.
About 67 liters?
Yes according to my calculations.
I bet on at least 65 liters and then I can drive about 40 miles.
The car will pull more than 1 liter mile I can guarantee.
Well, a straight 12a drinks more than a liter.
Yes.
Then it depends on the gear you have on rear axle and how big wheels it is and how easily it rolls.
This car will not have such great resistance.
It's a pretty small and narrow body.
The air resistance will be quite small so I don't think it will be so dangerous.
Next time you come, I hope the torpedo and doors have started.
-It feels like you want to work on?
Yes there are some things to do.
-Then they have to wait for the next section.
You're welcome!
See you!
Bye.