Hello!
Tjena, Douglas.
Sven Billred.
-I have heard that you are going to do a project?
Yes it is true.
-When should it be finished?
Hopefully to Elmia 2019.
It should go.
-Is there any sketch on what it should look like?
Well, most of it is already in the head.
But then I found a picture on the internet on a car.
This one is quite similar.
I will not use any bonnet or screens.
The style itself will be like this with Boat-tail at the back and the front with similar lanterns.
-What do you have for background?
The fact that you have built more cars can prove the wall.
Well, I have built a 1927 Chevrolet that I have used for 10 years.
I also have a Willys from 1939 which was a 4 door that I have built into a coupe.
Exactly after the original.
And that's the only one in Sweden.
There are some Willys Cuper from 1940-41 but they are unusual.
-Cool!
If you are wondering what sounds, it is a fluorescent lamp that creak.
It's an old garage.
I've been here for over 30 years.
It probably needed to be renovated.
-What are you going to build?
It's this car.
From the ground up it is a 1929 chevrolet truck.
I have been able to use the frame and it will be a so-called boat-tail racer.
Which they were built in the 1920s to the United States.
With your own engine.
A straight twelve!
Which I don't think is somewhere.
I haven't seen anyone anyway.
So it will be an exciting challenge.
-How do you come up with that idea?
I don't know ... you want to be odd.
It is among the strangest and the coolest I have seen.
And that's the point.
I try to build as much as I can myself.
Most of what is visible on the car will be hand -made.
That is the big challenge to do something of its own.
-I wish I had your knowledge.
It is Småland's stubbornness most.
I have put in a year's work.
And on average 4 hours a day.
It's every free time I have.
The biggest advantage is that there will not be a drop of varnish on it.
The entire body will be built in aluminum, ground down and polished.
Everything will be polished aluminum.
It mostly depends on myself.
I will not be dependent on anyone else.
-Can you show us around a little neighbor?
Yes, we can start here.
Here I have started, the frame is reinforced, targeted and rusted.
The engines are mounted.
They are not assembled but sit in place.
The lamps are a copy of Wood Lights as they are called in the United States.
They were very common in the 20-30s on prestige cars.
Very difficult to get hold of and terribly expensive.
They are handmade.
They are made of aluminum and brass.
Behind here you have the blinker.
Inside, there should be 2 lens lights from a motorcycle.
2 pcs 50 mm to half and high beam.
If you had to change a lamp.
Now this is this joint lighting so it is not often needed.
Hinges so you can open.
LED flashers and here the lamps should sit.
I have made my own brackets that should be in Art Deco style.
Then I had to make my own mold in wood.
Then I handed it in to Vetlanda foundry that made 3 so I have one in reserve.
So you can't buy.
-Oh my God!
Since the front lights were special, I had to do the special taillights.
Then I made these in aluminum with some brass.
Inside there is LED lighting from an MC.
Blinkers, parking and brake light.
-What do you get the ideas from?
I want to do something no one has done.
Ideally, there should be no one who has done anything like it.
-I think you are pretty lonely.
I haven't seen anyone else.
The radiator is the only thing I have not manufactured myself.
It is an aluminum cooler.
The cooler shell and the grill are its own manufacture.
The grid will be water cut in stainless steel.
It is going on with this pattern.
The grid will resemble a net but be much more stable.
This is a sample piece that has been cut into water.
The suction and the plates that sit here are water cut.
The exhaust pipe is backed by Ferrita in stainless steel.
Now it should be welded.
It will be the big job when it will also be polished.
There are many hours left on that exhaust pipe before it is finished.
Here I have more waterborne details.
And they should be welded together and sit here.
There will be the suction pipes.
There will be a tube along the engine where 3 carburetors sit.
-Hher God what a job.
Yes it is a puzzle.
-And everything should be welded and polished.
Yes.
-It will take an hour or two maybe.
Hahaha.
Here is the size of the rear wheel.
There are 17 "rims but it was not in the right size.
So I got to buy these rims and cut up and narrow off the rim so they should fit the tires I bought.
You can see on the inside where the cormorant is.
A snobbring will be mounted so you do not see the welding joint.
It should be founded before I put on the snob bridge.
The rutram and here is the shape of the cab so I'll see how it will be.
All this is made of aluminum that is filled with chemical metal to gain stability.
Then it becomes like a molded piece.
The cab will be glued on this plate.
So you can fold it down like this.
There is a lock on here on top.
It will be a brass plate with keyhole.
And then a spring in stainless steel.
This spring is provisional.
The principle is that you use a spring as a lock.
An exhaust system with silencer in stainless steel.
With a classic fishtail piece.
A little strange design on the muffler.
-The doors then?
They become completely newly made.
With your own frame and leather.
The door will be in this size that I have drawn out.
-Baktill so the 30s look like.
Yes, this is a model called Boat Tail.
It is that it looks like an up and down turn a boat.
In most cases, they did this in one piece.
I have done this as luggage so I can open.
This is the frame for the luggage door itself.
It is mostly for me to be able to pick up the cab ...
... Remove it and put it in.
The luggage is made according to the size of the cab.
-What is the next part of projects?
Now I am doing the skeleton on the body.
These are these parts that are bent and heated.
All the pieces will be welded firmly.
Then it will be dressed in aluminum.
These pieces too.
First, I have to complete the skeleton.
It is a lot of millimeter fit so it gets right from the start.
Here there will be lists.
This is a stainless steel prototype.
5 lists will be here.
I do this to make it a little life in the body and not just smooth sheet metal.
And it works as a reinforcement so it becomes more stable.
Then we have the interior ...
Then I made my own chairs in aluminum.
In a bomber Seat piece.
The dashboard is own manufactured and the rose polished.
Here there will be a tachometer.
With a pointer from a mora clock.
So it is big and clear.
-We look at the engines too.
There are 2 engines from Chevrolet Nova at 194 cubicum.
The engines were very nice when I bought them but will be completely renovated.
Straight sexes were often replaced to V8or.
Then the engines had not gone very far.
These engines have not gone beyond 3000 miles.
They were very nice on the inside.
Will change pistons and layers, etc.
The engines sit together on their own frame.
So they are silently mounted in this frame.
That part is suspended with rubber suspensions in the truck frame so it becomes a unit.
-How do you get the engines go together?
With 2 machine reefs.
One is turned like the flywheel and the other as the flywheel damper.
But reinforced, the weakest link on this engine will be the flywheel damper.
There, the shaft is the thinnest and there I have good size and larger packing boxes.
And more powerful locking.
It is connected with a double chain.
Water pumps are removed so that there are electric pumps that circulate one engine at a time.
There are double outlets on the cooler.
That one becomes the front engine and the other to the rear.
-The valve cover, have you taken it from a Finnish ferry?
Hahaha!
It is own manufactured.
I made a tool so I could smoke this pattern.
I did this on a smooth plate and bended with small bends.
This is what you can grind out and polish.
This is oil filling for the engines.
There will be 2 pcs here.
This one turns into the front engine and this one to the rear.
-You are the man of details.
That's the fun.
You can come up with something then manufacture it.
These are window hooks used on windows on the inside.
It is spring loaded and you can adjust the hardness.
They will be locks for inspection hatches on the engine.
I thought the style fit well.
Most screws and bolts are recessed.
But original was everything riveted.
Then I have turned rivets in brass.
And will be mounted here and glued.
So it looks riveted as it was original.
A therapy work when you are a little tired.
Then you can stand at the lathe and do these.
Only ordinary brass is polished.
-We others watch the football World Cup ... This will be something cool.
I hope no one else has done anything like it.
I can almost guarantee that no one has.
-Then we'll see if there have been any progress when I come back.
I hope so.
-Thanks for now.
Hello!