Hi, my name is Tobias and I work as a prosecutor in Eskilstuna.
I love my job as a prosecutor!
It is both exciting and varied and I feel that I often have the opportunity to make a difference in people's lives.
There were many reasons for me to apply for a medium -sized Swedish city.
My family and I had the opportunity to buy a house, without making a housing career in a larger city.
So now I live in an urban area outside Eskilstuna but I can still cycle to work in about 20 minutes through wonderful nature.
As an employee of the Prosecutor's Office, I am entitled to wellness, one hour a week.
When the work allows, I come out more often than that.
And it suits me perfectly, because I train to survive mountain marathon this summer.
So that's why I'm going to the local ski slope and now run for lunch.
As an employee of the Prosecutor's Office, I have confidence working hours.
And of course it means that I sometimes have to sit on a Sunday night and prepare Monday's goals.
But above all, it means to me,
A certain opportunity to dispose of my working hours I want.
And it has facilitated incredibly, in my everyday puzzle with toddlers, pick -ups and remains.
Do like me, become a prosecutor!