My name is Krister Hertting and I am project manager for Hilf-
-A project on immigrated women's health and way into Swedish society.
A sub-project within the high school's focus area health innovation-
-Focusing on women's path into leadership in the Swedish sports movement.
The project helps to find strategies that help sports to greater diversity.
We take a trip in the elevator and I'll tell you more.
Many children and young people participate in Swedish association sports, but girls with-
-Informer background is the group that participates at the very least.
The representation is also oblique within the leadership.
Generally, more men than women are leaders and-
-Ist represented are women with an immigrant background.
Therefore, a challenge for the sports movement will be to increase the diversity of leadership.
In an ongoing research project we interviewed immigrated women-
-If their experience of how they got into leadership positions in Swedish sports.
The results show that many women had a strong inner drive-
-Va äve personal meetings and any special person who supported-
-played a big role, sometimes even through contacts and activities at-
-For example, refugee homes.
But the results show above all-
-Th the need for purposeful strategies to recruit and retain-
-Immigrated women in sports leadership.
If you want to know more, you will have a great contact with me, thank you very much.