My name is Jasmine Tuvesson and I study Mechatronics Engineer-
-At Halmstad University.
And right now we are in Fab Lab.
I chose this program as I have always liked technology from an early age.
I ran around in the garage with dad and played with cars, bicycles and boat-
-And that's when I got this great interest in technology.
But I have also liked computers.
Computer games, both \ hardware \ hoch software have always been interesting.
So it was quite clear that I would choose mechatronics-
-Then it is a great mix of the entire engineering orientation.
I chose the University of Halmstad because it is close to my family members-
-Personally, I like a little smaller schools when you get the family feeling.
The best thing about my education is the ability to learn one-
-Sid range of these technical modules.
And then I refer to electronics, mechanics and computer science.
I have been able to be in Germany as an exchange student.
With the help of Halmstad University, they have helped me with an internship there.
So I have made an exchange half-spring-
-and six months as a trainee there.
I would like to work in the industry.
After doing my internship in Germany, I will now also read my master there.
I will read Industrial Security and Safety.
Possibly I would like to work at a medical facility.
And then help to produce medical technology for hospitals or-
-The dentist clinics and so on.
If you have what is required and if you want to become an engineer-
-So it is a very good start to get a good education and ...
-A good working life.