Student life in Halmstad.
Student Stephanie tells.
Hi my name is Stephanie and I read-
-IT-Forensics and information security at Halmstad University.
Right now I am on the western beach.
The best thing about plugging in Halmstad, I think is Halmstad.
It is a fairly large and very cozy city.
It is close to everything and I think the university is great.
The people are very wonderful and it is a fairly large school.
It is easy to get in touch with the teachers to get the help you need.
My favorite place at the college must probably be up at D5.
D5 is the floor is where we, IT forensic, for the most part.
There are our lab rooms.
There is also the opportunity to sit and study with their friends.
You can bring your lunch and sit there and eat, there is micro and everything.
So there I usually hang.
I thought the zeroing was great fun.
It was really noticed that those who planned were involved.
They had spent a lot of time and energy to make sure we zero-
-would get as fun as possible.
One got to see a lot of halmstad-
-What I thought was good because I am from Gothenburg.
You got to know a lot of new ones so when you started school-
-So you were not alone, but you had already come to know some.
Which I thought was wonderful.