Well, we are Jubël.
Fun that you have found here.
Today we will talk prejudice about Halmstad-
-The student life in Halmstad and University.
Welcome here.
Who do we have in front of us?
My name is Fannie Andersson and I study as a sports psychologist.
Right now I'm in the second year.
My name is Timmie.
I plug in business economics at the master's level here-
-and I've just started my third semester.
My name is Elin.
I read my third and last year on the business system program.
Who are we, then?
- Victor is my name.
- Seebastian is my name.
We are also Jubël - music duo from Halmstad.
Born and raised in this wonderful city.
And we are here today for us to run some prejudice.
We're starting the first question, I guess.
Are you ready?
I think so.
Throw some jingle here.
Students do only three things-
-Plugs, partying and gym.
- Otherwise, that's not wrong.
-No, it is not.
- It sounds like student life.
- Yes, that sounds wonderful.
It's kind of a clock that always goes around.
It's probably also because we have so many gyms here in Halmstad.
After all, there are almost as many gyms as pizzerias.
Most people who are studying at the university are from Halmstad.
Since I go for a master's program, I only have international classmates.
So I plug with classmates from all over the world.
-International.
-Really.
It is one from Halmstad, we are 3-4 pieces from Sweden-
-And then we have Europeans, some from Asia and from South America.
Exciting.
It is only played Per Gessle at the pre -parties.
–... and Jubël.
-Exactly.
-No.
-Not?
Jubël maybe, but not Per Gessle.
- It's not my ... - plus points.
Continue like that.
There is no student life in Halmstad.
Is it true?
Absolutely not.
It may not look the same as in the big student cities-
-But we have two student pubs.
-Tell me more.
Where is that?
-Exactly.
It is Lilla Smålands, which is located in a small basement at Nyhem.
-Still.
- Frightened, after all.
Then we have our big student pub Little heart-
-while driven by the student union.
It feels like the students have a secret life.
-Yes.
- Yes, a little so.
As a non-student, it doesn't feel like there are so many students in town.
- No, we stick to our pubs.
- With your community.
So don't get there and ruin.
I think it has to do with campus being outside.
It is not outside town, but it is not in the center-
-Or you have it a little south.
And then it becomes like the bubble we live in ports in that direction.
This side of the railway, so to speak.
And you do not want to put 300 bucks on entry.
-No.
- No, that's right.
If you cog your first exam you will be turned off.
-No.
But many are probably afraid of that-
-If I first coach I will never do this.
- Is it more a matter of setting?
-Yes.
Have you cogged?
-Not yet.
-Yes.
—Mixed.
Okay.
- But God ... - it does well.
You come directly from high school-
-And then it is not uncommon to pass all the tests right away.
But it's a completely different thing here.
There are much larger tasks and tentor-
-So you are not really prepared for that kind of test.
But it's totally okay to cog an exam.
You are not suspended and sent home.
You plug in.
Maybe an angry text message from mom saying: now you have not plugged-
-And then you say: No, I haven't.
You must have a green card in golf to get people to record you in Halmstad.
I really don't hope so, because then I'm run.
Then I have to move.
Is it a lot of golf talk?
Now you did not have many with Halmstad connection.
No, but many in my class play golf.
Halmstad is a golf city.
Yes, there is a lot of talk about it.
But now it has almost become more frisbee golf in the summer.
Yes, it has become a thing, I have seen.
What about paddle then?
Oh, all students have probably tried it at some point.
- We tested it.
- We talked about booking another.
You have complexes not to be as old and rich as Lund University.
Is that so?
-No.
- No, so we ...
Halmstad will never be Lund, and is not Lund-
-And we don't want to be Lund.
All bikes in Halmstad, regardless of the weather or wind.
How else should you get there?
Not a bus?
- Is there no buses?
- It's so close so it's unnecessary.
You still live at the far end.
Yes, it takes me 7 minutes to cycle.
Where do you live?
About at the City Library.
There is no distance and this is missing now that we have moved from here.
It is a damn mecca with collective here and there.
I imagine it is so in larger cities.
It is a project wherever you go.
I miss my bike.
- You have bought a new bike.
-Yes.
Cycle on it.
When the college comes on speech-
-Can you don't stop boasting about how good looking and cool the school is.
- We said that before.
- Yes, it's very nice.
I think many people get stuck for the big tower - Trade Center.
That it is visible everywhere-
-And it is the more modern thinking with glazed.
But does it have anything to do with the university?
The campus area is an area that not only consists of the university.
We take the majority of places here-
-But there are small businesses and the Trade Center is a place for different companies.
But we as students may be lucky to have lessons and other things in the Trade Center.
- You have to drink alcohol during zeroing.
-No.
You really don't have to.
But many people think so.
It is because that is what is in all articles.
Yes, but Halmstad's zeroing is not like zeroing in other cities.
I have been in x number of different cities-
-And was surprised when I came to Halmstad and didn't get a beer in hand-
-What we drive sober and have kind of soda in the days.
Late in the evening there is a party if you want.
Feels spontaneously really sensible.
Yes, it's fun to get to know their classmates in sober state-
-But still under zero.
If you are over 28, you are too old to study at college.
No.
No, I really don't think so.
We have one that is 32 in our class and he fits perfectly.
Sure, we are very young in our class- 97s, 98: or-
-It's some 94s, but then he comes and raises and is 32.
No matter how old you are, you can always start over.
You should always find what you want to do yourself.
Who is the oldest who goes to school?
- Oh, there is ... — it must be some record.
There are, after all, the courses that provide a professional degree, such as teachers-
-And nurse, and I think they have a higher average age.
It is not to late.
There must be some record on it.
Someone who is 65 or 70.
After all, there is a limit to when you can take CSN.
I think it's just before retirement.
Switch over from CSN to retirement.
There are re -exams but no surrounding parties.
Yeah.
- For us who cog exams, so.
-Thanks.
- Unfortunately, I couldn't stop it.
- No, okay.
The thing is well that I say that you have to value it-
-If you should be diplomatic in saying that was the way it was.
Yes, you might not go out to cog, because you want to party-
-But the possibility.
Has it been so ever that it has been a party, but you have to plug-
-But shit the same -now we drive.
I combine it then.
You bring the book with you then?
- Yeah.
-How?
- It's great.
–I have been sitting evening-
-What you should go out, so I-sits-
-Then we are a bunch that has a small party.
Then I spontaneously get some help too, when you have a submission.
And the faster you have written it clearly, the faster you can move on.
Then you can't determine the quality of this.
Then you see on the paper that it starts well, but then it is just ...
- It is lucky that we have computers.
-Yes.
It starts with writing style, as the first time you wrote ...
It's been a long time since he went to school.
He only wrote on paper.
It is not possible to understand the Dutch dialect.
Then we could not have this discussion.
No, exactly.
- You are still the farthest from here.
- Do you understand us?
Yes, yes, it was difficult in the beginning.
I still have to say that.
But those who come from Skåne speak so mushy so ...
Yes, but that's something else.
Halmstad is a mix there.
Yes, but they swing on the words all the time when they talk.
It was difficult to understand in the beginning.
But, don't you think so?
-I do not think so.
-No?
They Joddles Fram: Servant.
Students only eat noodles.
-No.
- Food boxes.
- Food boxes with noodles ...
...just kidding.
Do you have any budget?
Do you go after the cheapest?
When you see spaghetti, do you take the cheapest kind?
- Or you go too little ... - no, I always think about taste.
It is no idea to eat if it is not good.
- a little so ... - quality over quantity.
Very good.
In Halmstad there are more gyms than grocery stores.
-Yes.
- If you count on it, it certainly does.
Students drink more coffee than water in a day.
- Is it a lot of coffee?
I look at you two because I don't drink coffee.
- Coffee, type.
-Yes.
I've gone down now.
I went from 10 cups to type 3.
--Wow!
- It's still strong.
–10 cups.
- Yes, it is almost heart attack.
I had a week when I tried, when I locked myself.
Nobody wanted to be with me right then.
Yes, but ...
- There will be some cups in one day.
- Yes, it will be.
It was the last prejudice we had.
What have we learned today?
We have learned that there are more gyms than pizzerias.
Everyone in Halmstad plays paddle.
Golf is no longer relevant.
Paddle and muscles.
And there is a nice community between all students.
I thought it was nice.
This was everything from us.
We are Jubël.
We hope you thought this was fun and educational.
- students - out in life.
-Thanks.