Hello!
Do you know, what is time for today?
It's actually time for an Always Vlog!
This video I do in proud collaboration with Always
Binds, everyone!
Nostalgia, or what.
For those of you who may not have been with me for so long, I have actually worked with Always before.
A few years ago I made a full seven videos with them for six months
and they were so much appreciated
So I appreciated so much that you appreciate them so much
Now I and Always have
struck our brilliant skulls together again
It's time for a new Always vlog
And today I was going to talk about "Keep Going Like A Girl"
2014 I made an always vlog that was about the phrase "like a girl"
If one does anything "like a girl"
Then there is something that by definition in a bad way
They throw like a girl
They drive like a girlfriend
Or on the other hand
To do just about anything 'like a man'
Wow.
Cool, stable!
Like a man-like man!
Man up.
Grow some balls.
And this one might think is really strange
Because half of the world's population is girls
Or women.
Or girlfriends.
And about our identity
used as a slang to do something in a bad way
... then it's pretty sad.
I'm not going to agree to this
It can be repeated simply, so today we drive again.
But today I was going to talk about the phrase "keep going like a girl".
I think many people can recognize that you find it difficult to fail.
And like not just, uh, it doesn't work this time
It was sad, but again.
Without more ...
Oh no!
Everything is ruined, I will die!
And I also think then there are many who even shit in testing
Because then you avoid that risk of failure.
But this is really stupid.
It is clear that you have to be able to fail sometimes.
And this is exactly what Always and I want to change.
Keep Going.
Keep Going, Like A Girl.
Or as a guy, if you would rather.
Or as a queer, or as a human being.
Or like a boss ass bitch.
I am a girl, and I think deep down that everyone should "keep going like me".
But I'm thought or not, damn good at meat like a girl sometimes.
But I think it's not just girls using bindings.
So that I asked Always if it is okay to interpret the expression freely,
To throw in what one is or wants to be
And Always Ba, Woohoo, Keep Going Girl!
And the main point is thus, Keep GOing Like A Girl.
Maybe because girls are the best.
But I don't know.
And I know it's super easy for me and sit here and pray:
Come on and dare to fail!
But believe me, this is a struggle for me with.
Do you know what, I'm the worst at failing.
Not because I'm a bad loser.
I'm neither a bad loser nor a bad winner.
But I just think it's hard to disappoint myself.
Can we only agree that bad winners are ten times more difficult than bad losers?
Oh!
I much rather avoid situations there
There is a small risk that I can fail.
Than to throw myself in with a chance to actually succeed.
Which then means that you are a little stupid.
Because you miss out on very fun things.
Here comes a list of three really fun things that I have lost because I simply
Is too scared to fail:
One: dance pass at the gym.
The dance pass looks so fun.
But I think I'm too bad at dancing.
And then I don't even want to try to learn.
Because I know that I will fail
On the way to me having learned.
That is stupid
Two:
To apply for certain jobs or training.
I could really pray:
Apply.
And the absolute worst that could happen,
is that I would get a no.
But: This no is so scary.
The idea of going on a job interview
Or do an intake test
And black on white that: No, you're not good enough.
You have failed.
That thought
Is so much more difficult than what happiness would have been great
If I had actually come in.
I suck.
IM worthless.
I will die .
Poor and alone.
And cold.
Brr.
Three:
Standup.
This is so speaking,
Given that I am actually doing humor.
I think this;
Youtube, my occupation
Have elements of humor
I make an effort.
I want my videos
Must be entertaining and fun.
But the idea of facing an audience
And that the audience might not think I'm fun
Aaaaj, my heart.
I have wanted to test standup for four years.
FOUR YEARS.
I have booked in on three different gigs, and then pull myself out.
Two weeks before.
It is so tough
It may be the case that the thought
On failing is more difficult than an actual failure?
OH DAMN GIRL, THATS DEEP!
But I also think that in this total
The life of life to fail
Then you have succeeded with other things
By simply forgetting that you may be able to fail them.
Here some things that I have succeeded
Although I am absolutely fucking scared to fail:
I cut off all my hair.
Twice.
I became a freelancer.
And started an individual company.
And then a limited company.
And I failed twice before I finally understood how to fill in this damn form.
And then I moved here
To Stockholm.
From Gothenburg.
When I was 19 - I knew 0 people here.
And it is more difficult than you think to have to build up jobs, accommodation and social interaction
Completely again
I felt so lonely and unsuccessful for almost a year.
But now I have lived here for four years
And I'm so happy that I dared.
Inspiration!
So how do you do, to keep going?
I think it's super important to practice failing.
And because it is so terrible
You can start hard to start easily.
Buy a scratch card and try not to be disappointed unless you win anything.
On the whole, it is also a failure.
and then you can start increasing their failures
Look for a job!
That you won't get.
But!
Do not set yourself not to get it.
Set yourself to bet.
The risk is then that you will not get it.
There is a great risk that you will fail.
But what if you get it then.
Sometimes you may even have to test
Something that is doomed to failure
Just to learn to feel that feeling
Are one's failures so heavenly dangerous
I mean it's just ... Dreams ...
Like ... crushed ...
And the thing is that if you succeed, then you will come forward.
You are coming up.
But if you fail ...
Then you stay there.
You don't go backwards.
You don't get any worse.
You just ... stay there.
And then you have to try again.
Keep Going.
I believe in you.
And that was what I and loved Always wanted to talk to you today.
Failure ..
With now it is actually like this:
In a few weeks I will make one to Always vlog
and in that video i will expose myself to something
As I have been dreaming of for several years
But never dared to test because I am simply too scared to fail.
I'm so heavenly heavenly nervous.
Aah!
But I'm so tired of just holding back
Time to just go!
And Keep Going!
And so you want to be a little inspo too
And say: I can, so you can!
You don't want to miss this!
And i will reveal on my instagram in a few days
What it is that my challenge is
Aah!
Do you think it's hard to fail?
If you have fun failure stories, please write a comment and tell.
Friends, this was everything I had for today.
Thank you for checking and thank you always!
See you later!
Bye!
Take it beautifully and we will see just as usual the next Monday.