.........
My name is Joanna Lundin and working as
NPF educator at Källbrinksskolan in Huddinge.
And what I do, purely physically, is that I
wrists, coaches and educates students,
Parents and staff around NPF.
My name is Maria Koskinen and I am
Program manager here at the ESS high school,
on our social science program.
In my program responsibility I plan schedules,
service distribution, structures around meetings
and I am a link between students, teachers
And all staff and principals.
My name is Carina Backström and working as
Swedish teacher at high school.
My name is Emelie Sköld, I'm a teacher at
The ESS high school in Swedish, and is also a mentor
in a grade one class.
The biggest challenge in working with
Pupils with NPF is about emptying one
on energy, that they are so intense.
It's all or nothing, in everything.
While it is a challenge,
that is both tough and positive, that they think
outside the box.
That one all the time yourself
Must think outside the box.
We have to try to adapt as much as we can
after all of our students' needs and at the same time
Challenge, develop our students as much as possible.
And keep these two perspectives together
All the time, it's not always that simple.
Something that is important is that today's teachers are
Extremely flexible.
One cannot do a planning
And think that it should be followed to the point.
That's not the important thing.
The important thing is to
Students come to learning.
And maybe they were
Takes other ways than I had imagined.
But it does nothing, rather the opposite.
It is about activating them, that actually
Boll back, start discussions, get with
them in that "what do you want for something?"
and "What do you need?"
For we are good at that
come up with solutions all the time, say that
"This is what to do".
But that applies
to get with the student, that the student himself feels
that “I have the opportunity to influence and I
gets listened to ”.
The good thing to think about with these students
is that they often have a great vulnerability from school,
That they may not have received the support they needed.
Therefore, it is important to catch them quickly.
And I think it's a lot about attitude,
That we believe in the students, that everyone can.
That regardless of the conditions, we find
tools that hopefully make everyone
reaches in goal.
And reach their own goals, above all.
Otherwise we here at school think of in our
response, it is not to sit and cave
In what doesn't work.
Without looking at it
which is actually good, to work on the basis of pupils'
needs and students' strengths.
What is
Great, just when sitting in coach calls
with the students, is that they most often
Know themselves what they need.
That i can do
is to help them formulate and present
That for the other college, "This needs the students".
At the beginning of the autumn term we always have one
In-calls, enrollment calls, where we almost
interviewing the student, about what it feels
That it needs.
It may be about that
have to go out of the classroom shorter periods,
double sets of teaching materials, that one
want things to work with, with your hands
At the same time as you have a lesson.
We'll find out
Very much through these in calls.
What conditions we have to work with
and how we can develop together,
Me and the student.
An important part of the environment, in terms of
Aids, we call our SOS boxes.
In it there are lots of tools for students who
Need different types of aids.
It may be that one needs to sit on a cushion like
moving litigant, or a stress ball that
Pill with when I go through something.
It may be about visualizing time by the fact that
use a clock, where I show that
"Now I'll talk for ten minutes, then you have to take a break."
And so we have furnished on a little
different ways than we have done before.
There are pilates balls, standing tables, individual
booths to sit in, for example.
And the most important
part, as the students think is the best,
These are our time-timers.
A clear time tool
Which the students like very, very much.
For students with NPF it is important not to
have lots of distractors in the classroom, that it
there is a structure, that it is order and find out,
that not things lie in different places and
are hard to find.
Without us trying to hold
A structure as clearly as possible.
We have home classrooms, we choose to students
may stay in a classroom and that the teachers
moves on instead.
We have also done
A huge work during the summer where we have
removed student cabinets from the corridors and
Instead, chosen to have cabinets in the classrooms,
Just to save on the energy, to not the student
should go out, not remember which book they
Should pick up without getting back with the wrong book.
Without they have the books in the classroom so we
Easy to move on in teaching,
Although they do not have the book with them.
We also have a fixed structure in front of
the board in all classrooms, where we have the headlines
what lesson it is, what time the lesson is in progress,
when it is break, and what, how and
why.
So we clearly write up
what to do, how to do, and why we should
do it.
And so we have one last heading that
is "what should I do when I'm done?",
so that the student can continue to work,
Some are quickly ready.
But above all, I think the environment, I am.
I create the environment through my leadership,
by being in the classroom.
By the whole
Time with my way of being sets boundaries,
shows what is ok, dialogue, make it become
Lusty and fun.
So the most important bit
In the learning environment, it is the teacher.
We have made a number of adjustments of it
physical learning environment as well, the one that one pure
Krassst can see, as part of our NPF fuse.
Things we've done is that we have big,
clear watches in the corridors and
in the classrooms for it to be easy to
Keep track of time.
We have made sure it is
neutral and colors that are connected to
The school, so it should be calm impressions.
We have sofas in the corridors that are sound attenuated.
When one sits in there it is like a small
Koja, it's really nice to sit in there.
We have clear markings of where halls and
Expedition is there so it should be easy to
Find for the students.
Often when talking about making adjustments
Do you think of everything you can't do,
and we have tried to turn it around and see what we have,
Which is positive.
This is an old school
built in the 60s, with long corridors,
quite small classrooms, and there are none
Group room.
But we have done as best we could
With what we actually have.
And tried to see what
Is positive with our premises.
The changes
We have done has not really cost anything.
It is about changing the way of thinking,
About knowledge and about response.
For these students it is extremely important
with structure.
They need to know what
expected of them, what to do, when they are going to
Do it, and how to do it.
So that you
have a clear agenda on the board, one has the time
for the whole lesson so everyone knows when starting
and ends, one has a clear start and one
Clear end to the lesson.
And that I'm the one
that controls this structure, one might say
That I am the structure.
I say “Welcome,
be good to sit, close the toads,
Here I am, welcome to Swedish, today we will ...,
We start with ”, and so on.
"Now you are going to ..." that you are extremely clear with what
as expected of the students.
After all, all students feel good about it.
Structure is, as I said, very important for those
Here the students and we work with a
Color coding system here.
That means we have
Color coded, for example, you have Swedish
so it is red on the schedule, and so you have a
red cover and a red sticker on it
Teaching materials used.
So then they can just look;
"Red, then I bring the red with me".
It demands
not so much, they don't have to waste energy
On reading and looking, without they can only find it.
Very practical!
I try to create structure by using
PowerPoints that are clear, with which lesson
And where we are.
Clear start-up, clear end of the lesson-
much with the help of the structure we have on the board
But also checklists with what we will
do today, so they get the confirmation that
We have moved on.
And time-timers, that
We decide that we should have a review in
Ten minutes and then I can't go on
Talk, but then it's time to move on.
So it is also part of our structure.
As for the teaching, it is
very important that when you have had a review,
Then I know which students may
Have lost focus.
Directly up to them,
asks “are you with now, look here, we'll start here,
do this ". You might make special schedules for
Some students, "Do you know, do these three tasks now,
and when you're done
can you listen to a song, then you reached up
The hand I come and help you ”.
When students get longer jobs that maybe
should last for a while it is important to help
The student to stay focused all the way.
That man
can do as an educator is partly that one has
reconciliations.
They may work maybe two lessons,
then man gathered and has a reconciliation-
"How's it going, how are you located, what do you need to think
on now? ”If they work independently you have
maybe reconciliation with a student- “Ok, you are
here, remove that and do this. "So that
one all the time is with them on the way to
the goal and all the time point to it as they have
succeeded with.
We try not to have homework in that sense.
It is clear that there are tasks that sometimes
need to work with outside lesson time but
By the majority of occasions we try to see
to the fact that there is lesson time to work but
We also have the time of study as we know that many
Take advantage of.
So the idea is that they should not
have to take home lots of school work.
Not everyone has
the same conditions to plug at home.
Some need to rest and do something completely different
to recover for the next day.
I adapt my teaching by
try to be varied both on length and
on content.
Review preferably no longer
than a quarter, many people can't listen more than that.
But also vary work tasks,
orally or in writing, group work or
Individual work.
For it to fit like that
many as possible.
Usually hand out note support there
I have written fixed headlines on what we will
go through so that students can record
under those headings.
Audience copies for powerpoints.
But perhaps the most important thing is to get in
students' life world, to be able to vary
based on different things they have met in life
and can relate to which makes it a lot
Easier for them to understand different contexts.
How to do for a business to become
More NPF-adapted?
It's a huge question
and important question, and a very important foundation
is that everyone has a knowledge base so that everyone
Throughout the organization should understand what, for example
NPF means.
What we do to npf-secure our school is
That we constantly have our NPF glasses on us.
It's about looking at the physical
the learning environment, how we post our lessons,
It is about organization, about response,
And it's about knowledge.
I would
say is the basis of everything for through
knowledge you gain understanding, and otherwise it is
easy to do you to do lots of things without knowing
Why you do it.
And then it is easy to
one ends with it too because one does not
Understand the purpose of that.
So it's all about
That knowledge provides understanding.
Then the next step is what to do with it
Here the knowledge and it is the difficult part.
How to put up our structure, our schedule
and our entire arrangement at this school,
according to the needs of the students.
At our school we ensure the NPF knowledge
in the staff by having repeated
lectures, literature spreads, we encourage
everyone to attend courses and training and training and
In discussions this is something that whole
The time we bring.
An important foundation.
The collegiate learning that we talk a lot about
in the school world, is very important.
It is so
Development takes place at a school, I think.
We can bring in very professional lecturers but if
We then do not have the discussions in the college,
With each other, then it gives no outcome.
Because that's when we talk about how.
"How will
I use this knowledge in the classroom
And in my response to the students? ”
Also be able to take up difficulties, “Now I have learned
me how to handle concentration difficulties,
But this student that I have in my class,
Nothing works.
Whatever I do, I reach
not that student ". And we should be able to talk that
About and meet around.
Here at the ESS Gymnasium we work in Duo
meaning that we are always two teachers in
the classroom and through that I have learned
Very much about these students.
We can
Always check ideas and find different solutions.
At this school I can get extremely good support
As for students with NPF.
Partly I have
My team where we work a lot with this.
We talk all the time and help each other.
We support each other because it is sometimes tough.
Great school management, one can go in and piss
And get help.
You can ask for guidance.
We have an NPF educator who can guide one.
The absolute most fun thing about my job that does
that I, sometimes when it is heavy or that
rains and i'm tired and can't, it
is still to get to school and meet
These amazing students.
Get to work with them
and be part of their adult.
It makes me happy.
This is the most fun I know.
I love
to see these students develop, love to
be allowed to join in and build up their
Self -confidence.
I would not want to work
somewhere else than here.