Once you have broken a leg heals it-
-Do training you get muscles, if you cold form the antibody-
-And if the hairdresser cut an ugly hairstyle, you know that the hair is growing out again.
You can thank protein synthesis for that.
Our DNA is like a library-
-Or contains instructions on how the body should be built up and function.
In order to build up the body, not only instructions are needed but building material-
-and someone who can do the work.
It is the task of the proteins.
When protein is created, it is called protein synthesis.
It happens in two steps:
Transcription and translation.
Let's start with the transcription.
My recipe book represents our DNA-
-Or available in the Cell Core, our library.
The different pages of the book are our genes.
The yellow pages represent genes that are active-
-Ach contains recipes for the protein to be created in different cells.
In order to build the protein, the recipe must be out of the cell nucleus itself
-And the logical would be if the recipe was torn out.
But this information must be preserved in your DNA, so it is not possible.
How do you solve this?
Well, by copying the information.
This is the process we call transcription.
The part of the DNA to be copied is divided into a single spiral.
This binds enzyme and helps to create a copy.
The copy is called RNA instead of DNA.
It contains another type of sugar-
-And the nitrogen base Tymin is replaced with a nitrogen base called Uracil.
If the DNA string consists of G, C, G, A, A-
-blir copy, RNA: t, C, G, C, U, U-
-The uracil replaces thymine.
The type of RNA formed during the copy is called "Messenger RNA".
It is shortened the mrna.
It carries on a message-
-Shelve the recipe for the protein to be manufactured.
Now there is a copy of the recipe, the code for the protein's ingredients.
The next step is to form the protein itself.
Translation should take place.
This is done in the ribosomes, the cell's factories, which have the ingredients.
Everything that happens from here is a chemical process.
When MRNA arrives at the ribosomes, supplementary nitrogen bases should be switched on.
In the Ribosomes there is another RNA called TRNA-
-"Transfer RNA", which helps with it.
TRNA contains three nitrogen bases that encode a specific amino acid.
These are matched and linked to MRNA's chain of nitrogen bases.
A chemical process occurs which creates amino acids.
MRNA contains signals that mean "stop".
When the interconnection has reached there, the chain is ready.
Now the job is done and both TRNA and MRNA leave the amino acid sequence.
It takes itself to the golgia apparatus-
-Where the protein gets its last, specific properties.
This process happens all the time, in every cell, day in and day out.
We have a lot to thank the proteins for.
They heal your broken bone-
-Is involved in the immune system, build your muscles-
-And make sure you avoid an ugly hairstyle.
After a while, anyway.
Swedish text: Gabriella Eseland Iyuno Media Group for UR