There is a thing that the rulers do not agree on.
Something small that still seems important to everyone: what the Coronavirus should be called.
It's not racist.
It comes from China.
Stigmat is more dangerous than the virus itself.
Trump replaces "Corona" with "Chinese"
Åsa Larsson and Jack Werner started the Viral Reviewer.
Today, they run the source criticism, Sweden's national team in source criticism.
Now they, together with Edwin Safari, are doing Källkoll Corona.
Trump has wanted to call the virus the Chinese virus.
It suits him well.
He wants to blame for things in other countries.
It has been accused of racism.
People seem to want to divide things and each other into groups.
Group division can be used to spread hatred in the worst case-
-When there are dangers or diseases that are spread.
Then you can take the group that you think most badly om-
-And you put them in some scapegoat.
The Coronavirus has led to increased sinophobia.
Hate crime against East Asians, but also against People of Color, as black in China.
It experienced many Chinese in Africa during the Corona crisis's early stage-
-When Chinese were seen as a carrier.
Just as Black in China has been exposed to hop-
-Have Chinese outside China did that too.
It began to be noticed as early as February in Boston.
Concerns for the Coronavirus will decrease trade in Boston's Chinatown.
According to restaurant and bakery owners, sales have decreased by 50-70 %.
This seems to dilute suspicion between groups.
And it's a reminder that people don't like invisible things.
For example.
Radiation and virus.
But we are struggling to get hold of and handle it.
It is much easier if you have a visible thing that you can beware of.
The visible thing is people.
There are ancient ideas about which ones are usually blamed.
Conceptions about which groups are the worst.
Jews are such a group.
For thousands of years, the Jews have been blamed for various different things.
Take the deaths during the 1300s.
The dizzying victim stumbles around in their last moments.
Then people died in quantities.
Those who survived had a hard time staying Sane after this trauma.
The researchers do not know exactly how many people died.
But it is talked about that up to 1/3 of Europe's population died.
In some villages 80 %.
In such a village, I had not kept Sane either.
No.
In this terrible situation, people did everything to survive.
But survival also took strange forms.
They gave up on strangers.
People with another dialect or something strange.
Everything that made one a stranger made you suspect.
One of the largest alien groups that lived in Europe was then the Jews.
The Jews end up in the scapegoat again.
Then it was like that ...
False claims
-That intentionally spread this infection.
They started to persecute and torture the Jews.
If we jump to the 1980s, it was a disease that spread in the world.
The virus was HIV and the disease was AIDS.
Many homosexuals were affected.
Some male homosexuals' lifestyle has initiated a rare cancer epidemic.
Homosexuality had just stopped being classified as mental illness.
Many lived in an idea that LGBTQ people were sick-
-And maybe a little more contagious and spreading.
Then the LGBTQ person became the scapegoat for HIV/AIDS-
-For it was easier to see the physical people than the virus.
There was an incredibly stigma against gay people at that time.
But the world learned how the homosexuals took on the outbreak:
With great courage, great dignity and a lot of activism.
For Källkoll Corona there is educational material at Urplay.se.
Search "Källkoll Corona", Choose "Pedagogical Material"-
-And click on the worksheet.
In history, there is a tendency for us to baptize diseases for places.
-In completely incorrect.
-Right.
Type like Spanish sickness.
It was the brutal flu epidemic during the First World War.
And this ... Spain was a neutral country during the war.
They did not have war censorship in the news.
When disease cases began to dive up-
-reported Spain about it.
So it was unfairly baptized to Spanish illness.
East Asians have been exposed to threats during the pandemic.
Are there similar incidents with Italians?
Good question.
We have tried to check it.
It doesn't seem to be much like that.
When the cure of infection moved from Asia to Europe and USA-
-If you think it would change the image.
But it doesn't seem to have happened.
Some of the cases we found have been about Westerners in India-
-What has been thrown out because they were alleged to carry infection.
Perhaps the idea of the "ethnicity" of the infection has already settled.
We have decided: "It is an infection that is essentially Asian."
Which is completely wrong, because the infection is a pandemic.
All over the earth.
Diseases have no ethnicity.
With fact-examination, historical knowledge and humanity-
-Can you counteract the ignorance.
-What do we do?
-You do right.
Texting: Jussi Walles www.btistudios.com