-Ring Åsa.
We have to talk.
-Wo?
Okay.
-Heh, Åsa.
-Os.
We must have an intervention.
-Wo?
I have a lot of alarming information.
Your coffee drinking is Beyond Control.
This graph shows that you drank 20 cups only last Sunday.
-Hher God, Åsa.
-I have a sneaky picture ...
... which shows that you have been drinking late at night even
-This is awful, -The only that is awful ...
... is your use of information.
We make a section on this.
Journalists Åsa Larsson and Jack Werner started the Viral reviewer.
Today, they run the source criticism, Sweden's national team in source criticism.
Now they, together with Edwin Safari, are doing Källkoll Corona.
There have been a lot of graphs and statistics in recent weeks.
The Corona Pandemic is a worldwide business.
This is something that affects a lot of people, finances and numbers.
If one is to understand the development-
-It is often best included with graphs and statistics.
But that does not mean that all graphs show the truth.
The difficult thing is to understand the statistics right, like Edwin's absurd hopes.
But then see me.
What claims are wrong?
You make it sound like I drank 20 cups only on Sunday.
But you have summarized all the cups for my household all over the weekend.
Then you present that figure that it applies to be a day.
This is how the figures about how many people have died in Corona have been reported.
One has taken the numbers for all who have died during the weekend-
-And presented them on Monday or Tuesday.
Then the figures will be higher, although in fact, one assumes for days.
A bit like you did here, your cheeky.
-The curve is often much more even.
-But not everyone knows.
We called Peter Håkansson-
-Whith has written the book "Statistics in the news".
His sister -in -law in Croatia had heard about Sweden on the news.
Large increase in the number of dead.
We must explain that this is not true.
We have this backlog over the weekend-
-And then there will be new peaks when the backlog comes.
In addition, Edwin, your statistics are extensive.
You have brought water, decaffeinated tea and soft drinks.
That in itself is five of the twenty cups you mean I drank.
It is credible and relatively free from political influence.
So here it is in Sweden.
We include more and more in our statistics and our data.
Other countries do not include those who die in old age homes.
Therefore, we get bigger but also more accurate figures.
We are told here already-
-This in some other countries you become aware of much later.
Okay, maybe it was a little cheating with the graph.
But still, 15 cups you have been drinking.
15!
How sick is it, Åsa?
There you are wrong.
You count copper per household.
It makes it sound like I've been drinking everyone alone.
I have three people in my household and everyone has been drinking coffee this weekend.
You probably also got some coffee this weekend.
This is a problem when counting outbreaks per million inhabitants.
It causes less countries' outbreaks to seem worse than larger countries.
Take e.g.
This comparison between the US and Sweden.
It makes Sweden's outbreaks look worse than the US: s-
-But the United States has much more residents than Sweden.
The disease spreads as quickly from person to person-
-independent of how many people live in the country.
You infect just as quickly.
This means that the number of infected people is emerging about as quickly.
Therefore, there are as many infected in both countries.
Then it looks like Sweden has more infected per million inhabitants.
Small countries' figures will always look worse than large countries.
But the picture then?
I have a photo proof where you sit with a lot of cups.
It's a classic trick.
The picture is taken from a tricky angle.
This is the same as the picture the police in Stockholm posted.
It looks packed on the street-
-and there some taverns on the street were later closed-
-To they had had too poor infection protection mode.
But there is still a point here.
How far do you think it's-
-Between the left corner of the picture and the lightboard you see there?
-Scare 30-40 m. -90 m it really is.
The picture is a bit inzoomad-
-And then it looks like it is closer between the points and narrower.
We took a new picture on this part of the street, where it looks much further.
A girl in Norway-
-EVearing how to take pictures from different angles and show different things-
-By footing lego guys.
Here they appear to be many.
From the top you see that they are sparse.
Here is another picture that shows that I do not drink coffee without water.
Yes.
I only care about your health.
But then you come and ...
He would only know how many cups of coffee I drank.
For each section of Källkoll Corona there is educational material.
You can find it at Urplay.se.
Search "Källkoll Corona" and select "Pedagogical Material".
Click on the worksheet to open.
Texting: Henrik Johansson www.btistudios.com