-What do a journalist do?
-Writs articles and interviews.
Writes about society.
Interviewing people.
-Writing newspapers.
-interviews people.
Interview people and write newspapers about it, kind of.
It is probably the ones who investigate and write.
They collect articles and things-
-To write long stuff for your company or film clips.
-Have you seen?
-What?
Education Radio changes its name to VR.
Edwin Safari says UR should change its name to VR-
-To do everything in "virtual reality".
Huh?
Check that out.
There is nothing on UR's official accounts or from the press department.
It may not be official.
He said it was a rumor.
-Do you feel any at UR?
-Jack.
I'll call him.
Good, do it.
-What is this, Edwin?
-All who wonders can come.
We talk about the rumor at a press conference and start Källkoll!
-Do we not look up the rumor?
-We have no time.
It's a rumor.
God, now Calle calls SVT.
Hey!
Hello, Calle.
I've just heard about it so I don't know.
A reporter?
Ask him to attend the press conference.
-Come to the press conference!
-We'll see.
Okay, good.
Hello.
Calle, do you walk past the EDWIN Safari thing in the afternoon?
-It seems damn thin, right?
-Yes, but ...
He has made a comet career as an influencer.
It may be of interest to younger.
Welcome!
Fun that many could come when I tell-
-That new season of "Källkoll" gets rid of.
In the season ...
-Byter out of name to VR?
-Is it true?
Do you speak for UR in this question?
-It went like that.
-I hope you learned something.
They just wanted to know about the name change.
Journalists ask about what they think, not what you think.
-Are you talking to me?
-It was a follow -up question.
The President of Finland is here.
Ask him something!
I will, but I want to ask my follow -up question.
Are you listening?
Ask him something!
You can do it in different ways.
Anyone who is media trained can make it deal with what it wants to talk about.
Am I not trained?
I've been with you!
It is not the same to stand on TV and be pressured with questions.
Media training is about getting difficult questions and answering well.
It has a bad reputation as it is used to seem ground-
-And when people got crazy advice.
The government does not comment on the wikileak documents-
-Then these are third -party tasks.
Third party records.
I do not comment on the documents as there are third -party records.
He said "third party tasks" maybe 20 times.
Sometimes the examined try to meander.
They do not answer straight-
-On tries to get out of it.
As old center leader Maud Olofsson who had informed the prime minister-
-Fredrik Reinfeldt about a deal made by Vattenfall.
It was not good in the current studio when she refused to answer the question.
Did you inform the Prime Minister about the purchase of Nuon before the deal?
The Constitutional Committee says ... partly you do not agree.
Did you inform the Prime Minister about the purchase before the deal?
KU is constitutional.
Then I am too ...
-Heeds, Maud Olofsson.
-It has been adjusted.
I ask the question the third time.
Did you inform the Prime Minister about the purchase before the deal?
It is not the most important issue.
It is "runajs" to be chased by journalists.
Are there no limits?
There are limits.
Journalists in Sweden work after a regulatory
-which prevents overtramping.
One must find yourself being reviewed as holders of power.
One must be able to be opposed in the general debate.
This with rules of play for journalists ...
We have heard with Caspar Opitz, our new media ombudsman.
As a media ombudsman, I make sure that TV, radio, newspapers take care of Sig-
-And behaves schyst.
The rules of the game for press, radio and television are to-
-To the media to behave correctly, manage news correctly-
-time seek to describe the truth, be fair-
-Let everyone come to speak, be careful with human-
-What do not want to join in and behave correctly and schist.
If someone writes something stupid about you report it to me.
You do not have court and do with lawyers-
-Out you can report it to me, I look at it and help you.
In a self -cleaning system, the media takes care of it.
Newspapers, TV and radio say: "If we do anything wrong, we handle it."
"We don't need any politicians or courts, but we take care of it."
A self -cleaning system is important for democracy and the free word.
Media, television and newspapers should say what they want.
Politicians, judges and courts should not intervene.
In dictatorships, the first thing that happens is to stop the free press.
My role in our system is to keep the legislator away-
-No the media.
It is important for democracy.
Okay, but some don't look up what they post.
Not everyone follows mediaetic rules.
Some call themselves journalists without responsible publishers.
There are gossip sites that want to report rumors.
Just.
But with this one cannot decide what is right or not-
-Os the truth can show up anywhere.
Gossip sites may be right and established media can be wrong-
-Alt if they usually get a little more.
So there are everything from people who gossip online-
-To large media houses with hundreds of employees?
Yes.
I think we should go through the Swedish media map.
We can do that in our channel!
-Look!
Fine, huh?
-No really need some help.
No!
It's spartan, but nice anyway.
Yes!
And we have ... seven followers.
Oh ... I don't think I can join, actually.
-Shucks!
Whatever.
Let's go.
-Yes.
-Time.
-You usually divide magazines ...
... after when they come out.
In the past, newspapers were all that found-
-and they came out every day, week or month.
But now we read more online and it is a more even flow.
But in the past, those who were distributed every day were called daily newspapers.
Just.
Then they divided them into the morning and evening newspapers-
-Or which part of the day they covered.
Not everyone has a look at that.
Evening newspapers ... come out in the evening, right?
And morning in the morning.
Or?
There may be a little different news.
I do not know.
Evening newspapers in the evening, morning in the morning?
I think morning newspapers may be from the day before, kind of.
And evening newspaper comes from the day, or something.
Now the difference is perhaps mostly a style issue.
Evening newspapers are a bit more sniffy-
-While daily newspapers are a bit more fine cultural and do not take the gossip.
Think some.
But evening newspapers do good excavation journalism-
-and real blood dog digs and digs out injustice.
Examples of evening newspapers: Expressen, Aftonbladet.
Then we have the morning newspapers, and they, think a part-
-Have considered himself having finer ideals and be a little finer.
Examples of morning newspapers: Svenska Dagbladet, Dagens Nyheter.
Then we have local magazines.
There, for example, we have the Barometer in Småland or Västerbottencuriren.
There it can get cranky, when people expect national news-
-On a local newspaper website and read about a plastic bag that is burning.
Just.
It is meant that local magazines-
-Do cover the little life in the local community.
Then local magazines are very good at the local angle.
Do you remember the Skellefteå scarf guy?
In the middle of the crowd he stood, among thousands of other-
-With helmet, outstretched arms, and then that red scarf.
In Sweden, on top of all that-
-The we have SVT and Sweden's Radio with national news and local editors.
And so all magazines that can be about all-
-From hunting and fishing to sports and exercise.
Absolutely.
And on top of that we have all sites online.
Surely it was the Swedish media landscape?
-Bra clips!
-Hello!
You forgot to say how many journalists there are in Sweden.
-You usually say fourteen.
-But then not all news reporters.
But if not, what do the others do?
In addition to going to a press conference and asking the wrong questions to me.
We do this: We call one.
- Hi Fouad.
My friend has some questions about journalists.
How does a journalist know what is right or not?
We don't always know that.
We have to find out.
There are slightly different ways.
I usually contact authorities-
-and ask them to send me paper, because on them maybe it says things-
-What confirms something I think.
But sometimes you may need to talk to many people.
If a person says one thing one cannot always trust it-
-But about two, three, or four people say the same thing-
-Can you guess what they say is true.
Right.
Where do you get your tips from?
We get tips everywhere.
Above all people who hear from themselves-
-If things they think works less well in society and so on.
But companies and organizations often send press releases-
-To journalists when they want to tell about something good that has happened.
There are two of the places.
Then I usually dig a little-
-In the archives of the authorities among paper and decisions taken by politicians.
I think that is a way to find things that are exciting.
He seemed to be sway.
But he said that journalists are not always popular.
No, as he said, if journalists are and root and pee in things-
-And asks if such people don't want to answer.
Then journalists are also people with faults and shortcomings.
But then it is important that the corrections are highlighted and so on.
But some may not think that corrections get the place they would have-
-And that journalists are bad at admitting wrong.
And so there are cases where it has completely derailed.
For example.
German journalist Claas Relotius.
He won many awards for his journalism.
Now it turns out that he found most things.
He has mostly worked for Der Spiegel, but has also been published abroad.
And almost all his reports are fictional.
So embarrassing!
He has worked at huge story-
-And had started to fake things and find details.
Some colleagues had no idea and tried to warn the managers ...
-. but they didn't listen.
-It became a splendor scandal.
They would have listened.
The magazine had to do about a lot, they had to check all he wrote-
-To see if it is correct and about how they handle news control.
Yes.
And Edwin?
So it can end if you spread rumors.
Yeah ... yeah ..
Hello?
Now this rumor I spread has spread ...
And that it will start "Källkoll" again!
Yes, you see.
It is negative attention, but still attention.
This is how we come from seven to seven hundred thousand followers.
Join my channel.
I'll show you how to do this.
Swedish texture: Fröderberg/Karlsson Iyuno Media Group for UR