Welcome to the corner.
What a good song.
Thanks so much.
-
And you have written it with Jubël.
Yes they started writing it, then they called me-
-and said I would try to write a verse-
-For they thought I would fit in it.
The guys look happy.
I've listened to it a few times.
It is about any person-
-When you can't let go, right?
"I can't get you off my mind", we say basic:
"I can't get you out of my head."
Is it that you have a lock on a person you want to release?
Or as it is cozy to have left?
It is cozy to have left.
I think.
Before we can move on, I just want to double check.
-Did you get a taxi here?
-Yes.
Did you get food?
Were you well cared for?
-I got very good chocolate.
-Yes, here we offer.
You may know why I want to check out a little neighbor?
You are used to being involved in fairly large talk shows.
You have been with Jimmy Fallon.
In New York.
A little more viewers than the corner maybe.
What was it like to sit there in such an incredibly large entertainment program?
It was among the widest I have done.
I lost my vocabulary in English.
I barely dared to talk because I thought I would be really Swedish-
-and just get stuck.
So I just: "Edvin, what is it?"
-I didn't think was noticed.
-No, I kept talking.
It went okay anyway.
I had Edvin to lean on.
It was fun, because he asked me, "How did your band start?"
"Did you start singing in schools?"
I just yes.
Although it is completely wrong.
We did not start in schools at all, but in the Globe with Justin Bieber.
-Unbelievable.
-But I kept quiet ...
... because I couldn't explain because I didn't want to get stuck.
And then Edvin comes in and just: "No, you started so ..."
What a friend!
He threw you under the bus.
But does that mean you feel safer with me?
-Absolutely, you should have that.
-It is important to build trust.
It became some kind of hysteria, not just in the studio-
-Or above all backstage.
We have a clip from this.
It may be difficult to explain-
-But what was it like to experience that hysteria?
Sick.
It was like living in some strange Hollywood dream.
When you broke through as an artist you have an incredible fanbase.
So they get like crazy.
Do you ever get used to that?
I think that during the band time, when I was 14-16-
-So we had very loud fans.
And at that time you were a little more used to it-
-For you lived in every day.
While now, ten years later, things have changed.
Our fans have grown up and we have grown up-
-And new fans have come.
It does not happen as often-
-That people faint when they see me at ICA.