It is January 22 and I am in central Stockholm.
In a little while, the biggest demonstration will be organized against vaccines in Sweden's history.
The police have urged vaccination clinics to close in the immediate area.
We simply see what will happen and how many will show up.
Right now an hour before, almost no one demonstrates against the vaccine.
Instead, it is people who demonstrate for something else.
The idea of the video is to hear people's perspectives and thoughts.
I don't believe in a world where we divide ourselves into us and them.
I don't think there is any harm to hear people's different perspectives on this and other issues.
This is how we, I think, build a democratic society.
But there are some others who demonstrate here now and I was going to see what they have to say.
-Why are you here and demonstrate today?
-I demonstrate to stop the genocide in the northern part of Ethiopia, Tigray.
Tigray is surrounded by Eritrean and Ethiopian soldiers.
Right now in Tigray there is no electricity, no banking services, no medicine and no water.
People die from hunger, especially children.
We are here to give voice to the people in Tigray.
We want to stop the genocide.
-How do you think about the fact that vaccine opponents equate the vaccine with genocide like the Tigray genocide?
-Personally, I think it is not possible to compare genocide and vaccine passes.
There are two completely different things.
It is not possible to compare it to genocide as well.
It's not possible.
-Now those who demonstrate for Tigray have gone away.
Now people have begun to gather against the vaccine or restrictions we have had.
I was going to talk to them because I'm genuinely interested what they have to say.
"We are not slaves" it says, tell you what do you think?
-Yes, I think I'm a free living person and I don't want anyone forcing me or my children to vaccinate us.
I take vitamin D, vitamin C, selenium and zinc.
-Do you think it helps against Covid?
-Yes, I think it helps against Covid and I exercise a lot.
-Okay, thank you very much.
-All may weigh the risk of and against.
Do I think it helps and what is the risk of taking the vaccine anyway?
Is the risk to me greater than getting the disease?
Yes or no.
-As society at large, shouldn't people take the vaccine in solidarity?
-No I do not think so.
No.
-It is not far from the fact that you start comparing how, for example, you treat people in China where you start building up some type of scoring system.
-Social credits are called it.
-How did it happen that you got involved in this question?
-Yes, you can't really avoid it.
It's everywhere as well.
-But you are from Norrköping or anything?
-I am from Linköping.
-So you went here today from Linköping then?
-Yeah, that's right.
We went bus here the whole gang.
-Is it like a small popular movement that you also get to know each other?
-Yes, you have done this on the bus when you talk to others as well as when we feel the same way.
-Do you for the vaccine or?
-I am so damn the opposite so there is not.
-But you still have mouth protection?
-We are here to demonstrate against their fucking forced vaccination
We are against this thing, we are on the same page.
We should not start any fucking unrest.
We're just like you!
-What do you think?
-I think it is obvious that we are starting to get rid of our rights.
It will happen soon if we do nothing.
Everyone here, shit in where we come from for different political opinions or what we think.
We agree with this issue and it is extremely important.
If we do not do anything now, we will just see how we are becoming more and more off with our freedom.
-You mean that the vaccine pass will increase and that vaccine passes will be required to go to the gym.
What are you thinking?
-Yes, they have already talked about introducing it.
It will be.
-You have the Swedish flag here on you?
-Yes.
-How is it that?
-No, but it's probably part of Sweden to have freedom to choose.
You old you free.
-Why are you here today and demonstrate?
-No, but it's to stand up for our freedoms and no to the idiotic vaccine pass.
-So you're not vaccinated yet?
-No no no.
It never comes to the question.
-Why not?
-No, I can't receive anything I don't believe in?
Then I should explain myself.
-But how come you don't believe it when billions of people have already taken it?
-Yes, billions!
Why do I have to be one of them then?
-No, you don't have to.
-No!
-How did it happen that you started to get involved in this question?
-No, but I started to question very early.
I am always one here.
New things come, maybe there are back sides?
There may be good things about it, but there are also back sides.
The information is free to retrieve online and there are many good Youtube channels and other things, but I don't buy everything they say either.
I like my own way, but this?
No, this is another agenda behind.
-What do you think about demonstrating and that there are so many people here?
-Yes, but it's pretty.
-But I mean now when it is so high spread?
-No, it's no spread of infection.
-We get to see how many people get infected today then?
Maybe you or me!
-Yes, I've already had covid.
-Yes, but you see that is also a thing.
If you have already had it, most experts say that then you are protected.
Still, they want to vaccinate!
-But how do you think when you say that you vaccinate for society's best to protect the weakest in society?
-In risking one's own life as an effort and getting vaccine injury?
I would not set up and do it to protect someone else.
Who would stand up for me?
I mean my body has many years left to live, I intend to live.
I was going to do that and I mean no one would take the vaccine to protect me.
So stop, that's just a damn awkward argument simply.
No one does anything for anyone else, so it is in society today.
-I think this is a little exaggerated, but I still appreciate that people say what they believe in.
-Tjena, Hello!
-Hey man!
-It's on your sign to "the state is the virus", tell me!
-If we are going to live in fear, the state will live by us.
They will suck out our freedom and I'm pretty tired of it!
-The part syringes are graphen oxide in and it is a poison.
It has a connection here so that is why I go with it.
I got it from one so I haven't done it myself.
But I got it and now I had to explain how I look at it because it was a little matched what my truth is.
-Why we demonstrate today?
-Yes, why are you demonstrating?
-For human rights and because we do not want the vaccine pass in society.
I think it is for a totalitarian society to live in and there is nothing I put up with.
There is nothing I want in my society as well.
Then I think the story is repeated as it used to be.
-What do you mean by the story being repeated?
-Yes, but I think above all back to Hitler's time on the Juda pass.
If you look a little at how they are designed, they are quite as designed as the vaccine pass.
Then they removed rights for Jews as well as and I do not think we need to repeat and participate in it again.
-If you see it as taking the vaccine is voluntary.
-Yes, but it's every person's choice.
It is a free choice.
I can't influence you and you can't influence me, but this is just this with the vaccine pass it destroys so much more than the benefit.
Then every human being can do as they please.
-But when you draw parallels to the Second World War and the Jews, then the Jews had no choice at all?
How do you think about it?
-No, they had no choice.
Yes, how to say?
No, strike that question.
I have to think about it, it was a little quickly put there.
-I mean you still draw parallels to the Jews?
-Yes, but then you do that because what I pull the parallel to is the more what they were not allowed to do.
They were not allowed to go to the cinema, theater and meet loved ones if you say so.
It's a bit the same with the vaccine pass.
That is why I pulled that parallel as well as back to the Jews.
-What do you think is the reason for a vaccine pass?
-That is a good question.
It's control.
Checking people it feels like and it feels like it's a little too overcrowded.
They want a little more control over us.
There is no real evidence and evidence, after all, no one emerges and demonstrates real facts as well.
If I seek proof then what evidence is that right?
There are so many numbers that are manipulated and censored, so it is not possible to find real facts no matter how much I try to search.
Yes, it's hard.
Very difficult.
-I am not here to demonstrate, but I am here to support the whole movement.
We don't want vaccine passes.
We do not want any coercion and get junk into our arms.
Control, they want full control over the people, I think.
-How do you mean that the vaccine controls people or that it is easier to control people who are vaccinated?
-Yes, so they can only zip and read, they see who has.
It is registered on you, so they have control I think.
Electronic check.
-Yes, it's Bill Gates.
-Tell?
-Yes, but it's a person who obviously makes huge money in the vaccine industry and propagates for the entire population of the earth to vaccinate.
So have you taken it yet?
Have you received it yet?
Have you realized what it is about?
-So you mean that Bill Gates is behind this?
-Yes, but he is probably one of those who have earned this.
Okay.
-"Wake up! The only thing mutating are the lies"?
-Yes!
-So you don't believe in the Covid-19-Pandemic at all, right?
-No.
No.
-What is it on your sign?
-Yes, it says that Jesus is the way, the truth and the life.
There should not be a vaccine pass.
-So you mean Jesus is against Covid-19 or?
-Yes, he's against all that.
It does not come from God.
-Where of it will you think?
-Covid?
Yes, from Antichrist.
The New World Order.
-It's about it in the Bible.
If Corona they have calculated that it is 666.
So the covid pass is part of this that they should register and have control.
You cannot buy or sell if you do not have covid passes.
The same is in the Bible, although it says as in other words, but that is the same foundation.
After all, it is about to become this brand that is in the Book of Revelation 13:14.
-So you mean that or what do you think about the disease, isn't the disease covid-19 at all?
-Yes, Covid-19 there are, after all, they have made up in some way to be able to shoot in people lots of syringes, so-called vaccine.
-But what do you think is the reason, why do you think you have vaccinated so many people and urge people to vaccinate?
-For they want to reduce the population.
The world order wants control and reduce the population.
-So you mean it's a poison?
-Yes, after all, it is made of graph oxide according to doctors and researchers that I have looked at.
-What doctors are it?
-Yes, now I can't the names of them.
-I just thought of other Christians might claim to take the vaccine in solidarity with those who are weak in society?
-Yes, there are some Christians and I don't buy that.
No, so we Christians between us there are slightly different sentences there.
-Why are you here and demonstrate today?
-To that the whole fucking world is corrupt.
It's much more than just vaccine passes.
-Do you on the Covid-19-Pandemic?
-It's scam!
-How?
Money!
-The medicine companies or?
-Yes, Big Pharma.
-Big Pharma, Big Tech, Big Corporations.
Everything!
-But the vaccine you don't think work at all, right?
-No, that's a damn shit.
It's money behind everything.
Control and money.
-Is something more you want to develop?
-No, it will probably take a year to develop it as much as I have researched and know.
I know who those people are.
Bill Gates and Horungarna who are on and fucking us straight up and down.
-Where have you done that research on Bill Gates and so?
-Telegram.
A damn good app.
There it is not censored as it is done on Twitter, Facebook and other places like Youtube.
I'm pissed!
I'm not so damned at them anymore.
I am more pissed off at the sleeping bastards.
On the idiots who do not understand what was sealed.
I am angry with them!
It's stupid fucking sheep!
-Which follows the current as well, right?
-Yes.
-The they call me a conspiracy theory, right -wing extremist and Nazi and everything even though they are the Nazis!
-What I've read and heard, I don't trust the vaccines at all.
I also have some underlying diseases that I am more afraid of the vaccine than I am too covid.
-You haven't had covid or?
-No, not what I know.
-But you are not afraid to get covid here today considering that it is so high spread?
-No, I'm not actually.
I feel pretty confident in what is anyway.
I think it's a lot of scare.
Okay, it's a very serious illness anyway for those affected.
Many people have also died with underlying diseases and that is what I have.
-We have no pandemic, it is only statistics that they themselves have created.
-You mean the virus doesn't exist at all?
-There is not Covid-19 in that way.
It is a common flu or cold which has nothing to do with any virus.
It has to do with the body's slag products wanting out of the body on what you have eaten and taken in through water and air throughout the year.
Then when autumn comes and you do not have sun to get vitamin D and vitamin D so the immune system goes down, then all the sick who have a weak immune system will be.
Forget viruses!
-Are you here and demonstrate?
-Yes!
100%, of course!
-I have taken lots and took an extra to give out to someone.
-Do you want one?
-No, that's good thanks.
-What is it on that one then?
-Here it says "no to vaccine passes".
-Th there is plenty of other text.
-It's the Nordic resistance movement too?
-Yeah!
-I took it to release one to any random stranger for vaccine not being compulsory.
It should be voluntary and we should not be forced to take the vaccine to go to some places.
If we want to go to the cinema, we must vaccinate, but even if we are not vaccinated and want to go to the cinema, we will not.
It is to force us to vaccinate ourselves because we feel we want to go to the cinema, but if we want to go to the cinema we have to vaccinate and it will be a requirement then.
Because then you have to vaccinate and then go to the cinema.
I want to be able to go to the cinema without vaccinating myself, without feeling that I need to vaccinate in order to go on such stuff.
This is not okay how they are doing.
It is not OK!
We the people have had enough.
This is definitely not okay anywhere!
I have decided not to vaccinate.
If you disagree with it, that's your opinion.
I don't have the right to listen to your opinion.
I have my own opinion and you can't force me to believe in your opinion because I have decided that I will not vaccinate.
You can't push me to vaccinate me because you think I'm a danger.
Okay, I'm a danger but we're all in a danger.
What I believe in is that we humans are getting more and more, but we only have one earth.
I believe that this New World order like Illuminati that controls most of it wants to get down on humanity.
But they can't sit and say "unfortunately, but now so many have to die. You have to voluntarily die as well and kind of kill you".
No, that does not work.
Then they are smart to do so in such a way to reduce humanity's population that it does not increase.
The thing is what I think is that people want to put in voluntarily or involuntarily their views in others.
There are some who do not want to obey these opinions and those who want to put in these opinions have more power, but we the free peoples have our own choice and our own will.
They want to get rid of us.
We are born free!
We should always be free!
No one should force us to take anything to limit our freedom.
No!
-You have seen these NMRs that have run around a bit and it feels like some are mostly here because it is a large crowd that wants to be incite.
When they arrived here you saw a little.
-There are very masked people also with Bengals and stuff.
I don't know, it doesn't feel like everyone here to demonstrate against the vaccine pass either.
-It feels like everyone is not here on the same agenda, but it feels like some have a different view of this.
Giants!
-Yes to freedom, yes to freedom!
-You are one of the last left here now that the demonstration is running out and you stand here with your poster that says "Warning for vaccination pass".
Tell me more, what do you think?
I think our freedoms are taken away from us, especially our children.
This is probably not just about health, but it is about it being like China dictatorship this feels like.
We must stand up now when we can, before it becomes completely dictatorship.
-What do you think about the vaccine, is it toxic or?
-This I have heard, that's what it doesn't contain good stuff in it, so it should be voluntary if you want to take it.
They should also say what it is in the vaccine, you have not been told yet.
For example, with Pfizer, we may know about 75 years or something that the studies then come about how healthy it is and not.
No, I don't believe this.
-You haven't vaccinated you either?
-No.
-Why do you think that you vaccinate such a large part of the population if it is now a harmful vaccine?
-It may have to do with transhumanism.
New technology emerges, so there is a lot with vaccine.
It is not just that they should make money, but it can be very serious stuff behind, so you have to check it out.
-For example, what do you think?
-Yes, this with chip and stuff that we should be some kind of download and that you should have the internet in yourself, that you become one with the internet maybe.
I don't know, it sounds really strange but it's ..
-That the vaccine contains some kind of chip then you think?
-Yes, but it may be something that makes you hook up and become one in the network since the future.
I don't know, but I just feel that I am very skeptical until someone can say what it is in these so I think you should wait.
-I understand.
Okay, thank you very much!
-Yes thank you.
Hello!
-Thank you thank you.
Now the demonstration is largely over, there are some behind it.
It is just after five o'clock and it has been on since two o'clock.
There were a lot of people.
There were thousands of people, maybe about 2000-3000 people.
Not 20,000 or 18,000 that the organizers might have talked about, but there were still a lot of people.
It was difficult to move here at Sergel's square for a while because there were so many people.
I met people who all had in common that they did not like the vaccine.
Some were just critical of the vaccine and side effects that you can be or vaccine passes that you do not think it should be an indirect compulsory
-Mean's second hovered more and talked about the New World Order.
I also met the Nordic Resistance Movement here that did not want to put up an interview, but there were very different types of people who were here.
Others talked about Antichrist who had created the vaccine, so there are a lot of differences in this group of protesters but one thing that unites them.
Thank you for watching this video, comment if you have thoughts about this or if you think I should do another video about something.