The school has a very dark side too.
It felt like an experiment.
Whoever invented the railways received criticism.
The stamp came.
"We can't have whole houses full of stamps!"
It's almost the worst thing you can do to children, to divide them.
Everyone, all interesting ideas have started to say:
"You can't, so you can't do that?"
We all knew what temperaments we were.
You are sentenced and then you remain in that union.
"Now thick Daniel will be allowed to run, he needs exercise."
Yes, but it was mental abuse.
What a fucking society we are sitting in, that's what we are trying to change.
Rules about food, how to dress ...
There was a spiritual idea with everything.
You sat in the teacher's knee, and then the teacher held the mouth and nose with his hand.
Pain and horror would be so strong that the child "woke up".
It is a hell to change society.
You have to start by changing yourself.
Everyone has murdered someone, everyone has raped someone.
Then it might not do anything if you get a little frightened in the forest.
I am head of school at the school.
Would you say that something could happen today?
up through the air
away over the ocean
over the earth
in a staggering journey!
the queen of the morning
with the rosy rod
waving us out
against a waking world
the queen of the morning
with the rosy rod
For a year I have tried to understand  What we were with om-
- which magnificent goal  who justified the school's actions.
and Slowly but surely  I think I get closer to an answer.
This is my "dead", I am getting rid of all the books.
Cleaning out before flying from here -
- So others do not have to take care of it.
Of course, Steiner and Anthroposophy.
It is an experiment that has been going on for far too long.
You have been walking around and felt that you are intended for something bigger.
Then comes reality and hits one in the face: where are your high school grades?
Fuck no, you are like anyone as well.
Everyone is so damn pie.
As a child we were involved in  an experiment -
- which largely  was led by Pär Ahlbom.
After all, it is Pär who is the "inspirator".
I was asked by him, several were asked by him.
He was the spiritual principal.
Solvik, like all Waldorf schools, is based on an anthroposophical view of humanity.
Many people usually put similarities between anthroposophy and Waldorf school.
Yes, one is not conceivable without the other, so you understand.
At Solvik, it was mainly Pärs  Interpretation of Anthroposophy.
He was like the highest.
He sat on the throne at Solvik.
People come from all over the world to listen to him -
- And learn from him.
To truly understand  What we have been through, and why -
- I must understand Pär.
There he is.
If I were interested in earthly worries, I would beware.
Then I would say no to this movie job.
Actually.
But I'm not interested.
I am interested in something completely different -
- As then.
This with that he is so spiritually interested -
- Can it be reflected in what the students are about?
I really think so.
This is Elsa, Pär's daughter.
I broke my arms in six places and got such a serious concussion -
- That they had to drill holes in the temple to even out the pressure.
-How did you do it?
- The swing.
I had a near-death experience.
So, I don't know if I was dead -
- But I saw myself from the top when I was unconscious.
I know which way they went and how they put me in the car and stuff like that.
And Dad was totally ... So, he was so excited.
My value went up by a thousand percent when I had the near-death experience.
Pär is a convinced anthroposophtics.
Anthroposophy was created  by Rudolf Steiner -
–And for him was the spiritual life  as real as the physical.
We are almost not here, there is very little comparatively.
It is a continuous existence -
- Which is of a completely different dignity and reality.
that Steiner believed in knowing this -
- many of his followers  were due to his being clear.
that he could fully see  in the spiritual world.
He was clear -sighted, yes.
He says it all the time, "There is a difference between me and all of you."
Would you say that you are clear -sighted?
To some extent.
There are those who like it.
If a clear look is, then just sit and receive.
For all that comes out of that person is truth.
I had such impressions, I was often looking at the earth from the outside.
And knew that outside the world of mind began another world-
- which was even more real.
Clearly.
Me and the teacher have a conflict.
I run and hide under the pillows in one corner of the classroom.
Then he takes some classmates with him and jumps on the pillows -
- When I lie down.
People jump on me, lie on me -
- And I don't know what's up and what's down.
I remember thinking it didn't hurt as much to die as I thought.
And then it gets black.
It is a very difficult experience.
And then I wake up under the pillows and it is completely empty in the classroom.
There is no one there who says it is okay or takes care of me.
Maya's teacher does not want to participate in a  Interview.
He does not remember the event -
- But at the same time, it does not have  is unthinkable that it may have happened.
I get very sad when I think about that situation.
I think of myself as that little six -year -old girl.
I mourn what happened to her very much.
It is not Pär himself who has been accused  of being violent against the children.
but how the students  have perceived his reaction -
- goes as a red thread  through much of what I hear.
I tried to talk to Pär about my experiences, at a little more adult.
This experience of not having a sense of up and down ...
It became a philosophical discussion of it.
It was about-
—That I had an out -of -body experience -
- For then you do not have access to the balance mind.
It was turned to the fact that it was an exciting and special experience -
- As I was treated to experience.
It was like ... It was something really fantastic.
It sounds really sad.
If she really experienced death anxiety, then it is terrible -
- Meeting someone trying to make one think it was good.
Sadly, I don't remember the situation as it was.
I don't do that at all.
What can be so important that it  justifies such behavior?
How can a child's trauma  be perceived as something fantastic?
It has taken me a long time  to understand -
- But eventually the case the token down.
Steiner stated that man  in the future will develop -
- to a higher level of spirituality.
but that development is threatened.
He warns, and it has become just that.
I see an ongoing social disaster in full swing.
It is powerful forces, what we call materialism.
Steiner says that the modern  Society and its Materialism -
- Risk to Destroy  Our Spiritual Development.
Our only rescue is actually spiritual knowledge.
For the whole pedagogy is a matter of awakening the young man.
Through the Waldorf pedagogy, Steiner  saw an opportunity to counteract the threat.
Children are in closer contact with  The spiritual world, he explained.
You know, this is a truth, my friend.
Children meet angels.
All children!
And to stop it is a pure crime.
You mean that the role of the school is to help the children on their way to the spiritual?
Yes, so they can open up and do not close.
So that the opportunities exist.
The idea of an approaching threat is  The basis for the entire Waldorf pedagogy.
But Pär and other founders at Solvik  made a more radical interpretation.
When Steiner had done Waldorf School, they asked him: "Are you satisfied?"
Then he replied: "No. Much more art!"
"For materialism, people cure much faster than I thought."
The world becomes materialistic and cold at furious speed.
So we fought for a Waldorf school that Steiner would have wanted it.
Pär: If you take Steiner seriously, then you get a damn thinker.
with such a conviction  About the Spiritual World -
-Is it easier for me to understand  How a Near-death-experience-
- Can be seen as something positive.
Critics for Steiner would say that much cannot be proved ...
Yes exactly.
But what then proves?
I can't even prove that thoughts exist.
I don't actually care.
I think it's so damn stupid, so sluggish and so cheap.
Thus, I think the criticism of Steiner is cheap.
And if now you don't have the slightest interest -
- Because there is a world outside the sensual one, then you can have it.
Please, eat your sausage and lie in your bed and sleep-
- and fuck and make money, please.
What a life, what a limited fucking life.
Pär was the chief ideologist,  The Mentor of the Teachers.
But in contact with the students  it was the teachers themselves who decided.
and in his eagerness to "wake the students" -
- Some have been prepared  to go very far.
The teachers made a game with us ...
... who was voluntary.
You sat in the teacher's knee, and then the teacher held the mouth and nose with his hand.
He kept to his nose and mouth of us child-
- We were panicked as well.
You had to say when he was going to release, and then he usually released.
Or not.
So maybe he lasted a little longer.
So you were almost suffocated.
Some of us were incredibly brave and quite strong children in some way.
Sometimes I think he found a pleasure in forcing those kids -
- And go even further to crack them as well.
It was called "Mangling Children".
It was useful to manage a child.
They stood on our stomachs.
We lay there, seven to eight year olds, with our narrow little bodies.
The purpose was probably some form of ... shock therapy -
-or as well as near-death therapy.
Pain and horror would be so strong -
- That the child like "woke up".
The teacher confirms that they kept for  mouth and nose on the children.
He says it was an exercise  that had to do with breathing.
But he denies that he  should have stood on some children.
He doesn't want to be interviewed.
I recognize it from thoughts and ideas about the teaching -
- And some teachers who ... took methods.
During this year I  got to take part in so many stories -
- If teachers who must have been  violent against children at Solvik.
I don't understand, I've never beaten a child.
I do not understand.
I don't get it into my head how they could believe -
- That it would have to do with pedagogy.
No one takes responsibility for all broken people who left school -
- And for all the crap that has happened.
Nobody has said:
"Fuck, we fucked up. I wish I could correct it."
People just want to silence it and pretend it has never happened.
Take rods, all.
Each.
Pär is still at Solvik,  as a mentor for some teachers.
Sometimes he jumps in  into teaching.
But he is no longer responsible  for what is happening at school.
My name is Peter Friemann and I am today head of school at the school.
13 years ago  was Peter student at Solvik.
Facebook Group  with students' stories -
- became an eye opener for him as well.
There was pretty much that happened before I went here to school.
And that way, it became mostly a kind of surprise because ...
... It wasn't right with my experience when I went to school.
But at the same time, I had no doubt whatsoever that it was true.
It was quite clear that it had happened.
How serious did you think it was?
So, very serious.
A lot of what was described is something that people can break down.
Many former students  tell about a stray bullying -
- and a culture of violence between the students.
The question is how much of the  remains at the school today.
I would not say that the risk at Solvik is greater than at other schools.
After all, it is not as free as then.
It is more controlled, more structure.
And there are more rules that also apply to the children and so on.
Today when I visit the school,  so is very different.
There are  Schedules, Benches and Watches.
Most of the stories I heard  took place many years ago.
But the problems with teachers  who have been hard -handed with students -
- Works have been left to fairly  recently, albeit to a lesser extent.
There have been boundary cases.
There has been reason to look at it more closely on some occasions.
I would not say that there are teachers here who abuse the children -
- As a common feature of teaching.
I am convinced that it is not so.
Although much  seems to have changed at school -
- some things are equal.
Do not stop, then you get them in the skull.
Just go.
Helena is still  as a teacher.
and just a few years ago  was the Meete Rector.
Welcome!
How much of the anthroposophical steiner tanks-
- Are you experiencing there in school today?
There is a lot, as many teachers attended the Waldorförarhöre School -
- And brought thoughts from there.
There are also teachers left-
- Which has worked with the founders and brought thoughts from there.
You have understood the former teachers and founders -
- That they really took Steiner seriously.
One thing that is central to Steiner's thoughts is karma and reincarnation.
Right.
The essence of anthroposophy is that you are not here for the first time on earth.
You already have the bag full.
I have been told since I was a kid theories about what reincarnations -
- I have had before, and how it has affected how I am now.
Steiner said  that we live several lives on earth.
What we did in a life  affects how our next life becomes.
If one has a rather powerful personality -
- So maybe you have been an emperor in your last life for example.
A fine singing voice.
How to go and move.
if you have a big or small head.
whether you are noisy or shy.
Everything may have  with the child's karma.
How important was it to you and for you as a teacher in your response?
Fully one hundred percent important.
Most importantly!
According to Steiner, a Waldor Flear  should help the child on its karmic trip -
- so that it will further  in its spiritual development.
for if you live a life  without contact with the spiritual -
- so it can have consequences.
If I choose the other way in life, the materialistic ...
Then I get a full dividend as long as I am here.
And then...
Then it will be fun.
As a rule, it will be a march back, maybe without arms and legs.
Or almost without understanding.
After all, I've seen how difficult the disabled people -
—Rot their, or precisely because of their severe handicap -
–Not had any materialistic perception -
- The without helplessly extradited to an inner world.
So that such a life can repair a giant damage.
If you deny the spiritual world,  then you risk, according to Pär -
- to be disabled in the next life.
Everyone has murdered someone, everyone has raped someone -
- All has stolen something, and everyone has done something.
So then maybe it does not do anything if you get a little frightened in the forest.
Precisely that branch, when it lived -
- Then you could stand on it and go out.
This is Marcel.
He is a former  teacher and head of school at Solvik.
He was with us from the beginning,  and built the school.
When we hung up the swings, there were sometimes from ten feet up -
- That you would throw yourself down and hit a volt and so on.
Up here is the one I told you about.
- Here they did bungy jump.
-Yes.
That people basically broke their backs and there came ambulance helicopter -
- Was there anything reflected on then?
Then we noticed that "this does not hold".
Therefore, I felt that I could not stand for that swing anymore.
But it took a while for me to be able to say ...
--... that we remove it.
-In order to...?
In the beginning when someone fell, it was: "It fit in that person's life".
So there was some kind ... It doesn't happen by itself, not without further ado.
Something else would have happened to that person.
There were such thoughts that we often experienced -
- That if something happens, it is not by chance.
Then there is something inside.
The swing was thus left -
- With the motivation that if children  injured themselves, it was their karma -
- And that would not be counteracted.
Do you remember discussing the swings and saying it must be dangerous?
- "If you hit yourself, then you hit yourself."
-No.
- Can you have participated in the discussion?
-Absolutely not.
Absolutely crazy.
If you discussed, "Is it worthwhile that so many people settle off? Should the swing away?"
No.
First, I know that there are not many.
Me, Kristoffer and Iduna may be the ones who have hit the most.
Yes, but ... I actually haven't bothered that.
- But why haven't you bothered?
- I don't think it's important.
Children could have died.
Why don't you think it's important?
Well, I think that is very important.
So comes the School Inspectorate and wonders how much anthroposophy means.
Then it is important to be a little smart, and so you say:
"We are doing Waldorf pedagogy and not anthroposophy."
This with reincarnation there is nothing in the Waldorf pedagogy ...
... finished.
So I always thought when they came:
"Reply so they can accept it, it will be quiet."
I went to a school  where you should have let children bullied -
- because they were who they were.
a school where children were allowed to hurt themselves,  because it fit in their lives.
All this is anthroposophy.
And I see on the other side several students -
- That has been damaged by the consequences of this.
It is quite awkward against Steiner and his intentions -
- Trying to find angles that show that it can go awry.
How oblique has it been for Christianity, for Muhammedanism -
–Af the science or for the medicine?
It is not possible to reason so, to remove responsibility ...
I see a confused spoiled upper -class kid with too much leisure -
- As found on something and made people believe in him.
Because it's not ...
He is not behind all that.
He is funny.
He has his games, but ... yes ...
There is really no weight behind it.
He thinks he can see as well as the intangible in some way.
- You shake his head ... - He can't, but he wants it.
I think he has intellectually learned and knows a lot about it.
Then I think Dad wish he was one who could see longer ...
He sometimes pretends that he can talk to animals and such.
Hello friend.
Yes I know.
He often greets, I think.
Several times he has been injured and bitten by some poisonous centipa-
- Because he wants it so much.
He has certainly been cruel to people, but not present to his children.
He has always said, "I don't love you more than anyone else."
"I love people who can do something good."
- Does he own?
-Yes.
To feel that you have the family behind you, it has never been there.
It has always been the school.
Everyone looked up to him so damn much, and everything he said was team.
It was always like "Pär".
But he is not ... He is not God like that.
It is not possible to save that place.
It sits in the walls.
A former teacher has said that they did not tell the School Inspectorate -
- How much reincarnation and anthroposophy affect pedagogy.
- You just have to say what they want to hear.
- Yes, God ... yes, exactly.
These are exactly the things that the school needs to move on.
If there are such light -shaded things left -
- So you simply have to work them away.
I hear myself say on many questions: "Today it is different."
Obviously there are things that are a bit special here -
- As you need to continue working with.
If we choose to do school like this, then special situations - then arise -
- Where things can happen that don't happen anywhere?
The answer is probably yes.
Why is it so hard for you to talk about this?
Because I have my children in school, actually.
My children are in school now.
I don't want to expose them to anything -
- And I don't want to expose myself to anything.
- So they go to the school you yourself ...?
- I have put my children there.
-How is it that?
- Yes, I swore to never do.
Because my feeling is that the school has changed a lot.
The beautiful thing that was there when I walked there is left, but not as extreme.
The art and game are still there.
- I put my son on Solvik.
- Trot you have been through yourself?
Yes, but I went in and said, "Hello, Merete! So this is the situation ..."
My concern for what is left in the atmosphere -
- They were responsive to, I experienced.
So I believed in it.
But I regret it bitterly.
Robin had felt bullied by his teacher throughout his school time.
In 2010 he still chose Solvik  as a school for his son.
He probably got the same role, my son, as I got -
- And not placed in that.
I am in deep sadness that it became so at least -
- That he had to make the same trip as me in some way.
It seems that some problems  from the past have remained.
At the same time I see how the school  has changed in several ways.
But perhaps the  Most important question remains:
Which of Steiner's ideas are still alive?
I think of karma.
that you looked at children's injuries  as something that fit into their lives.
Is that attitude left at school?
Many teachers at the school are anthroposophists -
- As has cared a lot about what Steiner has said and so -
- So I dare not say that it is not left.
Steiner talked a lot about karma.
I think of the Solviks Teacher  who has been accused of -
- To with an educational thought  Have paired Children -
- where one needed to fight -
- and the other needed to learn  to stand up for himself.
Mm ... Yes, there we get into that swampy area -
- Which is almost similar to Karma or so there, or reincarnation.
Yes ... that's a tricky idea.
Would you say that something could happen today?
Yes, it is a little difficult, if you think the ideas remain.
It can easily happen without anyone noticing, if it is not pronounced.
If it were to be pronounced in the college, then my hope - is
- That it gets reactions that show that it may not be a good idea.
But I may not think that the school has done such a job around the issue -
- It is quite clear that this is not what we do.
I do not think so.
It would need to be done, actually.
Mm.
What Started  As a Story of My School Time -
- deals with suddenly about what is going on  for the children attending school today.
that they run the risk of being treated  from a karmap perspective.
Since the autumn of 2020  Solvik is included in the same organization -
- like the other Waldorf schools  in Sweden.
I want to know how Waldorfskole-  Federation views its new member.
Please Johannes, can you email me?
Do not want to participate - as the main organization of the Waldorf Schools
- And give you a picture of what a Waldorf school is?
I ask you now, hearing my prayer, write it down.
but they do not want to put up  in an interview.
They explain that they do not comment  about individual schools.
I have understood that it is not possible  to set similarity signs -
- Between Solvik  and other Waldorf schools.
but still it is actually so -
- that several of the Steiner books such as  Inspired Pär and Solvik's teacher -
- Is Such  that many Waldorflärs have read.
Books where karma and reincarnation  are included as part of pedagogy.
If you put your child at Waldorf school without really knowing what it is -
- So there may be a risk of misunderstanding, of course.
If the school claims to be a Waldorf school, it means to some extent-
- That such ideologies are at the bottom, is basically.
-Hello!
-Hello.
How's it going?
- Should we sit outside?
-We can do that.
But do you have to film?
Because ... there is something that is not quite fun.
People call and think you are looking to steal the entire Waldor's movement.
- That I want to steal the Waldor Movement?
-Yes.
After all, the Waldor Movement has to do with anthroposophy.
That connection is there.
- You can't remove it.
- not either.
But why are you affected by it?
You are not sitting with them.
No, but it calls people and says, "Beware, don't talk to Jasper there."
- "Beware what you say now."
- Yes, I understand.
And then I think, "But help!"
I have a question that has grown during this time, to you.
And it is: Do you really know what you do?
Are you thinking about what happens to school?
- You know, I shit in it.
- Sen, afterwards.
- For example, if it goes down.
- I'm not going to take responsibility for that.
The loyalty that I knew towards my school-
- Where I grew up, I don't feel as strong anymore.
- Because you heard all the stories?
- I've met so many now ...
Those who have been good as well as bad.
I don't feel that loyalty.
- Then you are freed in some way.
- Yes, I would say.
My School was a lottery,  with many victims.
But I also see how such  who had a good school time -
- Has difficult to find  his place in society.
It feels like you are a tourist in ... I always feel different.
It's like something that doesn't ...
Yes, maybe almost like you have to pretend a little to fit in.
I'm not really sure it's honest.
Yes, but Pär, there are a lot of people who do not feel that they find their place -
- Ute in this community.
It may happen that I have a blind page there.
I think they should have changed society instead.
That's my meaning.
I have met Pär  So many times in the past year.
He still does not seem to understand  What consequences his ideas have had.
But one day in November  So something happens that changes it.
I have to pull, my mom is dying.
I have to leave.
I'm sorry, I have to tag.
- But you want a car?
- Yes, gladly, if it goes.
- Do I have the car keys?
-Yes you have.
I can talk about whatever -
-But a spot or a sound reminiscent of her ...
So when I'm alone here, I cry all the time.
In itself insanely interesting, this condition.
After a long fight against the cancer,  So Pär's wife Karin dies.
I've never mourned before.
Never in my entire life.
And I have not understood how strange it is until now.
Dad has ...
I have never seen him have shame, feel guilt, show empathy.
I've never seen him feel someone else's pain, almost.
It's like this grief opened a small, small passage -
- To some kind of empathy.
One of the first times I was there so I also told him ...
Or I said straight out: "You have these problems."
It's a real ignition with me.
I've had a real diagnosis -
- So I actually haven't noticed how other people are doing.
Elsa at least-
- That, even if it is late, can change.
And I think I experience it.
That at the last minute I might start to grasp the canter.
I have been a kind of dictator.
I have been a kind of authority -
- which was a bit unreasonable.
And that made me a little gone.
I never got to know really.
And that was my own fault, that is.
I drove over everyone in every way, without having a clue about it.
Yes, I have created a kingdom that says:
"This is true, outside is not true. Don't believe it outside."
Turned on a sect.
It just had to be that I had been really snapped -
- So damn what people had started to put up with.
I forced people to adapt.
Those who did not want to adapt, they then became hostile or bad.
And those who adapted received reward.
Thus, they were accepted.
And that can be disgusting.
I know how much it can affect a human being -
- To have attended this school.
How difficult it is to get out of it, build up their knowledge bank ...
... and heal all the trauma that you have been exposed to.
I have the hope that my position here and now -
- For myself, it was not my fault.
What is freedom?
Is freedom to run around with muddy boots -
–And swing high up in the air?
Is it freedom?
Or is freedom to learn for real, if you want it now?
Children who may want to learn to count and read when they are seven years -
- That they may do it may be freedom for them.
It has been a bit of painful  Travel, Back in My Past -
- There my romanticized image  of the school went into ruins.
I try to find the words to  summarize what we have been through.
But I realize that a person  already 40 years ago understood -
- What was at stake  in this experiment:
Employment Teacher Ulla, who wrote a  Report on the newly started Solvik School.
"We have such different values and so different methods" -
- "Despite the fact that the basic material, the children and the final goals" -
- "The good and independent citizen, is the same."
"Do we work in elementary school wrong and Waldorflärna right?"
"Or is it the other way around? The answer is in the future."
"The saddest thing about the trials is only" -
- "That we have such a precious experimental material."
Stairway to Hell - this hill.
-Hey!
-Are you hungry?
-Is it good?
- I am joking.
- Hello!
-Did you get a haircut?
- Yes, I had a full beard.
Now I have ... Related.
- Are you done with the grief process?
-No no no.
I was gone too much all the time.
- I literally mean gone.
- Yes, both.
- Yes, it's hard that it was so.
- I just think like this, so ...
Had someone given my kid an ear file and cut the football with a knife ...
That person had never taken another step.
- But I have no idea.
-Yes!
I ran home afterwards.
In any case, he could build and stuff.
Yes, it's great.
That's what you had as a thought here, right?
Only you are good at building and painting, the personality does not matter.
Then you are welcome, whether you are a pedophile or child abuser ...
The only thing they were not allowed to be, it was a trained teacher.
Isn't it completely screwed up?
This is a place that no one has insight into, that is the problem.
Here, anything can happen, and no one knows.
Not even the parents know what happened to their children.
That's what I always tried to say:
You have favored and categorized children.
I prioritized everyone who jumped and painted and so on.
- And the others they bumped out.
-Yes it's true.
It is so.
It's just to regret that we were bad.
We were bad teachers.
I can only say that now I know how you feel.
Do you know that?
How do I feel, then?
Right now quite disappointed and cursed.
What I like about you, I like that, not because you are my son.
I also love you because you are my son, but it is quite fresh.
- For a year ago, then I didn't say so.
- You never said so.
But maybe it was nice?
Because it had been a fucking lie.
I can't knock on the door for 23 years and then all of a sudden it opens.
- Then maybe I don't want to go in.
- No, I have ... okay.
- It happens to others ... - you should try.
Texting: Ulrika Jansson Båving Swedish Media Text for SVT