C.Teletext.urfjarranhallå!
Hell...
- Curse.
Gubbfan from Kronofogden.
–Satan.
C.Teletext.urfjarranhallå!
You know what to do.
Hello!
Leif, I see you.
Oh ... I was looking for a snuff box.
-I found it.
-Open!
Excuse me, can you hold this one?
Now you have been served, Leif.
We will have the money within a week.
Otherwise we make a foreclosure of the house -
- And seizes valuables that achieve the sum.
Wait!
18 390 SEK ...
You must have added a zero or two too much.
No, Leif.
This time it does not work to tip-Exa over the last digit.
We will have the money within a week.
You don't want it to go like last time?
Do you miss the gun, which we seized?
A week, Leif.
You have forgotten a button.
Good luck!
Damn.
- Billy!
Billy!
- Has he gone?
-Yes.
Fy fuck.
Now it's bad, Billy.
- But huh, 18,390 bucks?!
- We have a week on us to pay.
- Then they come here and empty the kitchen.
-Hell!
Imagine if they take the computer.
Is that the one you are thinking about?
The damn dumb can!
I'm so tired of that computer.
We have a car worth several thousand.
What if they take it!
They strangle us from the kitchen.
We are starving, for the hell!
You are too fat to go to the store four kilometers.
There is only one thing to do.
We get to pick up the dad's old home burner.
- Is it so damn smart?
- You can't decide what is smart.
You have been sitting at the computer and emptied the brain of brain cells.
It's like living with a vegetable.
No, it's just driving.
And take and shower, for fuck.
It smells like pigs about you.
Yuk!
- Yeah, that went well.
-Good?
We have sold for SEK 400 ... not so damn good.
The liquor tastes for fuck anal cavity.
People rather drink themselves full of lubricants and gasoline.
I know.
We may make a new recipe.
But what hell!
What the hell are you doing?
You would be here in a week.
I prepare for the foreclosure.
It was a real route 740 ...
But you can probably get rid of five cardboard for it anyway.
I'm thinking of buying it later.
Turn it into an epatractor.
So the boy has something to drive around this summer.
Or you burn up the shit and drive it into a lake.
- You bastard, give a damn in Volvon!
- Snack, little Leif ...
Both you and I know that you will never fix the money.
Just as good that you say goodbye to the old harness.
Viewed in a week.
-What do we do now?
-Nothing.
They have been after us since we got out of my dad's purse.
A stamp in the neck.
-I can not take it.
I give up.
- Wait ... something we have to do.
- It's going well.
-Good?
Looks like something I do is going well.
I tried to fix a wife ...
... I tried to lower blood pressure, I tried to join the hunting team ...
Nothing goes well, Billy.
Everything I do goes to hell.
Yuk!
This body can no longer cope.
Leif ... Hello, Leif!
What the hell are you doing?
It is six o'clock at night.
I have cooked a new recipe.
Now damn!
Now I have got something good.
Taste!
Screw me!
You're a fucking genius, Billy.
I said it would settle.
It's the best thing I've been drinking since my father was on the move.
Fy fuck ...
Do you want to stay and rot, or should we get rid of the parasites?
-Here we go!
I can get up myself.
- come.
Fy hell ...
-Fuck off!
YES!
- You were the worst alchemist!
Billy Öhman - "Liquer Lord of the Sörbäcken Forests".
Soon they will be allowed to shut down Systembolaget down the village.
- How much did we get together?
–13 000. 13,000, Leif!
Fuck off.
Another round, we can pay off the damn crown bailiff.
Do you know something?
If there is money left, you can buy Playstation 4.
-You're joking?
You must not have fun, Leif.
-I'm not kidding.
And then you get your wisdom tooth yours.
-Is it true?
-I never lie.
Now we go to bed.
Alchemist.
C.Teletext.urfjarranodod Morning.
Time for local news.
C.Teletext.urfjarrani Sörbyn municipality has taken off a homemade liquor epidemic.
C.Teletext.urfjarran Police take this very seriously -
C.Teletext.urfjarran - when the crime is not just about home burning.
C.Teletext.urfjarranspriten contains methanol.
C.Teletext.urfjarranalla who consumed the liquor has been hit by temporary blindness -
C.Teletext.urfjarran - and Sörbyn Hospital is now overloaded by people being cared for ...
Billy, Billy!
Billy ... Billy ...
- Billy!
Billy!
- Yes, I'm here, Leif.
-Help!
I'm blind like a mole.
- Law, Leif!
-I can not see anything.
Let me go!
- Law, calm!
Do not you understand?
The body has started to put on me.
First the vision, then the legs start to quit and then I lie there ...
-It's over.
-Take it easy.
-I'm going to die!
Its over!
-Quiet...
Oh, calm down!
Oh my God.
- Release that.
- You let me go!
- Take the rifle.
Take the rifle, Billy!
-Okay.
Tell me the pipe at my head.
I do not want to live anymore.
Press off!
- But, God cursed.
Shoot me!
- Okay, it was the liquor, Leif!
I looked at the news.
Half the village has become blind.
It was my fault.
Your bastard.
You've made your own brother blind.
Now you have to push me to the hospital.
Come ...
Billy!
- What did you put in the fucking home cooler?
- I took a little bit of everything possible ...
- Not from the can in the caravan, well?
-Yes.
Cursed!
It's methanol, your fucking chicken brain!
- It is strange that I am blind!
- I tried to help.
Soft!
Soft?
Yes, I can be soft now that I look like a handicapped.
Good that I don't have to see your damned Nylle.
Now the father had been damn proud.
Congratulations.
So there ... it will take a week before the antidote had its effect.
But you will get the sight back.
I want you to wear these to make your eyes re -adjust.
So good!
Then you were done.
Thanks.
The person who sold the alcohol to you, what did it look like?
-No clue.
- It's hard to remember.
If you get in touch again, call me.
It is a very serious crime.
- Yes, we call.
-Thanks.
Thanks, Billy.
Good work.
Yuk!
Take it easy, Leif.
It is that way.
Follow me, just ...
Nämen Hello, boys!
I just wondered if you tried to throw away again.
Nämen, Leif, what handsome glasses!
They look really good on you.
Now it's been a week, and we still haven't seen any money.
- So now I want the car keys.
- Take it a little quiet with the picture keys.
–13,000 SEK.
- Boys, boys ...
You have gone hard on the savings box.
But it is taken five thousand, so I want the car keys.
Please, whatever but not the car.
You have taken stuff under the table before.
Either you take the car -
- Or you take something under the table and write off the debt.
- But ... what would it be, then?
- High pressure washer ...
... or the computer upstairs.
It's an old Macintosh.
Or Mulltoan ...
- This, then?
- The caravan?
-Yes.
The wife wants to get a caravan.
--Leif, I don't think ...
Wow, what a great idea!
It's super nice.
- It rolls on any good.
–Fan, Leif ...
Right.
Good, Billy, that you reminded me.
The keys we have lost ..
... but you arrange that.
- I might surprise her.
- It's damn nice.
Do you know what, boys?
We drive it!
-Write under here.
- I pull on a small crow.
Perfect!
Then you are debt free.
Hello hi.
I know who sold all the full spirits.
It is a man with a caravan that runs in the hooks.
Yes, it matches the description.
That's him.
Texting: SVT Language & amp;
Accessibility (C) Swedish Television AB 2019