These men believe that they are soon on their way home to Stockholm.
But they are cheated.
For King Kristian II of Denmark is not to be trusted.
He will be known in Sweden as Kristian tyrant.
Instead of letting them go home, he throws them in jail.
King Kristian II does not know about it, but when he lurks the Swedish nobles -
- And takes them to Denmark, so he teaches one of them a very important homework.
A lesson to never trust King Kristian.
It will save this man from being beheaded -
- And instead make him king over Sweden.
Known as Gustav Vasa.
We are in the late Middle Ages.
A time in the pest's cruel shadow -
- Filled with bloody rebellion and evil death.
Many get into the power struggle about Sweden and the Swedish throne.
But only one will succeed.
But it will require him to be both cunning and ruthless.
This is the story of our country.
About the people and forces that have shaped it -
- Endure from the ice age until our days.
This is the story of Sweden.
From the mid-1300s, the plague draws in waves across Europe.
Gotland is hit hard.
The once flourishing island has a hard time rising.
And now the next accident is soon here.
They are on their way to the churches.
It is urgent.
Now the bells have to call to warn the population.
/Church bells squeeze/
Gotland is invaded.
When the alarm is heard over the island, the farmers hurry to get ready for battle.
For Gotland's army consists of farmers.
The farmers on Gotland would by law have equipment for battle.
They are armed with brows, shields and weapons.
And they can fight.
But on the other hand, they were not prepared for such a large invasion as we see here.
All war -capable men are preparing for war.
From the age of 15, one would participate in the defense.
But some still had to stay home.
Probably they wanted to make sure that some younger ones survive -
- And take care of the yard.
The one who attacks Gotland is the Danish king Valdemar Atterdag.
He has an army of close to 2,000 Danish soldiers and German lego nectar.
Valdemar Atterdag is king in Denmark, and he wants to make his kingdom bigger.
He has conquered Skåne, Halland, Blekinge and Öland.
And now Gotland is in turn.
Around Gotland, coins and valuables are dug down -
- To be safe there until the victory is won ...
... or the looting is over.
The farmer soldiers walk towards Visby to meet the enemy.
They are moving towards a battle that has dramatic consequences -
- For both Sweden and their own future.
Outside Visby's walls, the peasant army has gathered to defend the island.
They stand with their loved ones - neighbors, cousins, fathers ...
... and sons.
We do not know why the peasant army chooses to gather outside Visby.
They may have been so that they wanted support from the city.
But the gates do not seem to have been opened.
The Visby residents and farmers have long been a conflict on trade in the Baltic Sea.
The city wall was built to exclude the farmers from the important trade.
So the relationship between the farmers and the city is bad.
You do not know how Visby acted in connection with the battle at the Ring Wall -
- But it is believed that the city was passive.
They wanted to wait and see what happened.
On July 27, 1361, the battle at Visby stands.
And when the invading army lets the arrows rain -
- Has the Gotland peasant army not long in life.
The Danes who came were all professionals.
In the long term, strength conditions were unequal.
The invading army continues to chop and settle forward -
- And panic erupts among the farmers.
But with the back to the ring wall, there is nowhere to escape.
On the battlefield outside Visby, upwards of 1,800 Gotlanders die on this day.
Almost all the island's farmers have come to fight.
Valdemar Atterdag and his German lego nectar do not negotiate.
And they take no prisoners.
Over 500 years later you will find mass graves from the Battle of Visby.
Nearly 1,200 skeletons.
As a Gotlander, you become very personally engaged in this -
- Although it was 600 years ago, you can very well relate to -
- That people go out of houses to defend their hometown and your family.
The youngest skeletons with combat damage are about 16 years old -
- And the youngest individuals in the graves are around 15 years old.
When the battle is over, a large part of Gotland's defense is eradicated.
The future of the Visby residents is now in King Valdemar's hands.
He is said to have threatened to burn down the city if the Visby residents did not pay a fee.
A so -called fire assessment.
There is a well -known painting depicting the fire estimation of Visby.
It hides here, in the National Museum's magazine.
Many of you may recognize it from the history books.
It is from 1882, and is thus painted many hundreds of years later.
It depicts something that probably never took place.
There is no evidence that King Valdemar threatened to burn down the city -
- If he did not get barrels filled with valuables, as the board tells.
The board describes a story that is recorded from the 17th century.
The fire estimation has not happened, but the city seems to have had to pay -
—Shere form of money and maybe goods to Valdemar -
- To avoid ravages and looting.
Following the Battle of Visby, Gotland's rural - is plundered -
- Of the invading forces.
No one knows how many taxes were dug down and remained in the ground.
But among those found is the down tax from central Gotland.
The largest medieval treasure in Scandinavia.
Valdemar has directed a hard blow to Sweden when he conquers Gotland.
But it will not be Valdemar who takes power over Sweden.
Instead, Margareta will do, Valdemar's daughter.
So far she is just a little eight year old at home in Denmark.
But she will be one of Europe's foremost female regents ever.
In the mid-1300s, the map of Sweden does not look like today.
Parts of southern Sweden are in Danish hands.
The fighting for power is constantly drawing on the boundaries.
Ordinary people's farms can be located in a lifetime -
- Both Swedish and Danish land.
But for most people it doesn't mean much.
They did not identify yourself as a Swedish but as a small lander or the West Goth.
You belonged to your landscape or your village or maybe your city.
You did not see it as belonging to a nation.
And people have something else to think about than which king governs.
For the plague returns in waves during the 1300s and 1400s-
- And it is generally a messy time for many.
It is a time of political chaos.
In the 1360s, three kings govern in Sweden.
There is civil war, and in the Baltic Sea pirates ravage.
So it's very worried.
But from the political chaos, something new will emerge.
Valdemar Atterdag's daughter Margareta is now an adult.
She is 44 years old and has been victorious from the fighting for power in Sweden.
She has made herself a queen and regent of not only Sweden -
–On also Denmark and Norway.
Now she is in Kalmar castle to strengthen and consolidate her power.
Margareta is a skilled politician and an extremely skilled negotiator.
She has a relationship that gives her a very good position.
Her father Valdemar Atterdag: King over Denmark.
Her husband Håkan: King over Norway.
Her father -in -law Magnus Eriksson: King over Sweden and former Norway.
In this way, she can claim power over all three kingdoms.
Margareta is not just an intelligent politician.
She is also actionable and takes violence if needed.
And now Margareta wants to tie the countries in the Nordic countries into a large union.
Parts of the Swedish nobility oppose Margaret's plans -
- But as a skilled negotiator, she wins over the most powerful in her cause.
In addition, many want calm and stability in Sweden -
- And that's something Margareta promises.
Therefore, they support the idea with the Kalmar Union.
The Kalmar Union means that a king should control the three Nordic kingdoms:
Swedish, the Danish and the Norwegian.
What happens in Kalmar 1397 is that Margareta looks to -
- That her adoptive son Erik of Pomerania is elected king over the Union.
The three kingdoms will function fairly independently within the Kalmar Union.
Each kingdom must have a national council and manage its internal affairs.
Over them, a king should have power, especially over foreign policy.
Foreign policy at this time is very much about war and trade.
And it is precisely the trade in the Baltic Sea that Margareta wants to gain control over.
A German trade association dominates and has a monopoly at the Baltic Sea trade.
The Trade Federation is called Hansan -
- And for Margareta, the Kalmar Union is a way to challenge Hansan.
Many people think Hansan has become too powerful-
- And want to access the money that Hansan earns.
The idea is that during a Union King, the Nordic countries can be strong enough -
- Pressing back Hansan.
The land areas of the Kalmar Union extend all the way from Finland in the east -
- To Greenland in the west.
Margareta succeeds in the negotiations.
The huge Kalmar Union becomes reality.
But there is a problem: the Union is on an unstable foundation.
The meeting in Kalmar was big politics, with negotiations that lasted for weeks.
There is still a resistance -
- Among some of the rich and powerful Swedish nobles.
They want to make sure that Sweden remains an election kingdom -
- And that "domestic men" sit in Swedish castles and counties, not Danes.
A struggle arises between Danish royal power with the Union King on one side-
- And parts of the Swedish nobility, who want more self -government, on the other.
The conflict becomes a problem for the Union throughout its existence.
But at the moment Sweden, Norway and Denmark have a new king - on paper.
The first Union King: Erik of Pomerania.
But in practice, Erik can only control in Norway.
In Sweden and Denmark, Margareta still decides.
But it is plague times and anyone can be affected, at any time.
Queen Margareta died in 1412 in Flensburg.
She was there to negotiate, and probably died of the plague.
And with Margaret's death, power is instead at Erik.
He fails to keep the Kalmar union together as skilled as Margareta.
He threw the country into a war against Hansan, which was very expensive.
He raised taxes to pay for the war -
- And he was very badly seen in the Swedish Empire at all.
In the 1430s, it starts to crack a lot in the joints of the Kalmar Union.
The time of rebellion dawns.
Everything starts in Bergslagen.
Erik's war against Hansan hit the mountain men hard.
The mountain men are dependent on Hansan for his trade with the iron -
- That comes directly from their blast furnaces.
And it is the mountain men in Bergslagen who themselves manage the trade with Hansan.
When Erik of Pomerania lets his vessels attack Hansan's ship in the Baltic Sea -
- It distinguishes the trade with Bergslagen, and it awakens the anger of the people.
And when Erik, to finance the war against Hansan, raises taxes -
–And the taxes are driven by a hated Danish bailiff in Bergslagen -
- Yes, then it will be the drop that causes the beaker to run over.
A rebellion flares up.
The people of Bergslagen are now starting to end up behind this man.
Engelbrekt Engelbrektsson collects the people -
- To be known as the Engelbrekts rebellion.
Engelbrekt comes from Bergslagen.
He is a mountain man and the lowadel-
- And has very strong financial interests in Bergslagen.
Engelbrekt is central.
He has the ability to gather large crowds-
- As he follows him in the rebellion he is involved in and starts.
Engelbrech's purposes are two.
First, dismiss Erik of Pomerania.
Secondly, support in particular the inhabitants of the cities and citizens -
- And the mountain men in their financial interests, which have been threatened by the war.
Engelbrekt's rebellion spreads from Bergslagen.
His forces reach down to southern Halland-
- And he gets supporters all the way up in the Finnish Ostrobothnia.
He is well on his way to defeat Erik by Pomerania -
- And free Sweden from Danish supremacy.
But the Swedish nobility is worried that Engelbrekt becomes too strong and powerful -
- And before he gets control over Sweden, they turn him back.
Two years after the Engelbrekts rebellion starts ...
... it ends when Engelbrekt is killed in a feud.
After his death, the power struggle continues on the rule of the Kalmar Union and Sweden.
Erik of Pomerania is set aside -
- And the new union kings that come after him will not be long -lasting.
Several Swedish noblemen continue to counteract the Danish union kings.
The conflict around the Kalmar Union is raging throughout the 15th century.
A city that ends up in the firing line is Lödöse in Västergötland.
After quarrels with Norway, the city's trade operations are forced to move a few miles.
And with the trade, many of Lödö's residents move.
Remains will then be a lot of possessions from people who lived in Lödöse.
That is why we have such a great wealth of archaeological finds from Gamla Lödöse.
You have actually found things about how the children were doing.
We have a brick where a child has trampled and left his footsteps.
This may indicate that children had to help, perhaps in brick production.
But we have also found finds that show that children were allowed to be children.
Toys we have found a number.
Everything from balls to woodwall.
And icebound, or skates, made of cow and horse legs.
Although there was time for ball games and skates for medieval children -
- So they probably had to spend most of the time helping their parents.
It was a rule that the children took the same profession as their parents.
But there is another path that breaks this pattern.
Namely the path of the church.
Some choose it as a career.
And it can lead all the way to the Pope in Rome.
It is the center of power at this time.
And all the way there reaches a man from Lilla Hossmo in Småland.
Hemming Gadh will later become a tray in the game about the Swedish throne -
- When he gives advice to Sweden's future king, Gustav Vasa.
Hemming Gadh is a climber.
He belongs to the lower upper class.
He reads as a priest and becomes secretary to the bishop in Linköping.
There he is discovered by the governor Sten Sture the older:
"That guy is smart. I want him as envoy in Rome."
Hemming rises in the degrees and becomes the chamberlain for Pope Alexander VI.
The Pope's Palace will be an important school.
What Hemming learns is the ruthless game of power.
Pope Alexander VI and his family, the Borgia family -
- is described by Machiavelli in the book Fursten as the watch type of evil.
Hemming Gadh is taught in gaining power and retaining them at all costs.
And he takes that mindset with him when he comes home to Sweden.
It is not just ideas about ruthless rulers that are spread in Europe.
The Renaissance flourishes, and ancient thoughts on art and science -
- Get new life.
In the end, this also affects Sweden.
During the 15th century comes the art of printing.
In 1483, Sweden's first book is printed.
Previously, books had been copied by hand, but now they become a mass medium.
A revolutionary invention that makes it easier to spread different messages.
And the art of letterpress will have a huge effect on society.
It also has the higher education institutions.
A few years before the first book is printed in Sweden -
- The country's first university in Uppsala is inaugurated.
Thus, Sweden is trained closer to Europe and the universities on the continent.
The Renaissance also affects the art.
Around Sweden, artwork is created with a new style.
The main painter is named Albertus Pictor -
- And his art can be seen in many churches around Sweden.
At the beginning of the 16th century, Hemming Gadh comes home to Sweden-
- With their experiences from Rome.
At the castle Tre Kronor in Stockholm he becomes an adviser -
- A new generation of power players.
One of them is the young Gustav Eriksson of the Vaasa family.
Sometimes Gustav is portrayed as underdog.
But that is not the case, because he belongs to the real social elite in Sweden.
Both of his parents were high.
His aunt Kristina Gyllenstierna -
- Was married to the Governor Sten Sture the younger one.
But despite that, he was far from a candidate to the Swedish throne.
Hemming shares his experiences from Rome-
- And learns the young Gustav Vasa to play the game of power.
And the lessons will be used by Gustav.
Soon he will meet someone who seems to be an extremely ruthless ruler.
Namely the Danish king Kristian II.
He who will be known to all Swedes as Kristian Tyrann.
We are now 18 years into the 16th century.
It has been over 100 years since Margareta created the Kalmar Union -
- And the union kings still find it difficult to control Sweden.
The resistance is strong.
Kristian, the latest Union King, has just tried to conquer Stockholm -
- To knock down the resistance.
But he fails.
Instead, he must negotiate peace.
Prior to negotiations, it was common to change hostage with each other.
A number of tall people were left to one side, and were replaced by the other-
- To have the negotiations in peace and quiet.
Together with some Swedish nobles -
- Has Gustav Eriksson Vaasa and Hemming Gadh was exchanged as hostage.
But to everyone's surprise, Kristian chooses not to negotiate at all.
Instead of negotiating, Kristian takes the hostage that catches.
And in this way Gustav learns not to trust Kristian.
A lesson that one day will save his life.
Gustav sits the prisoner in Denmark.
But after almost a year he manages to accommodate.
Gustav flees to Hansestaden Lübeck-
–And gets back from there to Sweden.
Hemming Gadh, on the other hand, he does not flee.
On the contrary.
A couple of years later, when Kristian II again tries to conquer Stockholm -
- So it is with Gadh by his side.
He will help Kristian take the city.
I think Kristian appeals to Hemming Gadh's vanity.
"You are so wise and wise, and you are not appreciated in this camp."
"This is not a national conflict, there are different interests."
"You can gain from supporting me."
Regardless of Hemming's motive, he can lead the woman who leads Stockholm's defense -
- Opening the city's gates and giving up the opposition to King Kristian.
That woman is none other than Kristina Gyllenstierna -
- Sink to the Governor Sten Sture.
It may seem idiotic to open the city gates -
- But Kristina has negotiated a really good amnesty.
No one should be punished.
Everyone who has resisted should keep their goods.
Kristina has large goods in Sweden and Finland, which she is promised to keep.
We are at Stortorget in the Old Town.
People are on their way to work and tourists try Swedish coffee.
But it was not 500 years ago so calm and quiet.
Because when Kristina gives up the defense of Stockholm -
–And opens the city's gates for Danish King Kristian -
- So one of the most brutal events in Swedish history begins.
And it takes place right here.
Stockholm's blood bath.
It all begins with Kristian being crowned King, even over Sweden.
The fine noble families and the men of the church are invited to a large coronation party.
Initially, the coronation and the big party go just as planned.
Old enemies and allies meet, and the king is in a brilliant mood.
But then everything turns.
On the third day of the coronation party, King Kristian locks the gates to the party.
No one comes out.
Archbishop Trolle is now accusing the king's former opponent of heresy.
It changes the whole situation.
The amnesty they have just received from the king suddenly no longer applies.
Heresy is a crime against the teachings of the church, that one deviates from the norm -
- or physically attack the church.
Only the church can decide what is heretics -
- As it is a crime against God, and that is punished with death.
A heretical king cannot withdraw a worldly king.
In this way, the heretics do at Stockholm's carnage - do
- The amnesty no longer applies.
It has become meaningless.
Kristian does not oppose the chain of the chain.
Instead, he lets the executions.
These are terrible scenes that take place here on Stortorget -
- During some dark days in November 1520.
The designated heretics are hung or beheaded with ax or sword.
Over 100 men are executed and burned during these days.
It is difficult to know why the carnage became so extensive.
King Kristian had his reasons for a political cleansing -
- But you have speculated on Archbishop Trolle and King Kristian -
- Howed up in advance about the charteridom.
In that case, it would explain:
The events on Stortorget were completely in line with what the king actually wanted.
Now much of the political resistance to King Kristian is gone.
Two who can get away with the blood bath are Gustav Eriksson and Hemming Gadh.
Kristian II sends Hemming Gadh to Finland before the carnage.
The idea is that Hemming will persuade the Union opponents in Finland -
- To stand on the king's side.
But Kristian does not trust Hemming.
Instead, he makes sure that Hemming is executed when he comes to Finland.
Gustav Eriksson had learned the homework -
- Then he was captured by Kristian a few years earlier.
So when Gustav was invited to Kristian's coronation, he chose to fail.
Gustav hides during the carnage, but his family and relatives -
--Åker to Stockholm to participate in the festivities.
Stockholm's carnage affects Gustav most personally.
His father and several other relatives are beheaded.
His mother and three sisters are thrown in prison in Denmark.
When Gustav finds out that Danish jacks are looking for him -
- He escapes to Dalarna.
The purpose is to bring the dale men in a rebellion against the Danish royal power.
At the same time as Gustav seeks support in Dalarna -
- Kristian takes home to Denmark from Stockholm.
On the way through Sweden, he executes even more opponents -
- In even more carnage.
When Kristian's men let drinking several monks at Nydala Monastery -
- He is given the nickname "tyrant".
Kristian II makes several mistakes when he takes power after the carnage.
He raises taxes, leaves the country and tries to disarm the farmers.
But the farmers want to be armed, so they rebel.
Together with Gustav now rises to King Kristian.
Now the farmers in Småland are also joining the uprising.
And the leader of the fight becomes Gustav Vasa.
But some castles and castles are difficult to conquer for the peasant soldiers.
To succeed, mercenaries and a fleet are required.
So Gustav turns to the Germans.
Gustav Vasa borrows money from Lübeck -
–And when Lübeck sees that he is about to succeed with his business -
- So they send military reinforcement, a whole army that helps him.
But the help is not free.
Gustav puts in debt to Lübeck.
Gustav's army eventually wins the war, and he is elected to King Gustav -
- The first of the Vaasa family, June 6, 1523.
And that means the definitive end for the Kalmar Union.
Gustav is chosen as king has several reasons.
He has the right background, and above all, almost all competition is gone.
All heads for the large nobles are beheaded in the carnage.
When Gustav is elected king, a new chapter begins in Sweden's history.
So Gustav sees it, and he affects how the story of him is written.
Gustav builds up the image of himself as the rescuer of the Swedish people -
- And convinces many generations that this was really the case.
Again and again he has been depicted as Sweden's country father.
The most grand statue is here at the Nordic Museum.
But the road to country father gets crooked.
When he takes power, he is a very poor king.
The help he received from Lübeck was expensive, and now they demand the money back.
But Gustav is not the one who pays for himself.
The Swedish people will do that.
Dalkarls who helped Gustav Vasa reacted negatively to the Posters -
- And pretty soon they rebelled against him.
Gustav tries hard -handed to beat down the uprising, but the Dalfolk does not give up -
- And the deeply indebted king is starting to have serious problems.
But something has recently happened in Germany, who will play Gustav in his hands.
A few years before Gustav takes power, the German monk has Martin Luther -
- Started protest against the Catholic Pope Church.
A change, or reformation, of the church is underway.
There is a strong criticism of the Catholic Church -
- And how the priesthood behaves throughout Europe.
Many princes now see an opportunity to gain greater power and wealth.
One of them is Gustav Vasa.
The motives for his part regarding the Reformation -
- Is probably largely economic.
The Catholic Church in Sweden will become a Swedish church.
The pope is no longer the highest hen.
The king should be.
King Gustav.
All this is usually called Västerås recess.
The krona strengthens its finances by seizing the church's properties.
The bishops lose their power, and their military followers are reduced.
The monasteries are closed and the nobility regains their goods which they donated to the church.
So the winners of this reform package are the king and the nobility.
When the church's land and properties change owners, the king's economy is improved.
With money in the pocket, Gustav Vasa manages to beat down the uprising in Dalarna -
- So the men are forced to give up.
Gustav is not content to take control of the church's properties.
He also wants to take control of the language of the church:
The Bible should be translated into a language that the people understand, ie.
Swedish.
The New Testament is printed in Swedish three years after Gustav was selected as king.
Then it is decided that the fair in the churches should also be held in Swedish.
The Old Testament is also translated over time.
Gustav Vasa's Bible is the first Bible in Swedish.
During this time, bibles are printed in the vernacular.
Gustav Vasa wanted to show that his vernacular, ie the Swedish - -
- Can be used for religion, not just Latin.
You had the idea that it should be a state, a language.
In this way, the Bible is also a means of power, a way to manifest power.
Gustav Vasa's Bible translation is of great importance for the Swedish language.
As the New Testament is spread to all parish churches in Sweden -
–Af the priests get something to relate to spelling -
- And this is the first time this is happening in the Swedish language.
Gustav Vasa's Bible gets an enormous weight-
- For the Swedish writing language norm.
With Vasa's Bible, the bookstores establish itself, Ä and Ö in our alphabet.
But Gustav Vasa is mainly interested in strengthening the royal power.
He puts a lot of effort into building the Swedish state apparatus.
Gustav centralizes the kingdom.
He builds up a bailiff -
- And is in constant connection with the bailiffs.
They write to each other.
The bailiffs are liable to account, so they have to go to the Royal Palace -
- To the counting chamber, and report their accounts.
This is the first phase of Sweden's state formation process in the 16th century.
But outside the country, the changes are not appreciated -
- And the nitic bailiffs that demand the people on their properties.
Especially not in Småland.
There, a man rises to the king's bailiffs.
Nils Dacke has had enough.
When Nils Dacke kills Gustav Vasa's bailiffs, a rebellion begins in Småland.
Dacke feud.
We are now in the early 1540s.
For many, Nils Dacke is a rebel leader -
- But according to Gustav Vasa, he is a whore man, traitor and heretic.
Gustav Vasa uses propaganda against Dacke and his men.
He calls them Småland forest thieves, to reduce them -
-And pretending that there is a small local problem in Småland -
- While the dissatisfaction is in fact widespread throughout the country.
But Nils Dacke is not a forest thief -
–On a Småland farmer who lives with his wife Elin and their son -
- In the yard Flaka in southern Småland.
Life in Småland at this time is poor.
But people are used to taking care of themselves and deciding on their lives.
They don't want anyone to change that.
Not even the king.
There are several things that make the dacke uprising flare up.
Not just new taxes should be paid.
Now that the king is the high leader of the church -
- He begins to empty the churches on rime judges, to replenish the Treasury.
The jacks who collect church silver end up on a collision course with the people.
For in the churches, among the church silver -
- There is the object that the people themselves have paid, such as bridal crowns.
And they would like to see their daughters carry bridal crown as they get married.
They do not understand why the king collects such objects and melts them down.
It may not be so strange that people get angry and want to strike back.
The strange thing is that an ordinary farmer leads the uprising.
Nils Dacke is against the king's new requirements and increased control.
He wants it as it used to be.
Dacke's rebellion spreads -
- And Gustav's jacks is an easy prey for Dacke's men in the loud forests.
Soon Gustav Vasa realizes that the uprising is starting to become a serious problem.
The king then withdraws his troops -
- And signs a ceasefire with Nils Dacke.
But peace is not long lasting.
The king strikes back with full force -
- And his men finally manage to get Nils Dacke, and kill him.
Gustav Vasa is very ruthless and is looking for Nils Dacke's relatives.
He executes many, such as Dacke's mother and others who have been in contact with him.
He does not want an uprising atmosphere in Småland, which risks blossoming.
Gustav Vasa lets Nils Dacke's head on a pile at Kalmar Castle.
A warning of how things are going for anyone who sits up against King Gustav.
A crown of copper was put on the head-
- To show that Nils Dacke was a rebel and false leader.
But the Dacke uprising changes King Gustav and Sweden.
Gustav Vasa has so far been quite burdus in his politics.
He has often just pushed through things and ignored what people thought.
Nowadays you see him go around.
He tries to read the situation.
He makes more successive changes, and even
the return.
He tries more to gain popularity in the people, after the Dacke feud.
Gustav Vasa is dead.
He has ruled Sweden for 40 years -
- And managed to create order and stability in the kingdom.
The situation in Sweden is far from the uncertainty that prevailed -
-After the pest's ravages in the late 1300s.
It is over to constant rebellion and power struggles between different interests.
The Danish influence over Sweden is over-
- And the country has become independent and united under Gustav Vasa.
He leaves behind a well -organized country.
It is good finances and filled barns.
There is a lot of silver in the royal tax chamber.
He has created peace.
It is well functioning to be the 16th century.
Gustav Vasa has been described both as a country father and the dictator.
He was unscrupulous and did not pull for lies, manipulation and violence.
But he was also another.
In the letters, a person with great humor emerges.
And he was a loving father who was constantly worried about his children.
Gustav's children are gathered around the coffin.
Vasa's body is located in a chamber at Stockholm Castle for eight weeks.
The body is embalmed and he is prepared.
And the director behind all this is Erik.
Now he has taken over -
- And the other children may adhere to what he says.
Gustav had led the Riksdag to agree to make Sweden an inheritance.
The king should no longer be chosen, but the crown should be inherited from father to son.
And since Erik is the eldest son, it is he who becomes king: Erik XIV.
Gustav will be the first king in Sweden, which is buried here in Uppsala Cathedral.
That he is located here, at the foremost place in the church -
- shows clearly that he won power both across the kingdom and across the church.
After Gustav Vasa's death, a new era begins in our history.
Sweden will be a great power, and the price for it will be high.
Texting: Ulrika Jansson Båving Swedish Media Text for SVT