Norrland - a beautiful landscape with high mountains.
Miles -long primeval forest and a population living in harmony with nature.
But for the brothers Öhman in Sörbäcken, everyday life is not harmonious.
C.Teletext.urfjarranleif!
Yes, it's Leif.
It seems to be dead.
There will be no protein today either.
I'm starting to move home.
Damn!
See if you find lingonberries or mushrooms or any fuck.
- Yes, but Leif ... - it doesn't matter!
I might as well die anyway.
Hello!
Cursed boot fucking!
It is better than the safe.
Not a bastard finds this.
Damn!
Check out what I found, Leif!
I might not have done it!
The ragging gang came with the bag.
- The thunk?
- No, he sits inside.
It was Jimmy with the knife's cousin, Damp-Janne.
-Oh my God!
Did he see you?
-I do not think so.
Hell!
Damn!
What have I done?
What in the whole ...?
Pull me backwards through the gates of hell, Billy.
Oh my God!
I can't turn from Damp-Janne.
Billy, don't you understand?
We have lived in this caravan for almost a year.
I shit in whose money it is.
This is a gift from above.
Now we have the chance, Billy, to start a new life.
There is only one house for sale.
Sörbäcken is our home.
Starting price 200,000?
We have 700,000 in the bag.
Take it easy.
Do not go around with gold fever in the skull.
Now you have to push down the price first.
Calm down!
- Here it is, Billy.
- The dream house!
It is newly renovated.
We can shoot pigs from the upstairs.
- Think, soon it's ours.
- It is long.
We need to remove other speculators.
-How?
-I have a plan.
Hello Hello!
Welcome.
Here you go.
There are prospectus on the table.
Hello.
- Hello.
It's such a nice light input!
When we renovate it becomes perfect.
Well, so that's where they hung.
The family who lived here before, everyone hung.
But they have well taken down the hooks.
No, corner, we pull.
This could be our bedroom.
Oh oh oh...
I am from the radiation authority and measure the radiation.
Fy hell.
- I get full ruling on the radar, so I move outward -
- Whatever I get miscarriage, no, malformations.
A cozy kitchen.
What do you think, the old man?
God!
Well ... Greger has already found here.
Dirty-Gger, as he is called.
He lives close.
A rough sex offender, or pedophile - I mix it together.
Tjena, Greger!
- He smells of new people.
Oh my God!
Come kids, we've been looking clearly.
Fy fuck, Leif, you are a genius.
Not a bastard is interested.
Take it easy.
It's long before this is done.
- Were you doing?
-I beg.
Haven't you heard of praying?
Then you get what you want.
Quiet now.
Why haven't you said it before?
Then we will see what Leif Öhman wants.
I want a castle by a lake, seven wives in bikini running around -
- And dolphins that spray money out of their heads.
- It's not a wish game!
Pea brain - this is reality.
People become like Hyenor when bidding is left.
I don't know what I do if we don't get the house.
Not another day here!
- It certainly goes well.
-We'll see.
That's our only chance.
Now fate may decide our future.
I'll be coming soon.
Soon the biding begins.
C.Teletext. sound signc. sound
- God, what you are scared!
-Sorry.
That was not the point.
I was going to ask if any people are interested in the kitchen.
No not yet.
It's a bit strange.
200,000 for this is not so stupid.
No, that's fine.
We will see now that the bidding starts.
I'll put the cards on the table for you.
My brother is completely ruined.
We have lived in a caravan for almost a year.
It is pretty hard.
Sörbäcken is our home, so it is important for us that we get the house.
But if you are interested, you should place a bid.
-Yes Yes.
Yes, or maybe.
- It is clear that you are going!
- Yes, then we do.
- How much do you want to put?
Let's say three or two hundred ... a thousand.
Perhaps.
If it's possible.
Yes, it goes.
I will call.
Hi Andreas.
I stand away at Sörbäcken and we have a first bid.
Yes exactly.
Starting price.
Your name?
You don't have to say your real name, you can take an alias.
Well.
Type ...
Should you take Pelle Paltnacke?
Pelle Paltnacke.
Good!
Okay, now we're up and running.
Pelle Paltnacke ... okay, then we'll see what you are going for.
Username: Mister Handsome 3000.
Well, then we say so.
Good!
Huh?
Mister Handsome 3000?
Ahm ... Now there has been a counter -bid of SEK 250,000.
-Oh!
Well.
It was ... damn.
- You can think and wait a bit.
No, dammit.
We must have the kitchen.
Raise.
Toss 50,000 more.
Okay.
You wanna play tough, man, you wanna fuck with mr cool?
You Wanna Play Hard?
Leif, tough to you.
No fucking meseri.
Now it will be shock rise.
So, Pelle Paltnacke.
What do you say now?
-What are they saying?
- They shocked with 100,000.
Hell!
Shut up, love, and let me think!
Sorry...
Shock height back.
100,000 more.
No!
Satan!
Okay, Leif, calm, calm.
Now you have to think tactically.
This is all you have.
Come on now, God, Buddah, Allah or what you are called.
Help me now.
SEK 700,000.
Yes, okay.
Wait.
SEK 700,000.
What do you feel - do you want to raise, right?
No, I have no more money now.
-No.
- I thank me for me.
Hello!
Thus, 700,000 ...
Leif, I have some bad news.
Worse than we are panca?
I have bid against Pelle Paltnacke.
He was hard as Satan-
- But then I stepped in with 700,000. Then he gave up.
The house is ours, the brother.
What kind of bad news did you have?
It was nothing special.
I was out pissing and saw that the car ...
Shit in the car!
We have our own house.
Yours and mine, the brother!
- Are you not happy?
-Yes.
Good!
Then we move in.
Okay...
I'll find out who Pelle Paltnacke is.
Shit in it, we have the house.
Is there anyone who bought that jerk?
What a fucking nuts.
Texting: SVT Language & amp;
Accessibility (C) Swedish Television AB 2018