Today we will talk about women and their crises.
Was life that you had hoped?
Did you get married right ...
The c. sound phone rings
Svensson.
Hello Sara.
Thanks.
40 years, yes ... side change Gustav calls it - page change and sub -40-0.
He is thick, yes ... yet he dances belly dance when he drinks too much.
Here he comes.
It looks like he is trying to focus his eyes.
Come over late.
Bye.
This is the kitchen.
I'm your wife ... Lena.
Good morning yourself.
Sara called and thanked the entertainment ...
I must have eaten something inappropriate yesterday.
It may have been the flower soil.
Why do you have to be like this at parties?
I'm Swedish.
In Sweden we have to drink liquor to have fun.
My 40th birthday you celebrated with dancing belly dance to my managers.
Nobody thinks of things like that when it's a party.
If you're looking for trouble you've come to the right place ...
Sorry!
It must be an adult's right to have a drink.
A drink?
You drank directly from the trunk bowl.
- Is the dad who has cleaned up?
- We help like a real family.
In real families you drink glass.
- No one asks how I feel.
- No one dares.
It's meant to think about what I have done to my life.
You should not believe everything you read.
Imagine if you believed all about Björn Borg!
Not words about Björn Borg!
Björn Borg is just a underwear!
- Five straight Wimbledon!
- "Six open French."
- Bear Borg is more than a underwear!
-Certainly.
Treasury.
- I regret it more than something else.
- Serve it when he can hear it.
That I stopped exercising.
I was about to become a figure skater.
The coaches thought I could go as far as possible.
When I swirled out on the ice, I felt free and strong and beautiful.
- I could have become someone!
- But then dad came ...
Have you never dreamed of anything bigger, something alive?
Something that really means something!
I'll take a walk.
-Did you have any 40-year crisis?
- With this body?
Never!
... but nice ridges have it.
A whole Trave European parliamentarian says ...
Can you help me?
I am not a cleaning lover.
You are a belly dancer.
- When she comes, it will be nice!
- You missed a grain of dust under TV - n.
-Where have you been?
- In the ice rink.
It was figure skating.
Max and Lina, don't make the same mistake as me.
Find your dream and stick to it!
So it should look!
Everything works only you dare.
-Where are you going?
- To Nymans and watch TV.
-What should we do?
- I usually run with valium.
- I was the best in the group as a 11 -year -old.
- I was best at pissing the highest.
There was nothing particular of me anyway.
Life rushes past and you walk around in a ridiculous hat ...
I try to lighten the mood.
-Do you love me?
- It is clear that I love you.
We have a whole life together.
The kids, the summer cottage ...
... bank loans, interest rates, amortization, insurance premiums, ICA cards ...
Sorry I tried to spread some joy!
-Hello!
Is the ice princess inside?
- She's up there ... and sour.
Why do women become so sensitive just because they turn 40?
No one cared about me then.
But I'm a man.
I have no feelings.
We are different.
Do you remember when I turned 30?
- You called the fire brigade in the middle of the night.
- I needed to feel that someone was listening.
- During the time Olsson's house burned down ... –Lena needs some romance.
- The song you sang ... - "It's nice to shit in deep snow"?
- It might not be quite right.
- I have sung at every party!
- It's tradition!
- But Lena needs to be surprised.
You may find something new.
We could start tipping systems ...
- Now I go to Lena.
-At your own risk.
It's me - Sara.
I am unarmed.
I don't want anything bad.
C.Sangly is to shit in meter -depth snow no, it does not work.
She is right.
How is it?
- How do men work?
- No further, unfortunately.
What do you think love is for Gustav?
World Cup 1974. Ralf Edström's 4-2 goal against Germany.
I want him to love me.
Not Björn Borg, not the trunk bowl.
ME.
You should be able to compete out.
He could well surprise me sometime with a flower, a kiss, a trip ...
- Has he really never done that?
-No.
Well, before he was really fun sometimes.
He would teach mom drink snaps.
She ran around the neighborhood in just the panties and sang "Que Sera Sera" ...
- Gustav ran after and filmed.
- What a beautiful memory ...
He was so nice.
He was so romantic.
- What says Lina and Max?
-Nothing.
They are with Nymans.
Life may be passing them too.
They do not know how fast it goes.
An error cut when you are eleven years old, and the ice princess becomes a postman's wife.
Have you heard the story of the giant pad and the butterfly?
The toad was in love with a butterfly but he never came close to it.
- The butterfly was up in the air.
- Is Gustav or I the giant pad?
It does not matter!
Do you know what he did to reach the butterfly?
He jumped.
He missed the butterfly, landed on the asphalt and burst.
- What a horrifying history.
- Yes, but he dared to jump!
- You want to jump too?
- No, I really don't want to!
Greet the giant pad down there that it is his turn to jump now!
-Who are you?
-I am death.
- Are you coming to pick me up?
- I have long gone by your side.
- How long will she be up there?
- Till we show that we love her.
Then I starve to death.
You get to cook!
-Why me?
- Because I'm a man and you're a woman.
You'll never be a man.
At its height a mopedist.
- Here is the ticket to the family peace!
–Ditt wills?
We should show mom that we love her - surprise her!
- Should you change socks?
- First, we will do something together.
Here is the recipe for Tournedos a la Gustav.
The first thing I invited to your mom.
I had put priestly collapses all over the dashboard on the folk car bus.
I kept the food warm on the engine block.
I want to recall that moment.
- First look, first kiss ... - first stomach dance ...
- Can't you help me?
- Everything for love!
He is hungry ... It is clear that we will help you.
- But then came!
- Do you think it's free?
Should you have money to show some love?!
No money - no love.
- We can also go!
- Hundred bucks.
You do what I ask you.
–200 ... and we clean the downstairs.
-Okay okay.
- I run and buy food.
- Do not glue to buy a new folk bus!
–50 to you and 150 to me.
-Yes.
No ... huh?
- What do we say when she comes?
- Hello fucking stew!
Well ... try something more romantic.
-Have you seen!
Is everything ready now, Max?
- Yes, now we are just waiting for Madame.
She comes.
I said you loved her.
- Did she go on it?
- I certainly love your mom.
Quiet now!
- Do you do my mom go on this?
- I have been a lot of fun in my day ...
You scrubbed Grandpa's roof for him to like you more.
-It worked.
I had to borrow the drill.
- hire it.
- Have you tried to be yourself?
-Once.
There were 20 stitches.
In your places!
Stand in a row!
Welcome!
To the woman of my life - Tournedos a la Gustav.
- Dad has a sense of raw materials.
- Just the best is good enough for you.
- Be so good and there, honey.
- Don't you recognize the food?
- A pathetic evening 15 years ago ... - "poetic", max.
Two young people with life ahead of them ...
I didn't know what the future looked like - just with whom I wanted to share it.
We raise a bowl for the world's most beautiful 40 -year -old.
- Lena Olin!
- If you put her next to you ...
--... then you take Lena Olin.
- Max!
The first time I saw you mom -
- I decided that she was the nicest I've seen.
- I still think so!
- Mom, you start.
I've been a real bag of shit.
- A big, stinking heap ... - we actually eat.
- Sen is dishes Lina and I.
- So you two may be for yourself.
- Have you been bribed?
- Do you do love can be purchased?
- We just want to relieve you here at home.
- Mom, we're your slaves.
- They have promised to clear the garden.
-Not really.
- You want a mountain bike?
-Are you threatening me?
- Would I threaten my son?
-What are you talking about?
- It is a little word play Max came on ... - We have not played any word play.
- Mom, I'm afraid that Dad is lying.
- Just now I take nothing.
Great!
Have you never played this before?
I'm saying figs.
-What are you talking about?
- Right again!
- Your turn.
- This will never go.
- Indeed!
- Max, think about the bike ...
Unfortunately.
200 bucks are too little to clear the garden.
Enemies everywhere.
- It was too good to be true.
- They would set up.
- Renating garden was not included in the price.
- You have bribed them.
- Would I try to buy feelings?
-Yes.
Yeah?!
Sorry so terribly much!
I just wanted to make you a little happy.
I took the help of two traitors - two Lars Skarke!
We could be a wonderful family if we just wanted to!
If you had more money ...
Good night.
But mom, 200 bucks to clear the garden?
I have a better business proposal.
Two hours of work ...
Gustav ...
Do you read Björn Borg -book?
It's good, huh?
Thanks.
It was at least as good as 15 years ago, but less exhaust.
I had more garlic then.
And real cream, instead of creme fraiche.
I did what I could.
I can't replace the kids.
Or can you?
Against Dobermann -Pinschrar ...?
It is not your fault that it became like this.
- No, it's the children's.
- No, that's my fault.
Life has gone so fast.
I just lived in Vivalla and played hide and seek.
When I had finished, I was 40.
- Where have all the years taken?
- POFF.
It felt strange to come to the ice rink ... aj!
Happy birthday darling!
- Gustav ... - They are completely newly sanded.
It's size 32. I have 38.
That was the size they had left.
You can't get everything.
- The kids ... - no.
Tonight they clean the garage.
-How much?
–150 ... where.
They become millionaires!
C.Teletext.urfjarran Dad, how do you back with the car?
Texting: SVT Sub -text (C) Swedish Television AB