You have to stop eating in bed!
Here are the plates I was looking for.
C. Head talk - Someone is in the sauna.
-What is this?!
A meatball mask!
C. Head talk of it!
Did Max give me this C. Head talk because I would do away with it?
You will notice that on the neighbors tomorrow when you pick up the magazine.
Think, tomorrow is New Year's Eve.
16 of our years together are coming to an end.
C. HOVA PATEREDU thinks we should re -evaluate how we C. Head talk has had it and how we should have it.
Yes, I think it's important.
I want to know.
How do you look at the future?
C. Head talkative self looks at the future C. Head Tapersunking as I see on a painting:
C. Head talk not what it represents, who C. Head talk it ... and is not interested.
- Yeah.
How old are you?
C. Head talk - 37.
You are 43. And the average life expectancy for a Swedish man is 74 years old.
- You have lived more than half your life.
C. Head talk - have you so much further left then?!
C. sound fractures
Come in, max.
Do you want to lie with us?
- No thanks, it is not necessary.
- Hi, we don't bother?
C. Head Tapers - Leaves Göran and Annika in our room?
- We have to ask you again.
Don't you want to come to a party tomorrow?
The C. Head talk is kind, C. Head talkativemen New Year's Eve is sacred.
Please!
You were the first we met here, and Gustav was so helpful!
- ni mixes him with someone ... –OVa Uddevalla - friends come.
- We want them to meet you.
- It sounds pretty nice.
Come on now!
They want to know who you are and what you look like.
C. Head talk we lend our photo album?
- Come, Göran.
It's no idea.
- No ... - sorry we disturbed.
- Good night on you.
Hello.
-Hello!
-Now I'm ashamed.
They like us.
C. Head talk - why are they fucking in the middle of the night then?
Good night.
- Don't eat it.
C. Head talk - I just have to hold it.
C. Head talk, watch ... C. Head talk, clock, call ...
Good morning Dad.
How can you eat ribs and mimosa salad now?
The C. Head talk is my family's New Year's breakfast since C. Head talk generations!
With new spice this year!
-What then?
Thinner?
C. Head Tapers - Thai Curry.
C. Head talkative father said that a life without adventure C. Head talkative is nothing worth it!
- He was also a postman, huh?
C. Head talkative - and that you and Max will also be.
Dad, may I ask one thing?
Was your life that you had imagined?
C. Head talk - yes - actually.
Exactly.
-Is it true.
C. Head Tapers I got everything I wanted.
C. Head talkative wife and two children who love me.
C. Head talk work where everyone loves me.
- Then you have to say congratulations ... C. Head Tapers - Away ... You ponder on the future.
C. Head talkum is done at your age.
But my C. Head Praise father taught me something before he died.
To open a sardine can with one hand.
C. Head Tapersehan looked me in the eyes and said: C. Head Tapers "make you no hopes".
C. Head talk - "Then you will never be disappointed."
-How horrible!
C. Head talk and therefore I have done the opposite.
C. Head Tableman must believe that everything is possible!
If I find something I want to do, you help me?
C. Head talk - yes, in 15 years you want to move well.
- Should I move when I'm 30?
The C. Head talk is not useful to stay at home C. Head talk.
But we don't throw you out!
Good morning...
Surely we can celebrate the twelve in the square?
- It seems fun as a change?
C. Head talk - no.
C. Head talk we have celebrated here for 16 years ...
--... So we should find something new.
-They are waiting!
C. Head talk - What are you talking about?
- We will eat at Göran and Annika.
- For you have made ribs ... –Anika has baked pallets.
C. Head talkative - Nice in life!
- Come, kids.
C. Head talk I have eaten this food for 16 years C. Head talk, I will do it today too!
C. Head talk tare or in the mornings.
- We will go soon.
- We don't like Aunt Karin.
She doesn't like you either.
But on New Year's Eve, the family drinks coffee there.
- I would rather stay home.
-Me too!
Uncle Hans smells bad.
Yes.
Dad is allowed to sit next to him.
Go and change!
Put on a dress, rope.
Good that you came.
We will buy flowers on the road.
Why do you look like that?
This New Year's Eve we will do something new.
- Close us as Norwegian opponents?
C. Head talk - no ... ski.
-I get it.
C. Head talk - that I want to avoid having to go?
- Every year you try to get away!
- What stupid you look!
C. Head talk - I try to avoid Aunt Karin.
- Once a year is not so dangerous!
- She gets so much fun when you come.
C. Head talk - she does not recognize us!
- Last year I was "Mr. Lagerwall".
- I can't go ...
You never have to meet Aunt Karin anymore.
C. Head talk - you should not regret it!
- Mom, we go if you want.
C. Head talk - no, in two minutes Ivanhoe begins.
- I am the only one who has ideas!
- You only find things you like.
C. Head talk - now I understand nothing!
C. Head talkative self buys skis, spruce - and video C. Head talk I do not know how it works.
C. Head talk - everything for you to enjoy it!
- We should do things together, we four.
Or just you two.
C. The head talk is hard to be a father.
We want C. Head talkators about the material standard.
- And the mail hat I got in Christmas?
C. Head talk - you like clothes ...
Beautiful father and daughter's relationship!
C. Head talk - she is souring for her to live at home.
- Moving is natural development!
C. Head talk, they told the EU.
Now we go to C. Head talkative Mostril Karin.
She does not jaw against.
- It's because she's deaf.
- Come, Lina.
Dad has cleared clearly.
That we have to go through the same procedure every year!
- What did the fireworks cost?
C. Head talkative thing is that it becomes beautiful.
- What did they cost?
C. Head talk - think when we look out ...
What did the cursed rockets cost?
C. Head talkative two thousand ... But then you got C. Head Tapers' Majesty on the purchase ...
- What did you get, you said?
C. Head talkative - Majesty.
The only thing in the county.
No one has dared to buy it before.
The C. Head talkared goes 1 km up and explodes C. Head Tapersi a cascade of colors.
- It's deadly!
C. Head talk - A greeting to everyone in Vivalla.
The C. Head talkum was a nice C. Head talkator's aunt Karin.
C. The head talk is about inviting yourself.
As she hugged you today!
What did you say?
C. Head talk - that I was Prince Bertil.
- The main thing is that you had a good time.
C. Head talkative self invited her to the fox hunt.
C. Head talk and you got packages!
- Two sacks and a sudde rubber.
C. Head talk - yes ... there you see.
- You then, Lina?
This.
A mixture between a Lovikkavante and a pot.
C. Head Precate ... Time to make in order.
C. Head talker line can help mom with the food.
- What is it?
C. Head Tapers - Hummer and Champagne.
C. Head Tapers - Shrimp and Christmas must as usual.
C. Head Tapers, Help me with the firing ramp.
- Hi, Gustav.
C. Head talk - no ...
C. Head talk - we can't go to your party.
Go home.
- Göran and I want to talk to you.
- Jobbly!
I'm waiting outside.
- We have to ask ...
You have not been able to come to any party.
Don't you like to spend time with us?
We cannot come today because we have other plans.
C. Head talk and it can happen more times.
It would be a shame if the friendship was destroyed because we cannot be honest.
The C. Head talk is you right in. We should be able to c. Head talkative way anything to each other!
Nice that you say so, Gustav!
- What thin -haired you have become.
C. Head talkative - va?
I feel I can say that now.
The flint is visible.
-Come now.
- We would be honest.
And it was stupid.
Happy new year everyone!
C. Head talk - I have to do something.
- It's nothing you can do.
- It delays before it falls off.
C. Head talk - I have to do something now!
C. Head Precate Annika!
The pallets we got this morning, C. Headpratarede was dry!
C. Head talkative giant ethras!
C. Head talk - There she sees what honesty means!
How she can get up after that, I don't understand that.
C. Head talk - no, old man, are you satisfied now?
- I wanted to be there at twelve.
- No one was there!
- Yes, Fill - Ragnar was there.
C. Head talk, now sit down on the sofa, C. Head talk, I will tell you.
C. Head talk ... First I should ask you: C. Head talkative do you mark something special?
- Yes, a ketchup spot on the jacket.
C. Head talk - it's chili sauce.
C. Head talk - do you mark something else?
- Do we not use TV?
C. Head Tapersjust it!
It is now in the garage.
C. HOVA PATERVI will do something that I dreamed of!
- See on TV in the garage?
C. Head talk - no ...
C. Head Tapers - N has taken up too much C. Head talk of our precious time.
C. Head talk we will talk to each other.
C. Head talkatives down!
C. HOVA PATERALA must invite a little!
On New Year's Eve, I thought you wanted to watch TV.
C. Head talkative oven, I record everything.
C. Head Tapers' Vemo feel urged to start?
Any C. Head of Call wants to tell you about a New Year's promise?
C. Head Tapers or something fun to tell?
C. Head talkative word is free!
- It seems nice at Göran.
- Max!
- Okay, I can start.
At work on Monday, someone had carried the binders to the conference room.
We had to help carry them back.
C. Head talk, yes ... there you see.
C. Head talkative can happen in the office.
C. Head talketer, Lena ... - Any other C. Head talk, if something has recently been?
C. Head talk, then I can tell you something.
C. Head talk at Posten many people think we should C. Head talk to the cover material on data.
That's certainly good.
You win time.
-What are you doing?
C. Head talk - we talk!
C. Head Tapers What are you dreaming of, Max?
About that there is peace and that the school burns down.
C. Head talk we keep our thumbs for it.
C. Head talk - you then?
About standing in the square in a few hours.
C. Head talkum The dream I can crush directly.
C. Head talk - yes ...
- This is going well, Dad ... C. Head Tapers - What are you thinking about such a night?
-Should I be honest?
C. Head talkative - obviously!
C. Head talk - What should you say?
- You probably expect it.
C. Head Tapers, help me pull in TV - n.
C. Head talk - you prepare the supper.
- Table the shrimp, you mean?
C. Head talk - pick up the peanut rings and must.
C. Head talkative prawns directly from the Arctic Ocean to you ...
... via six months in Konsum's freezer counter.
C. Head talkative thinking, it is strange ... by all C. Head talkatives shrimp in the Antarctic water -
C. Head talk - Hams this particular on my plate.
C. Head talkative self wonders if it was predetermined.
- It may be on the packaging ... C. Head talk - This is important!
Is this important?
C. Head Certificate does not.
Give me the chili mayonnaise!
- Where is Max?
C. Head talk - I don't think he wants shrimp.
C. Head Taper happened when we set up the rockets C. Head talk - he wanted to be for himself.
Don't leave him alone when he starts thinking!
C. Head TapersHur Many shrimp Should we add C. Head Tapers?
Eight?
Four?
Three...
Little old man, are you here?
Why don't you get down to us?
How did you have it before I and Lina were born?
Was it more fun?
The old man ... It is clear that everything became more fun when you arrived.
At least more difficult.
You get a lot to think about ... Why do you ask?
Time goes by so fast.
I remember the summer when I was six years old.
- I thought you could swim!
-It's not that.
Everything was so easy.
We played on the beach, went up and ate and then we could go and play again.
You can still play as much as you want!
No!
Soon I start high school and then everything is over.
I have to get girlfriend -
- Appeal Roll - On and play drums in some band.
You think too much.
At your age you do not want to become an adult.
You learn.
- You can't fight against?
- That life takes one where it wants.
- To a townhouse in Vivalla?
-Why not?
I have two wonderful kids, and a man who is okay ...
- Dad has soon eaten the shrimp!
- Take them up!
And Dad.
The shrimp is enough.
Max ... once when I was little and low and thought like this ...
--... Then Dad said something very wise.
-What then?
"Go to sleep"?
"Life is always next to you and you can do whatever you want with it."
- Here we come with all the shrimp!
- Watch down, so we eat.
- Mums!
C. Head talk - How is it, max?
Are you sad?
- No, it's better now.
C. Head Tapers - Bra.
I'll make you really happy!
- Should you go again?
C. Head Tapers-No.
You have longed, and this year ...
C. HOVA PATEREDU SHOULD ARE LIGHT at the fireworks!
C. Head talk - I stand next to all the time.
That's probably what mom is afraid of ... Three shrimp left.
C. Head Tapers I can take them!
C. Head Tapers - Ok, give me a bottle.
- What are you doing?
C. Head talk fixes the champagne.
C. Head talk - selection de loire and our bag!
- It can't be drinked.
C. Head talk, you can mix it C. Head Trocado.
- They have started to postpone the rockets!
C. Head Tapers - Max, Match!
And your Majesty!
C. Head talk - ni looks best from the bedroom.
-Exciting!
That they can ... What is so fun?
That it slams?
- It has to do with masculinity.
- You mean it's idiotic?
Happy New Year!
I will be nagging dad so you can go on a language trip.
I'll nag so he buys the necklace for your birthday.
Wouldn't you postpone the rocket?
- Did it stay nice?
- It was hard to see.
- Were you satisfied?
C. Head Precate ... a little butt chop it felt.
C. HEAD PATHERED WANTED far too low ...
-Happy New!
C. Head talk - Where was anyone injured?
No, everyone got out.
- Majesty took a round in their kitchen.
- I had to extinguish.
But the smoke remains ...
C. Head talkative - nice, we got to celebrate anyway!
-Come in!
Here are our friends from Uddevalla.
- Here is Gustav, Lena, Max and Lina.
C. Head talkatively that you came.
Remove the champagne.
If there is too little bubbles then there is a soft drink machine.
Happy New Year!
Maybe we should promise one and the other for the next New Year.
- No fireworks!
- And no ribs for breakfast.
- and lobster instead of shrimp!
- And we celebrate the twelve in the square.
C. Head talkative idea!
We can invite them home, C. Head talk, we celebrate here.
C. Head talkative - bowl for a new year!
- Hope it will be as good as last.
Try to think positively!
HAPPY NEW YEAR!
SVT program text: