- When will the party then, Lina?
-Tomorrow night.
Everyone should sleep over.
Sleep over?
It's only 50 meters there.
You know how it is at those parties.
-No.
What about those parties?
- Yes, what about those parties?
- We talk, have fun ... you know.
- No, I don't actually.
- You never tell.
- Then I would never go!
- We have never forbidden you to go.
-Yes!
You were eight years old and wanted to go to Bajsk beer party!
The upbringing is difficult.
We're talking about getting kids, but ... is it worth the trouble?
No.
I'm kidding.
You do not get the community you have with your children otherwise.
If you don't get a dog ... you get to sleep over if everyone else gets.
Good, then I don't have to ask Dad, huh?
He never lets me go!
Now he just thinks about that match.
- This morning he trained towards my door!
- Go up and tell him then!
No idea.
I just have to stand in goal ...
- What is it for the match you are talking about?
- Gustav's boys team has some anniversary.
C. Head talkum feels pretty good.
Two quick C. Head talk drawings, past the defense ... goals!
- Tough resistance.
Most of the green ... C. Head talk - it's important with preparation.
Where have you made of all the food?
C. Head talk - no danger, I ate up.
- What are you celebrating?
C. Head talkative for exactly 25 years ago we played final C. Head talk to Backlura.
Ha, what a match!
- It stood 2–2 at full time.
- Gustav decided everything.
- He shot five meters outside the goal ... - How did you track all friends?
C. Head talk - is important you are happy to lie in!
- All lives here in Vivalla.
The C. Head Tapers there is not really true.
C. Head Precate Jalle went directly into the world.
C. HOVE PATERENW York, Tokyo, Paris ... C. HOVE PREPRAKERHAN KNOW how life should be lived.
- So he won't come ... C. Head talk - he has his life, a lot to do!
- Dad, I have to ask ... C. Head Tapers - Sen.
I have to go out on my round.
What he is ambitious!
Which round does he take?
The light track?
He takes a lap around the square by car.
He says it fans so nice.
He doesn't listen to me!
You know it's something he always listens to.
Fuss.
Have you never thought about becoming a professional?
C. Head talk, but I don't regret C. Head talk I chose the family.
-You're lying!
C. Head talk - yes.
I can't cope.
Should I set up the cones right away?
C. Head talk - no, I need some proteins.
- I thought you would lose weight!
C. Head talk - I do.
I only eat the cream.
- Dad, I think you make the victory goal.
- Have you had something broken again?
-No.
We rarely praise dad.
C. Head talkative self goes and run push ups.
- Line, what are you doing?
- I want to go to that party.
- Yeah ... it's just going?
-No.
I have to get to sleep over too.
- Dad will say no.
- It's just going in and saying it!
- He actually understands more than we think.
- You are right, max.
Thanks.
Idiot!
C. Head Tapers ... Twenty, twenty ...
C. Head Treaty ... Twenty -two, twenty -three, twenty -four ...
-Dad!
C. Head talk --... Twenty -seven ... - Hello, old man!
- You have said that we should be honest.
C. Head talk - beautifully.
Did I say that?
On Saturday, Ulrika will have a small party.
C. Head talketetack, old man, C. Head talkature I have this match.
Listen!
Everyone else should sleep over.
I would also like to do it.
You know everyone!
It's Jeanette, Sofie, Tobias, Marcus ... the usual ones.
C. Head talk - and Petter?
- Why are you afraid of Petter?
C. Head talk at the back with you at Bion C. Head talk - I just don't like that!
How do you know we have been to the cinema?
Do you spy on me?
C. Head talk - "Spy" has such a boring sound ... - Can I go or not?
C. Head talk - What does mom say?
- It's okay if you like it.
C. Head Tapers Can I decide?
C. Head talk, fuck ...
C. Head Tapers I decide ...
C. Head Tapers ... that you get to sleep over.
C. Head talkative self is sometimes overprotective.
If C. Head talkative self is to have fun, you should too!
C. Head talkativesvensson.
C. Head Tapersgustav Svensson.
Postman, yes.
C. Head talk?
C. Head Tapers Jalle?!
Is it you, Jalle?
C. Head Tapers are you?
C. Head talk on an airplane?
Do you come here to the C. Head Capricant match?
- He comes to the match!
C. Head Tapersbra Hotel?
Never come to question!
C. Head Taper!
You will sleep here with us!
C. Head Tapraredu gets to meet my family.
C. Head Precate, they have nothing else for themselves.
-What then?
C. Head talkative - my daughter jumps with joy.
C. Head talk, Jalle.
See you there, yes.
C. Head talk for the phase, Jalle.
Hello then, Jalle.
C. Head talkative - Jalle, Jalle ... It was Jalle.
- Yeah, it was Jalle ...
C. Head talkative he comes here.
C. Head Tapraredu may meet your dad's best friend.
- But the party then?
C. Head talk - party it will be!
C. Head talkative Jalle starts c. Head talk - oh, oh, oh ...
Hello.
Gustav, you have a match tomorrow.
I was going to go out with Annika.
C. Head talkum you or I tell you?
You!
C. Head talk guess who sleeps in the couch C. Head talkative morning.
- You, if you arrive late home.
C. Head talk - no.
Jalle!
Jalle Norén.
C. Head talkatine best friend!
He is on his way here.
C. HOVE PARTERHAN CALLED FROM HIS PRIVATE.
-Perfect.
Then I go out with Annika.
C. Head talk - you don't understand ...
C. Head Tapers Jalle should only stay for a day C. Head talk and must feel welcome.
- You think I should fit up with you.
C. Head talk - no.
He should meet my family.
C. Head talk - but you have time with the other, so ... —gustav, it's Annika's poetry evening.
C. Head talk - you don't like poetry?
- I'll do that!
C. Head talkatives me ... I want to show you!
C. Head Tapraredu is the finest I have.
So you said when you wanted me to repaint the boat too.
C. Head talk - remember how nice it was!
- I have friends I want to meet.
C. Head talk - Jalle is my best friend!
- You haven't talked about 25 years.
C. The head talk here never understands girls!
C. Head talk noise does not need to meet.
C. Head talk and I have each other here.
- Heart sits on the other side ... C. Head talk - don't you!
C. Head talk - I fix what is to be prepared.
- I haven't said yes.
The C. Head talkum did not do the C. Head talk I was free either.
-What's that?
C. Head talkative - Mitt life.
Don't read anything more fun?
C. Head talkative here I have gathered the best memories.
C. Head talkative summers we had, Jalle and I!
C. Head talkative here we have just climbed C. Head Tapers in the neighbor's oak.
C. Head talk - what madman.
Hanging in one hand!
- Where are you?
C. Head talkative self had just lost.
The C. Head talk was the first summer we met C. Head talk - then we hung together every day.
C. Head talk, Jalle turns fifteen years old.
C. Head talkative self was there evenly.
C. Head talk - there, down in the right corner, I stand.
- Jalle was the girls' favorite?
C. Head talkative self was not far behind!
When the picture C. Head talkatoreogs we would meet some girls.
- Was that why you looked so happy?
C. Head talk - no, I had just eaten.
C. Head talk here is the pictures of the pictures!
So we looked C. Head Precate Restrax before kick off against Backlura.
C. Head talk - 25 years ago ... then you were on top!
- What you look young, and slim!
C. Head talk - it's not me.
I'm sitting there.
- Sensors that I didn't see the match.
C. Head talk - but you came on the banquet.
- You offered beer in the dressing room!
C. Head talkative here!
Look!
Do you remember?
C. Head Tapers - Min Old Amazon, 57th.
- Of course, I remember.
It was the nicest thing I knew when we went to Björkudden.
Just you and me.
What memories ...
C. Head talk, such cars are no longer made.
C. Head Tableman looks at pictures, and then C. Head talkative feelings and the atmosphere come back.
Okay.
I ignore Annika's poetry evening.
C. Head talkatives you?!
C. Head Tapers What I would do without you?
C. Head talk.
C. Head talk list of everything that needs to be fixed.
I will help you if Lina is allowed to go to her party.
C. Head talk - she meets Jalle for a while.
- You don't follow?
–Gustav ... C. Head talkative - I promise.
19.00: Jalle's arrival.
National anthem, followed by short welcome fireworks.
- Card Welcome Fireworks?
C. Head talk - We save the big for the dessert.
Yes Yes...
I promise, I follow another time.
Your poems are very nice.
The one about the tortoise and the tissue too!
Greeting Göran, and good luck!
Hello.
- Hi, has Dad talked to you?
- Yes, this morning.
I will serve from the right and not in a hurry when I show slides ...
I have to go when I'm done.
Well, I will be half past two ...
I make sure you get away.
It is a dinner in all simplicity.
Where should it stand - the friendship standard?
We'll keep it up when they arrive.
Nämen ... does he have no sense of proportions?
Wait until you hear the welcome speech!
- Are you ready?
C. sound fanfare
The gods of the Olympics may be faded when Jalle ...
Turn off!
Now you forget what Dad has said.
I'm going to make a nice dinner.
Just be kind and pretty dressed.
C. Head talk - How is it going?
Is everything ready?
- You would help with the pictures.
C. Head talk - I and Göran have arranged one thing.
- Pentecress Opera?
Dancing bears?
C. Head talk out of the window.
Nämen look, an Amazon!
C. Head talk!
EN 57th.
All original.
C. Head Precate Jalle will not believe his eyes.
- A friend of mine owns it.
C. Head talk - I should take care of it as my child!
Göran, take the car and stick!
- Feel free to take Jalle over on a drink.
- First, he should see 1,100 slides ...
Yes, you want to show how nice you had it these years.
It is mostly short at Gustav at work.
C. Head talk, Jalle and I C. C. Head Torget Torget cruised.
We planned the future.
C. Head talkative ideas!
If we held together, C. Head talk we have gone as far as possible.
- He does not seem to be handicapped alone ... - and now you will get together again.
C. Head talkative an idea ... nothing strange.
-What then?
Europe's largest grocery store!
- What is Göran talking about?
C. Head talk I got an idea Jalle hung on.
C. Head talkative I thought we could do something new.
- As Europe's largest grocery store?!
C. Head talk - do not hang up on the wording.
C. Head talkative - now it is a place to knit.
- I have to go too.
Feel free to come over.
C. Head talkator will be coming in a couple of hours.
C. Head Tapers Bli not sorry if there is no C. Head talk department store.
One must be realistic.
C. Head talk may want us to do something in the United States C. Head talk.
Is Petter there?
Who is he dancing with?!
Ingela?!
!
Try to lock her in or something.
On toa or something ...
I hurry as much as possible.
- Where is the maximum somewhere?
- I thought he was in the kitchen with you.
Max!
Come up from the basement.
They are coming soon.
I don't want these clothes!
It's Dad who has fixed them ...
- You don't look wise!
-You look great.
You look like a successful dwarf.
- Lina, put out the napkins.
I have to help Max with the fly.
- Hi, has he come yet?
- Don't you read poetry?
No, I got so curious about Jalle.
Does he have his own jet?
- Have you talked to Gustav?
- No - Göran.
- That Gustav is best ice cream with one!
- Yes, it is undeniably a mystery.
- You would leave them in peace!
-I will.
Did you bring the camcorder?
- No, really not!
- Then I have to take this one.
- Now they come.
- See how he looks - then you have to go.
Lina, pick up the standard.
- Max, stand here!
And the text ... the melody is "SJ, SJ, old friend".
C.Sangjalle, Jalle, old friend C.Sang thinking that you are here again!
C.Sangåren goes, but you consist, c.Sangvår's very best friend
-HURRAY!
-Look here!
- But where is Jalle?
C. Head talk - on the way to London.
C. Head talk - he had some important meeting.
- But dinner then?
C. Head Taper Eat It!
Should we take the song again?
- But Gustav ... - are you very sad, dad?
C. Head Tapers, Why?
Everything I thought meant C. Head Taper when I was young was just air.
C. Head talkative self did not recognize him.
When I was a beer in a beer, he refused.
C. Head talk - It wasn't good for the figure ... - It's true maybe ...
C. Head talkator was not interested in C. Head talk.
-That's weird!
- What did he say when he saw the Amazon?
C. Head talk - he didn't see it.
He has a driver.
- This car is as nice as yours.
- What happened to it really?
Unfortunately, C. Head talk - it disappeared.
- It went through the ice.
C. Head talk - we were delayed and took a new road.
Dad tried to embrace over Vättern.
C. Head talk - What are you doing here?
You miss the party.
- I can be here with you instead.
C. Head talkative not you have to.
-Good!
- Max, where are you going?
Save the cake from Göran and Annika.
- I put a little under your bed.
C. Head talk is the only thing I'm good at.
- No, you know many things.
C. Head talk - As what then?
You can all Östergötland's postal code by the way.
I forgot to ask how it went.
C. HOVA PATERVI WON.
3–2.
I made the victory.
- Then you must have become a match hero!
C. Head talk - they carried me on the shoulders around the square.
- Did they orde it?
C. Head talk - yes, almost.
C. Headpratarede dropped me outside Consum.
Gustav, can you get to Björkudden now in the winter?
You and I can have an anniversary.
You and I and an Amazon from –57.
Should we check out our old place, at the dock?
C. Head talk, I like you.
C. Head talk in the hat, Mrs. Svensson!
Hello, Lena ... - Gustav ...
I have something that can cheer you up.
A poem that I would have read ...
C. Head Tapstarta!
Start!
The sun is rising - the morning red sea is resting, silver scrup ...
C. Head talkative set, your bang!
SVT Program Set Sign C.Redkarin C. Head Tapersesesvik