In tonight's section of Ifs, immigrants for Swedes:
Greek from Alby, Thanos Fotas.
Sweden's most fun Chinese, Evelyn Mok.
Sweden's second best celebrity dancer, Filip Dikmen.
The Persian songbird from Örebro, Jasmine Kara.
Graaf-Kera Pirate Captain Louie Marti.
Kosovoalbanian telephone fraudster Laura Ukaj.
The Finnish Tiktok Kanyan from Rimbo, Liam Kalevi.
The Roman-Jewish horse dealer Chang Frick.
The world's Swedishest Arab, Elaf Ali.
The Latin King, Douglas "Dogge" León.
Last but not least, our program manager Ahmed Berhan.
Welcome to IFS, where the panelists' social security numbers start at 0101.
I am Ahmed Berhan, your humble program manager.
You look at the quiz about all culture in Sweden.
Keep the applause for the competitors: Lennart, Linnea and Pontus.
The contestant chooses one in the panel that I ask another question.
Then the contestant decides whether they are lying or not.
It is a small advantage to start, and that advantage goes to Linnea.
- Who in our wonderful panel do you choose?
–Alaf.
–Yes.
The government had an honorary guest that they had booked into a luxury hotel.
When she was going to eat hotel breakfast, the staff ran after her -
- And said she was not allowed to eat there, because she was wearing Roma clothes.
–That's What Happened.
- Lite skeptical, I would say.
-In order to...?
- It sounds a bit unlikely.
- I say it's false.
- You say it's false.
Wrong.
The answer was absolutely true, and it was horrible.
The guest of honor was Diana Nyman from the Roma Council in Gothenburg.
We continue with the next competitor, Pontus.
- What do you want to talk to?
- I want to talk to Miss Ukaj.
--Wow!
-Okay okay...
- "All right."
--Laura.
It is Ahmed as a baby.
That looks like you today, so I don't know what you are talking about.
Ay, papi.
-No.
Laura?
–Okay, it's like this ...
All Blatte Parents scare their children -
- With such sick stories that make the children traumatized.
The rest is history, which is why we are singles.
It was a girl who got tired of the mother reading the Qur'an.
She watched TV, certainly something exciting.
She hit the Qur'an and then turned into that.
Is it true or false that it is the story of how that picture came about?
It was a good story, at least.
But whether it is true or false ...
- It feels ... - brother, you have two options.
It's false.
I think it's false.
- Unfortunately, it's true.
--Ay, papi.
The picture spread at the Muslim Forum from 2005–
–And was the most popular in the early 2010s.
Better luck next time.
- On to the third competition: Lennart.
- Come again, now we're cracking zero.
- Now we crack zero.
Yes...
- What do you choose?
- Jasmine.
I was a little disappointed, because you look like the men who usually choose me.
I am waiting...
Was it just me who felt that Lennart was laughing a little too hard?
- It came from here.
- Next round.
- Next round, yes.
- Jasmine.
Laleh played Eva's buddy -
- In "Eva & amp; Adam - four birthdays and one failure", I have for me.
She was an annoying friend, one who mucked a lot.
Her name was Fatima.
I join the no-sayers and say it's false.
I'm saying fake.
Bram, there is no button.
No.
Just that, there was no button here.
Lennart, congratulations!
You have received the first point of the evening.
She played a girl who was picked up from Lebanon for an arranged marriage.
That movie is obviously called "Jalla! Jalla!".
- Linnaeus, are you ready to take a point?
-Yes.
- What do you choose?
-Thanos.
Thanos.
That is what happens when a Swedish police chief marries a Turkish.
No, this was a campaign made ten years ago -
-Where you tried to attract a lot of town-kids to become cops.
Okay...
Okay!
Is that the information I get?
I like the word "Aina".
I'm kind of happy.
It was the Swedish I heard.
She will be happy with Aina - we are traumatized!
That's why I say it's true.
Congratulations, Linnea!
You've received your first point.
The Ainabil was standing in the Stockholm Police booth during the UNG08 festival 2006.
Lennart and Linnea have received points.
Time for you to shine.
- So I'll fail again?
- What do you choose?
Chang.
"The livestock service".
Well, it has little to do with it.
The Swedish film industry was very released.
You were the first to show breasts, and you had real intercourse on film.
- It was so the fallow sausage was invented.
- Yes, exactly, that was so.
Only the three Swedes took the joke.
- I didn't take anything.
"Fun ..." - "What sausage? I don't get."
- Does it feel awkward?
- I think Chang goes with falsehood.
You don't think Swedish film was released and challenging?
- I choose that it is false.
- You think Chang is lying?
- Everyone believes.
- I don't trust him either.
He has a face that you do not trust, but today does not lie Chang.
I don't know if you should applaud, cry or laugh.
In the 50-60s it was artistic but in the 70s pure porn videos-
- With quality rolls such as the island of love and the livestock service.
- Lennart, are you ready to take a point?
-Obvious.
- What do you want to talk to?
- I have to take Evelyn, then.
Evelyn.
From Kalle when I went in the third.
And also that I get that question.
Mongo comes from mongoloid ...
... which was a racial biological term.
That was what they called people from Mongolia, p.g.a.
The folds in the eyes.
Or as I call it, my eyes.
Then they started calling people with Down syndrome for that -
- Because they had similar eyes.
Then it became in popular "mongo", a degrading word.
-Thanks so much.
-You are welcome.
Yes...
Here the bad conscience emerges.
I belong to that generation that ...
Worked at the Ras Biology Institute?
- No, but that heard those words.
- "Heard"?
You got guilt because you heard those words?
Okay then, "said".
Therefore, I am convinced that it is true.
Otherwise, I have humiliated people when I was little unnecessary.
Lennart, you've got one more point.
In old Swedish race biology, "the Mongoloid breed group" was said about East Asians.
Shout-out, Djingis Khan.
- Conduct, I just say.
- We accept your apology, Lennart.
- Linnaeus, who do you choose?
- I choose Louie.
-Louie, Louie, Louie!
- EL Gitano.
I would rather not talk about that, because then they will send us back.
You are a smart man.
It all started with two brothers, who then grew big.
They were not accepted by anyone.
They built their own village which then became a city.
We call that city Rome today.
That is why gypsies, or Roma, call themselves Roma.
But according to researchers, it turns out that we are accompanied from India as well.
In some way I like that story.
- It's pretty nice, huh?
- Yes, so I say it's true.
- He will be expelled to India.
–Rom, Bre, Rome.
You think he tells the truth, and he does.
Roma said they originate from Rome-
- But it turned out that they originate from India.
The Romans were the first black shells to lie that they came from Italy.
- Pontus, who in the panel do you choose?
- Help me, Dogge.
- So, should I help you?
-Yes.
Dogge, your legend, this feels like something you can answer really well.
/ Finnish mining/ when standing outside Systembolaget and moving in the door.
-No.
- Casshus sausage.
The Finnish jerk is an effective contraceptive.
When you have / sound with your mouth / sex, you pull it out before you come ...
--... so you get outside.
- With a trumpet, right?
How do you have sex, dogge?
It is called "the Finnish jerk".
You have to move out lightning fast.
- You said it was an effective method?
- Yes, it usually works ...
- Dogge has type five children.
- I don't use Finnish jerk.
- No, I think it's false.
- False?
Heavy you are, Pontus.
Dogge, thank you for telling you the truth.
- Unfortunately, no point.
Finnish jerk is an old Swedish expression which means interrupted intercourse.
What we today call "pull-out game strong".
There was no point.
Lennart, you have been on a role.
Who do you choose?
It must be Liam, because you point to yourself.
Here comes a good question.
It means "male lies" - empty talk from men who do not help.
- What was the word?
–A so that it will help you ...
I just play with.
The guy reads three basic courses Somali on Södertörn.
- The word was "naag nool".
- Yes, straight off, just.
Absolutely.
–Liam, thank you for your lie.
-No!
It actually describes a hard working and enduring woman.
/ Cheer/ does it have to do with Finnish jerk?
- Linnaeus, time for the last question.
- And there is one left: Filip.
She was one of the few celebrities who openly supported Paolo Roberto -
- After he went there for sex purchases.
He had apparently been her PT when she trained for "caliphate".
Yes.
- What was her called?
--Gizem Erdogan.
She was in "Caliphate" and "Thin Blue Line".
I believe in it - that's true.
Everyone laughs ...
You think Gizem Erdogan put a heart on Paolo Roberto's Instagram?
Obviously it's false.
She commented on a heart and a star on Yasin's Instagram post -
- If he had nothing to do with the kidnapping of Einár.
Although you did not get points now, you and Lennart have gone to the final.
Unfortunately, Pontus, there will be no more competition for you.
- A big applause!
In the final it is about getting to five points first.
But if you answer wrong, your opponent will receive the point.
Lennart, are you ready to get started?
Please and choose a panelist.
–Alaf.
–Yes.
We start the final with a picture question.
In the picture we see an eritreanic word.
Do you want to test pronounce it?
-ENKOAKO.
- You said it with confidence.
-Elaf, do you want to test?
- I think it is pronounced enkoaho.
-What does it mean?
- You often hear it when it is election year.
-When it is...?
- The year!
This means party leadership debate.
ENQWAQQUHO ... yes, of course it is.
You can see that.
You believe in it.
Me and the other Eritrean giggles for ourselves ...
... for Eritrea has not had a election year since we arrived.
We chose a shuno and we have been riding with him since then.
So, no, that doesn't mean party leadership debate, but eggs.
-Egg?
- Lennart, unfortunately, no points.
But, Linnea, you got a point.
- Linnaeus, who do you choose to choose?
- "Who do you choose to choose"?
- What do you choose?
- I take Dogge.
- Linnaeus chose me.
- Do you vomit Linnea?
-No.
I say no, unfortunately.
- Dogge has six children, not five.
She would be number seven.
It's not possible.
- Allh, Haram, what is this?
-Sorry.
Reggae is soft music.
You chill, smoke a fat, soft and feel good.
Reggaeton is basically a base drink with rum in ...
Rome, banana, a little sea salt.
- It's fat najs.
-I do not believe that.
Huh?
Wait, wait - lucky I didn't choose you.
It says a lot that Dogge needs a woman who believes in his lies.
You chose not to believe it?
I think there is something else, some music or some kind of dance.
I think you know more than you say.
- Linnaeus, you're right.
-Yes!
It is clear that Dogge lied to you.
Reggaeton is also a music style -
- A more modern, harder style, inspired by dancehall and hip hop.
Linnea has apparently hung on La Isla.
- Congratulations to the point.
- Lennart?
- Now it will be Chang.
Bosnia, Serbia and the area around it are called the Balkans.
From all the juggies that stand on the balcony and smoke yellow blend-
- And screams at their kids.
Balkans, balcony - you know, Serbo -Croatian.
No, it actually comes from when the Ottoman Empire existed.
Then there was another, less kingdom in the northwest, called Balkania.
From there, the name has lived on to the Balkans.
- It's false.
- You think falsely?
- You think Chang is lying?
- Yes, today.
Congratulations, Lennart - a point!
The name comes from Turkish for "forest -covered mountains".
The forest trailer came by name.
- Linena?
–Yes.
I choose Evelyn.
–Evelyn?
-Yes.
They hug the fruit and kind of make a wax of it.
They use it to grow their hair, because Iranians are hairy.
Every Iranian has your eye exactly, I swear.
- No more Iran parties for her.
- But you have a point there.
I make laser and wax, so it's quiet.
What are you saying?
Are Gooje Sabz juice used to make wax, to grow up?
-Why not?
Yes, I think so.
- You choose to believe in Evelyn?
- Unfortunately, it cost you a point.
-Damn!
You eat them with salt, largely.
It's plum.
Nam-nam-nam.
Because you answered wrong, Lennart received a point.
Now it is 2–2, so it's tight.
Lennart, should we see if you take the lead?
Who do you choose?
To take the lead ... Jasmine.
You and I, Lennart.
Jasmine.
To dust is to eat the rub.
For example, Kalle on Stureplan might say:
"I'm going past Sturehof and dust all oysters."
Or maybe naser dust all ghormeh sabzi.
He eats all the tading too, so there is nothing left for the family.
- He eats everything, simply.
- In our time, "dust" was to hit someone.
-Yes exactly.
- Lennart just: "Yes, exactly!"
I've heard this, but if that's what you said ...
-True or false?
- That you dust ...
You sweep the plate, cleanse everything - it should be ... false.
Jasmine has not lied to you at all.
Damma is hose to eat.
You did not take the lead, but let Linnea dust a point from you.
- Linnaeus.
–Yes.
I was going to take someone who looked a little tired out -
- But many looked tired.
I choose Liam.
- Why this attack on the panelists?
- I was just going to live them up a bit.
The first time it was "well", and now I look a little tired.
Najs.
Money.
It is swindled to have ten kids.
No, there are perfumed pieces of wood that you light fire on.
There will be incense that protects against evil spirits, such as the social and Kronofogden.
- Where can you buy it?
–Dm: a later.
- What did you say it was called?
- Bakhoor.
- Sorry, say that you.
Bakhoor.
- I think it's true.
- It is clear that it is true.
Now you got a point, and you already have 4 points.
Lennart, if you answer wrong now, then you have given the whole profit to Linnea.
- Given, huh?
- Given the entire win for Linnea.
- Don't let me dust on TV.
- Now I take Thanos.
-Traditionally?
- He buys the adidas overall first.
–And stomach bag.
- It's how he comes here.
He contacts the bride's father or brother and has to negotiate with them.
He must pay compensation because they lose labor on the farm -
- When he marries his daughter.
It may be that he pays a thousand bucks as a symbolic sum.
Would the workforce be the daughter?
- Yes, because she also works in the yard.
- I actually think it's true.
The game is still running.
You've got one more point.
It is a custom called bridal prize in Swedish.
There have been a number of cultures around the world.
Linna, now it's your turn.
You can take home the whole thing now.
--Laura.
-Finally!
- Help me to win!
- Power puff ping pongs are here.
In the summer of 2021, people from the place of street race on Strandvägen drove.
The Östermalmers did not appreciate it.
How did the police stop it?
They wanted to party, as every blatte does.
They wanted to park, eat danger, drink Red Bull and be cool.
They didn't get it.
What happened?
Well, the cops turned off the street.
Have you control where your tax money went in the summer of 2021?
In the summer of 2021, it was Corona.
So I think it's false.
You think it's false?
You just lost a point.
-No!
–I'm not a liar.
It's true.
As Linnea answered wrong, it says 4–4.
You have given us an exciting final.
Is it time to end this?
Remember - if you answer wrong, Linnea gets the point.
It's just ... - Louie.
Good, Lennart.
Trust me - I'm gypsy.
It is a kind of draft cake from the Middle East.
May contain pistachios or other nuts.
I think the memory everyone has is that you get so sticky about your hands.
You have to have a strong detergent or degreasing to remove the dress.
But incredibly good, incredibly sweet.
I love it.
I have two words in my head.
In this case, it is "balaklava".
Baklava, balaklava, baklava ... Fan.
It's good, delicious, one of them.
It seems to us that we like it.
Fy, this is hard, this I can.
Many backlaws at Lennart.
That's any instrument too, huh?
Balaklava ...
No, just that, balalas.
It's true.
- You think Louie tells the truth?
- It shines the truth about him.
-Are you sure about that?
- Lennart, you had it, you said it.
Baklava is the sweet, balaklava is what Louie uses when he makes withdrawals.
When I pledge can I have it with me.
- Yeah, balaklava, yes!
Damn.
- Exact, it's a robbery hat.
Given that you answered wrongly, literally stole Linnea a point -
- And she has won the entire competition.
A big applause for tonight's winner, Linnea!
Come on and you should get your prize.
- Keep up the applause.
Awesome work!
You should get your fine IFS diploma for your participation and your profit.
Thanks to the fantastic competition, to the fantastic audience -
- To all of you who look at home and to our fantastic panel!
See you when we see you.
Texting: Jens Jakobsson Swedish Media Text for SVT