In tonight's section of Ifs, quiz about all culture in Sweden:
The character chameleon from Botkyrka, Thanos Fotas.
Who is she?
Her name is Jwan Rassuli.
If you cross Angola and Degeberga you get Petrina Solange.
All of Sweden's Habibi: Mr Slick - Ricky Rich.
She runs humor ping pong between Gbg and London: Evelyn Mok.
Farstabarn on the Grammys and Gold Bag plane: Jelassi.
One-man troll factory: Hanif Bali.
And back in public service in a humor rum: Kodjo Akolor.
Last but not least - our program manager Ahmed Berhan.
Welcome to IFS, your favorite program's favorite program.
This is our fantastic competitors: Isabell!
At green we have Christer.
And at the far end we have Joakim.
This quiz goes so that the contestants choose one in the panel -
- As they ask another question, then they will decide if the panelist is lying.
Christer, you start the evening.
When I met Christer, he said, "Fun to be here."
"I was going to have a fly, but didn't want to be nicer than you."
You can choose one in the panel.
Who do you want to talk to?
- Then we are investing in Kodjo.
- You said I would be allowed to participate here.
- I thought I would stand there.
- I thought that too.
You are the first from Vallentuna in the panel.
No one in the audience knows where it is.
The first from Vallentuna sitting in something.
- In addition to inside.
- Hey!
Zing.
Kodjo, if you eat ISKU Dhex Karis, what do you eat then?
Honestly, it is an Icelandic dish where you mix different types of fat:
Election fat, dolphin fat, sometimes shark fat.
In a pot, down into the soil, fermenting.
Then you eat it.
I don't want to say Geggga, for the Icelanders who look.
- But like a sauce, I can say.
- I think it sounds ...
I've never heard of it.
You are a lot to speak truth, so I think you are lying.
- What the hell happened, Christer?
- You think Kodjo is lying?
-Yes.
- Drying.
Congratulations to a point.
Neither Icelandic nor anything from Game of Thrones.
Isku Dhex Karis is a Somali dish: potatoes, meat and lots of spices.
- Joakim, time for you to shine.
- Then we run Evelyn.
-Hello!
–EVeryn ...
It is ... it is the countries that Swedes go to the most on holiday -
- And also the countries that top the list of countries with the most sex tourism.
So ... coincidence?
I don't know.
Also the countries where I do best at Tinder.
What are you saying?
Spain, Germany, Dominican Republic and Thailand.
- I think it's false.
-You think Evelyn is lying.
Joakim, unfortunately no points for you.
It's true.
Evelyn is popular on Tinder-
“But it is also the countries that are in the top of the world for sex tourism.
"Sex sells" apparently also applies to the travel industry.
What else does Germany have to offer?
Isabell, welcome into the match.
Who do you choose?
I think Ricky Rich and I ... it will be good.
-Yes.
Can you trust me?
- I trust that it will be good.
Oh, oh, oh, she looked at you and called you Habibi.
Ricky, time for image question.
Sadibou Sy is a Swedish-Senegalesian Fighter-
- As recently became world champion in MMA in PFL.
But what else makes him unique?
He is not only the first Swede who won a world title in MMA -
- He is also the youngest ever.
So, Shunon just got ... Shunon is only 16 bast.
- He is still alive?
-Yes.
I love that she paused the game to correct your Swedish.
Then I am.
He looked ... pretty young.
-Yes.
Yes, but I believe in you.
- You believe in Ricky Rich.
- Sadobou Sy is 16 years old.
- It doesn't feel that way ...
Isabell has never heard the phrase "Black Don't Crack".
- Unfortunately ...
- No point.
It's false.
- Attach.
I who believed in you.
Isabell can work at the Migration Board.
- I may submit an application.
-What are you saying?
"What do you say, Ahmed? Are you ten years? Absolutely."
You are ten years old and have three children.
Great!
- Some work quickly.
- Sadibou is definitely not 16.
He is actually 36 years old.
What makes him stand out as fighter-
- Is he only has 40 % of his view left.
- Cheriters.
Will it be another point?
- I drive at Jelassi.
YES!
I believe in you.
We have discussed that.
Jelassi ... IKEA received criticism in connection with the launching new products -
- In Saudi Arabia.
What was that about?
Arabs are very proud of names.
My name is Fatima Linnéa.
What the fuck?
In any case, they replaced the names of the products.
Type the bookshelf Billy was Mohammed.
Kajsa ... type some sink Kajsa became Khala.
They simply replaced all names.
For example, Stockholm became Riyadh.
–And, yes ... it continues.
--Hm ...
Yes, it's a pretty good ... explanation, but it knows damn ...
- Arabs stick to the names.
-I've heard...
I recognize that it has been something, but can't touch if it was.
I thought you would say "I actually know of Saudi Arabia".
-What are you saying?
-No I do not think so.
You choose not to believe in Fatima Linnéa.
Congratulations, Christer, you've got one more point.
In the catalog that was launched there in 2012–
- Ikea removed almost all women, including
A girl who did homework.
"Ew, a girl learning!"
For those who believe that Ikea understood the criticism - absolutely not.
For 2017, a similar catalog for Orthodox Jews came in Israel.
Inga Gäris.
Poor us girls, then.
You do chaos with us in society.
Honestly.
- Why do you remove our faces?
- No one hears us.
We are edited away.
Najs.
Congratulations, Christer, another point.
Awesome work.
Joakim, let's jump into the scoreboard.
- Now we want a point.
Petrina.
- Petrina, time for a picture question.
It must be in Belgium where pedophiles hang out these teddy bears -
- To show that it is busy in the basement.
Nämen, me ...
There are so many who want to laugh, but I hear how they suffocate it.
We will all burn in hell.
No, it is in Albania you hang them out to scare away evil spirits.
If I was an evil spirit, it would have worked.
These are terrible teddy bears.
Albania?
Yes...
It could be true, but I didn't really think ...
... the houses looked like my performance of what Albanian house looks like, so ...
- But I think you are lying.
- Then the houses did not look like in Albania?
–Yes.
- not p.g.a.
The sickest tradition?
It was the architecture that was wrong.
- Unfortunately, no points now either.
-No!
It's true.
It is an Albanian way to scare away evil spirits.
And all the tourism, if you ask me.
What Petrina said was true.
- Isabell, should we catch a point?
-I think so.
- Who do we do it?
–Hanif.
-Good choice.
- I like your shirt.
Hanif is a statistician in Hawaii Five-0.
- Hanif ...
They are all too nice to pay taxes.
No, but they all have through different stages in history seen -
- As a threat to the security of the kingdom, and treated like crap.
Therefore, they have now received a consolation award and are national minorities.
"National Minorities" is the answer?
You wanted to answer that they were too stingy to pay taxes?
I feel I trust you.
It's the shirt.
You trust Hanif?
Awesome work, you've got your first point.
It's true.
There are five national minorities in Sweden: Roma, Sami, Jews -
- Sweden finds and towers.
Sick that no nationality that is here is seen as a threat to the security of the kingdom.
What happens in Tornedalen?
Why are they ...?
Have you missed something?
Quite frankly, I didn't even know they existed, before this.
When I heard Tornedalen ... "I've seen the story of the ring. Who were they?"
- Cheritr, you've had good flow.
-Thanos.
Check out the man, confidence on top!
-How are you brother?
- Just good, brother.
Otuz Bir means 31 in Turkish, but it's also hose.
For what?
It is a hose for masturb.
In Turkish culture it is "to draw a 31st".
1, 2, 28, 29, 30 ...
Strong or mild sauce?
Rice, bulgur or french fries?
Right now I wonder why I chose you.
I believe in you.
You choose to believe in Thanos, that Otuz Bir is a hose for a hand trolley.
Christer, you've just trolled on a new point.
Congratulations!
It's true.
Otuz Bir is a hose to jerk.
Otuz Bir Geçmek is Turkish and means "31 moves".
Do you know how many guys will start counting?
1, 2, 3, 4 ...
"I can jerk COK quickly, me!"
I get all Turkish issues.
I will not be able to go to Fittja.
I want your class trip to go up.
Is it too late to leave the program?
Christer, congratulations to points.
Full pot.
- Joakim, on to you.
- Sista the chance to score.
-This is it.
- Jwan.
-Yes.
Yes.
All three words mean prostitution in Kurdish, Arabic and Persian.
It is from there the English word ho comes from - from Hookah.
Oh ... yes ... I don't have the faintest idea.
No, that's why you're here.
What are you saying?
Do you think Nargile, Hookah and Shisha mean the same thing:
-Prostitution.
- I believe in you, Jwan.
Kindly.
- You choose to believe in Jwan.
–Yes.
Unfortunately, you made it wrong. It's false.
You also heard the audience:
“Yeah ...”
"Joakim ..." Nargile, Hookah and Shisha mean the same thing all three:
Hookah.
Dear child has many names.
It was an Iranian who invented the hookah in India in the 16th century.
- It's always Iranians.
- Don't start now!
Don't start!
Isabell, it's your turn now.
And as you notice, all panelists are consumed.
This means that your next panelist will be randomly selected.
We like this.
It went great last.
Hanif, in 1996, took place the first kebab riot in Stockholm.
What was that about?
Thanos put extra garlic sauce on the kebab and then became the worst fight.
No, it wasn't.
It was the big kebabintifadan.
Two Palestinian brothers lowered the price of kebabs against each other all the time.
In the end, the kebab was as cheap.
It was the big kebab.
I don't know, but your shirt is very beautiful.
- I trust you again.
- I think Isabell has taken mushrooms.
She looks at Hanif's shirt.
"It's amazing! It feels like hot air."
- You choose to believe in Hanif?
-Yes.
You know what?
Go on your feeling, because it gives you another point - so congratulations!
It's true.
The large kebab brawl 1996 was about two kebab stands -
- which was driven by two brothers.
As a result, they basically gave away kebabs.
Or as we call it: The Good Old Days.
A huge applause to Joakim that does not move on to the final round.
An even bigger applause to our finalists, Isabell and Christer!
This is what we should do now: It's about coming first to five.
What is different is: If you answer wrong, the point goes to the opponent.
- Isabell starts.
-Oh.
I choose Petrina.
Petrina, 2022 created a library book controversy in Gothenburg.
Why?
There were no pictures.
No, but it was a book that contained IS propaganda.
It said that people who wanted democracy would die.
You got tips on how to create a caliphate.
But no evil-
- Which has nothing to do with it, it is the most read book in Gothenburg.
No, but it was the IS propaganda that was controversial.
-I trust you.
It's true.
- You love to trust people.
- Yes, I'm a little blue -eyed.
- You choose to trust Petrina.
Do you know what it means?
You get points.
-Cruelly.
-It was a book with IS propaganda ...
... at a library in Gothenburg.
10 times it was lent out before it was removed.
If you return the book, can you see who borrowed it?
Those people are on a very special list.
- Sick to return the books.
- Jihadists are law -abiding.
"It's haram to twist, habibi. Here."
- Congratulations on the point, Isabell.
–Evelyn.
- Hi, Christer!
Hi, Evelyn!
Evelyn ...
It was an English newspaper that wrote an article where the heading read:
"Mr. Tegnell - Sexiest Corona Expert On Earth."
"At Least If You Ask the Swedes."
It was the most shared English article about Sweden.
He was on TV every day for two years.
I love that you decide on whether you think Tegnell is good looking or not.
- "He was on TV" ... - I have already decided.
Evelyn is nicer.
I think you speak ...
- I think you speak the truth.
-Thanks.
You choose to believe in Evelyn.
This means that the score goes to Isabell.
-No!
Oh ... —Sorry, Christer.
The article was about a man from Australia who went to Sweden -
- To remove parts of their ears for aesthetic reasons.
The article was shared 2.5 million times.
He left Australia?
He could only have bathed with a shark?
Or?
I have no idea why he went here to operate.
He removed type the entire back of the ear.
All doctors in Australia said no, but one in Sweden: "Come. It's quiet."
Thank you the Moderates as privatized health care.
Let's move on.
Isabell, you have 2 p, we'll see if you get a third.
- What do you choose?
- I think I choose Kodjo.
Hurray!
Hello.
--Codjo ... - Hi.
A picture from when I started on radio.
That's what Sweden looked like then.
It is actually Gustav Badin, known as Couchi when he came here.
He was given as a gift to Queen Lovisa Ulrika in the 18th century.
He became her servant.
Then he was released and worked as a freight.
He has made the same trip as you.
- What did you say his name was?
- Gustav Badin.
- She thinks it's you in the picture.
- "What did you say you were called?"
- What do you say, Isabell?
-I do not believe that.
You think it's false.
- The point goes to you, Christer.
-Is it true?
-Yes.
Gustav Badin from the Danish Caribbean was given as a gift to Lovisa Ulrika -
- Who adopted him and had him as a valet.
He was the best friend with Bellman.
Behind every large, white man who knows music -
- There is a small, black man who wrote the shit.
- What do you think wrote the Bellman joke?
--That's what I'm saying!
Every time he came to the castle: "It was a German, a Danish and Bellman."
"You won't believe what the Swedes did."
- Better luck next time.
- CHRISTERS, we continue with you.
–Hanif.
So you know who is a guy or a girl.
No, I'm serious.
In Thailand they have many who change the sex.
And then you want to know who really is a guy or a girl.
- They are good at makeup.
- Hanif has been in Thailand.
Therefore, they put a ring in the ID actions that are pink or blue-
- So you know what you are going home with.
Yes, you, it was a damn good explanation.
But now I'm sitting in the shit again.
Consider when you were in Phuket -74.
No, I ... no.
-What are you saying?
-You're lying.
It's false.
Christer says Hanif is lying.
- Christer, you got a point.
It's false.
One is assigned a color, because each day has a color -
- Enough Thai tradition, so the weekday you are born becomes your happiness color.
Do they have a color for each day?
Are there 365 colors?
7 days a week.
What's with you?
- We cut it away later.
-No.
It's the trailer.
-Isabell ... —ya.
You're so cute.
"Is that my turn?"
It is your turn.
What do you choose?
I feel like ... Thanos.
-Thanos.
–Yes.
There is a tradition, because they lived like "out in the woods" before.
- Then the dad tore ... - before?
-Thanos.
- He is tearing off the sweater.
He struggles in pieces for the baby to be swept into it.
It is an ancient Serbian tradition.
He feels "she has given birth to the baby" ...
Then when his macho ego is gone, then only ...
It feels a bit strange, but when the child comes out of the mother -
- So maybe it needs a little ... some of the dad, so it should feel at home.
So I think it can be true, though it sounds very false.
- I think it's true.
–Din logic is incredible:
True, though it's false.
And do you know what?
It gives you one more point.
True.
It is a tradition to tear off the shirt to wrap the child.
Nowadays you bring several shirts and sweaters.
It is a congratulations.
So that more people can do it.
Only Serbs can make a birth male.
- Drying.
- Christer.
- Jelassi.
It is an Albanian blood revenge.
An ancient word that was used in the past.
Eye for an eye, tooth for a tooth.
- Valle Shota.
Shota ... - It sounds more like a shot.
- Yes ... - but ...
- Valle Shota.
Yes ... - it sounds aggressive.
- It sounds very ... exciting.
-"Exciting."
Swedish diplomacy.
It sounds like Albanian diplomacy.
Now Thanos woke up.
- But, yes ... the name, I drive on it.
- You think it's true?
-Yes.
- Valle Shota is about revenge.
Eye for an eye, tooth for a tooth.
Unfortunately, Christer.
The point goes to Isabell.
It's false.
There is an Albanian blood revenge tradition, but it is called Gjakmarrje.
Albaner, don't shoot me for the pronunciation.
Valle Shota is a nice folk dance.
It is seen at a wedding.
It is also called the duck dance.
- Now, Isabell, it is very exciting.
-Yes.
You don't know why?
Right now it is 4-2 to you.
If you answer correctly now, you have won.
Aha!
Yes...
Who do you choose to put your card on?
- I choose Jwan.
- Jwan.
You should get a video question.
This is a Norwegian news feature from the toughest ghetto in the Nordic region.
- But what is it about?
- About our king, Zlatan Ibrahimovic.
It is a news report from the Norwegians, because they felt -
- That Zlatan humiliated them by not running a training match with them.
- They made a report on Zlatan.
- Are you a big football fan?
No, but I have for myself somewhere that I have heard this clip before.
But this particular clip I think is not about Zlatan.
So I think that's not true.
But I don't know what it was about.
You just need to answer true or false.
- It's false.
- It's false?
We look at the clip.
I'll cut his tongue.
Cut ears.
I'll do chaos with him.
Isabell, you have not only received points but won the entire competition.
Congratulations!
Come, Isabell.
Come.
A large applause for our winner.
Here you have your IFS diploma.
And here you have your price - a shisha.
One stands applause to our winner.
A large applause to our competitors.
Our fantastic panel.
To all of you who looked at home, thank you so much!
See you again soon.
-What a thing.
-It is perfect.
You know what to do with it.
Texting: Barbro Garneij Swedish Media Text for SVT
Nice work.