In tonight's section of Ifs, the question of all culture in Sweden:
She's here, she's there, she's everywhere - Petrina Solange.
Flying Kurden from Lund, Alanbaloo.
The Persian humor cat from Husby, Melody Farshin.
Youtube juggling Momo Alikar.
Sweden's most fun Chinese, Evelyn Mok.
Greek from Alby, Thanos Fotas.
The Greek from Rinkeby, Alexandra Pascalidou.
The champion's champion and Botkyrka's Finest, Michel Tornéus.
The man with big A and even bigger B.
Up with our hands, because now we want to see Ahmed Berhan!
IFS is back.
My name is Ahmed Berhan.
Behind me we have Theresa ...
... Anton, and at orange color: Erika.
This competition goes like this: You choose one in the panel to talk to -
- You should decide whether the panelist is lying or not.
- We start closest to Therese.
--Theresi-a!
--Theresia?
-Oh really.
So.
Suddenly it is important to pronounce people's names correctly.
-Exactly.
- Pluden is important, Theresa.
--Theresia.
Who do you choose?
- I am a little curious about Alanbaloo.
--Alanbaloo.
Najs.
- It is clear you are.
-Alan ...
Baba Nu-El is Santa Claus, though in Arabic.
Habibte.
But he gives no presents, he gives "Bengs".
- He gives no presents, but money?
- Bengs.
-Exactly.
Santa Claus in the Middle East.
- That comes with Bengar.
Theresia, she learns quickly.
-No.
- The plot does not pass the Middle East?
No, it is unlikely.
She just: "He can't leave the wagon anywhere. They will turn the reindeer."
You say it's false.
You choose not to trust Alan.
Unfortunately, Theresia, no Christmas present for you.
It's true.
-Baba Nu-El is Santa Claus in Arabic.
- I told you: Trust me.
Did you know that the real plot comes from Turkey?
-Please!
- It's Thanos cousin.
- The germs react at once.
-What?
Saint Nikolaus was Greek?
- He was Greek.
Bravo.
Alexandra, give them a history lesson.
Nikolaus gave gifts to the poor, no one else received gifts.
- So working class plot?
-Yes exactly.
- Type Robin Hood.
- Long before Robin Hood.
Robin Hood has been spinning from the Greeks.
- Plice everything is from Greece.
-Thanks for the information.
Bravely tried.
Better luck next time.
Anton, I'm curious ...
I heard that you were looking for Idol 2020 as a fun thing.
How far did you get?
- No one.
I had to turn in the door.
- In IFS you are always welcome.
Fun to have you here.
Who in the panel?
Yes, there should probably be no other than Evelyn.
-Hello Anton.
- We should run a picture question.
Based on self -confidence, jewelry and women:
Sweden's first gangsta rapper.
No, but Anton ... this is actually -
- Nordic adopted person, simply.
Okay.
It could be.
Absolutely.
Looked a bit like a record cover from Kanye West, maybe.
No, I don't think it's true.
- You choose not to trust Evelyn.
-Unfortunately.
It is not unfortunately, because it just gave you a point.
Congratulations, Anton!
It's false.
The painting represents the first Chinese in Sweden.
-Choi A-FUK.
- It's a real name.
He came in the 18th century.
He spoke Swedish on a peculiar ...
He came in the 18th century and they have the stomach to complain in his Swedish?!
- There wasn't SFI then, exactly.
- But we saw the same picture?
-Yes.
- I thought he looked black.
There are blacks in China.
I should not come up with race biology.
- I thought you cut Petrina.
- I thought so too.
Petrina: "When did they take that picture of me?"
- Erik, time for you to shine.
--Let's go!
- Good energy.
Who do you choose?
- I want to choose Petrina.
Because it's gay.
You can give her points right away.
Walla, I'll check if I have ...
This is because the Prophet Muhammad thinks that one should not be blamed.
Do not wear silk, gold and stuff.
So it's like a Muslim variant of the Jantelagen, type.
Spontaneously it sounds reasonable.
Otherwise, I don't know what the reason would be.
- Because it's gay.
- But the best things are gay.
Yes ... no, I think it's true.
-It's true?
Congratulations, Erika.
True.
-Yes!
The Prophet should have said that men who are dressed in silk lack character -
–And you should not flase wealth.
No gold, no silk.
Therefore, Mom calls me her third daughter.
--Theresia, I believe in you.
-Good.
I think Thanos.
Thanos ...
It means...
–... masturber.
-Yes.
Runkare.
Jerk Off.
Otuz Bir in Turkish.
No, it's bullshit.
One hundred percent.
- You don't think so?
-No.
I know what that means.
- You know what that means?
- Yeah!
I have a mechanic who is Greek, and he says Malaka all the time.
Malaka ...
Theresia ... seriously ...
You should have trusted Thanos.
Change mechanics, because it is true.
Are you kidding?
Malaka is Greek hose for jerks, Wankare.
Dear action has many names.
"Idiot" is what he has told me.
It is a word that has it ... thus, the academic translation ...
- Pascalidou.
- Let the Greek that can answer.
Everything Thanos says is true.
Idiot is a Greek word.
But Malakas is -
- A antique Greek word used about everything and everyone, for all jerks.
-Sick.
--Thanos, are you a malca?
If I'm a malca?
Eh ...
I have the same answer as my friends when asked if they are Muslims:
I identify as Malaka, but I'm not practicing.
Unfortunately, no points this time.
- Anton, who do you choose?
-Michel.
In 1975, Sweden defeated Chile in tennis during the Davis Cup in Båstad.
The Chilean stuck with the Swedish wife.
No, the Chilean cod and became a shit.
He threw the racket on the judge and pissed on the pitch.
Temperament.
Terribly stupid to choose the sports guy when I can't do anything about sports.
But it sounds reasonable.
I had done it too.
Was that so you left Idol?
"Fuck you!"
KSSS ....
- You think it's true?
-Yes.
- It's false.
There will be no point.
- Skit too.
The reason why the match has been remembered is that about 6,000 protesters-
- Tried to stop the match to mark against Chile's military dictatorship.
- Chileans - everything becomes political.
- Viva La Revolución!
Hoola Bandoola Band made a song called Stop the match.
- So, in Swedish?
- Hoola Bandoola is a Swedish band.
Well!
Did they let go of the match song during the match?
It was a little late.
Fat bad to play it when the match is over.
Unfortunately, Anton.
No point.
- Erika, now we drive.
Eh ... I'll take melody.
- Melody, you should get a picture question.
-Okay.
If you see this can of a family with a foreign background ...
Secrets about how to Islamize Sweden.
- In Knew it.
-No.
Honestly...
Our parents are the most unconscious environmentally friendly citizens.
They refuse to throw something that can be reused.
They wash out of freezer bags.
Turkish yogurt can-your new food box.
Danish cookies will then be your forever and ever syllabus.
Yes exactly!
It is standard in any grandmother or grandmother too, so ...
I thought spontaneously when I saw it: "Ah, sewing things."
So I hope it's the same for everyone.
I think that's true.
You think it's true.
Absolutely right, Erika.
You got one more point.
The Danish Cookie can is unofficial sewing can in many immigrant homes.
Theresia, this is the third round.
Your last chance to try to get points.
I believe in you.
Forget your mechanic.
We solve this together.
And this is not my jerk hand.
- Who do you choose to talk to?
- Momo.
YES!
I didn't want to say that before, but Theresia makes me embarrassed.
She is very beautiful.
It gets a little ...
Theresia should move to Hjulsta?
-Warm welcome!
- A video question.
An order for 22 pizzas.
Why did he think it was a joke?
Because the Swedish Democrats received 22 % in the municipal elections -
–And they wanted 22 pizzas to celebrate their blah-blad-blah success.
You produced your Swedish Swedish to talk about SD.
-I had to.
-What are you saying?
22 % did they convert to 22 pizzas?
SD wanted to celebrate with pizza.
Yes or no?
I'm in that.
Absolutely.
What good that you talk very ...
- I talk a little fast.
- Very Swedish too.
Okay.
I have said falsely twice, so I say false again.
Third time lucky.
I say false again.
- Congratulations, you get your first point!
- Tank you!
It's false.
The clip was from 2021 when there was a hostage frame at the Hällbyanstalten.
The perpetrators first demanded a helicopter and a lot of money.
However, the ransom was negotiated down to 20 pizzas.
- Anton, your turn.
Yes.
Alexandra.
Explosives.
No, honestly Andonis ... you also have a Greek name.
Thanos: Oh-hoo!
Congratulations.
It must carry very much luck.
"Anton comes from Greek Andonis."
It's not my fault.
But back to Alfred Nobel and Rinkeby.
It is quite obvious.
No one may have missed that the last 30 years -
–Have Nobel Laureate Welling to Rinkeby -
- To meet students at Rinkeby Library.
I don't know how many Nobel award winners I met these 30 years.
Maybe 29 or something like that.
So that's the reason.
Yes ... I have no idea about this, but ...
Yes, it feels like they need some literature, huh.
Do you say that to a writer from Rinkeby?!
Here we have another!
Momo, forward with the hand grenade.
I am not afraid of the sixth member of the Babblarna, so it is quiet.
What happens?
--Andonis ... —si, yeah ...
What are you saying?
Is it Alexandra said true or false?
- It is clear that it is true.
- You think it's true.
In order to?
Because it feels good.
Heavy you are, Anton.
Congratulations, you got a point!
True.
The Nobel Laureates in Literature visit Rinkeby Library.
They get a booklet with the children's impression of their work.
Theresia, you got a point, but unfortunately you will not go to the next round.
Erika, you have a question left, but as you can see, all panelists consumed -
- What means that your last panelist will be ...
Thanos, what is a shishko?
A Shishko is what suburban men become when they get married and have children.
It's a thick.
- A thick?
-Yes?
- you eat a lot of shish kebab, so ... - you become a shisko.
It's not an expression I've heard before, so I just get free.
Eh ...
I think that's true.
It would have been fun if it was true.
It would have been fun.
You know what?
Always bet on the fun.
It just gave you one more point.
You got a full pot!
Shishko is a hose for thick and comes from Turkish.
Theresia, thank you for joining.
Your trip ends here.
A large applause.
And a large applause to our finalists Anton and Erika.
In the final round it goes like this: it is about -
- To come first to five points.
The score goes over if you answer wrong.
Erika, you start.
Who do you want to talk to?
I like Evelyn's dress, so I choose her.
Poland's national anthem has a unique connection to Sweden.
How?
It praises the RUT deduction.
No, but this is how it is ... Poland is the only country in the world -
- As mentioned in Sweden in its national anthem.
They do that because they are still varnished that we invaded them -
- Type a hundred trillion years ago.
So they eat it in the song.
It feels like they are getting revenge now, because now they are taking over our construction industry.
- The name, that is, that is the answer.
-Okay.
It feels strange to bring another country in their national song
- So the question is whether they have it just to fuck.
- So we say it's true.
- You say it's true ...
... that Poland has added a dissate to Sweden in its national anthem?
-Yes.
- It's true, Erika.
Congratulations!
It is the only country that mentions Sweden in the text.
Sweden does not even mention Sweden in its national anthem.
But it is a dissent for a conflict for a long time.
"We remember."
- Anton.
- We run Thanos.
–OKay, Frank.
Let's do this.
–Thanos ...
If you have Thai parents, what do you learn early on your feet?
You will learn that.
You can do happy ending with them.
You who have got Thai massage know that they use your feet in massage.
They learn that their feet can be a tool for healing people.
Okay...
- A tool for making money?
- No, to heal other people!
- Like other people?
Okay.
- Thai massage, they ...
-No.
-Okay.
You need!
I know.
- Cok tense.
- I have never heard of that.
It may well be true, but we drive on false.
You drive that it is false.
Awesome work, Anton, you got a point!
It's false.
They learn to the underside of the feet -
- Is a dirty body part and it is ugly to show the soles of the feet to others.
- It will be happy ending for Andonis.
- Should you give it?
Should I give it?
No, I'm not very good at Thai massage.
It's my job.
- ERIKA.
–Mm ...
- I choose Michel.
- Michel ...
Iranians do it because it is the best way to get rid of body hair.
No, the body cleanses from everything bad that has been during the year.
You skip, and then you become reborn.
New Year.
I'm saying true, I'm pretty sure I've heard it.
- And that sounds good.
- That's why you skip fires?
- I could have done it.
Absolutely.
-You know what?
Congratulations, one more point, Erika!
It's true.
And the fire party usually takes place the day before the spring equinox.
Several cultures celebrate Nouruz in different ways: Persians, Kurds, Afghans and others.
Listen...
We might be an elite jump ...
... but we jump in high heels.
Michel, Melody actually has SM records in long jump in high heels.
Anton, should we see if you manage to level out the scoreboard?
- We choose Petrina, I think.
- A picture question.
What the fuck?
This means that you text with the king.
No, there are different countries' crisis codes.
Depending on where you are, the crisis code is different.
There are three different countries.
The first thought was that there are different ways of laughing, in different languages.
It can be really tacted.
I don't think it's crisis codes.
You say it's false.
Congratulations, Anton, you got one more point.
You not only got one more point, now the fucking nailed the answer.
It is how to laugh online in different languages.
Arabic: h-h-h-h!
Portuguese: K-K-K-K!
And Ukraine and Russia: r-r-r-r-r!
Why am I not surprised-
- The Russian laugh sounds like an automatic weapon.
Rada-rat ...!
Ukraine has changed laughter now.
They don't drive in the Russian anymore.
- What have they switched to?
- Brrrr!
- They don't want Russian laughter.
- Yes, we understood that.
Welcome to "Two Greeks and one conversation".
Wait, a dialogue.
Dialogue comes from Greek's Diálogos.
You get to compensate for every time you got to play Turk.
Now the Greek arrived.
Anton, you smooth out the point.
- Erika, can you take back the lead?
I take Alexandra.
If Syrians say "I'm going to my girl and drinking coffee", what do they mean?
So this ... It's a code word if you are gay.
Because homosexuality is so incredibly charged in some cultures -
- So they have code words.
Then they say: "I'll be home to my girl and drink coffee."
If you are gay, you understand what will happen there.
But if you are straight-
- So you think they should go to their girl and drink coffee.
They say, "I'm going home to my girl and drinking coffee."
"No, I'm going home to my girl. What? Don't you think I have a girl?"
Erika ...
A good code word.
And cute.
I want it to be true, but say false.
You want it to be true, but choose falsely.
You are doing absolutely right.
Congratulations, you've got one more point.
It is not code for homosexuality.
This means the guy's family goes to the girl's family -
- To ask about the daughter's hand.
- We continue with you, Anton.
- We run on Momo now.
Momo ... FB may be abbreviation for Facebook -
- But what does the abbreviation FB mean in the resort?
Okay ... FB is feminine ...
... and KB is masculine.
You describe people as a pussy carrier and cock carrier -
- But don't want to say it, because it is ugly to say so.
For example, FB here.
And here's my KB.
–My fucking kb.
-Exactly.
- What do you say, Anton?
- You feel very credible.
But you feel too credible, so I think it's a spectacle.
You say it's false.
This means you got one more point.
FB, as we all here in the audience hear for the first time -
- Detects insurance fraud.
A very dishonest and illegal act.
Like water injury their computer to get a new one.
- ERIKA.
-Yes.
I choose Catlady Melody.
Melody, at an Indian wedding, the bride is probably painted with henna.
-Why?
- It's like a written contract.
There you promise to never sell your sari-
- To a white woman who is going to a Halloween party.
Never ever.
No, quite frankly ... It is so that the bridal couple stay apart -
- Including the wedding night.
Henna has a strong scent - a fantastic cockblock.
Mm ... no.
I'm pretty sure I've seen a program om-
- That it should be some kind of story.
- You don't trust a Fellow Catlady?
-Unfortunately.
You did that right in, Erika.
It's false.
You got one more point.
Henna, a.k.a.
Halal Tattoos, given to the bride -
- As a sign of good health and happiness.
- Do you mark what it says?
- I see what happens.
Everything is at stake.
If you answer wrong, you don't just lose the round ...
--... without the whole game show.
- Jajemans.
-Here we go.
Dad Baloo.
Alan, the word Aina who is a slang for police comes from Turkish Aynasiz.
-What does it mean?
- It means pig with a gun.
In Turkey, they give their pigs guns at a very young age.
Skåne: No, I'm just kidding.
The name, Aynasiz itself means "without a mirror" -
- For the police cars before in Turkey only had a side mirror.
One on the left side, no one on the right.
It is meant that the police cannot see themselves in the mirror.
I do not believe that.
That sounds stupid.
It's Turkey.
Anton, you say it's false.
Aynasiz means "without mirror" in Turkish.
The term refers to the fact that police officers cannot see themselves in the mirror.
It's true.
The point goes to Erika.
Erika, you have won not just one point, but the whole game!
Congratulations, Erika.
-Here you have received an IFS diploma.
- TACKS.
-A nice stop match-t-shirt.
-Thanks so much.
A warm applause for the winner, our competitors, the fantastic panel -
- Our wonderful audience.
To all of you at home, see you again soon.
Texting: Barbro Garneij Swedish Media Text for SVT