Art - or weirdness.
Sweden's art history is part of the huge story of our country.
We will with some impacts show art-
- As depicts changes and creation power.
The thirty-year war.
It went on when she was born ...
... Little Kristina 1626.
And when she became queen, 18 years later, it was still going on.
She became a warrior queen even though she was burning for art and science.
Here is a portrait of Kristina–
- Painted the same year she was crowned.
Coronation portraits usually be with a mantle with hermelin fur -
- And a large crown, sprout and faith.
But this is almost private.
She stands on a balcony, leaning against a balustrade with a little questioning look -
- Near as if we are bothering her.
It's a bit special, because the portrait is about her role -
- As queen, as a ruler.
But it does in a discreet way.
That portrait i.a.
is known for in art history is -
- That is an allegorical portrait, it tells more than what we just see.
This is the elements - the four elements.
The water is the fountain that sprays here at the back.
The earth is the globe on which the queen puts her hand.
And the air is the natural power that gets this veil -
- As she agrees with her left hand - to lift and be filled as a sail.
Then an element is missing: the fire.
Where is the fire?
It is Kristina herself.
You can read it easily as a defense for the monarchy:
That a unifying principle is needed ...
... Someone who with wisdom and understanding as well as controls it all.
The great power time.
For some, the dreams still live today about the time -
- Then Sweden was a respected and dreaded country in Europe.
For Kristina, the time as a regent was no dream.
She wanted something else.
In December 1644, Queen Kristina turned 18 -
- And became of legal age.
The frozen capital of the new superpower -
- Filled with foreign diplomats and scholars.
Formed Catholics bid for a more beautiful world and a more beautiful life.
She longed away from beer drinking generals -
–And High -voiced theologians.
I think this is how she wanted to be perceived.
Her decision to abdicate has matured.
She is produced more as a philosopher or writer -
–Or as well as learning persons -
- which can be discussed quickly with philosophers and poets.
And she could.
In 1654 she finally made her plans on abdication -
- And his longing for further horizons.
A well -known view of Rom travelers: Piazza del Popolo.
This is where Queen Kristina rode in at her entry into Rome 1655–
- On the way to kiss the pope's foot.
The Pope received Kristina who became one of the city's cultural personalities.
She had retained the queen title and she lived in a palace -
- With art and service people.
Here we have Kristina as a Romanian.
Many have described Kristina during the autumn of her age in Rome-
–As a short, small and bite -gum -
- With double chin, a dirty wig.
She did not care about her appearance.
Here she is like a Roman Empress.
There were many sculpted portraits -
- Where you see this high hairstyle with curls.
A little classic tunic.
In her final phase, she identified more with the Roman environment -
- There she still lives on as a kind of mythical figure.
From her last notes we know she was tired.
It tasted sand in her mouth.
She was prepared for a major adventure:
What started only when you enter through the copper gates of death.
There are probably no regent portraits from the 17th century that are more important.
They are so unusual -
- With a reigning queen with that kind of personality.
So I would say that these two are key works in Swedish art history.
Texting: Karin Esevik © Swedish Television AB 2023