-Hell!
What happens, Leif?
-I do not know.
Take it easy.
What the hell...
The name, who do we have here, then?
Little Billy and Thick-Leffe.
Hello, Damp-Janne.
It seems to be going pretty well for you.
New house and everything.
Where did you get the money from?
Reply when I talk to you, fat!
Yes, we have ... saved some, so ...
Well, you've saved?
How good you are.
But I thought of a thing.
It's a bit strange that while someone steals 700,000 from us -
- So you buy this piss truck.
Yes, as I said, we have actually taken care of and saved some.
I think there are more Billy called Billy here in the areas ...
There is one down in Sörbyn, I know.
Damn...
No ... oh, no, no, no!
Little fucking rat!
You turned money from us.
-Stand on you.
Not a word.
- Known!
- Make something, Leif!
- Billy, don't say a word!
Good, Billy.
Thick-Leffe, your little pig ... it was you like ...
Yes, yes, yes, yes!
We were.
Or, Billy found them and twisted them.
Then we bought houses for all money.
So you gave 700,000 for this fucking piss?
- How fuck should we solve this?
- We do anything ...
Oh, no, we do anything.
Janne, whatever!
You will have to pay!
- Snip, we do anything!
- Done fucking pissluder!
Fuck!
Janne, Janne ...
Quiet.
- What the hell is that?
- AMPETAMINE TO THE NORTH NEXT WEATHER ...
Last time we did business with them they blew us.
- We send the thicknesses.
- Delivering the thick?
Exactly.
You are absolutely right, Jimmy.
Get the bag.
- Now you work for me, your fucking.
-We do anything, Damp-Janne.
You will deliver half a kilo of amphetamine to Stockholm for me.
And then you will make sure to get the money from the store, to me.
If you fuck this up, I cut off Little Billy's small knees here -
- And make minced meat of them, which you will be allowed to eat then.
You have 24 hours on you.
Now we are at risk, I can say.
God cursed.
Better to kill yourself and settle in the family grave -
- Entry to have such leather bumps on the neck.
- Attempts be a little calm, Leif.
-How?
With that shit in the house!
We can try to think a little more positively about it.
Positively?
Why have I not thought about it, that you can think positively?
Then we can go down with Lill-Volvon and take the opportunity to go on Gröna Lund.
Then we can eat sugar candy and go shopping for clothes in Ullared.
- What a good idea!
Now I get calm.
- You look, it works.
God damn!
What happened to your skull when you got out of your mother's vulva?
It became one fucking chromosome error.
Did you crash the fontanel to the floor?
Think, damn!
We shall deliver death -gossip -
-To some mafioso leader in Stockholm from some fucking league.
And you sit like a bird's nest and want to think positively?
We have to go.
Dress yourself, you can't look like any small chubby session.
Put on your leather pie from the student.
Now it's sharp, boy.
Do you think they can do it?
If not, we may move abroad.
Then we are driven.
- The league never lets us down then.
-We have no choice.
--Hm.
I go there and monitor it.
- Fan, are you snappy?
Make sure it doesn't hurt.
I stay at a distance.
- Why do you smoke?
- All criminals do.
It shows power and a "I am not afraid of death" attitude.
-Attitude?
-Yes.
Yeah?
You fuck with me, yes?
You see these motherfucking killer eyes?
If you fuck with my relatives and provoke me, I'll kill your relatives.
Yeah, I'm the devil.
- Do you understand?
Test!
Yeah!
You ... you little ... you are stupid.
I hate you!
-You ... you want to fuck with me?
-Oh my God.
God cursed, Billy.
You can't look like that and behave.
You get to practice on the way down.
Yeah, you like fucking?
You fuck me first, then I fuck you.
Okay, deal?
You know what I'm gonna do with you?
Be Afraid, because I'm Billy the ...
-Satan!
–... Fuck Machine.
Silent, Billy!
Dun!
They have certainly had a spark on us.
Satan!
It will be imprisonment for 25 years, I promise.
Sit and rot in some fucking cell.
Satan!
Satan in hell, now it's run!
- oh, fuck ... - hell ...
-What are you doing?
- Imagine.
-Positively?
- I don't think positively!
What do we do with the drug?
Having it in the car is too risky.
We have to do in some other way.
It was near the eye, Billy.
- "Knotty with a taste of licorice."
- The girls like when I have such.
- The package was unopened.
- I may use one a week.
- "Extra small, best before" ... - but God damn ...!
Hold in. So, pour in here.
Satan ...
- Don't spill.
Try to hit the hole.
-I try to!
So.
It will be fine.
Satan ...
So.
Swallow it.
- I don't like licorice.
-We have no choice.
If we come across a dog patrol, then this is the safest way.
I have to push it up from the other side.
Not in the car.
Out here.
Do not hold on to the car, the filth.
Out!
Quiet.
Now they are soon in Stockholm, but they have something fucking fuffens for themselves.
Satan, it is not possible.
Was your less?
Jump into the car now.
You may swallow it as other people.
- Billy, hurry up now!
- It's not possible, I'll come.
I don't know if I can do this ...
If you have entered the crime, you have to run the line.
It's fine.
- Come again now, the brother!
-We'll fix it.
C.Lndelif's stomach mudders
- Fan, I think a condom broke.
–Wa?
c. soundbilly's stomach rumble
Hell, what it was burning to.
I think a burst with me too.
- How long have you had the condoms?
- Yes, they are not purple.
-What happens?
The whole stomach burns.
- Yes, what do you think happens by death?
- Her God ... I'm starting to feel effect.
- Now it gases on, I can say.
- I feel dry in the gums.
- It's like I should give birth to children.
- Fan, what a nice!
- I have never felt this way!
- Who wants to argue with "The Druglords"?
- i'm gonna fuck you right up the ass.
- Fan, what horny and cool I am!
–You Wanna Fuck With Us?
It presses!
I feel like a brown deer!
We go there, shit out the drug, get the money and go home.
-Good!
-Okay.
Now damn ...
- Well!
- Yeah, who do we have here, then?
Damp-Jan's new running boys?
So he was too cowardly to come today too, the little thorn?
And what does he send?
Two semi -fat bonn lips.
Where the hell is my jacket?
Yes, now maybe it has become a small incident here that we can probably solve ...
The drug you are talking about, we have been inserted into the intestinal tract.
We smuggled it in condoms, and then one ... or two burst.
Or all.
- We thought to shit it out.
- What the hell are you saying?
He says the drug is in our anal holes.
I hear what he says, but this is no fucking game!
- Lugn ... –Okay, I understand.
Satan!
Waoo!
Satan ...
You don't touch my brother, your damn anabolic pig.
Damn, it's going to hell.
Now you are not so cocky, the beard steak.
Are you going to sleep?
Good night, sleep a little.
- Hi, Oops!
How does this feel?
- It's not over yet, damn Bonnläpp!
Let me do it.
- Do you remember this bottle?
What the hell?
Fy damn, I have to shit.
Fy fuck ...
Satan ...
How's it going, Leif?
Can I do anything?
Fy damn, I'm so damn bad.
Oh my God.
I have to get mine out.
I think I have internal bleeding, I don't feel good.
My God, Damp-Janne will kill us.
- I have to call him.
- Do you really?
We have no choice.
We have swamped the whole shit.
Cursed ...
- Janne.
- Hi, it's Leif.
-How's it going?
-It is quiet.
-How are you?
Is everything cool?
- It's like that.
You know ... yes ...
A small thing has happened.
We didn't really get the money ...
Shit in the money, we don't want any trouble.
I heard what happened yesterday.
We don't want any problems.
We hear, Leffe.
Hello!
Check.
Mine is whole.
I'm damn good, me.
My God ... Now we go home to Sörbäcken right away.
- Should we not go to Gröna Lund?
- Pack the bag, now we go home!
Texting: Ulrika Jansson Båving Swedish Media Text for SVT