In tonight's section of Ifs, the quiz about all culture in Sweden.
The shoe -throwing author, Elaf Ali.
Grammis -nominated mop mushroom from Valsta, VC Barre.
Felicia "Lock in my children and valuables" Jackson.
The Greek suburban philosopher Thanos is photographed.
Paludan's Sugardaddy Chang Frick.
Humor Sweden's Yao Ming, Evelyn Mok.
Jalla, that's MFB's Musti Jaralla.
And the whole of Sweden's TV4-Brasse, Tilde de Paula.
As always, the punchline profile with style, host Ahmed Berhan!
What happens, good people.
Welcome to IFS.
The only program that is more explosive than a staircase in any suburb.
My name is Ahmed Berhan, I am your host.
Here, my ladies and gentlemen, are the contestants:
Most recently we have Rosa Pantern from Älvsjö, Christina.
Next to her: Repps green, because he is nice.
Oskar!
Farthest in Orange Ring corner, pound for pound -
- Sweden's best librarian: Annika!
Christina, which panelist do you choose to start tonight's performance with?
- I choose Tilde.
-Tilde!
This is your question.
It is probably roughly the equivalent of the Swedish ...
"No. Maybe you would think about the chorus."
A little nicer way to say:
Now this coffee hour, date or evening is over.
Interesting.
I didn't think Tilde would lie the first thing she does.
But that's false.
Christina came full in Loaded.
- You think Tilde is lying.
Congratulations, Christina!
You've received a point.
False.
The aunt is about to predict your future -
- Gee answers about your love life, future riches ... Turkish voodoo amanah.
Oskar, who do you choose to chew with?
I take the young foal, VC Barre.
Whether, welcome.
We are fat happy that you are with.
Heavy you are.
Question:
He usually uses lots of spices, maybe a little sweaty hairs ...
Just kidding.
He usually uses yogurt, sriracha, spices ...
Fanta.
It doesn't have to be Fanta.
It can be any orange soda.
Zingo also works.
Even the black skulls: "huh?"
What do you say, Oskar?
Have you tasted the kebab sauce in southern Sweden?
-I have.
It does not taste zingo.
- But it's the best, right?
I think VC is drawing a lie.
I think he is lying.
- Unfortunately, Oskar.
-No!
There will be no point for you.
He absolutely does not lie.
They have Fanta in their kebab sauce.
Better luck next time.
- Annika?
- I choose Chang.
- Chang.
They would stop begging and become enterprising -
- And got money to start a limited company.
A good investment.
The state got everything back through the Jack Vegas machines.
The audience is so racist that they: "Is this true?"
The point is that you wanted to get Roma to start a business and get started.
A type Start own contribution.
You got 30,000 per skull.
- No, I don't think they would ... - that Roma can run a business?
Yes.
But the state did not distribute money to start a business.
-What are you saying?
True or false?
- False.
Congratulations, Annika.
One point!
What Chang said was false.
It was a damages due to the illegal Rome register of Skåne Police.
4,700 children and adults were in it and had the right to seek damages.
Do you know what I call it?
Genealogy.
- Did you get damages?
-No.
They hustled me, those bastards.
Truth.
I got, Ahmed Taikon.
What happens, BRE?
-Let's move on.
- Christina?
-Yes.
- I move on with Evelyn.
–Evelyn?
So she could eat in bed.
Nobody Else?
Just me?
This doctor was one who performed innocence operations -
- What is operations to restore the retina -
- Which really does not exist.
He would perform an operation, but had to set up at the last moment.
He then gave the woman the advice to put in chicken liver in the snippan -
-So, once she lay with her husband on their first night -
- She was bleeding anyway.
–When Keeping it Real goes Wrong.
- It sounded so sick ...
... so it's true.
- You think it's true?
-Yes.
Doctors in Sweden recommend stopping a chicken liver.
Throughout Evelyn's explanation, I saw how Barre became a vegetarian.
Christina, congratulations to your second score.
It's true.
It came out when SVT examined innocence operations.
10–44 salmon can be paid for something that was never there.
–Oskar, your turn.
Who do you choose?
- I take Elaf.
I like we went to the same hairdresser.
The stylist there can only do one thing.
She just: "Ball on everyone."
- Elaf?
If you thought that Ahmed Fes just, then you might agree with the Kurds.
These are actually the words for bargains and fish.
It comes from the Kurds finding that the fish sounds sound so.
You sound like my son in six months.
He may mimic the bargain sound, but I don't think that's right.
You're lying.
-No!
- Unfortunately, Oskar.
No point for you this time.
It's crushed box.
Never been so much Svennebanan in my entire life.
FECE and TEAR are definitely FIS and bargain in Kurdish.
Annika, we move on.
Who do you choose to talk to?
-Thanos.
- What happens, Ahmed?
Time for a picture question.
This is a childhood image on Thanos when he was a pimp in Botkyrka -93.
We see this boy from Turkey celebrating a ceremony for several days -
-Do to dress up for prince.
He has inherited his first sausage kiosk.
No, but ... this is from a Turkish custom.
It is such a thing that you cannot translate directly into Swedish.
But it is a type of injunction -
- Where the parents introduce each child.
It is not "engagements for children", but the families will get to know each other.
In case they click as they pass their teens, they will get married.
The custom is called Sujuk in Turkish.
What do you say about this engagement party à la junior?
I have a hard time believing in it.
-I understand.
- With that suit and such.
Check out, he looks like a suky.
It's true!
- No, I probably don't think so.
- You don't think so?
You do that right in. Congratulations to another point, Annika.
The boy celebrates his circumcision which is considered the first step towards becoming a man.
/Grunts/
As you say in Swedish: "No hat indoors."
Wait!
Pause!
Do you celebrate circumcision if you look like that?
What did I get?
An ax was picked up in the living room.
The brother, you are not Turk.
I want to be Turk now.
Check out how he looks!
Powerful.
- It actually stands 2–2 ... --... 0.
- How does it feel, Oskar?
- Swenway in cubic.
Feels canon.
- Do you like pickled herring?
- No, I'm a vegetarian.
I do.
I'm the Swede here.
Christina, can you keep up the success and get a third point?
- What do you trust?
- Not on anyone.
- Musti delivers so I answer correctly.
- Musti?
The first thing I think about is that it is SD that demonstrates for BLM.
For real, Christina.
I'll give you a point.
What you see is a Persian New Year's plot -
–As during the holiday Norouz and spread joy -
- As Santa Claus, but I call him Black Claus.
They look happy.
Type.
- Do you think that Musti is lying?
- I think he is lying.
Unfortunately, there will be no point.
It's true.
The racist Black Face character is called Haji Firuz-
- And has a similar origin as Dutch Zwarte Piet.
A slave boy who will cheer up his master's mood.
In Iran you do it during the New Year, and in the Netherlands during Christmas.
To all Iranians out there who say: "He has only soot in the face" ...
Khafe Sho!
Don't lie to us.
The Dutch tried with it too.
- Oskar, we move on with you.
You still have no points.
Who are you running on?
- Yes ... - Felicia, help me out.
-Yes.
The influencer Rebecca Stella was a snack ice cream 2020.
She did something talented for once.
Just kidding!
Never Happened.
She explained why she does not have dark colors in her makeup collection.
Why she just has bright colors.
Because blacks do not buy makeup.
I like clouting glass panes, but, yes ... you speak the truth.
Of all you trusted Felicia.
Courageously!
Congratulations to your first point, Oskar.
Felicia did not lie.
She would advertise her makeup.
A follower wondered why she just sold bright concealers.
Rebecca Stella replied: "The truth is that dark colors barely sell."
Can be because Rebecca uses all the dark colors itself.
Annika, you have a question left.
But all panelists are already chosen.
Therefore, your panelist will be ...
Chang?
Harald Edelstam, black carnation, a well -known name for Swedish chile.
Por Que?
He was a traveler down in Chile and sniffed a lot.
His own snuff tasted carnation.
Down there he was called the black carnation.
Many Chileans began to sniff this snuff.
Outside the Nordic countries, Chile is funny enough the country that buys the most snuff.
No!
So it was not.
- Normally seen a sniffing chiler?
- It wasn't what it was about.
She doesn't trust anything.
What did I tell you?
Pound for Pound, Sweden's best librarian.
- Why don't you believe in Chang?
- He was well ambassador to Chile.
Yes, he spread snus to people.
Congratulations to your third point.
Full pot in the first round.
What Chang said was false.
Harald Edelstam or black carnation -
-Was Sweden's ambassador to Chile in the 70s.
He saved hundreds from the violence of the military dictatorship, a bit like Schindler.
It rounds off the first round.
Christina and Annika go to the final.
Thank you, Oskar, who has competed and competed.
It's time for the final round.
It's just like the first round -
- In addition if you answer wrong, that point goes over to Annika.
It is only about five.
We start with the one who got a full pot in the first round: Annika.
I heard that you had learned some suburban hose.
-What have you learned?
--Walla.
/Pronounces that as Voilá/
I have to hear about that.
Say it one more time.
--Walla.
/ Voilá/ –Anika, who do you choose?
–Evelyn.
- Voilá, Annika.
Walla.
The worst is that Annika uses Walla better than you do.
Evelyn?
That's how they make their sauerkraut.
No, but that means that if it is a Croatian couple ...
... and they try to have children, and that's hard -
-As one of the traditions, a superstition -
- That you put cabbage on your feet to help fertility.
Say Walla.
No I do not think so.
Congratulations to the first point in the final round, Annika.
It's false.
Cabbage on the feet is considered to reduce swelling and heal wounds.
According to Balkan Morsas.
- Christina, who do you take?
I think my son Benjamin knows who VC Barre is.
- I honor him and take you.
-Brother?
In Spain, it is a tradition among young people to yeah, have sex, at twelve.
-Have!
- I just like it.
Have!
Twelve grapes should be printed at twelve.
Then you have to print one in yourself every time the church bell strikes.
It is said that you are lucky that year, if you have done so.
The only thing I heard was yeah, printing, sex, intercourse.
What happens, Bram?
I wish Annika came here.
She could walk.
Now she can yeah too.
- Christina?
- I've heard something about the grapes.
But Spain?
I hang a lot there.
I have not printed grapes there.
But I believe in you, because it sounds so strange.
It doesn't sound stranger than saying "pressing grapes".
-What do you think?
True or false?
- Sant.
You think that's true?
Congratulations, Christina, you have received a point!
YES!
In Spain, twelve grapes should be printed at midnight.
One every time the church bell is squeezed, to get lucky for the new year.
- Annika, ready to take this on?
- Yeah.
- What do you choose?
- Felicia.
She makes jazz hands.
She is a sick big Broadway fan, if you didn't know.
I was just joking.
She makes a butterfly because she has a butterfly tattooed in the swan.
It is a protest that players are not allowed to take off the sweater when they score goals.
That's why she does so.
I do not think so.
- You don't believe in Felicia's explanation?
- Butterfly!
Annika knows that if you have a butterfly on the flank you will not show it.
- It's actually true.
- Congratulations to your other points!
You are quick.
I have to say that.
Kosovare Asllani makes the Albanian eagle as you can see on the Albanian flag.
Let's move on.
- Christina, your turn.
I know that Elaf has the nicest shoes I have seen, so I choose her.
- Should I show them?
-Yes thank you.
-Elaf?
–Yes.
Another image question.
Yes, one of these four is sacred.
It is actually the multivitamin juice.
The resort loves it.
Do not know why.
Maybe because it's so cheap.
You get all your vitamins with a glass.
Therefore, everyone is so long.
Check, Ahmed.
Eh ... my best friend is Turk so we drink the ayran a lot.
Do you say that?
I say it was false, despite stylish shoes.
You say it's false?
Unfortunately, there will be no point for you.
- But a point to Annika.
- Shit too!
One thing was fun.
When Elaf said multivitamin-
- I heard a person in the audience there who started applauding.
The correct answer is Glockengold multivitamin, a very cute juice -
- With dyes in which contains a little, a little ... no vitamins at all.
Congratulations to the bonus points, Annika.
Who do you choose?
-Tilde.
- Brazil!
Brazil!
Annika, the special thing about these three countries is ...
At all IKEA they sell Swedish food - meatballs and everything possible.
In the three countries, most Kalles caviar are eaten, except in Sweden.
But I have bonus information.
I have lived in ... Portuguese: Brasil.
-E Você Também Fala Português?
- Fala Fala Nada.
Então Você Sabe Que Isso é a Verdade, Né?
This will be fun.
- That the Swedish queen, Silvia, is half -breeze.
I have lived in Brazil and they always ask: Você Conhece a Rainha?
So: Do you know the queen?
Therefore, it is not called Kalles Caviar in Brazil, but Rainha Silvia.
It is a picture of the tube on our queen.
- Wasn't it fun?
-Yes.
Hope that is true only.
-No.
They probably don't like caviar.
-You Break My Heart.
Meu Coração!
It sounds like Ronaldinho when you close your eyes.
She has him on the inside.
Why can't caviar be one of our biggest exports?
- I don't think people like caviar.
-You are absolutely right.
Congratulations.
People don't like caviar, Kalle.
False.
All of those countries use the Swedish combat plane Jas Gripen.
We give an applause to Annika because she got another point.
Christina, if you look at the result it stands 4-1 to Annika.
If you answer wrong, Annika has won the whole thing.
- I tag now uphill.
-I believe in you.
Who do you choose?
Thanos was chopped, so we choose him.
Which plant ended up being grown in Sweden in the 16th century ...
Feels like you have the answer.
I say this, but not because I'm Greek.
It was garlic.
That's it.
- No more expenses?
- Should I sound like a Greek guy?
It was garlic, it came in the 70s with labor immigration and ...
I have to put this one.
You want an answer.
What are you saying?
True or false?
-Comeback?
True.
- You think it was true?
The game continues, my ladies and gentlemen.
- Congratulations, Christina!
True.
For a long time in the 20th century, garlic was only available at Apoteket-
- And was almost forgotten in cooking.
But then the Turks came, they put it in Tzatzki.
Annika, now it's your turn.
If you answer correctly, take this home.
Are you ready?
I see that library brain just "Frrr".
- Musti.
- I, Musti.
It was a strike ... a word I learned today.
... as the police did at a wedding.
And they seized several criminals there.
After the strike they noticed, "Okay, this is where everyone is."
It was a good opportunity to arrest more criminals, because there everyone gathers.
Especially those who keep a low profile.
So it was a strike that the police made.
Strike.
- What do you say, Annika?
- I think it's true.
You think it's true?
Congratulations, Christina.
You just got a point.
As we see now, much more even.
It was an effort against tax fault in Södertälje.
The proceeds from Syrian wedding floors were high -
- But the tax paid Very Low.
The effort also showed that 1/3 of the liquor sold was full spirit.
Christina, it now stands 4-3 to Annika.
- Should we try to get a fourth point?
-Yes thank you.
I choose the plush suit.
- The shoes match.
- Fan, what a good looking!
Several shoes up.
Christina, you chose Chang.
But if you answer the wrong, the point goes to Annika.
Then she has won.
Chang, football player Maradona's old Argentine club ...
They had pink clothes.
Not as good looking as this one.
They thought they were goofy.
They were bullied.
At that time you couldn't be feminine when you were a guy.
They just: "Walla, the man. We must have new colors."
They go down to the harbor and hang.
There comes a boat with a Swedish flag.
"We drive yellow and blue."
Shit happens.
You should hear Chang's history pod.
It's crazy.
- Christina?
Can you trust a rum?
I think, of course, Sweden comes and delivers its colors.
True.
–Sant?
- Helt sick, but ...
You are still in the match.
Congratulations to your fourth point!
For those who know mathematics, you see that it is 4–4.
Over to a thing called closest to win.
Oh, great fun!
Oh!
How many Muslims were there in Sweden in 1953?
OOOH!
It was my cousins from Kulu, from Konya they have come.
We meet Södertälje Scania, we start working ...
I say 12 990.
Christina and Annika, ready?
How many Muslims existed in Sweden in 1953?
- When do you think we came here?
- The librarian takes it home.
Christina guesses 21,000, Annika guesses 3,000. The correct answer ...
How many Muslims existed in Sweden in 1953?
About 500.
That means: - Annika, you win.
Congratulations, Annika!
Here you have your diploma.
Here you have your Turkish coffee set, so you can predict people.
Congratulations Congratulations!
Awesome work.
That's all we had for today.
Thanks to all of you who have looked.
Thank you our fantastic panelists, fantastic competitors.
We meet again!
Texting: Cristel Nyqvist Swedish Media Text for SVT