Is it so smart to go to this year's village party, Leif?
Of course, Billy.
We have been there every damn year.
Yes, but Tony is angry because we put him there for the burglary.
Shit in that inbred Stockholmer.
There is nothing to care about.
Can I see?
c.teletext.sangc.sangju more We are together c.Sangju happier we become
Bowl!
It is a great shame that you are going to move, Tony.
That Sörbäcken should lose such a nice boy as you.
I can't stay here anymore.
The brothers Öhman are sick in the head.
It may not have been easy.
First, they had to kill your dog.
I have been detained twice for things I haven't done.
- Do you have any buyer at the house?
- Some have been and checked.
Hello.
What nice weather!
- Do you want to have anything?
- A little filling is always good.
-Here.
Tell me if there is anything.
-I will.
Have a nice evening.
What the hell are you doing?
You have your own mom to pick up?
Hello!
Hey.
Well, is it a village party, right?
Are you really invited to this year's party?
What the hell do you mean, Micke?
- I don't think ... - it's clear that they are invited.
Everyone in the village must come.
Right?
Of course.
Otherwise, they miss this whole competition that we have run.
- The competition like us ... - Yes, just that!
The competition, yes.
It is a tradition - the acid streaming competition.
It'll be fun.
- So there!
-What should we do?
Eat?
You should eat up each jar of acid streaming on time.
The bun has the record in 1.30 minutes.
There are 5,000 bucks in the pot.
-Are you ready?
- We really need the money.
–Yes.
Shall we drive?
Drive!
- Hurry, Billy.
- Good, fight!
Come on, Leif!
Work hard.
-Working at.
-I can not...
Good, Bill ... Come on.
In with them.
Five thousand bucks!
- It's just spewing up.
Working at.
-Clear!
Stop time.
Great!
New record time - during the minute, actually.
- Do we get the price?
- The price?
There is no price.
Did you think there was a price for real?
- Do you joke, right?
- You are the joke.
Doesn't it smell damn bad here?
- You might have to go home.
–What damn, the bun ...?
- No one wants you to be here.
If anyone wants them to be left, you can raise a hand.
- No hands come up.
- We drove your cat to the vet.
- After that you had run on it, yes.
- Tomas?
You killed my son's dog, accused him of poaching -
- And put him there for burglary.
Do you think there are some who want you here?
You can go home.
- Now we are partying.
We take a nub.
Hell!
It still smells like crap all over the body after four showers.
-Oh my God!
- It doesn't go away.
-What should we do?
- Yes, Billy.
That bastard ...
He has turned every one in the village against us, joking us out to everyone.
- It requires revenge.
-What then?
- No, Leif!
- We play them a joke.
This is not good.
- Leif!
- But, Leif ... -!
Down on the hill!
Insect.
-What should you do?
You can't shoot.
- I should scare them a little.
Think about it.
Is it so smart?
He pulled down his pants in front of the entire village.
We can't just sit here.
- We must have a backlash.
-A shot.
Fucking pigs.
Should you have a party without us?
- Her God, Leif!
- Did you see the can?
What was that?
I feel like a sniper, as if you are in a war zone.
I understand that it feels cool, but it is enough now.
Small shooter in the guard, ready to shoot.
Check out the princess cake, Billy.
- It was the last.
Stop the rifle.
- A to, Billy.
Look, Tony.
A full bag-in-box!
We can have it for dinner tonight.
We have the goal in sight.
Battle woman with wine box.
Not the wine box.
She holds it.
Stop it!
Cursed!
-What have you done?
- It was you who shot.
Blame me!
May I look?
Oh my God.
That bastard.
- I'll come, mom.
-He is coming here!
- We have made a love blind.
- What anxiety.
- Now damn!
Open the door!
–What have you set up?
- Do you see that I am?
You shot.
Is it the police?
It's Tony Nilsson from Sörbäcken.
Leif and Billy have shot the mother in the eye.
You may send a car here.
Mm ... Third time liked, Leif.
Two dots before.
You would get a foot buoy if it became a third.
I was not aware of the dots.
No one has informed us about them.
Where would I have received them from?
You drove 210 km/h on 30-road, outside a school.
We were running out of gasoline, so we took off to roll home.
You blasted a fox stew into the air.
Yes, and it is called game care.
With 1.5 kg explosives, which you had turned from the mine.
Okay, you took me.
I did wrong.
How long are you drawn with old sins?
Should I be stamped in the neck as livestock?
It was two weeks ago, Leif.
Now it will be a foot buoy for six months, and there is nothing you can say.
- Damn Fittsnut.
-What did you say?
He said nothing ... he said nice snuff.
Fine as snuff.
He thinks it will be wonderful to take care of.
C.Teletext.urfjarran test to post the house on the yellow sides.
I have already done that.
It takes time to sell houses out here.
C.Teletext.urfjarranja, that's enough.
How is it going?
Have you tested the saw?
Yes, it is made of cryptonite or something fucking titanium.
c.Teletext. sound sign
Hello guys.
I was going to come by, just.
It has gone over control this whole thing between us.
This with the footbojan and registration ...
I had to report because I thought my mom had become blind.
I understand.
It was not meant to shoot her in the eye.
No, who does it?
I get it.
Sorry for what happened at the party.
I have a little pardon-mig cake.
You can take it with you.
- We pull a line over this.
- Yes, it's good if we can do it.
Greet that I apologize to my mother.
Is she about to go?
We go down to Stockholm.
She is a little cut, so I go with.
- What nice that we got to talk out!
- Thanks for the cake, Tony.
- I should not disturb any more.
-See ya.
Have a good one.
Take care of you, and eat it up before it melts.
Then you just have to turn side, change chapters and move on.
I think I've learned a lesson from all this.
It is that you can apologize.
I feel good about this, you are doing well, the mother, Tony - everyone benefits from it.
- You can actually apologize.
- Giantfint said.
I agree with.
Just accept the footboy and move on with life.
Now we chop in.
Damn, how good it was!
- It was very much chocolate.
- Near Besk, but in a good way.
- Her god, this is how the sky tastes.
–What nice by Tony.
Fy damn, what good it was!
What are you doing?
Let's see.
Leif Öhman here.
I want to rent a sludge cleaner tonight.
C.Teletext.urfjarranvi has no empty cars tonight.
If you have one that is full, I would like to take it.
I can empty it for you.
The brother picks it up tonight, so I do the job myself.
Good.
I don't know if I can do it, Leif.
You can do it yourself.
Do you hear forgotten the footcuff?
If I walk 20 meters, the entire police force comes.
Is that what you want?
No, get started then, for hell.
What do you say now, Tony?
C.Teletext. sound signc. sounding sound
Hell!
What is going on?
Oh!
What the hell, the whole house is full of crap!
"Welcome, your bastard. I am king in the village."
"If you have something countless, you can come over and take that eye to eye."
"Leif Öhman."
Run, run!
Texting: Karin Hagman (C) Swedish Television AB 2019