- How is it really to be a manager?
- I am a little sore in the fist.
- They don't sound?
- I talk about squash.
- IIdioti that managers should play squash!
- be glad you are not a hairdresser.
Aino Nilsson showed a photo of Grace and Rainier: "So I want to look".
- Making her to Grace is difficult.
- Yes, I made her Rainier.
But oh, what have you done in the forehead?
Hi, Lina.
There is a home in Karlstad where patients can roam freely.
-She is in love.
A new guy who is cute.
- And he beats her?
- But Sara!
He asked what she was called.
- What did she answer?
She vomited ... a little on one shoe.
Then she went into a cupboard.
I don't get a word out of her.
Are you trying to?
–Ah ... she has a father?
-No.
He has subscribed to the ice hall.
Max will be the best in ice hockey ...
In the beginning you have to take it easy.
- Gustav met Rask at Konsum ... - did he - croofed on his star to son?
He said that Max should learn to skate before joining the team.
Gustav chased a fast with the shopping cart and threw back potatoes at him.
The world is full of mature men.
Why do I help you with the accounting?
- I owe your bank so much.
-Right.
Thanks.
- Do you fill in the VAT with pink ink?
-It's a lip pen.
Clinique Midnight Purple.
Nice to blue control tasks ...
They will probably come soon.
Do you think Max got to play today?
Am I ugly?
Max says guys don't like girls with dental position.
Your dental position is not visible!
People thought I had a harmonica in my mouth.
- You didn't get any guys either?
- Some musicians heard ...
- I was cared for.
You will do that.
- Of what?
Flies?
- What was all these guys called, then?
- God, what was they called ...
- It was dad and ... - you have just been with dad.
We fell in love and that way it is.
Isn't life fantastic?
Really.
C.Sangseiern is spring, Seiern is spring!
C.Sangvi has won, Seiern is spring!
I haven't been so much since I cut the lawn.
When Tage Erlander was prime minister.
- Max, did you have to join the ice?
Don't chat about details!
Nothing goes up to see you on the bench with winning instinct in your eyes!
Rasmus says the sign means:
"Fit max, so he doesn't infect on the ice."
Don't worry about Rasmus!
On Saturday you play center instead of Rasmus Rask!
No one learns to skate in two days.
Well, Börje Salming.
- You brother has made progress today.
- Did he think be in the dressing room?
- Have you been injured?
- She has entered a cupboard.
- What was it wrong with Techno?
- She had met a guy.
Now things happen!
What's his name?
- Peter.
--Forsberg?
Runesson!
Gumman, it's time for conversation between father and daughter ...
You're twelve years ...
-Fourteen!
- Same the same.
When I was your age, I was terribly fond of a girl.
I didn't dare talk to her.
But she had been just as fond of me.
- Was she blind?
-No.
Because I didn't dare talk to her, I never got to meet her.
That's one thing you have to find out:
What he thinks about Tre Kronor's new team lineup.
- Her god, do people have no humor?
- Strange, you who are so fun!
- Thanks, the old man.
How does it feel now?
- I will never place in the team.
Trust me, I have said.
Rask should see what a Svensson goes for!
Exercise, so I take care of the rest.
Okay, but I want a snowboard.
It's done.
The most important thing is not to play ...
--... without crushing Kjell-Åke Rask.
- It's time for a little tactic talk.
This is your team.
That's the team you are in. Max!
You get in the middle zone, fits back to Bengt-Åke Rydin ...
... dribbles past Näslund to Max Svensson ... Yes!
Here you get the puck.
No, this little black!
Here comes Max Svensson again, he dribbles past Makarov, he is free.
- He is approaching the goal and ... - no!
Sara, for hell!
You are in the middle of the goal yard!
Your father tried to tackle me over the fence.
"Sarge" ...
- Is it something, skating on gravel?
-Endurance!
Stop dipping now.
What does he look like?
I do not know.
It blackens to the eyes.
- What do you feel when you meet him?
- That I want to vomit.
You could have better conditions ... Lina, don't get so nervous.
I envy you.
You have life ahead of you, unlimited with dreams.
–And dental position.
-It belongs to the.
- You have fat hair, pimples, foot fungus.
- Thanks, that's enough.
I'll show one thing that few have seen ...
Guess how old I am.
Fifteen years.
- You don't look wise!
- You look like that at your age.
–What do you have in the cheek?
- A perch traits.
I was a punk.
We fought against the establishment, the government, the king and the whole court.
But it was then and today is today.
- So here you catch the one you are in love with.
- You call.
-Never!
What if he answers!
Then you can talk to him.
Call now.
And take this in case that ... you know.
Good luck!
Hello!
This is Lina Svensson.
In 7A.
With long hair.
Just that, I am ... that vomits.
Did you get the shoes clean?
Good.
Huh?
Party?
Tonight?
Gladly.
Where?
I'll just pick up the pen.
How should you be able to score if you close your eyes?
- I get gravel in my eyes!
- Fill on the water bottle.
And no scratches in the parquet!
-Carelessness!
-Do you have a pen?
I took home 60 pens from work.
They are among other things I took home.
Have you put on the handset?!
-Hear!
- Someone talks at the other end.
If Peter goes to this party without me, I murder you!
Idiot!
-I'm finished.
- Then we set up the cones.
Makarov will be round.
Kjell-Åke and Rasmus Rask you tackle!
... to Bengt-Åke Rydin.
Max Svensson threads by.
Great!
Around the box there ...
-How does it feel?
Are you nervous?
- No, I'm used to you.
Tomorrow, Max Svensson will debut as a center in Ekberga IF.
I also don't like Kjell - Åke but you exaggerate.
He's evil!
It was he who tore the mini golf course.
- The city needed a parking garage.
- Man does not tear a cultural heritage!
Bane eight with the ceramic site, track twelve with the moat ...
Someone has to show where the boundaries go.
And "someone" is our ten -year -old son Max?
Do not worry.
He is starting to really like hockey.
-Look!
-What is it?
Börje Salming's parents live luxury in Florida.
"Salming's parents spend half the year in Börje's summer house."
Look, if you are in the swimming pool you can almost reach the orange tree.
- Max will never be a new Börje Salming.
- Never say!
- Think if we had square miles with grass!
- Who would take care of that grass?
You can't even buy gasoline for the mower.
That grass is shot by pedro ...
... the Mexican in Sombrero standing and rakes.
- Look, Pedro comes with drinks ... - put away that newspaper.
Lina looked for four hours for the party.
- I have asked for forgiveness.
- I found her in Vålberg.
She stared into a Bratvurst and mumbled about "the darkness to take everyone".
- I should make up her.
- Can she sit mainly on the match?
Important!
Buy new skates for Max.
Hans does not fit.
- He got new skates a week!
- They don't fit mentally.
He is not mentally safe with them.
Then you are chanceless on the ice.
- Everything must be true!
-You are sick.
No, I only have workouts in the ass.
Lena?
Cut me!
Do what the hell you just want me to sit here in peace and quiet!
Gustav just learned that Max is not taken out.
He carried Max in the car and screamed "So easily you do not dump a Svensson!"
My husband thinks he is Honken and my daughter glare into a Bratwurst.
-What have I done wrong?
- You use the wrong conditioner.
-What should I do?
- Don't you read about that housewife?
- Who shot his family?
- She who moved out into the forest.
It's been a long time since I saw such a happy person.
- It said she needs help.
- I thought it looked so cozy.
Kjell-Åke Rask was here yesterday and his son.
It was as usual ...
Rasmus always refuses to take off the helmet and Kjell-Åke refuses to pay.
How could he demolish the mini golf course?
Didn't Gustav have track record there?
Yes.
He would baptize Max on track nine.
Romantic ... It's nice that Gustav tries to give him a homework.
He can do it in a healthy way - kill him.
- Sara, Peter called!
- Don't you lowered a hat?
He wants us to go to the cinema.
You have to make me nice!
- Hallå ... - What do you think he likes?
- Everything except perch traits.
- Labor traits?
- Can I have this?
-You are very cute.
Is everything perfect?
-Almost.
The female is on the entrance.
- I take care of them.
C.Sangseiern is spring, Seiern is spring!
C.Sangnita judge, split his thighs!
Pack the bags.
Pedro is waiting with the drinks in Florida.
- Max spent the match on the rink.
- Did you spike him in the coffin?
Be proud of our son.
From the exchange bench to the center forward in three days!
- He wouldn't play?
-I had to.
Rasmus didn't come.
Someone had locked him in the dressing room.
Would I lock in a ten -year -old guy?
- Something goes the limit.
–In eleven?
Our son made the decisive victory goal!
Max Svensson showed who is Ekberga's real hockey star!
I got the puck in my neck when I knotted the skates.
You steered it in!
What a presence!
You can go as far as possible.
- This I think we are celebrating!
-I think so too.
Be so good, read.
-What is this?
- Read!
"I hereby swear that Max should never have to do with hockey again."
"I guarantee he gets a snowboard before the week is over."
-Sign.
-Never.
You start getting it in.
All great sportsmen end when they are on top.
-Sign!
- I squeezed me when I locked the door.
- To the dressing room ... another!
- You locked that boy!
I think Rasmus learned something.
- That is boring in changing rooms?
- That you don't tease Max unpunished!
He had comic books and during the break he got juice through straws in the lock.
-Sign!
-Impossible.
What would Borg have been if his parents had not been behind him?
- Consultant maybe?
- I never sign!
–Okay ... matches.
- Should he start smoking?
- Serve goodbye to your autograph collection.
- You don't!
--Borg, Martin Dahlin, Makarov ... - I do!
It is a pleasure to do business with you.
- I will miss him.
- He lives here.
I mean Pedro, the gardener.
Pedro is dead.
Salming's father drove him over with the lawnmower.
He left a message to you: "Cut the grass himself, and stop dreaming."
- Hi, Honken, how did the match go?
- Line, sorry.
I've been stupid.
So now I think we go to the cinema!
We had so much fun last time.
- Whatever shudder at the end!
- When the thunderbump was chased by robbers?
- Should we see if it is still going?
- I will go to the cinema with Peter.
- Then we get company!
I invite.
- Peter offers.
Thank you!
Me, just me.
-Bye.
-Have fun!
Don't come home prematurely.
- You can invite me to the cinema.
- If I have to decide the movie!
Nothing signed, please?
Gustav ...
We'll probably have to do it another time.
Kjell-Åke's Merca stayed outside!
Okay.
We have to sort out one and the other.
-Are you sure about that?
- I've never been so sure!
Okay we do this way ...
We pick up Max and jump out through the bathroom window.
He had the club in his hand.
Kjell-Åke stood behind and held the dogs.
Max, we're going out with the car a turn!
Texting: SVT Sub -text (C) Swedish Television AB