After this meeting, nothing will be the same.
For in the stock boats there is a load that will change life in fundamentals -
- For all future generations here in the Nordic countries.
We are in the Stone Age.
A period of over 10,000 years, then the first people to come here -
- Must adapt to a whimsical and unpredictable climate.
Archaeological finds tell of a woman's life as a stone -age hunter ...
... and about others who come here to become farmers.
These are the first residents -
- Which creates the foundation of the country we live in today.
This is the story of our country.
About the people and forces that have shaped it -
- Endure from the ice age until our days.
This is the story of Sweden.
The first people to set foot here do it to hunt.
They have followed the animals north and meet a whole new landscape.
Until recently, the land was unavailable -
- Deputy embedded under a huge ice cover, over 1,000 meters thick.
Inland ice.
The last ice age lasted over 100,000 years.
But then something happens that changes the spread of ice.
I.a.
This is how the slope of the earth's axis changes -
–And 14,500 years ago it gets warmer -
- And the ice is starting to melt.
One might think that the landscape at the icy is dead and barren -
- But it is also extremely fertile, and we quickly get flora and fauna.
This is people very interested in -
- So the icy is something that people follow, you might say.
The first people to come here are dark -skinned with blue eyes.
They are hunters who follow the prey animals into Sweden -
- To the new hunting grounds.
You move above great distances.
It can be about today's Germany, up to southern Sweden -
–And maybe even
Central Sweden.
It is thus thousands of kilometers.
The hunters can search for several days on the huge expanses -
- Whey they manage to trap an animal.
They often chased in family groups, and in some situations it was required -
- That everyone who could help - men, women and young people.
It was a great collective work, and it was about sneaking forward.
You had hand signs to signal to each other and not scare the prey.
You are several people, certainly also dogs, who drive the animals -
–Up on tops or down in watercours -
- Where it is easier to take the animals and where they cannot escape.
One must remember that these people were hugely vulnerable.
It was a gigantic tundra landscape with many miles to the nearest neighbors.
No mistakes may be committed.
It is precisely on the edge that you can manage in this environment.
So these people were incredibly dependent on each other.
The hunters moving in the landscape leave tracks that we can see today.
The earliest finds from people in Sweden are different tools of flint.
Here, for example, we find scraps used in leather preparation -
- But also lace from arrows or spears.
We know from historical hunter society that the story was incredibly important:
What you have been through how the prey animals behaved, how hunting methods worked.
This was an incredibly important way to pass on knowledge.
The story is also a way to build up social cohabitation.
You can tell amazing, exciting stories.
In larger investigations, it has been possible to find - -
- The storyteller among hunter people in the world has more children than the average.
So, you have social success if you are good at telling.
The first hunters only come here in the summers to hunt.
The winters are too cold, so the rest of the year they live down in Germany.
But it will soon change.
As the inland ice melts away, our Swedish nature begins to see the light of day.
When the weight of ice disappears, the land surface -
- And we get a land rise that is going on in large parts of Sweden today.
Gradually, the Northern European landscape emerges, as we know it.
At this time, the trees are attached to our latitudes, and begin to spread.
And where sly and shrubs grow up soon form birch and pine -
- A brand new landscape for man to live and live in.
With the new landscape, major cultural changes are also taking place.
Now more people are starting to come in, who stay for longer periods.
The young Swedish forest provides both protection and building materials.
As the climate gets warmer, Sweden gets its first permanent residents.
They spread into southern Sweden and up along the Norwegian coast.
Man becomes more resident on the coast, inside the inland.
From now, Sweden can in many ways be said to be colonized for real.
With the help of DNA analyzes we have been able to see that these people-
- Had quite much darker complexion than is common here today.
They were also blue -eyed to a large extent.
But the people who moved here from the south are not alone.
For at about the same time, others who are also looking for new hunting grounds - come.
- And places to stay.
And they come from the north -
- From areas that are today Finland and Russia.
They look a little different from the southern group.
There are individuals with lighter hair and individuals with darker hair.
And at the skin pigmentation level, it is average slightly lighter pigmentation -
- Enta in the southern group.
It seems that these people meet fairly quickly and have children -
- What makes us get a mix in the look.
But we are now starting to go towards a lighter pigmentation -
- Among the people living in these areas.
It will take many thousands of years and more migrations -
- The Scandinavians get the skin color that is the dominant today.
When people start living here all year -
- A new chapter is being started in our history.
They create settlements from Skåne to northern Norrland.
They move across large areas, follow the animals and look for edible plants.
They live both on the coast and inland, at streams and lakes.
Interestingly, you get a colonization from the north.
It is conceivable that the move to Norrland is happening quickly.
Large areas become ice -free as the ice melts away.
Excavations in recent years also show -
- That you lived very close to the icy 10,000 years ago.
This woman should forever enroll in Swedish history.
Over 10,000 years ago, she lived near Österöd, outside Lysekil.
And that's how she got her name: Österödskoman.
Her skeleton gives a unique insight into how to live in the older Stone Age.
She is dated to about 8,000 BC, ie 10,000 years ago.
It is thus the most complete, oldest skeleton we have in Sweden.
The early Stone Age hunters live together in family groups -
- On 15-20 people.
They are skilled hunters.
And you will find a good place ...
... then you settle down there and stay as long as there is food.
The skeletons of the Österöds give us clues about the life she lived -
- And what she looked like.
From her skeleton we have managed to extract DNA.
It makes us know quite a lot about hereditary diseases, how she looked out -
- And how she is related to other groups and individuals at that time.
She is athletic and quite long.
When we reconstruct her body length, she becomes up to 170 cm.
In her inheritance we see that she had dark hair.
She had pretty light skin and dark eyes.
The climate continues to become warmer -
- And in lakes, sea and rapids there are plenty of fish.
Stone age hunters are at least as much collectors and fishermen.
Fishing was an incredibly important part of the economy during this time.
We find fish traps - Mjärdar.
It has an opening where the fish can swim in, but they do not find out.
And then Mjärden is regularly witnessing, emptying it on fish.
The fixed fishing gear means that you can catch large amounts of fish -
- As many people saturate.
The dog was invaluable to the Stone Age hunters.
It served as a guard animal, but was above all important during the hunt.
The dog was more than just a tool, it was part of the group.
We see the dog's special importance, among other things.
in the dog graves we find.
Here, sometimes the animal has been sprinkled with reddocks, as in human engraves.
Perhaps the dog was seen as more related to man than with the wild animals.
The Stone Age families are nomads and often move.
But traveling with young children is difficult.
To be easy to move, you try to keep the number of children down.
In analyzes of teeth you can see that breastfeeding time has been long-
- And it may have been a way to limit childbirth.
With nature's pantry - fish in the sea and more prey than humans -
- Is life good for the Stone Age hunter.
But there are things that threaten.
Generally, the period is seen as peaceful: plenty of resources, no congestion.
Violence would not be room for.
But we see unusually much violence:
You have pucked each other, even
scalped each other.
One must assert one's own land-
- And the permanent fishing spots that groups build and maintain.
They may be at the heart of the group's own territory.
To abandon something, to break up and find new landscapes-
- was nothing strange.
The Stone Age is characterized by major changes -
–And because you live a mobile life in fairly large areas -
- So this is exactly what you are very good at.
The Österöd woman lives a long life.
Her skeleton shows signs that she had an elite athlete's physique.
In her pelvic bone we saw changes -
- As previously linked to giving birth to many children.
Today, the changes are associated with male football players.
So it has nothing to do with childbirth, but with an active life.
This is what has given rise to the changes we see in the pelvic bone.
Man has not changed so much since the hunter and collector's age.
They probably had equal opportunities to grow old then, as we have today.
They managed from infections and bone fractures and other-
- So you could get really old.
She turns around 70 years old -
- And probably she is buried by loved ones at the coastal band in Bohuslän.
This is where you find her grave - 10,000 years later.
She has been given her current name after the farm Österöd a bit away.
What she died of we do not know, but the remains give a crucial puzzle piece-
- In the knowledge of our history and who we have been.
The life of our ancestors will take a new turn.
For on the other side of the Atlantic, something happens that will be the beginning of a time -
- With dramatic changes in the climate.
First, the temperature suddenly drops.
From a life in a warm, comfortable climate, you now find it difficult to survive.
The last of the Canadian inland ice melts away.
Huge amounts of melt water accumulate in Lake Agassiz - and it falls.
All melt water that then comes out in the North Atlantic in a very short time -
- Emphasize sea circulation in the North Atlantic -
- And it leads to above all colder winters up here.
As the golf current is weakened, the flow of hot water is reduced from the tropics -
- To our part of the world, and the average temperature drops.
This cold and dry period lasts for almost 150 years.
Houses and villages are left fate.
For those who fail to adapt, there is only an end - death.
Of course, when the big changes occur, people react.
It is not impossible that this particular event had such great consequences -
- You started to question the old way of living.
But then the climate turns again.
After a century, the golf current regains its power.
It gets warmer.
These major climate change back and forth -
- Not only implies people's way of life, but also their faith.
A modern person has a scientific explanation in the climate.
These people must have had other explanations of what happened.
For example, we see an increased closure of victims in large lakes.
Probably it is about wanting to try to restore a balance-
- Between the landscape and man.
We don't know much about what the faith of the Stone Age hunters looked like.
But they have left tracks that can be interpreted.
There were many places that were important to the hunters:
Strange stones and places, where you could sacrifice to sky gods.
But archaeologically, it is very clear -
- That human residues and funerals are often found in connection with water.
It can be interpreted as thinking -
- The road to the realm of death went through the water.
At a overgrown lake north of Motala, the archaeologists make a scary find.
7,700 years ago, here took place an eerie ritual.
So we found the first skull ...
... and shortly thereafter one more skull.
And then it continued like that.
When you look at Motala, we see a picture of skulls -
- Established on piles in water.
And it may look pretty scary.
But I think it is possible to turn into something positive too.
Because they have no slaughter injuries -
- We interpret it as the bodies decomposed in peace and quiet.
Then other people have put them on piles and taken care of the skulls.
And then you might be able to make comparisons with Catholic relics -
—There remains of holy people revered -
- Because the remains are handled in a nice way and so on.
This is about hunter gathers who often live scattered in the landscape.
They have probably been buried within the framework of a smaller group-
- But since then they wanted to honor the dead with a second funeral ceremony -
- Where a larger group of people have the opportunity to attend.
Motala Ström was not just a place for rituals and funerals.
Many people also seem to have been met for other reasons.
We believe that Motala stream at this time became an important hub -
—While, hunter gathers collected from the surrounding lands-
- One or a couple of times a year.
This was important because people needed to meet from all over the tribe.
Not least the young people who would find a partner.
In order not to get married within the family, a larger selection was given in that way.
It has now been over 2,000 years since the last cold period -
- And since then, the temperature has only continued to increase.
The Scandinavian climate is getting warmer -
- And is more reminiscent of what it is like in France or southern England today.
It can be difficult to imagine -
- But then there were turtles and pelicans in the Swedish lakes.
We are at Nämforsen in the Ångerman River.
This was a sea bay then and nature looked different.
It was hot and there was plenty of food.
Probably life was quite comfortable for the Stone Age hunters here.
They left traces behind them.
The oldest ones are 6,000 years old.
The rock carving area is one of the largest in Europe.
And the pictures tell us about people's lives and world of thought.
About 400 boats are carved - everything from large ships to small boats.
There are 700 animals depicted, of which 460 are roughly safe moose.
The moose must have been of great importance, because it is to such a large extent.
The reason for carving in precisely moose -
- It is that you use the moose in every conceivable context.
She gives clothes, she gives meat, and she is part of nature's fertility.
There was plenty of game and fish here far inside the bay.
In a protected location, it was a perfect place for the Stone Age man.
And when the salmon played in the bay, it became a gathering place for many more.
The carvings are the tracks you left behind for future generations.
For 8,000 years, Scandinavia has lived as hunters and collectors -
- And adapted life to the availability of food and the animals' movements.
A life in constant movement.
But all that will change soon ...
The mild, humid climate attracts a new group of people to move here.
First comes individual men who explore the new lands.
And then whole families.
With them they have a precious load and a special knowledge -
- This will lead to one of the biggest changes in our history.
It is now that we are starting to grow our food.
Agriculture comes from the Middle East.
Here they had grown and refined grain -
- Maybe 10,000 years, and livestock had been kept for almost as long.
Knowledge is surprisingly slowly spreading from Central Europe into the Nordic countries.
Maybe it finally came here because there was unbroken ground here -
- In combination with human curiosity.
This is the beginning of modern life that we live today.
When the Stone Age farmers begin to settle in the areas of the hunters -
- arises a risk of conflicts.
But negotiations and gifts can solve difficult situations.
There may have been conflicts, but we will find no traces after that.
It may have been peaceful - you have solved situations with negotiation.
It is likely that the movements have been planned fairly carefully -
–Annatted the landscape and negotiated with the hunter collectors in the area-
- If you could settle and under what conditions, etc.
A big difference between being a hunter and being a farmer is -
- That the farmer can produce surplus.
It doesn't mean just-
- You can save for worse times, you can also help people around.
In fact, the peasant life requires an increasing cooperation -
—Man between different groups -
- And that's why we get a society that may be more similar to what we have today.
This went pretty fast.
In individual generations -
- The population in southern Sweden, mainly through immigration.
The first cereals you grow are wheat and single grains -
- And this is the cereal that we still use.
With the Stone Age farmers, not only comes the knowledge of cultivation.
There will also be a new kind of beautifully decorated ceramic.
Archaeologists call the new farmer culture for funnel tramp culture-
—Af after one of the typical vascular forms of ceramics available from the period -
- With the form of just a funnel beaker.
Characteristic, besides the funnel form, is that you often decorated the necks.
One has been able to have them buried in the ground, swallow-
- And have both food and fresh water in these vessels.
You could say that it is a form of refrigerator.
With agriculture you become more resident and live in the same place all year round.
One advantage of being a farmer is that you can house a larger family.
You need many who can work in the yard and you need many children.
During this period, we also see that child mortality is declining.
There are both farmers and hunter collectors groups at the same time.
We see in the archaeological material that they have exchanged objects.
But we also look at DNA in the skeleton, that they did not have children with each other.
They have lived separately for 1,000 years - that's 40 generations -
- So there must have been strong barriers to mix.
But with the new way of life a new threat emerges: diseases.
One lives not only near the animals -
- You also live close to the stools and their own stools.
This means that we come into contact with brand new microorganisms -
- Oloba parasites and other things that lead to intestinal infections.
And when many live closely together, respiratory infections also increase.
Tuberculosis and flu and the like.
With the new agricultural culture, new ways will also bury the dead.
Some get their last rest in graves built of colossal boulders.
With the more resident lifestyle that the farmers bring with them -
- The way of thinking is changed.
The tombs are not only ritually important -
-What they also become a way to show the greatness and success of the family.
You start to distinguish between those who have power, and those who lack it.
The big stone tombs have corridors -
- And they are targeting the sun's rise in late autumn.
In the ancient Nordic calendar, it was the time when the spirits of the dead arrived -
-And there is something that lives in Halloween and in Halloween -day -
- When we visit cemeteries and so on.
In the opening, gifts were added that the dead brought with them in life after this.
It could be ceramics ...
... amber beads ...
... and of course pieces of the valuable flint.
The flint was the lubricant of society.
They opened flint mines in Skåne and Denmark, and then traveled expeditions -
- Maybe every year and changed flint axes, and then they went home.
This was done throughout southern Sweden, right up to Mälardalen.
There they sacrificed a lot of Flintan -
- To the gods, mainly mother earth, to get good harvests.
You did not need the flint axes.
The usual axes in the local stone species were at least as effective.
The time is almost six meters long.
Here in front is the chamber where the dead were laid for their last rest.
The roof consists of four large roofing hills, between one and two meters wide.
The stones in the hallway are a little lower than in the chamber.
In order to handle the level difference, a keystone of granite - has been placed
- An extra strong rock that could carry the weight from the roof block.
An incredibly complicated and skillfully done work.
The stone chamber tombs were engineering or architecture at a very high level -
- And for this job, builders were required.
There is a way to build graves on the east side Sweden -
- And one on the west side.
Two different architectural traditions are believed.
This particular grave is built about 5,300 years ago.
It belonged to a Stone Age family for many generations.
Such a grave is also a way to showcase its wealth and power.
Society becomes more unequal.
Not material really, but ritually.
Some people and families gained great ritual power.
Empty.
power over life and death.
The first human victims appear now -
- What is an extreme way to mark its influence.
Here is a young woman.
She was 18-20 years old when she died.
Of the findings, we can see that she has not died a natural death.
The young woman is killed in a lake 5,000 years ago, outside Falköping.
The stomach content has been preserved.
She had eaten lots of raspberries before she died.
That's how she got her name - the raspberry girl.
She is Sweden's first known human sacrifice.
The way she was in the water shows that she did not drown in the usual way.
Her hands were tied on her stomach.
Her legs and feet were connected to the back of the thigh, towards the buttocks.
This clearly shows that she has not only fallen into the water and drowned -
- The way she has been brought about life.
Someone has helped.
You do this to achieve a result, maybe better harvests.
It can be peace with the gods.
It can be peace with the ancestors.
There may be social reasons.
You take a person's life - with spectator masses.
And it's about highlighting:
"It is me who decides who is allowed to live and who is allowed to die."
At the time when the raspberry girl is killed -
- If a new group of people have begun to move through Europe, towards Sweden.
And they have something with them that makes the Stone Age start to come to an end.
This is a new group of people.
They have their origin in what is today Russia and Ukraine.
They move quickly across the continent and up to Scandinavia -
- Among other things by riding horses.
Some people in this group ended their days here.
When this roundabout in Linköping was built, a stone -age grave was found.
Before the construction could be completed, the archaeologists had to dig out the place.
What was found was unique.
The gifts that the dead have brought with them in the grave -
- shows that a new era in our history is on the way.
It is a funeral of a young couple.
We don't know what killed them, but we know they died early.
They are buried together 4,500 years ago -
-Added by gifts for the last trip.
Gifts that tell them that they belong to a new culture: the combat culture.
And it will be dominant throughout southern Scandinavia.
Battle ax culture is called it, after the battle ax - which was unlucky.
Above all, it was a symbolic object that one showed -
- To show that you were an important member of society.
Looking at past migration waves or change processes-
- Hos the Stone Age hunters or farms, so it happens for a long time.
But here it only takes a few hundred years.
The man and woman are not alone in their grave.
At the same time with the couple, a three -month -old infant is also buried.
In the grave is also a dog and objects that tell about the family.
There are no visible injuries -
- So they may have drowned or died of illness.
It is a well -ordered pair-
- Probably with a lot of power and a leading function in the countryside.
The woman is exciting, because she has had a magic bag full of gear -
- As a knife, a lace, bearer, a amber pearl and much more.
This shows that she probably has been medicine woman -
- But also a leader of rituals.
In front of her nose she has a victim of deer horns -
- As we lead the rituals in addition.
Then the first people came here to hunt in the summers a lot has happened.
At the end of the Stone Age, the various groups that have populated our country-
- Gained joint children.
The Northern Age of Stone Age learned from each other -
- Explores to new generations.
The people here have become the sum of their history.
The vast majority will live their lives as farmers -
- But in the north people keep lives in the hunt and the collection.
In the mountain grave there are also signs that the Stone Age is soon over.
For next to the dead are small spirals - in copper.
And they warn that a new time is on the way.
A new chapter in our history -
- Then golden bronze and shiny iron break through up here in the Nordic countries.
The pursuit of metals causes people to embark on dangerous travel -
- And leave the Stone Age behind.
It is the time of the metals.
Texting: Ulrika Jansson Båving Swedish Media Text for SVT