Art - or weirdness.
Sweden's art history is part of the huge story of our country.
We will with some impacts show art-
- As depicts changes and creation power.
This is in many ways an outstanding painting.
It is linked to a court party -
–As which took place in 1747–
–In a small social words created in the court circles:
The academia of the small champions.
They devoted themselves to different types of tables, ie.
Living paintings.
They had readings and poetic performances.
And probably the chicken board has been part of such a table.
Perhaps it could not have been done other than during the time of freedom -
-At the middle of the 18th century.
It is a litigant a period in Sweden.
Crown Prince Adolf Fredrik has married Princess Lovisa Ulrika.
And you put strong confidence in this young couple.
They are culturally interested.
Many cultural projects are gaining momentum in connection with their marriage.
You are working intensively to get the new castle in Stockholm.
One would have been involved at that time.
Science and culture take great steps.
Freedom and healthy winds blow.
In the construction team at the castle, the first artistic drawer academy starts.
Johan Pasch, who painted the chicken board, is one of the first students.
It's an exciting theme here.
This is the Crown Princess's hoof girls - ie.
the women from the high nobility -
- which were selected to be in the Crown Princess's courting.
We can also identify several of them.
Ernestine von Griesheim, Henrika Juliana von Liewen, Charlotta Sparre -
--Ul rich and Agneta Strömfelt and Catharina Charlotta Taube.
And the rooster - Count Tessin.
Carl Gustaf Tessin was the heaviest power player of the time, and party fixers -
- And the client of the chicken board.
He gave himself it in Christmas.
In bathrobe with freshly powdered lid wig nonchalantly placed at the workbench -
- He looks up from a copper stick.
The globe suggests that he sees the whole of Europe as his playground.
One should not throw stone-
-But Mr. Tessin would have had a hard time getting through the metoo movement.
His companion in Paris wrote troubled letters to Tessin's father.
One may wonder about the Father's thoughts when Weslander writes -
- That he is afraid that Carl Gustaf will wear a French disease.
He was some kind of peeping empty figure.
After all, the whole idea comes from -
- That he has seen how they dress at some time.
And there are stories from Paris-
- If he looks at different ladies through keyholes and stuff like that.
We believe that there is a subtle erotic play in the foundation of the subject.
Erotic or not-the art takes great steps during the 18th century.
Adolf Fredriks and Lovisa Ulrika's son Gustav III founded the Academy of Arts -
- Where Johan Pasch's niece Ulrika becomes the first female member ...
... before women would gain access.
It is a very important break for female artists in Sweden.
Female artists were often hidden in the studios and brothers' studios.
But there was no doubt that there was a female activity.
Yes, if you have been waiting, it is now that they show up in art history ...
... the women.
The winds of change are on their way.
Texting: Karin Esevik © Swedish Television AB 2023