c. sounded rooster gal
-So there.
The whole damn house, swine.
-Jajamän.
So clean that you can transplant a heart or feed a kid here.
c. soundtuppen gal
-Satan, how tired I am on the rooster!
-He calms down soon.
He has been wrong for three days, Billy.
I'm about to lose it soon.
Time for this week's bingo draw.
Satan!
Bingo!
The next issue is Ingemar 22. two, second.
Four in a row.
Now damn.
Come on now, Leffe!
The last number to win the high pressure washer is ...
-... Niklas ... -niklas ...
c. soundtuppen gal
Now I didn't hear what the hell they said!
Repeat!
-Thanks, and congratulations to the winner.
-Curse!
-How did bingo go?
-To hell.
That fucking rooster crazy, so you don't know what number to blip in.
I get so damned.
Look at him.
Black little devil eyes.
I give myself a damn that it lacks soul.
I have seen this on Discovery.
Soulless animals running around and haunting people.
You get cold corps from the fanfare.
That fucking rooster is driving me crazy.
Not quiet ever, crazy day and night.
You can't sleep or be awake.
-I know.
-We have to do something for him.
I have a plan, Billy.
Should we play the rooster a little splash?
Then he will shit down.
-Heazing, little rooster.
-We hurry us before the neighbor arrives.
So, the little rooster, now you should taste a little rinse of the system.
So yes.
Hope you get a hefty bowel rinse, rooster.
What a fool.
Check out, what a chicken brain.
-Take all that, you.
Hear!
-Hear!
c. soundtuppen gal
C. sound noise
-What the hell happens?
I'm afraid.
-Break, I think.
-Hop out of bed.
-I do not want to.
Jump up, I say!
-Hell!
-It's someone in the living room.
-Do first, you.
-No, you have weapons.
This is a classic combat tactic.
You send in the lid.
Then I come from the periphery and strike.
Okay okay.
-Satan ... are you with?
-Yes.
One two Three!
Aaahh!
What the hell?
- Leif, come here!
-What hell ... -fy fuck in hell.
It's crap everywhere.
God damn!
-As I don't ate you to close?
-Sorry.
Take it easy.
Calm?
Well, that I haven't thought about it before.
We are suitable for now when the house is full of bird diarrhea.
We're going to bed-
-And watching TV, baking a cake and taking a beer.
Oh, how cozy and quiet!
Sorry, Leif, but it was actually you who gave him the diarrhea.
Yes, we can clean up here anyway.
What have I said about walking around with the snuff stick and tearing down the furniture?
It is five o'clock, I have morning stands.
But empty that fucking mucus, and stop running around like a horny pig!
You are filled up like a testosterone bucket, it sprays smoke from the ears.
But I might want to wait until I get married.
Unlike others.
c. soundtuppen gal
-I shoot him.
I take the rifle.
-Calm now.
What do you think the neighbor says if he finds a lead ball in the rooster?
We can go there for bird knobs or rooster murder.
When they shoot wolves it becomes a damn life.
But Leif, it's not so damn easy to be smart when you can't sleep.
-I'm about to go crazy.
-Do and witness the traps at the swamp.
-Revältorna?
-Yes.
See if you find any fox.
-Why?
-Because I say it.
Trust me.
Okay.
A living fox.
Don't kill that bastard.
Satan ... Check out, Leif.
-Oh, damn.
-Take it calmly, he's aggressive.
Calm down, the fox.
You get food soon.
Oh, damn.
I can take him.
c. soundtuppen gal
You, now you shut up.
We're tired of your gaping.
- Are you ready?
-Drive!
-Okay, are you with?
One two Three!
We invite the police to our meetings, but they do not want to come.
But what the hell ...!
Foxy!
What in all the hell?
Hell!
-Hallå, Tony!
-What the hell do you want now?
We just wanted to say hello.
What do you have in the bag?
-A fox.
-What did you say?
A fox?
Just.
I found it in the chicken farm.
Tuppfan had killed it.
Had the rooster killed a fox?
Just.
If you walk on the hens, he gets crazy.
Oh, fuck.
There was probably no danger.
It had scabies, so it might be just as good.
Was it a scabbard that he killed, the rooster?
Just.
It sat in the groin, so it was just as good that it died.
- Ajök!
-Where is it special?
-We just wanted to say hello.
-Talk a little.
-Nice.
Do you want to get in for coffee?
What good, you are not welcome.
Hello!
-Damn!
-A scabbar was the icing on.
-Surely it is scabies?
-I can't determine it on a straight arm.
You may leave samples.
Follow here.
You get no help from today's healthcare.
Taxes should be paid, but damn they can help one.
-We don't pay that much tax?
-And then they don't have to do their job?
The health care should work well, regardless of who pays!
Shit the same.
What should we do?
I am scratching the scalp.
We have to clean up the kitchen.
Clear!
Good work.
-But we can't sleep in the kitchen?
-What then?
If we are going to get rid of the rice, we may well clean ourselves as well.
c. soundtuppen gal
The c. sound car gets Soppatorsk
-Gud damn!
-It probably won't work.
So attentive.
Don't you think I see that we have rashes all over the body?
-It's that fucking rooster's fault.
-I don't know if I can handle more.
Now the measure is raw, Billy.
-Want to drive hard towards hard, so ... -Are you safe?
I'm sure, I'm tired of that spring bag.
Komsi.
Komsi, the little monster up.
Come then, the little monster up.
Good.
c. soundtuppen gal
C. soundkalabalik
Billy!
Help, Billy!
Help!
C. sound shot
Billy to Leif.
-Leif here.
-I heard a shot.
Did you hear?
Yes, it's clear as hell, Billy.
-What was it for bangs?
-I shot the roof fan.
Did you shoot the rooster?
I go to Spain and have sold the hens.
The rooster cannot be sold.
I will enjoy three months in the sun, and avoid you.
It gets damn nice.
-What are you going to do with the yard, then?
-I'll rent it out.
How nice you are on your face.
Have you surveyed yourself?
Really good.
-I struggled with a menth dog ... -stir more, I would like to hear.
-You then rent out the yard?
-Yes.
Fy Satan!
-Do you have a berry?
-Absolutely.
-Oh, Fy Satan, what a nice silence!
-I thought I would be mental ill.
-Me too.
-Oh my God...
C. sound mobile signal
Yes, Leffe.
Hello.
It was from the health center in Sörbyn.
We have received your test results.
It was no vermin.
-What the hell was it, then?
-Stress rash.
Have you slept poorly?
-Yes, you can safely say that.
-I suggest...
It is no danger, the problem is solved.
But thanks anyway.
Well, the brother, now I'm going to enjoy a whole night's sleep.
-Do it.
-Good night to you.
Good night.
C. sound truck sounds and cockroaches
Did you hear?
Our new neighbors, Leif ...
God damn!
Texting: Ulrika Jansson Båving Swedish Media Text for SVT