Joseph, we must seek protection for the night.
Oh Maria, every inn in Bethlehem is full.
- The child is on the way.
What should I do?
- Stick and lie down in the stable.
- So it doesn't stand!
Read what stands!
- Read.
This is very exciting.
- Now comes the three smart guys.
-The three wise men.
- What do they play?
- Gymn teacher, the curator and the carpet.
You get great like Mary.
With your hair and smile you probably get the role.
Just not Jesus is afraid of the dental position.
You're just jealous.
I'm terrified!
She will be embarrassed.
- Sara, twenty are looking for the role.
- Just one from an actor family!
Look here.
It is your own meat and theater blood.
Your father with some of the country's foremost actors.
I was at the Dramaten!
- He sold sausages during the break.
- I was an actor!
- You jumped in like Jarl Kulle's horse.
- It went great.
- Set to the stage at the inn.
- No one saw.
- Jarl hill saw!
- He is a bit conventional.
He was not prepared for the horse to settle down and order beer.
-What have I said?
- "A good actor is the role."
We have the ability to shape the thoughts and dreams of people.
- I will play Maria, not you.
-Obvious...
I dreamed that you were on stage in front of a cheering audience.
I cried.
- Because you were not on stage?
- Because I was proud of Lina!
- Did you have a doll that could be Jesus?
- Yes, in the wind.
- GRODAN BALL?
- No one knows what the Jesus child looked like.
I don't think he was green.
Christmas is important!
We can show how much we love each other.
How much should I love you to get a snowboard?
- Did you know why we celebrate Christmas?
- GRODAN BALL was born.
- Come, dad, we're late.
- It's someone else who controls our lives!
Kalle Stropp?
- How do you think it goes for Lina?
- I worry about is Gustav.
- He has given Lina theater lessons.
- Imagine that he was an actor ...
He sold sausages and tore tickets.
He always tries to enlarge it.
I bought that blouse for Lina.
What does Max want?
A snowboard!
- What have we said about the listening?
- That you should not be discovered.
-There is a snowboard in the wind.
-I knew it!
I get one!
YES!
- Iidiot!
- Think about what you say.
He is ten years old.
You would have your own family that you could decorate and bake gingerbread with.
Yes, where are they somewhere?
At Christmas you should be with your loved ones.
Gustav eats Christmas lunch with the corporate ... - Hello, old man.
Did you get the role?
-What's that?
- You will see that - Jesus child!
- She got stuck in the frog threads.
- Jessica gets the role.
I know that.
-Why?
- She is dark and goes to our theater.
I talked to a man in the salon.
He thought you were great!
White beard, big nose?
Fill - Ragnar usually sits there and warm up.
- When she knows if she is taken out?
-Tomorrow.
The courier makes a report.
The new culture manager says that the children's theater must be revitalized.
-Have you talked to him?
- I bumped into him on the way out.
He seems nice.
Now I'm going down town a turn.
-Where are you going?
- You have some Christmas cases ...
- Can't I go with you then?
- You don't want to know what you get!
I get the same thing as last year.
Nothing.
- What should we give a line?
- She wants a horse ...
She can't spend her puberty with an Ardennes!
If she wants to do horse jumping, we must support her.
I always support the kids.
How many times have I pushed her there?
-Two.
- But my enthusiasm is boundless!
I encourage her theater interest.
She has nothing!
-Where's the newspaper?
- You are a postman!
The days when I'm free I want it to come punctual!
- The magazine has not arrived.
- It went to the forest.
Never give up.
Think of Björn Borg!
Pettersson is delays.
He is a shame for the post office!
- He got diploma for punctuality.
-He got what he deserved!
Who wants to eat a fool with old postal managers?
It is better than standing and screaming "Rights Knights should win".
I was a little jealous.
Extremely little.
I think you can expect better judgment from managers ...
- Here it says which ones are selected.
-How interesting...
- "Maria is played by Jessica Lindén."
- It gets better down.
"When the gates were closed, the director had not found Herod."
"Then the fire door was torn up and a man stormed in."
"In sounding Hebrew, Gustav Svensson delivered Herod's final replica" -
- "And became the play's last puzzle piece."
What phase is this?!
Have you planned it from the beginning?
What do you think about me?!
It was pure luck.
I stood drinking coffee.
It says you talked in Hebrew!
- I don't know where it came from.
- From these maybe.
To interpret Herod, Herod in Old Hebrew, the Herod of our time ...
White flag!
Capitulation!
I wanted to maximize the family's chances of getting back to the limelight!
100 percent greater chance of success.
What is it?
Are you crying?
Yes, because I don't have to join.
Are you ashamed to stand on stage with me?
It was very fun to hear.
When I was young, all amateur theaters wanted me!
- Did they buy someone who sold sausages?
- It's an Advent game for children.
Is it so terribly dangerous?
- Yes, dangerous.
- Thanks for encouragement.
I want to show the children what it was like when Jesus was born.
Ikhman Hanuva.
- "Let the kids come to me."
- Her god, poor child!
Respond!
Is there anyone who can answer?
Oh my God!
Svensson.
Sara, it loosens all the time.
You have to get over now.
Thanks.
Huh ...
Every newborn boy in the land of Israel must be ... killed.
With different tones: I am ... yes ... I ... yes ...
It's me, King Herod ...
- Can you interrogate me at the text?
-No I do not have the energy.
- I help you with the math homework.
- You can never anything ...
I try anyway!
Read.
Otherwise, I make sure you get to play the Jesus child.
- Take where Herod comes into the stable.
- He never entered the stable!
In my version everyone is in the stable.
Read now, Antichrist!
- What do you want here, noble king?
- Max, I haven't come in yet.
- Max ... - what do you want here, noble king?
Is there ... Is there any newborn boy child?
No, here is only me and my wife.
What kind of children's crime is my ear belonging to the crib there?
Big king, it's just my old donkey.
-I understand.
Farewell, carpenter.
- Is he going on that?
No.
But I'm king.
I can come back the next day.
- I should attach the beard.
- With staple gun?
-Can I go now?
- Yes, but remove the dishwasher.
- Do you think this will hold?
-Certainly.
Are you nervous?
- The wise men should stay away.
- Yes, the carpet was a boot.
- She stood in the way.
- Is it just two wise men now?
I may need some turning space.
Interrogate me on the text.
We start where Herod leaves the stable.
Fa...
Farewell, carpenter.
Don't forget that Herod is the King of the Jews.
More powerful than the sea, cruel than desert - the sun, wilder than Babylon's barbarian ...
Hello Darling.
Gustav is incredible.
- You should have become an actor.
She exaggerates.
I have some details to file on.
The photo dealer asked me to bring these.
What is it?
-Christmas card.
- Are our friends interested in this?
- It's Herod.
He belongs to Christmas.
- You are in loose beards and cardboard crown!
You have to have some imagination.
You never become a great actor.
It's a Christmas game for children!
Many large theater profiles started as a child actors.
- They were children when they started!
- I know well!
I'm not saying I'm going to become an actor -
- But if things go well, you must stand open.
- This has risen to your head.
-Not at all.
What is this, then?
We are well for the fuck a family!
- Is anyone seeing Dad?
- Bakom the curtain.
- Gustav, here we are!
-Silent!
Someone can believe we know him!
- It's hardly someone you recognize.
- It's mostly school children.
- In premiere there should be celebrities.
- It is - there are filled -ragnar.
I hope all is going well.
Gustav gets devastated if not everything is true.
- He has few replicas.
What can go wrong?
- Sure most of it ...
The courier's new cultural director was theater reviewer before -
- But he was too hard.
He called the death dance "an easy trifle".
- He talks to Jessica's dad.
- Brown in her.
She will get a horse in Christmas present ...
- Dad is the head of Ekberga Invest!
- Our father is the King of the Jews!
- Have Gustav participated in television programs?
- He was an audience in Café Norrköping.
Look!
I got my ad!
"Do you like Herod's beard? Get the same at Salong Virlvel."
Certainly many children who want full beard ...
I check for the emergency exits.
Why would it go to the forest just because Gustav never succeeded before?
-Quiet.
- You will be in disaster situations!
In Zion's land, a star shone over Bethlehem ...
Snark!
- then?
Arvidsjaur?
- It's too close!
After all, they went out.
It was not Gustav's fault that some la straw in the crib
- But Dad threw a torch into it.
- He dropped it.
-Why are you so happy?
- It's actually a shame about Jessica!
- She had prepared the role for weeks.
- But she was not prepared for Herod.
We can send flowers and invite them and talk about it in peace and quiet.
- Dad get to explain how it started!
- He got stuck with the sandal in the crib.
- Then he dropped the torch in the straw.
-Stop.
The children looked terrified.
Dad stood there and milled trying to extinguish the fire.
Imagine if they hadn't been out on time!
- Good morning ... or "yach mammenam".
- Don't you think it's enough now?!
Read.
Read, I say.
"The Herod's Herod is here."
"The Advent game becomes a big theater."
“Svensson's interpretation of Herod is uncompromising.
"Especially strong is he" -
- "When he sticks the crib on fire and calls for Satan."
There you see.
I made a success!
This reviewer is an idiot!
C.Teletext.kudskylk.kuddörrklockan
- It's to me.
- You stay here!
I showed the children genuine feelings, that there is a world of flesh and blood.
- They did not have a golden gold.
- They didn't let go of smoke damage!
Dad, there are some who want to talk to you.
Hello.
My name is Monika Rydell.
I am a school curator.
You have to accompany the low school.
It is complete chaos.
- No students dare to enter.
- The kids scream that Herod is there.
We have tried to calm them down all morning.
Follow and show that you are not herods and do not intend to kill them.
There will be no more performances.
- We're talking about it tonight.
Tonight, you should fire the hall.
It looks too damn good.
Come along.
- Father, the King of the Jews.
–Ach Laminan!
-What does it mean?
- "You can always sell sausages during the break."
Texting: SVT Sub -text (C) Swedish Television AB