-Yeah, then we were lice panka again.
-A-cash is coming soon.
You only celebrate years once a year.
-Should it be fun, then?
-What do you think?
-Have you bought something for me?
-Do not try.
-How many packages will I get?
-But dream, Leif Öhman.
I can get a clue, so I have something to hope for?
You have to wait like everyone else.
You get the packages tomorrow when you turn years.
-WAVA and wait.
I want now.
-It I shit well.
Satan!
I forgot to buy snuff.
Damn!
Emergency.
-What do you do with the savings money?
-Needless mode ... Must buy snuff.
Is the log you bought in Wednesday ending?
Yes maybe.
I get stressed for the birthday and sniff more.
I get to go down to the kiosk, Billy.
-NA, Leffe!
-Hey.
The situation?
Good!
Friday and everything.
Then you have to go home and snap a cold.
What do you want?
-Ad a lice.
-I am sad, it's over.
The whole shit is over, the whole Sörbyn.
The delivery did not come, so the closest place is Luleå.
-Do you have portion snus or anything, then?
-The joint, I have nothing.
-See ya.
Greeting Dad.
-I do it.
The snuff is over in the whole damn municipality.
We get to go to Luleå.
Luleå?
But what the hell, it's 40 miles!
We have no choice right now.
Abstinence begins to crawl on.
How the hell should we get down there without money and gasoline?
-Then maybe you can fix gasoline.
-How?
My God ... I am celebrating years tomorrow and you just ask stupid things.
Use the skull!
How the hell do we usually do?
-Yes Yes.
-Thanks!
Set up now, so we can go.
Fuck!
But what Satan in hell ...!
Damn!
Uh, damn!
-Hello!
Servant, Tony.
-What the hell do you want, Leif?
I ... thought to check if you happen to have a snuff.
No.
And I still hadn't invited.
Listen, Tony, I've been thinking about a lot of things.
Yes that...
What kind of parabol do you have?
How many channels do you have in the subscription?
Surely you are in control of?
You see the cord from my antenna to you.
You have turned the signal.
So you have thought of that?
Then we sorted it out.
-Where is there anything more?
-No, just that.
-nice ... -Ha a good life!
Fy Satan, it was close to the eye.
Now we go to Luleå!
-Abstinens!
The heart barely manages to beat.
-Breathe.
You will soon get your snuff.
So it is when you start with this kind of poison.
Like having a demon in the ass.
The c. sound engine chop
But what the hell?
What in he ...
-Come on now.
No no no!
Satan!
-Damn...
Surely it was gasoline you hose?
Blow on me!
-Gud damn!
You hose diesel!
-But chill down.
Well, chilla?
Then I can fold the seat at the bottom and lie down to die.
That we have a snuff lack can we shit in. Do you have a piña colada you can borrow?
God, how nice I have it now!
-Yes Yes.
Sorry, okay?
-Curse!
What are we going to do now?
They may have gasoline.
We can go and ask.
Wait here, you.
C. sound shot
-Stay!
-What the hell...?
But what the hell?
Jump in the car!
Jump in, fast!
-Hurry hurry!
-Stand, for hell!
Damn!
-What are you doing?!
-Cok if the boy hid snuff in the car!
-You can't steal a car!
-Check if he hid snuff!
My God, boy ... insanity it is.
Woooh!
So yes.
We have to put on a coal, so we can get to the kiosk.
-No ... open the door.
-I just closed.
Please, come on.
Open, please.
Oh thank you!
-Do you buy a lot?
-No, just a box of snuff.
Unfortunately, but it's over.
Are you kidding?
You are pulling my leg!
You drive with me, Karljävel!
You're lying!
The whole community is against me.
-Do you also hold on?
-Quiet...
-It's life and death!
-I can't do anything.
-Aaahh!
Stop it!
-Hearru, Leif, take it easy.
I sold the last box to him who goes there.
But what the hell ... Leif, it's neighboring!
-I can't cope ... -Yes, we drive after.
-I can go myself!
-Quiet.
No, stop it.
Have it.
Unwind.
He went to Sörbäcken.
Sure as hell it was the neighbor.
Cursed fancies.
I'll call him!
Of course he has blocked me.
Perfect...!
Fy damn, I don't recognize the body.
The organs are starting to beat.
Go now!
Stay!
-What the hell do you want?
Away!
-I have called the police.
-Check.
-Who fuck is that?
-No fuck I know.
-It's my epa.
-I have called the police.
-We shit in that.
-Shoo!
Away, boy!
-No has broken the engine.
I don't have time with this.
Hell.
Tony?
-Tone!
-Hell...!
Take it easy!
Calm down, breathe.
Sorry, I explain.
Do it!
I want to hear an explanation.
The snuff is over in the whole damn Norrbotten, and you bought the last box.
I am being rotten.
Snuff deficiency ...
-Can, put off!
Quiet!
-In fucking idiot.
I sneaked in, because I know where the key is.
You get SEK 200 for the snuff box.
-I can call the police.
-2,000 bucks.
You get 2,000 when I get the unemployment insurance fund.
I really need the snuff, Tony.
Do you know what we do?
Here's how we do.
-2,000 bucks and the team.
-Wo?
No...
-Yes.
-Okay.
-I will build a chicken farm there.
-No, that's ...
-Do you want your snuff box or not?
-Yes, yes.
Taken.
Wow, what a deal.
-Fy fuck, please.
-The team is mine.
-Yes.
-Okay?
As soon as you get it, you stick.
So.
Stick!
Stick, I said.
Thank you God!
No no!
Faaan!
No!
-What happened?
Didn't you get it?
-Nicotin -free snuff ...
I'm going to die.
Nicotine -free snuff!
It's over...
-It was he who took epan.
-Leif Öhman, come here!
Never.
No!
Let me go!
Write my will, Billy!
You get everything!
Write!
Wait!
You should not give gifts in advance, but this is an exception.
Actually, you are turning years tomorrow, but ... open.
You have to wait for that one.
God damn, Billy Öhman!
Texting: Ulrika Jansson Båving Swedish Media Text for SVT