In tonight's section of Ifs, quiz about all culture in Sweden:
Greek humor philosopher Thanos photographed.
Love soldier Dominika Peczynski.
Humor ping pong between Gbg and London: Evelyn Mok.
Music Aid Filip Dikmen.
The Notorious B.I.G ... o.
The emerald from Babylon - Elaf Ali.
The only fun teacher - Tomas Kaminski.
Gothenburg's best Somalis - Assia Dahir.
And last, but also absolutely at the longest in the studio - Ahmed Berhan.
You look at the program which is messier than a Polish parliament.
Quiz about all culture in Sweden.
Here are our fantastic competitors.
Next to me we have the poding midwife Manda.
Next to it we have the ticticing snuff enthusiast Zoofie.
And last: a blast from the past!
The champion's champion is back.
The power pack from Gottsunda - Patrick!
This program goes like this: The contestants choose one in the panel -
- As I ask another question.
Then they list if the panelist is lying.
Sorry, are you called Amanda or Manda?
Is it a "cool" abbreviation?
Hems her Scanian: No, no "cool" abbreviation.
Now she drives!
I apologize, Manda.
Which of our panelists do you start talking to?
- Filip.
- Hello, Manda!
In Indonesia, there may be a ban on newlyweds.
Which?
You must not go to the toilet in three days after the marriage.
It's an old tradition.
If you can do it, the marriage will be happy.
I don't know if they get unhappy by pooping on ...
It sounds completely unlikely that you would ... like gas ... no.
You don't think it's true?
You think Filip is lying to you.
You don't know how expensive wedding food is.
It's about keeping it in the stomach.
Because that's true!
Unfortunately, there will be no points.
What Filip said is true.
The bridal couple should keep from going to the toilet for three days.
Among today's Indoneser, however, few do this - lactose and whatnot -
- But many people are joking about it.
- Zoofie.
-Hello.
- What do you want to talk to?
- Koverski.
- I feel it is my brother.
- We have two strange names.
Zoofie ...
- Do you really sofie?
- No, Zoofie.
It is just spelled skewed.
- Why do you spell it in "Blattiska"?
- I am so called.
-Where are you from?
-Zoo...
Kaminski, my Polish brother - Oliver Ingrosso from Wish.
You know that!
I might inherit a little.
Hope!
Welcome to IFS, Brother.
It's your debut, and your first question is:
It is to wash Swedish floors.
Nämen, the tradition ... it's during Easter, zoofie -
-And it's called Smigus-Dyngus.
Strange, but then we pronounce it.
You throw water at each other.
Today everyone throws at each other -
-But in the 16th century only threw boys at women-
- To show interest: "I like you."
- They couldn't make them wet otherwise.
-Just.
"Are you wet for me now?"
We may not start the Wet T-shirt concept- but you are welcome.
- Zoofie?
- Well, please!
This sounds so unreasonable that it can be true.
I want to believe that you speak the truth.
-Do it.
- I say it's true.
You believe in the Polish tradition Smigus-Dyngus?
Smigus-Dyngus!
Absolutely right, Ahmed.
Do you know what, zoofie?
Congratulations to your first point.
Bravo, Zoofie!
It's true.
Poland's contribution to world culture-Smigus-Dyngus-
- Is an Easter tradition where Poles throw water at each other.
- Patrick, Patrick, Patrick.
- Patrick!
- You know how this goes, so ... —Minika.
-Good evening!
-Hello.
Dominika, who is known as the king of Rinkeby?
It is an old man who has lived there about since it was built.
He likes to go to a hamburger restaurant and has received a penny.
You might not say the brand.
He appeals to himself in Vi-form as plural's majestatis.
He smokes two cig too, one in each hand.
He has written on petitions -
- To rename Rinkeby Square to King's square.
But it has not been so yet, unfortunately.
He is very popular locally.
He thinks he is "Royal" for real, though he is not.
- I think it's false.
-Why?
You can't see Shonon walking around with a crown from a hamburger restaurant?
-I do not think so.
- You think she is lying to you.
Patrick, you continue the victory train.
Congratulations to your first point.
It's false.
Real estate mogul Mikael Andersson -
–A which owned a lot of properties in mainly Rinkeby and Husby -
- Went under the name King of Rinkeby.
- Manda, who do you put your cards on?
–Alaf.
Elaf, we watch a video question.
Type African Braveheart.
First and foremost - African Braveheart is Black Panthers.
Just ... what was it we looked at?
Well, what we saw is Afghanistan's national sport -
— Which is called buzkashi and is based on two teams meeting each other -
- Because riding horses and trying to score goals.
But instead of scoring a goal with a ball or a puck-
- They use a dead goat.
- Najs!
- A dead goat?
- It's Afghanistan.
-Right.
Premise!
Yes, it could in itself match.
- What do you say, Manda?
-No that is not true.
Not?
You are in control of Afghan national sports?
That goat bit you into the ass.
It's true!
No!
Afghanistan's national sport was banned by the Taliban in the 90s-
- Because it was considered immoral.
Who knew they were animal friends?!
Then when Americans came: "This is fat fun."
So from 2001 it has been legal in Afghanistan again.
- Good that it is not a living goat.
- Zoofie, who do you choose to talk to?
- I think I can trust Assia.
--Assia.
In the middle stands environmental engineer Mohamed Hussein Roble.
Why is he known?
It's Dree Low after he put off with the music.
No I'm joking.
Zooo-Fie!
Zoofie, this is actually the man -
-As was Greta Thunberg's NO teacher at the Global High School in Stockholm.
It was he who gave her the idea to strike on Fridays for the environment.
-White People turns everything from black!
-Do you understand?!
Under Black History Month!
In the movie about Greta's life, Roble will be played by Robert Gustafsson.
You could speak the truth, but you could also lie.
- I'm black?!
-Yes.
No!
A Freudian "slip"!
Wow!
No, it wasn't so I thought, I promise.
No, I think you are lying.
I think it's false.
- You choose to think it's false?
-Yes.
You know what?
Congratulations!
You just got one more point.
Mohamed is definitely not Greta's NO teacher-
- Soma was Somalia's prime minister between 2020 and 2022. Congratulations!
Patrick ...
- What do you choose?
- I take the Greek up there.
Thanos ... What kind of coffee does Syrians offer during a memorial?
Okay, see now ...
Baklava, a little cream cake, chocolate cake ...
Then it goes over to a little meze: hummus, lahm bi ajin, queue -
- Grilled chicken, lamb, french fries and a cappuccino.
No, but they have a thing for bran.
They offer bran during the memorial for those who have passed away.
No, I think it's false.
Semlor is a Svennegrej.
If he only knew who runs all the pastry shops ...
False?
You do that right in. It's not true.
Why make it even more depressing by bidding on bran ...
... when you can bid on pastries?
It is a snack Syrian offers.
- They die for a fucking pastry.
- It's better than Semla anyway.
- You have problems with the almond paste?
- I don't like the proportions.
Why has the worst gut and so small head?
Understanding!
It's haesh ...
He identifies himself with it: "This is my people!"
- Congratulations to your point, Patrick.
-Thanks.
Manda, you stare at the panel and know for sure who you want to talk to.
- You must not choose.
Do you know why?
-No.
You have received a letter - a letter from Botkyrka.
Here is one of Botkyrka's most popular sandwiches, with two ingredients:
Cheese and this Turkish sausage.
Is it true that the sausage is called suck cock?
–As he "angry" or "suck"?
- Sucking.
- Well, why not?!
- More strange things have happened there?
- It must have done.
-You are absolutely right.
It is called suck cock.
It is a Turkish sausage called Sucuk.
But in Botkyrka, in the people's mouth - no pun intended -
- It is called for suck cock.
Exactly!
What is it...?
You rarely see a woman making this reaction to suck cock: "Yes!"
- Zoofie, should we move on to you?
-Yes.
Evelyn.
You want Evelyn.
–Evelyn.
-Hello!
- You may have heard a Chinese ... - Yes, I've heard many Chinese.
- Then you have heard them say "nei ga".
- mm.
Say it, Evelyn!
I ask you, say that!
I am waiting...
-What does it mean?
- Who was in Paris?
Say!
It is not pronounced that way.
It is pronounced "Nage".
Here you get an "N-Word Pass".
Say it once!
I'm kidding, give it!
It's a Chinese word, and a nasty word -
- But it's not as you think it was.
It is ... nei ga is like ... it means kind of horny, you can say -
–Fast ten times worse.
So it's kind of like this ...
If you say it means that kind of that ... yours ...
-To the point!
-She doesn't want to happen to say the n-word.
- I focus!
-She just: "It's called ne-ne ..."
Danish pastry!
If you get called it then it means -
- That your mother's mother's mother's mother was a horn.
You got out of her ...
Everyone who has come out of there, all generations, is whores.
Do you believe in Evelyn?
Being a generational Horozpu çocugu?
- It's probably false.
- You think that?
That it does not mean at all Evelyn just has Claimat.
You just got 1 point.
It is not at all a swearing.
It is a fill word: "the", "where" or "it".
That's why you use it in Chinese rap: "Neigga, please!"
- Patrick, your third question.
- Big O.
Big o ...
Paolo Roberto and Niklas Wahlgren.
- You said yeah, huh?
-Rapper!
No, but it was Sebbe Staxx and Leo "Chinese" from the cartel.
It was about knuckling, giggled and nagging ...
It became Mizeria - they ended up sliding.
It was a special number-
- Made together with BRIS, which was called Anchor from the resort.
- Patrick?
- I think it's false.
- False?
Patrick, Patrick, Patrick ... - I'm wrong?
Absolutely not!
You never stop taking points.
Congratulations to one more!
The two rappers on the Kalle Duck cover-
- no less than the Stockholm legends Ison & amp;
Fille.
As you can see, it was called Ison & amp;
Fille in Ankeborg.
Awesome work, zoofie and Patrick.
- Manda, thank you for joining.
It was great fun to have you here.
- Now it's time for the duel.
The duel goes like this: I'm a single ruler -
- So can no longer choose a panelist, but I choose two for you.
One tells the truth and the other lying -
- And you should decide who it is that tells the truth.
Jalla, then we drive!
Zoofie, you start.
You get a prime duo to work with.
No less than Thanos and Assia!
From Botkyrka to Gbg, Thanos and Assia.
What does "Yep" mean?
Yep means, among other things, having intercourse.
To have sex.
FUCK.
Oh, someone went clear sfi!
Don't listen to Infinity Gauntlet.
What it really means is that ...
It's a verb.
It comes from Turkish Yapçemi ...
... and that means help in all its bends.
For example: "Damn, I have to yeah dad in the garage because he needs help."
Or: "Please, can you yeah me?"
Why are you laughing?
Never have yeah any?!
- Zoofie.
- I know that Thanos speaks the truth.
I've heard it more times than I wanted -
- For the preschool class for grade two.
–And they talk about it?!
-Yes.
"Zoofie, if you fuck my grades I will yeah you."
You choose to believe in thanos-
- And of course you are doing just right in. Congratulations, Zoofie!
Yep has a double meaning depending on tone:
"Should we yeah?"
Or: "I will yeah you, do you understand?!"
Everything is in the emphasis.
Patrick, are you ready to yeah a point?
- Yeah!
–Yes?
Patrick, the two competitors you should talk to are Big O and Elaf.
When to use this hand gesture?
This hand gesture is used ...
In Sweden you do not talk so much to the hands -
- But we from warmer latitudes do.
This is kind of so: "huh?!"
It is when you do not take anything, or so: "Really?!"
Kind of like that.
Brother, when you do so, it means: "How much is the time?"
But when you do, it's hot, brother.
Incitement against sofa group.
- horse against sofa group.
- "Horse against sofa group" - I said it.
Then brother, you are going to the cent and meet a mush.
Brother, the time!
You stand 200 meters, I just: "Brrr!"
It's the time, brother.
Time is Money, brother.
So this is "what is the time"?
As for a round circle?
- Not 360 ... 90.
-Not like that?
- type "it's half six"?
- But ... - Are you done?
Thank you so much for your monologues and your answers.
-What are you saying?
- I am completely confused.
Big O says, "How much is it?"
Elaf says it is when you are confused: "huh?!"
- Are you on Big O or Elaf?
–Alaf.
- You believe in Elaf?
- We drive on Elaf.
You got 1 point, yes!
You use it when someone does something scary or you get confused.
Cruelly!
Congratulations to your score.
- Zoofie ...
You will now get a whole Polish buffet, for your two competitors -
- Is Dominika and Kaminski.
Mizeria comes from the Polish -
-And is used as a hose for "misery".
But what does it really mean?
This is how you describe Anders and Dominika's marriage.
Mizeria is also in Poland ...
- She didn't even deny it.
- She just kept going!
Mizeria is Mizeria.
But in this case it is about -
- A cucumber that is so beaten when it ends up in a cucumber salad ...
From the beginning it was a stubborn western cucumber, hard and fresh.
Then you plan it so incredibly thin -
- That it becomes like a leached old scrub.
A complete misery condition.
Good salad, despite the name.
Mizeria!
- Two poles and who is lying ...?
- It is carved as stuck.
Exactly.
But believe in me now.
Mizeria is a Polish birthday tradition.
The birthday child sits in the middle, then everyone dances around in arm hook.
Finally, you fall into the birthday child.
It should symbolize the misery around you, but the family always takes care of you.
- Type A Polish Böghög?
-Exactly!
Do you think it's a cucumber salad or a Polish birthday tradition?
Please, I don't want to answer this.
You said I would trust you.
But it sounds unreasonable -
- And Dominika nodded when Kaminski answered, so he probably speaks the truth.
- So Dominika revealed themselves?
- Yes, you nodded when he talked.
- I nodded because he is lying.
- I have chosen him.
Great, don't listen to the pole, listen to the pole!
Great.
Zoofie, you trusted Kaminski.
But Dominika gave you the truth.
Mizeria is a Polish cucumber salad.
Patrick, right now it stands 1-1.
If you take this question home, you win.
Otherwise, it will be a matter of rash.
You will of course receive the last duo: Filip and Evelyn.
BAM-BAM-BAAAM!
So ... xin!
Fight!
Filip and Evelyn.
Salty bae in all glory-
- But Turks also salt in something called Isik.
What do you salt?
Turks salt, among other things.
children in the hope that when these children grow up -
- They do not smell of bad sweat smell.
What are you going to say?
What do you know about Turks, the man?
- I've been to Alanya.
-Oh!
- The whitest Evelyn has said!
- "I've been to Skärholmen."
Nämen, okay ... The thing is like this: In Turkey, dogs ...
In Turkey and some Muslim countries, dogs are considered to be a dirty animal.
Unlike in China, where it is a good animal.
I knew it!
Rappappa!
As in Asian countries, one salt their dogs -
- But then you do it in Turkey because the dog is a dirty animal.
So you usually have a small vessel with salt at the door -
- So that the dog is allowed to put the paws in the salt vessel to be purified.
That is a fucking Chinese beauty cure.
Listen!
But yours, then!
Salt babies.
We eat dogs, not babies.
The salt is placed on the child so that they can smell less sweat and older.
Then you slide them in the oven!
The best part is that you both behave like you have a normal answer.
Like one of you is more logical than the other.
- Patrick, good luck!
The dogs probably don't even come in.
So I believe in Filip.
- You don't think the dogs come in?
- You don't think they come into the house?
- They are dirty and do not come in.
- Not alive anyway!
You believe in Filip: Turks salt babies - not dogs - not
- In hope that they will not smell sweat.
Yes, the man!
Congratulations, you got one more point.
Isik is an old Turkish tradition where the baby was used.
It was hoped it would stop smelling sweat, and be long and be lucky.
The tradition is not so common today.
With the correct answer, Patrick has won again.
Congratulations!
A big applause for our winner!
Patrick, arrived here.
Arrived, arrived, arrived.
Of course, you should get your prize.
Your own Kalle Duck/Ison & amp;
Fille-poster.
Give a big applause to our winner - Patrick!
To our fantastic panel, the awesome competitors - all of you have seen tonight.
See you in the final.
- See you next week!
Feel the best.
- Thanks for looking.
-Thanks.
Texting: Mia Magnusson Sveriges Television AB 2024