Don't forget to water upstairs.
No ... now I have to go.
I don't want to miss the plane.
- Do you have everything?
–Sí, Senora.
- They don't speak Spanish in Greece.
- The language of love is the same.
Imagine getting to experience something!
You can do this here too.
Fresh potatoes are now available at Konsum.
- What a wonderful you will get it!
-But I miss Max's TV performance.
It's not a Nobel Prize, Sara.
We are in the 5th!
- Everyone we know will look.
- The grandmother wants to go down and cheer.
- She just wants to be on TV.
Good luck.
Don't let them push you too hard.
- Oh now, otherwise I'm not watering.
--Ciao!
I also want to go to Greece.
You don't have to be nervous.
It will go so well.
Now say honestly what you think.
The signature melody fades out.
Then we run: Hello Max, you know most even though you are little
Crack the others, they are plague push them down into the shit
Those children who have not started crying then dare not answer a single question.
Just!
- Now you are on your way to the future, Max.
My dreams were crushed, but no one should sniff you in your place in the sun.
- What have you been sniffed at?
- District 1.
Downstairs all the way and mailboxes in south position.
But my son will win in the 5th!
- Created as Lindberg's boy.
- I can't hear more about Svante.
He had pondus already then.
He is now 25 years old and adviser to the government.
We in the 5th sell the bait from the wheat!
Max, sit!
Why should I read so much?
You don't even get the price.
For your and our government's future.
-A book.
- Oh, what a surprise ...
There has been a lot of reading.
But you should read this for your own sake.
To widen your views.
We in the 5th are just the beginning.
- It is Jeopardy, the red thread ... - it may be a later question.
- Set up now.
- I come up and say good night.
Gustav, we may not give him more books.
This was a philosophy book that would give new perspectives on things.
We may place too great demands on him.
- When would Lina come from the disco?
- You would pick her up now at 11 o'clock.
- Can't you remind me?
- If you have a daughter?
Why should she run out?
What is wrong with TV?
Boys.
She is 14 years old, this is now the start.
- You remember what you did then?
-Hell!
My poor girl, Dad is coming!
- Tell Mom what you have done!
-Nothing!
- See it!
Still, the truth comes out.
-I have danced.
-Tell everything!
- With a guy.
- What would have happened if I arrived later?
- She had danced another dance ...
- I know what those dances are aiming for!
–What then, Gustav?
Tell!
- Not now ... —Sex?
Next time you will pick me up.
Dad is too sensitive.
- Who whistles in her like that?
- The biology teacher, maybe.
That goat!
They actually have sex education.
Empty.
Max has it.
What's with you?
If not I look at our children, who should do it?
-Alf Svensson?
- We must not stifle the children.
- Max has not played anything a week.
- I don't think you understand.
- Max should be on television.
-It's exciting.
But he must feel that it is a game!
It all knows that when you compete you should have fun.
You said that before the crash as well.
My brother has a mark in the forehead yet.
- He stood in the way.
- He was in the kitchen!
It was slippery in the grass - I was slanted.
He won ... that fourth.
Be careful with max.
He is sensitive.
- Max is good, a genius.
- What goes into his head stops.
Yes, you ... he has after me!
But Max knows how to produce it.
Soon everything will be in live broadcast.
Sweden will be aware of what a wonderful son we have been nurtured.
It will probably be good.
Sleep now.
c.Teletext.kjudskylk.kudvi in 5's signature melody
Sleep now!
- By the roof ... the dynamite man?
No, the deck cord: Mr. X would go to the cinema.
- But he had lost the key ... - I can't hear.
I am worried.
It is the fourth bank that is blown up this month.
Imagine if he rob us.
- He makes a mistake and gets stuck.
-Good morning.
Did you sleep well?
-No.
–The poor conscience gives poor sleep ...
I don't have a bad conscience.
I am ashamed.
For you.
You stood and flashed with the high beam for Jeanette and Erik.
They had orgies!
The girl stack is no more than 14 years.
They are siblings.
Erik gave her a hug.
Shit the same!
I care about my daughter!
Where is Max?
In bed.
He has been reading all night.
He does not give up until he knows everything.
He has to sleep!
Einstein slept three hours a day.
And invented the atomic bomb ...
Good morning, o wandering reference book!
- What are you thinking about?
- Death and our meaningless existence.
- I should not join us in the 5th.
- Humor gives distance to the tasks!
I'm not going to join us in the 5th.
Thanks.
The book gave me so much.
-No!
- What is that book?
Well, the one?
A philosophy book.
What is it called?
Read on the cover, it usually stands there!
Yes ... "Weight Fom Vivfaff".
-What did you say?
- "Mevöven as a driving force".
Shall we go?
"With death as a driving force" ...
The bookstore said it had got many thinkers on the right track ...
"Big thinkers?"
Max is ten years!
It was anything but tables and years.
Now you really got him on the right track!
You know how he becomes.
When he read about toads, he demanded that we move down to the cart.
I'll get him on his feet.
Soon we will have our sunbeam back, trust me.
O beautiful virgin, I'll save you.
O Dyre Prince, watch out for the dragon!
Servant everyone!
Max, what the hell is it with you?
Max, say something!
Now you have been like this for two days.
Think, spotlight, TV cameras ... all girls watching.
Stop.
I'm not going to go to Vi in the 5th.
Those who write such books know nothing about life.
Most are even
kill!
So it goes when you think too much!
- Take with your brother on something fun.
-What then?
Funeral?
Burials are a mockery against those who have not been resting.
-What are you talking about?
- About death, the only promise of life.
Little old man, listen to me ...
You probably have seventy years left to live.
- That's why I'm sorry.
- Why are you sorry for that?
It's like not eating a cake because you are afraid it will end.
- or not be part of Vi in the 5th.
- He should not be there!
- Have you called the class director?
-It's occupied.
Not for two days!
I'll call.
Max is in progress!
Before, he could barely sit still!
Such outbreaks take on the forces ... but soon he will be up and running again.
I gotta go!
-Where are you going?
- Out and lift with foreign men.
She is going to Jeanette.
What does the teacher have for telephone numbers?
It's the last chance!
Come on!
Say something to mom ...
18 26 40.
Hello, that's Max's mom.
I don't think Max can join us in the 5th.
He is scratchy.
Well, you've been thinking about it before?
Roger Olsson stands up?
We keep our fingers crossed!
It's not possible.
May I have the handset!
Yes.
Bye.
- Max, it solves!
Roger Olsson cannot handle the press.
After all, that poor man is a nerve wreck.
It was he who fainted in the Lucia train when he was going to read the Christmas gospel.
- I take a walk.
- It's getting dark.
Darkness is my home.
Take a walk.
I fix chocolate ... and sandwiches.
-It's my fault.
-Mine too.
- Max has to catch himself.
- I just wanted to pepper him!
I saw Svante Lindberg step out of his BMW and hug his parents ...
It is useful to think the opposite to their parents.
As I did when I married you.
Like when I told my mother that I refused to have baskets!
- Then we had been married for three years.
-But anyway...
-Where is he?!
- No classmates know.
- I go and look.
- There they come!
- No ... - Here you are always equally welcome.
Did you see Max?
He has been away for three hours.
He has disappeared!
Maybe it was Max I saw.
- I may have seen wrong.
-Tell!
There was someone on the bridge screaming about death and we in the 5th.
- He is depressed!
- He just makes himself.
- You never worry about it.
- Yes, but I just get shit for that!
I go and look!
c. soundsirenes
Little old man!
Come, they will take him!
Svante Lindberg ... it is he who robbed all banks.
- He is an adviser to the government!
-Not any more...
It is even for the last question.
C.Teletext.kudskylk.kudhejaramsa
What is the president of Finland?
- Sausages or cheese on the sandwiches?
-Both.
- Ahtisaari.
- Has Roger fainted yet?
-Soon.
Roger, you have to hurry to answer.
- It's just a matter of seconds.
- Why do they force him to compete?
- The match is over.
- There he fainted!
Roger ... what about you?
Do you hear me?
They didn't have a chance without you, Max.
We send flowers or chocolate to Roger!
Do not do it.
He is allergic to both.
-Hello!
-Hello Sara!
Here you travel away to experience something, and what happens?
Abroad has no more to offer than the motherland!
- Have you read?
- A hundred times.
"The perpetrator was traced to his parents' home."
"After Max Svensson showed the way to the hiding place, the man could be arrested."
- He tried to hide in our hut.
- It's a picture here!
Yes, you ... that's my son, it!
HA!
Svante Lindberg ...
He said he was a explorer and had lived on the South Pole for three years.
No, he was an adviser to the government.
Gustav, did you see with his own eyes when he won in the 5th?
No, but I trust the guy ...
That lies!
Stand here and lie to buy Christmas magazines!
- I will return every one!
- But Gustav, it's thirteen years ago!
- How did you go for you in the 5th?
- My son has more important things for himself!
- How time is the first interview?
-The clock seven comes local TV.
- We must be rested in the pictures.
- It's max to be photographed.
Video -angle lens ... Even if you hide, you come along!
My son and I wish you a good night.
- Don't Max be in Vi in the 5th?
- It can be so hysterical with that.
We want to keep Max on earth.
- Do you have no pictures from Greece?
-Certainly...
- This is the first day.
- What a hairy they are!
I was in their volleyball team!
Adonis is so good looking.
And the bearded ...
- Do you have no pictures in the hotel?
- Yes, here is the hotel.
- was then?
- That little whites behind Teodor.
He was absolutely incredible.
What a man!
He showed me the island in two days.
Do you know where we slept?
On a lava beach.
It was hard, and we wore no clothes.
Lina, get up now.
I'll be coming soon.
- More!
Texting: SVT Sub -text (C) Swedish Television AB