C.Teletext.kjekylk. soundbilly whines
Billy, what is it?
Are you sorry for Elin to move?
Huh?
Hörtu, Gubb ... Billy.
I'll go and talk to her, so maybe she stops.
Don't worry, Billy.
I go and talk to her.
- Hi, Leif!
-Hello.
How is it?
You look a bit sad.
Yes, but what the hell.
Do you have to move?
Billy is shit.
I have no job here, and can't say no to the service in Stockholm.
What the hell, you can work with us.
–And do what then?
- You can change roof tiles on the house.
–And what would the salary be?
-We can divide the A-box into three, maybe.
- You realize that it is not possible?
- Yes, but tell us if we can do something.
C.Teletext.urfjarran Russian spy with connections to the Russian intelligence service -
C.Teletext.urfjarran - is free in the county.
C.Teletext.urfjarranhan is suspected to have stolen documents relating to the security of the kingdom.
C.Teletext.urfjarransäpo now goes out with a search for the man, who is in his 30s-
C.Teletext.urfjarran - Has green eyes, light brown hair and is about 185 cm long.
C.Tetetext.urfjarransäpo urges everyone to be attentive -
C.Teletext.urfjarran - and tip the police if you see something suspicious.
Now it is important to be on guard.
But as I said, tell us if you need help with something and we will solve it.
You look nice.
But my brother is on his way here to help me.
–What any ... - thank you.
Greeting Billy.
I will.
Bye.
Do you workout?
You are quite breathless.
- You have to see one thing.
-Not now.
Leif, silent.
Stop.
You have to follow down in the basement and see one thing.
Follow.
Just come along!
-What's with you?
-Go!
-What the hell?
-It is the Russian spy.
I heard about it on the radio, and then it knocked on the door.
I recognized him right away.
He asked if he could come in and borrow the phone.
-And then?
He is completely knocked out.
- I ran and picked up the bridge.
I slammed at him at the Atlas so that he went on the slopes.
-Satan!
Well done, Billy.
-Thanks.
- ELIN will see us as heroes.
- I also thought about it.
- But what are we doing now?
Calling the police?
- No, fuck!
Are you mad?
- They said on the radio ... - reality is something completely different.
This is corruption at the highest level.
It's Spetsnaz, Säpo, Cia, FBI, Obama, Bush, Putin ...
The whole league is after us.
If we go to the police, we will be the target.
It is only a matter of time before we have laser pointer in every window.
Now we take him to Säpo.
That's the only thing we can do.
- How to do it?
- We check that he is not bugging.
Then we build a provisional prison camp and begin the hearings.
We have to be damn low now.
Now we run a classic tactic: "Good cop, Bad Cop."
- What am I, then?
- "Good", of course.
- Imagine if I want to be "bad cop", then?
- The brain!
You don't have that pondus.
I'm "bad cop", and you're "good".
Are you in?
Then I throw water.
Yes ... Hello, Mr. Spy.
My name is "Biley", and this is my brother ...
Quiet, Billy ... Bond.
Mr Bond, be quiet.
- You should not say our names.
-Sorry.
So you want to play cool and tough?
You want to play tough with us, two agents from Sweden?
Yeah, Little Russian Fucker.
Have you see Pure Evil Before?
Just look into these eyes.
Karate King 600, SUCK MY ASS!
Suck my fucking ass, you fucking little boy.
You think you can come here and fuck with us?
You Russian Ass!
Shit.
Take it easy, agent Öhman.
In Almost Broke The Whole Prison.
Damn, nothing seems to bite him.
We may try to come up with something new.
- What should we do, Leif?
- We are allowed to run water harvester.
- Isn't it a little hard?
- Kingdom security is at stake.
We drive hard towards hard.
Now it must be so.
What do you say now, Russian Spy-Man?
Exactly.
Maybe you don't feel anything now -
- Bet in one hour or two, or three, it's going to Hurt Real Bad.
Yeah, Insane.
Crazy in the brain.
It's Water Torture.
"Boom" on your forehead.
So it's better for you to tell us where the chair documents are.
Do like this if you are going to tell us.
Damn, it doesn't work.
Should I tickle him?
Are you nuts?
You can't go into the cage with him!
I don't know if the torture works.
We have to come up with something new.
Stay.
Damn, he's stiff.
What should we do?
We can bring him to Stockholm, to Säpo.
No middlemen.
I go and drill an air hole in the luggage lid.
You may keep guard.
We have to bring him there.
Good.
-Leif!
-Hi Elin.
What have you done?
I clean the luggage lid.
We will transport a thing.
- You look totally sick!
- Yeah ... oh, damn.
I've got some little psoriasis ... it dries together when it's cold.
-What are you doing then?
- I wait for my brother.
He would have been here four hours ago.
- For four hours ago?
- He would help me with the move.
His phone is off.
I'm starting to get worried.
You haven't seen or heard anything?
No.
What does he look like, then?
We are quite different.
He is tall and has brown hair.
Is he clever and a little well -trained at the same time?
Yes ... yes, he is enough.
Blue jacket - could he have it?
- He could definitely have that.
-Okay.
No, I haven't seen anything.
I must go.
It starts to burn, so I have to change protective capsule.
I was going to ask ... can you help me a little?
There is quite a lot to wear.
Not now, as I said.
I have to in and lubricate ... the whole body.
But you, what is the brother's name?
I might bump into him on the road.
–Emil Grönstedt.
- Yes, we must be heard later.
- Now it burns on.
- Health Billy.
He has not seen anything either.
What do you say now, you russian bitch?
-Quiet.
–Look Who's Here.
- My Brother's Going to Fuck You Up ... - Billy!
Stop it.
- I ran at Elin out here.
- You told the spy?
Do you remember that her brother would come and help her with the move?
He has not appeared yet, and it is four hours since he would have arrived.
Yes, what?
Have you murdered Elin's brother, your bastard?!
Are you nuts?
Think about it now.
That is Elin's brother.
Is Elin's brother a spy?
That is Elin's brother, and the spy is on the loose.
Think about it.
-Oh no.
Damn, hell.
What should we do?
-Yes that...
Hello - Hello.
Or hello.
There has been a little misunderstanding, you might say.
If I move off the tape then maybe I can ask some control questions?
Fy fuck ...
- Is it you who is Emil Grönstedt?
-Yes.
What are you doing?!
–And you are Elin's brother?
-Yes.
Why have you tied me up in a chicken farm?
We thought you were a Russian spy.
- Do I see as a Russian spy?
-No I do not know.
You have to be shy.
- Go and heat some food.
- I remove the cage.
- You should get something good in the stomach.
- Conduct ... - take the stuff now!
Yes, Emil, we understand that you are angry and disappointed with us.
I have some patch on the wounds here ...
Should we really give him everything?
Yes, we have to give him something.
It's good if we take care of it nicely.
Three thousand kronor.
You can eat up the food in peace and quiet -
- So we go to Elin and talk about everything that has happened.
- Does it feel okay?
- It's far from okay, but ...
Go and do it now.
Thanks so much, Emil.
Sorry again.
I take care of the talk, and we will see how it goes.
Hello!
Fine visit.
Yes ... Can we get in and talk about a thing?
Absolutely.
Come in.
Was it something special?
Yes, at that Russian story and your brother who have not arrived.
What a fucking clue he is.
- Emil, come!
His car paved five miles away, his phone is stone dead ...
Hello!
Emil.
Leif and Billy.
C.Teletext.urfjarranskanden after the Russian spy continues.
C.Teletext.urfjarrannu Säpo goes out with a picture of the suspected man.
C.Teletext.urfjarran Large sum is promised to the one whose tips lead to an arrest:
C.Teletext.Surfjarrannaremare has set SEK 1.2 million.
Damn how sick it runs around a spy ...
Nice guys.
God damn!
SWEDISH SUPPORT: SVT Subtitle (C) Swedish Television AB 2017