So who the hell are they?
for real
Its no one
But oh!
Who decides?
Huh?
You realize you have to listen to me!?!
Okay?!
You understand that?!
!
Right?
So do you get it?!
Please stop
You should listen to me that do you realize huh?!?
I will fuck you kill you
You will die
Ouch
So for real
I haven't done anything I promise
It was he who looked at me
Yes but it doesn't matter
Vaa !!!
Do you get it??
Do you understand it or ??
You should listen to me do you understand ??
HA!
Who the hell do you think you are ??
I have not done anything!!
You know I haven't done anything!
So I get so damn angry at you you get it or!?!
Give you !!
No
So on real
Ouch
I decide on you!
You're just shit!
You're not worth anything!
You hope I understand huh ??
Please put off
You are not a world anything huh !!
Ouch
So fit you as hell !!
You should be suitable as hell
You know i haven't done anything
For the hell
You are !!
Seriously
Stop
But Aje
You are nothing !!
Do you get it!
You are worthless!
Help
Who do you think will help you?
Do you think someone cares about pathetic little you or?
Watch yourself
Thank you for reacting.
You are the only one who has reacted today.
This is a social experiment !!
Thanks!!
Thanks so much !!