These are actually my home neighborhoods.
I lived for many years just above Karlberg Castle.
So I've been very much here-
- Run Karlberg and the castle park, the lawn here by the water.
So I really feel at home here.
I was 24 years old.
We were based in the Sinai desert in Egypt, and suddenly Israel invades southern Lebanon.
The UN quickly decides in the Security Council to form a new UN force: Unifil.
We are regrouped into southern Lebanon.
In Lebanon it was a war -like situation where there was a fight in several different places -
- And where we also were exposed to direct or indirect shooting.
So it was a completely different situation with many uncertain elements.
Already in the first week there was a shock message.
We were then told that a patrol -
- As was out driving with a terrain car had gone on a mine.
The boss in that patrol, fan junker Karl-Oskar Johansson-
- Howed dead by a minsp.
It was a very heavy message, and I will never forget the collection -
- We had at the company headquarters where we received an account for what had happened.
There were those who signed a contract to go to Sinai and do that assignment -
- As did not want to remain.
There were such.
But in the end, everyone stopped but a few.
There were a few who moved back to Sinai.
Most others, most of the strength, which was over 240 men -
—The elected to stay in Lebanon and complete the assignment -
- which was to prepare for other nations that took over.
We do not see any rescue workers, there is no clearing ...
... is also a show of the very latest in Russian military technology ...
... the militia Maap's closest roadblock ...
... this tape -moving artillery piece ...
... there a child was killed and another seven people were injured.
After Lebanon, I decided.
One of the reasons was precisely that I met many foreign correspondents -
- As I got to guide through my position,
I thought this was a great way to continue traveling.
Because it was very loss of travel that drove me -
- Both regarding international military service and also journalism.
Physically speaking, I have been badly out twice.
One time was in present Congo-
- Where we ended up in crossfire and were shot.
My photographer got a ball that went straight through the leg.
We managed to put a bandage on the injury -
- And, thanks to us being educated, get him to care.
The second occasion was in Bosnia -
- Where we drove a car from Pale, the Bosnian Services headquarters, down towards Sarajevo.
When we round a mountain bump, there are three masked men -
- With dark clothes and masks and aims at my face and tries to stop us.
But we had already discussed conceivable scenarios and agreed -
- If we would drive and then you push into the car from behind.
The rear window disappears, it turns some bullets into the plate -
- And I feel I have been met.
But it is a superficial injury.
It goes outside the ribs, and eventually gets stuck in the arm.
When traveling in this type of area -
- Conflict or disaster areas, so I think it's partly the same type-
–As people who are drawn to these areas because they want to make an effort -
- And they want to be where they really affect.
It can be journalists, aid workers or doctors -
–And even soldiers who go out to make a mission-
- Therefore, you think you can do useful.
"Today during the morning Karlsson and I go into a burial ground and look."
"All graves are shredded or broken."
"The graves are plundered."
"Many chests are opened and the corpses are completely visible."
"We photograph and leave."
It has certainly shaped me a lot as a human being, the experiences -
- And you learn a lot about yourself when you end up in stressful situations.
Then you are put to the test and learn a lot about yourself.
So it was definitely an effect of that service.
I remember a scene already from Arlanda when we landed and sat in a bus -
- I think it was against Strängnäs, P10, and would disrupt.
Then comes a white truck and everyone says -
-"Yeah, a UN car", "There comes the supplian", someone shouts and jokes.
Then we dismiss - and then it was over.
After all, there was no readiness at that time to take care of people -
- Which has been involved in traumatic experiences, but we just went home.
I felt a little lost from the beginning.
After having come home from an extremely dramatic period -
- Getting home to Sweden where it didn't happen that much.
It was a restructuring period.
Before Christmas I went, for the first time ever -
- For I had time left and bonus points to do away with, and looked where I could get?
I looked where I could come?
Yes, Beirut.
So I flew to Beirut and was there for a week as a tourist -
- For the first time, and it was pretty cool because I like Lebanon.
It is an incredibly complicated -
- And right now quite tragic country because there is so much that goes the wrong path.
But I like the people there, they live as well as for the day.
They may have to do it.
My name is Stefan Borg.
I am a foreign veteran.