Can you get better at using
Photos and videos when you learn Swedish
I will tip that a little about in this video
Hello and welcome to Swedish with Kalle
I text the movie so turn on the subtitle
If you have not done so
and I think
that one can use pictures
and photos and video on very many
different ways to learn a language
and i think more and more about it because
I myself am trying to teach through instagram
and such movies but
Even more on Instagram where one can use
Video and movies in different ways
so my question is simply
How do you use pictures and photos and videos today
and how can you try to do in new ways
so
A simple suggestion is that
you just shoot things you look around you
and turns up in the lexicon or asking someone
what these things are called or
You can ask a little more open
What can you tell about this picture?
If you want you can also get some app
that allows you to write in the pictures
So then you can take a photo and then write a word or sentence
in the picture, so that
you remember that afterwards
you could also use
video camera to, when you learn a new word,
How to film yourself and say the word
And then you can watch the movie again
And then you hear the word and remember it.
or you might be able to ask the person who teaches you the word
If that person can say the word
or pronounce the word
But a good way may be to first learn a word
or a sentence with good pronunciation
and then record yourself when you say this sentence
and so try to listen to it sometime later
I think there are a lot of things you can do
you may have some time over
Take a picture from a newspaper
Print a picture from the Internet
Look a little at the picture and write a little on it
It can be simple words like the "sea" and "heaven"
or “the clouds” and “the sun
or it might be a situation where something happens
Just think a little, how can I tell you about this picture
What words do I need, what is called
that when a person does this
and if you are good at drawing or painting yourself
so use it to train the language
Paint a beautiful landscape
and at the same time think about what the different things are called
Write a text next to or write on the picture
Sign up small series
where something happens
You can also share with friends who train Swedish
So you can use this
In order to develop the language together
Because I think it will be both more fun
But you also help the brain
to process the language in unkind ways
Share photos with each other
record small movies of something happening
Talk to the movie or write to the movie
Send the movie to your buddy
and write a little what's going on in the movie
there are certainly many ways that I have not even thought of
But as I said, I think pictures
can make it more fun
and that it can help you remember better
so think about any way or some ways
that might suit you to
It will be more fun and you should learn
a little more and a little faster
Yes, I am happy to receive tips and comments
and thoughts and questions about this so
Do not hesitate, write a comment
and send to me and then I answer it when I have time
Thank you for listening, Hello Hello