Good morning everyone in the group.
Hope you have a good Sunday.
I hope I will have time to continue recording these ...
Small films
and I have thought about that
the question that almost all the time comes in the group
of new members are
How can I speak Swedish?
How can I get better at speaking Swedish?
How can I practice it?
And many want Swedish friends or they want someone to talk to
But it might be difficult to meet someone.
So this is an important issue and it is a difficult question
Many who seem to think about this.
So I would like to discuss this in the group.
That we can help each other with different ideas.
about how to practice talking more and exercising in different ways
And I believe a word that is important here
It is to be creative
creative
It means to think in different ways
Think about new ways.
Use their imagination.
Find different solutions to problems.
And I sometimes think when we practice language that ...
That we just do the same thing.
We get stuck in some ...
Some patterns.
We exercise the same way all the time.
And this thing about talking is something that many people think is hard.
So then maybe it will be to get stuck
In some things
You may not exercise at all because you are shy or nervous.
Or you exercise the same way with the same people.
because one does not get new ideas
I would like to try to give you some tips
and I want you to give tips to each other in
In the comments and in the group.
So that we can get better at practicing talking.
Next movie I will try to talk more about this.
Right now you can only, if you have any comments ...
or thoughts, or want to write something about this so ...
So do it in the comment to this group
To this movie, to this post
so
so we'll see what we come up with
What ideas we get
Okay, have a great Sunday and then we will hear again soon.