Hello
In this movie I will
Talk about building calls
a thought I have, a suggestion or
An idea I would like to discuss
so this movie gets a little more philosophical
If you want to listen to it
So turn on the subtitles on your mobile or your computer
so that you can listen and read at the same time
Because then it becomes easier to understand
so build calls, hm
We often talk about that
Build sentences
So when you put together several words into a sentence
Then you build a sentence
We can talk about building texts when we put together
several sentences to pieces and several pieces to
a text, we can talk about
To build up our vocabulary
and we can talk, maybe, about building words when we write letters
I don't know, we use building as a
metaphor for many different things
We can build up our confidence
and we can build up a community
so we build many different things and
I think quite often
calls that I have with
one person or more persons
over time, ie a conversation, a discussion
a thought exchange, an exchange of meaning
over time
not just once but several times
I think about it as building up a
Call
and I think this might be a thought
which can also become a tool for you to be
more creative with your own
Language training
for you may have
Places online, you have people
around you at your school, at your job
at your language café
The librarian you meet every week
There may be different people or places
maybe a Facebook group or this one
Youtube channel if you usually comment here
where you, so to speak, have the opportunity to little
step by step but still strategically
build one
Call
and it's all about
along with another person or several people
I can say with another human being because
make it a little easier, that together with another
human being building up common references
build
things you both understand
things you've been talking about
and as you return *to *
to, you will return to so that
You understand a little what I mean by some things
I understand how you think, it can be about
things where we know we agree
It may be about things where we know we don't
agree
It may be about me
know your interests
and you know my interests so that
we can in that way can
navigate in a discussion and use it
knowledge we have about each other
In order to make the call more
interesting and deepen the call
and put in new
ideas and new thoughts that we know will
bear fruit, as we know
will give results, which will lead on
that will make us get
new interesting things to talk about
so that
with some persons not happening this
for various reasons
You may, like, discuss a little on the surface
you cold talk, you switch some words
about weather and wind, and the family and what you did yesterday
and what to do on holiday
But it will not be going on
But with other people it becomes natural
so
that the conversation is deepened
so that you get to know more about the other person and so on
But I think this is something you can do
actively
When you notice that another person
have something in common with you or you
becomes curious about another person
so
Begin as well as note
What does this person like to talk about
what is he or she interested in
where could we build a contact and make
A contact stronger
ehm
I feel that this happens quite often
in different ways with people around me
It may be that I notice that a colleague
enjoy talking about books, yes then it becomes like a thing
We will return to, I try to remember
What the colleague said last, what books
We have talked about, what associations
We have done around this
It can be music of course because I
always so interested in music but it may
deal with language with another person maybe
that there is someone that I come back
to talk about language and how to learn language
I hear my colleagues talk about
Football, that's their way of making contact
but that in some way
Using this metaphor
to try to add something
do something more vibrant or more
complex or more developed
or more in -depth
In order to receive the call
more interesting
and then one must
use their curiosity and both in some way
show what one yourself likes
and what one thinks and thinks
you have to give it out but you have to be receptive too
You have to listen
on what the other gives for signals
what he or she tells about or shows
and so on
and
this with getting opportunities
Talking a language is also
a creative action and it's not easy at the beginning
You know that I know it's not easy
but
Still you always have the opportunity to
try as well
give something into a relationship
into a contact, show something
tell me something, dare to be personal
with the linguistic and
communicative tools you have
and in that way
So to say, develop and fortify
a contact
and
There is something there
There is a possibility, there is a scope for action
where you can create it yourself
by going a little beyond
the most superficial, the most common
the most predictable and obvious
When you comment on this movie
When you make a post in a Facebook group
When you tell you something in class
When you sit in the pocket
at your job or your school
so think about how you could give
something more personal, something more
not so expected and predictable
Without something that can
awaken new thoughts, new ideas
In a conversation with another person
I think there is a lot
exciting to explore here, very interesting
to think about and I think a lot
That's probably what I hope for with my videos
and my blog posts and my instagram posts
really I want to
try to build different calls
build a discussion with those who follow me
oh
around language, around culture
around life
Uhm
just
it really is
As is the very goal of communication
is to build understanding and contact
It's a kind of play or
a kind of game with those
Social and communicative
skills and tools we have somehow
To create more
interesting calls and more
more interesting relationships in that way
So think a little about this
How can you get a little more creative
in your communicating, in your
Construction of calls
Also when training Swedish
But of course even in your native language you can think about this
and please comment on this
This was really an invitation to a call
so that
You are welcome to build on my thoughts
or say against or whatever you want to do
that said, please comment, or ask if it was something that was difficult
but
I think it's a nice metaphor
to build calls
Talk to you soon
have it so good so long, hello hello