Hello Hello
I got a question about
I could make a movie about how to write
a review
and i'm pretty sure of
that there are movies from
For example, SFI teachers and
Swedish as a second language teacher who is about how to write
a review
So I want to try to answer the question
In a slightly different way maybe
Because I think it's always an important issue to ask
Why do we write reviews
What is the meaning of a review
Who reads it and why does someone read
a review
Then I think a little about myself that
I am reading reviews sometimes, not a huge
in newspapers and online and so
And then I read reviews
because I want to discover new writers
or i want to find new books
or i might want to know
How a new book is, if I have read
books by a writer and so have that writer
released a new book, published a new book
Then I want to know if that book is good
what it is about, about it is the same
as previous books or about
The author has written in a new way and such
So you might say that is the summary of that is the summary
of why do you write reviews, JO
because a reader
Reads the reviews because that person
Am curious
the author who has written the book or the book itself
or both
And you also read reviews
some in any case, because it is a kind
Talks about books going on
in newspapers and on
Internet, on different websites
So that writers write books
Critics and reviewers
Reads and reacts and discusses
The books and
We who are ordinary readers, we read the books we read
the reviews and this helps us to
think and understand and discuss
the books, it gives us, so to speak, a
bigger and more profound
understanding of what we read
It's like the point I think, as I said
In other contexts: to write
is to talk, write is communication
With readers
and reviews are a way to
yes
discuss
Books, discuss
literature by writing about it, both to
other writers and perhaps the author himself
Reads reviews and the gears read the review
and that makes
We get a richer understanding
a richer picture of
the books we read and the authors we read
So this I think you should have
in the head, one should think about this
When writing a review, of course, you can get a list
on what should be with, there is certainly
that you should bring a little about the action
Tell us a little about the writer, say what you think
absolutely, but why should you bring it
Well because the one who reads your review
is curious about the writer and or
The book and also
Maybe the person is interested in reading this book
self and then want to know if it is a good book
and if the book fits him or her
so it is clear that one needs to know
a little about the action in the book in order to be able to
decide if it is a book
as I want to read and then you can't tell a little
because then it becomes uninteresting, that only
Write: The book is about love
It is far too general;
It gives me
no picture of what the book is all about and to say
The book is about a couple that first becomes happy
And you think it will be great
for them but then they become unhappy and at the end so
they kill each other
Then you tell you too much, that is, you can't tell
anything about what is happening in the book or exactly what is happening
Without you have to tell you a little
you have to give a tastes, a feeling
Small clues
You need to suggest
what the book is all about in an approximately
So that I can think: Yes, this sounds interesting, this is a
story I am interested in
This is a topic or theme that interests me
So one can generally talk about theme
and give examples of about what the action is
and also tell me a little about what style
the book is written in, is like
is it simple language, is the difficult language
is it very poetic, is it
just telling, it can make
I get more curious or less curious
On a book, I might be craving a challenge
and want to read something difficult or I might just
want something easy and entertaining to read
So it's interesting to pick up, the style of the book
And the language
and even the genre, if you can
tell about which genre book belongs to
is it a realistic novel
is that a historical story, is that
a romantic story, is that a horror story
Is it about the future, science fiction
and so on, it also helps the reader to
Some readers may be like this: I think
best about imagination / fantasy
books, so I want to read about that
but realistic books I am not so interested in
so tell us something about which genre it is
then happy to say something about the writer
Either you present the writer a little
Then you think the reader is not aware
The author since before
But is it a famous writer then maybe it's better to
say a little about how this one
the book, the new book is relate to
Books and styles
As this writer has written before
and then you have to
have some control over that writer but that
may be of interest to the reader that now has
the writer it and it suddenly wrote
A science pocket book
He or she has never done that before.
It does
he or she good or it makes them bad
so
maybe not good / bad but how
works this new style, this new genre
for the author who has written in a different way than before.
It's interesting.
For a curious reader to read about
And then you usually say that
A review should contain a review
You should say what you think about the book
and of course it is interesting
sometimes
but it depends a little on
It is interesting if you can explain why
you think the book is good or bad
And it might be more interesting to try
So to say explain to the reader that if you are interested
of this and this you will
Enough like it, if you appreciate
such books this is a book for you
It's not that interesting what you really think
The interesting thing is what readers
may like the book or what
The reader may feel if he or she reads the book
There is an exception, if you are one
Famous reviewer who writes many reviews
and many read your reviews
Then the reader may have a
relationship with that particular reviewer
so that
For example, I.
is interested in what exactly the
The reviewer likes
a book or something
so then it is a little more interesting that what
that person thinks, but if you are so to speak
Don't write reviews often
So I don't know anything about your taste
and what you appreciate and do not appreciate
And then it is not very interesting what exactly you think about the book
I want to have a chance to guess more
What I will like the book
But it can still be involved and
We practice writing reviews
Personal reviews
Of course, some
of what a review
may contain
And then you can, too, if you have
More space, want to write a longer review
so you can also turn into it
as more becomes real
Genuine criticism
And then I do not mean criticism that criticizes
Without criticism like putting the book in relationship
To other books and other authors
to describe
and examine and analyze how the book
relate
to politics and society
and religion and psychology thus
put the text and writer
and the book in relation to
other things in history and society
And then the purpose is to
give the reader a deeper
Function of the book
I can sometimes do so that if I read
A book that I find interesting, but I may not
understands everything or i want to deepen my understanding
of the book
Then I look at reviews after I
have read the book because they might be able to
give me
Insights about
what the writer has thought or
In which context, in which context like this
the text
have come to how it is to be understood
So it can also be interesting
Then you need more space
one needs to be able to write more
Should you write a fairly short review then you just have
little space for such in -depth
comments or analysis-
parts, analyze the text
so that
The reader can get help to, yes, get a
deeper understanding of the text simply
But it's really the most fun
to get to that step, to really
Start thinking about yourself, what is this text about
what does it stand in relationship
to for others
texts and things outside the text
So please test it a little
If your teacher says that;
Write as much as you want
Try to write a little more
in -depth about what this book is about
But the most important thing is, as I said, what I said at the beginning
Try to give the reader of your review
a sense of what the text is about
of which style and genre this is
what kind of writer
and something to help the reader understand
Does this book fit me or don't fit me
Then I think you will get a
will write a good review
Yes, these were my tips;
not so much
grammar or sentences or phrases now
Without more
How to think
When writing a text and in this case a review
So I hope this gave you some thoughts
or any ideas and
The discussion can, as always, continue in the comments
Down there
Write someone about what you think about reviews
Do you read reviews yourself, do you usually write reviews
What do you think about it
go for it
The comment field is yours
And then you will have a good time, so we will see you again soon
bye