Hello and good morning everyone.
It's Sunday.
and that means that soon it is work week again and time to
tackle
Swedish studies
And in this video I want to test one thing
It is a simple challenge to you who are watching
If you want to be with me on a thing
and it is a challenge a small
a small
No, not a test is not.
How to explain challenge?
I do not know.
No, not a test is not.
How to explain challenge?
I do not know.
It's called "Challenge" in English.
And many
Many Swedish use the word "challenge" even when they speak Swedish
But the Swedish word is challenge anyway
and my little challenge (coming) there are two steps
sometime today
Take ten minutes
and sit down
and plan your studies
Monday to Friday
so think through the week
and plan some things to do
To train Swedish.
It depends on how much time you have to exercise ...
You might just ...
It can be as simple as deciding that you should read
read for 30 minutes each day
or maybe work out a bit with your favorite app
or you can plan to go to a language café
Or maybe you have a small study schedule for each day
or so maybe you have a small study schedule for each day with different things
It depends on how you exercise and how much time you have
but
try making some form of plan
maybe set some goals too
I will learn 20 new words
or
I will learn 10 phrases that I can use in a clothing store
It depends after all what level you are at
and what goals you have with learning Swedish
Some form of plan, planning, set up some goals
It's step 1
And then step 2, if you wish, you will be very happy to share
your plan or your goals
or just a small part of it
In a comment on this video.
It would be fun to see
what you have for study goals for the week to come
And then on Friday we can look
about how it has gone
If you have reached your goal or if you have followed your planning
So, I'll do the same for my Somali, I'll be sitting a bit today someday
and think about, how I should be able to train a little
for my part I have trained a lot with apps
So I try
train some more by reading and writing
on paper instead
so there will be something with it
But I haven't been able to think
or i haven't been able to plan it yet
So I get to see myself, but as I said
Do a little planning, perhaps put up some special target
and if you want
Write a little comment and tell us what you intend to do
To train Swedish this week to come
Okay this was all for this time, see you again soon
And have a nice Sunday and ...
A good start to the week to come
Have a nice day!
Bye.