Welcome to the Gothenburg City Library.
Mirjam is my name and work as a program librarian
and we have for some time made a series of reading armchairs
that is actually an old program series from the 90s
There the actors at the City Theater of Gothenburg
come in after the Saturday rehearsals and
told stories or read poems on different themes.
We invited Gothenburg's freelance actors for this
And we have been running for three semesters now.
And today we have Timo Nieminen and
Annika Nordin here and the theme are prospects.
Yes right now we have to keep away from each other.
For it is hard to hug you have to keep more than one
arm's length.
It is said that every time we hug someone hot
So our lives are extended by a whole day.
At least it says Paulo Coelho.
So we would not be able to write a book about all types
of hugs that exist for it would never end.
There are as many types of hugs as there are
people,
situations,
Relationships.
So here's a reading chair
full of poetic, lyrical, crazy,
Romantic hugs.
But
at a safe distance,
like this.
Prospects yes ..
In the synonym dictionary we find words like:
panoramic,
hope,
hopes,
Views.
And from views
the associations can easily go to windows.
Windows, it is a strong theme of many artists through the ages.
Charles Baudelaire highlighted in one of his prosepoem:
There is nothing deeper,
Secret
richer, richer,
dumb and more dazzling
than a window illuminated by a light flame.
What to look like in the sun is always less interesting
than the one that adds
Behind a window pane.
In this black hole
living life
Dreaming
Suffering.
From Baudelaire to Saarikoski, Pentti Saarikoski.
One dark gray morning I go to buy wine.
The only one in the small bus and in the big one, out of three.
Until a day when the little one is no longer needed
It replaces the big one and we, we have become a winery
And the great bus drivers drive the small and the small bus drivers chop our firewood.
Desolate to be the only bus's only
and embarrassing that in the big product one of three looking down at the knee
A dark gray morning in February.
New thoughts are not needed for a long time
On the high bridge I doubt its strength
The fairway is dredged for larger boats
null
The smoke of factories over the city is the city of spirit
that speaks without opening the mouth
for in its mouth
there are bad teeth
bad
teeth
Supermarket is low house planned after human dimensions
Also the short hand must be able to reach
In the bank, the bank director, today in the shirt sleeves
Everything killed in a moment
I take my pirkka from his desk edge and sticks
Here, here I want to leave my name
But it is not possible, you forgot this,
The name must be worn on the pocket every minute
null
And behind the boiler
And one looks at me as a human being
that is looking for excesses
In the market I buy coffee and butter
on the system wine
In the cafe I sit and look at the high villas opposite
where there lives people who are happy,
in its way
Other people who turned the wind so that the spirit of the city
not breathe against them
Sunny mornings and
the sailboat's mood in the strait
null
a sober grogg with summer evening on the other side
promises made them
null
New thoughts are not needed for a long time
I sit quietly
with the coffee and butter and wine in the box on the journey home
in the big bus, one of the three
null
and in the small, the only one
Then the driver runs
alone.
From the balcony
is quite clearly visible a overgrown pond
The flute has toasted
The turkey is dead
Ringing laundry house has rotted in the valley
null
The carps are aged there
The former connection with the sea has ceased
null
The sign is read
Everything is forbidden
The pond is turned off
Shameful water lilies do their best
submit
melancholy
And dream
in defense
Harry Martinson
Suddenly the whole pamped lay for my soul
with raising horizons, roaming horns
horses, sheep and fleeing ostriches and gazelles
And butterflies
In millions.
Gauchon rolling his horse over winding rivers
damp flowering virgin soil
brown moors along glittering ocean
Vidalita
null
Taube
Took us out into the world many times.
Out in the world there was also a poet called Emelie Dickinson
in the 1800s
lived and worked in the United States but was first discovered during the 20th century
She paid tribute to everyday life
And the art
Everyday life wakes and surrounds us
is a drama that lives
Other tragedy goes down when performed
this one
is played best when the audience has gone home
and the lodges have been closed
Hamlet
Was Hamlet to himself if Shakespeare never wrote
If Romeo never for his Julia suffered
null
would the play ever have a playground
In the theater no one closed
Human heart
And as a tribute to
Books and literature she writes
No ship can, like the book, bring far out from land
and no runner like the poem run freely without tape
It is the mediumless trip to Cape Farewell
So simple
is the vessel that carries a person's soul