Very funny that you are so many who come here and hope too -
That you are many who sit and listen to this online.
The title of our lecture, proximity to nature - has a way to better health?
with question marks.
It might also have the sub -heading, we are on the right track.
Not least with the image you can see here.
My name is Åsa Engström and I am, as I said, professor of nursing,
Also subject representatives there.
Also a nurse and worked primarily in intensive care
And courses linked to it.
And this with the importance of nature is something that is warm to me.
And maybe a little contrast to the high -tech.
Päivi and I work together on many issues linked to this.
You may introduce yourself.
Päivi Juuso is my name, assistant professor at the department of
Nursing and medical technology.
And just as Åsa says,
Colleague and we have worked and work in many different projects together.
I am a district nurse, primarily worked in sparsely populated areas.
So this with nature is very close really, my everyday life -
And my everyday life.
It will be great fun -
To give this lecture for you.
And also welcomes all of you -
on site and all of you on the web.
null
[Åsa:] Then we drive.
[Päivi:] Then we drive.
In the advertisement that was on the net and in the newspaper and such.
We asked these questions.
These are really the ones we will discuss during the lecture.
We will also make attempts to answer them.
First, we have, much indicates that animals and nature have a positive -
impact on human health.
But is that right?
And does it matter what kind of nature we stay in?
Increases well -being when we are in a forest or near water, -
Or does it work just as well if we are in a park?
And this with the importance of climate for health then?
Finally, this is done with having care, care and rehabilitation outdoors.
Is it really possible to implement?
That is what we will discuss the next moment.
[Päivi:] Yes, exactly.
Then we get into this with, the animals really have -
a positive impact on human health.
How did you understand it, Åsa?
[Åsa:] Yes, we are pretty much agreed that the animals have a very -
Positive impact on our health.
It can create one, what should we say, health and well -being -
So everyday.
To have a spinning cat -
Or a dog near him, maybe we stress down, that we relax.
There are also very good effects when it comes to clean, -
What should we say, in terms of treatment.
This with that, -
a dog or cat or a pet.
Can be both comfort when we are -
lonely and sad.
A company.
It trains us to have social interactions with others.
And in many ways there are both evidence and example -
On the fact that, this is useful for our health.
There are also a lot of theories around the importance of animals.
Many of them just show that we can get a sense of context -
when we have animals.
Also a meaningfulness.
It becomes a different meaning to go out and go, when we have a dog -
that we should go out and join.
Than just go out and go and so on.
So there are really good effects of this.
Horse therapy is something we will show examples of, and so on.
You also know that there is something called effect models.
So precisely that oxytocin, the hormone that makes us feel good, -
increases with animals.
So in many ways, touch, closeness and a company.
In addition, we know that you have animals, especially for example, -
dog or horse.
We move much more.
It is also a health effect.
[Päivi:] mm, exactly.
And even if we did not, you mentioned a little with animals in healthcare, for example.
So there is also the kind of interaction between animals and human, - -
right?
[Åsa:] Absolutely.
That's how it is.
Which is of great importance.
We will also mention this with, for example, -
The importance of being able to be on a farm, among animals.
And what it can add.
So as I said, answer yes.
[Päivi:] Exactly.
Exactly.
[Åsa:] But if we continue.
We also had this with -
Nature as such.
If it has any positive impact -
on human health.
[Åsa:] Is there any evidence for it?
[Päivi:] Yes, exactly.
Yes.
This is really a very interesting question.
For it comes -
Most often natural, for many of us, the nature has behind the corner.
Or at least in this part of the country.
Then it is that, when we talk about nature, we can mean them -
Natural environments.
Thus, environments that are untouched by man.
Which becomes more like a wilderness.
But we can also mean natural environments, -
which are constructed.
Like parks, for example.
And that is in close connection, for example to cities, if we say -
Like here.
And yes absolutely, on Åsa's question we could say that, -
It has been found that nature has a bearing on health.
But what significance it has, actually has to do with it.
How it is provided.
What does nature look like, what is it for nature, -
We will get more into it.
And how far from us is.
So what accessibility do we have to nature.
Historically, for example, we know that even Hippocrates -
Built hospitals on open spaces and by lakes.
Just to have access to nature.
And man as a patient -
could roam in nature and thus also find a balance.
In them here, then you talked a lot about these fluids in the body.
So you find a balance between what is sick and what is not sick.
So you find health there.
So there are a lot of people -
Such descriptions.
Also our guru, Florence Nightingale.
Have also lifted it historically when you look at it.
That there was a value of being in nature and having access to nature, -
With fresh air and so on.
When looking at pure evidence, -
Then you see that, what you can say is that the light is important.
The light and also, what to say, the distance.
So, for example, you train your eye very early to look at longer distances as well.
Unlike how we do maybe today.
And sound of course.
And how the sound affects us.
There you can also imagine that there is a difference between if there is noise -
Or if we can hear birdwatchers.
Of course, access to nature also promotes the conditions -
for the physical activity.
Then we have to remember, we don't always talk about physical activity -
Like you have to jog or do something more heavy.
But on the other hand, you come out and walk.
And staying in nature, in one way or another.
Staying in nature can also increase the interaction.
I think we will come a little about this with interactions with people.
But of course also animals, which Åsa was in.
But the interaction with people is increasing and has increased, in connection with -
Among other things, the pandemic that has been now.
Outdoors we have that opportunity.
All in all, it can also be said that, this relaxing environment.
If we find it relaxing, our mental health really improves.
And the proximity to these particular environments, promotes health -
and well -being in humans.
But then I think like this, it has any significance what type -
by nature we stay in?
[Päivi:] Yes, exactly.
That has actually been studied.
As you can see here, three different pictures.
If you are used to being in the forest and nature, you may not think so much -
That there is such a big difference in these pictures.
But on the other hand, it has been found that, just if you look at -
first picture.
It is not so recovery or soothing, -
The environment when it is dense forest, for example.
Without man striving to have, -
For example, as in the third picture, the open surface.
It could be, -
In addition to there is a path, also an opportunity for an open area -
Or a lake.
This has been possible to demonstrate this in research.
That it is recovery.
But we must not detract from - anyway -
This with the importance of the parks.
So when you in urban planning, -
for example.
Looking at, how to promote activity among one's population.
So it is reasonable to have this in mind, - -
That how the environment should have our cities around our cities.
Then maybe these parks - maybe these parks -
May be a little closer.
So we also have access to them.
Because it is precisely the open spaces that can be health promotion.
There is also always a distinction between that, how close and how much -
Noise is around.
But that there is still an asset -
At least to them here.
Where we really also talk about the opportunity to recover -
By, you usually talk about getting a feeling of -
a context.
But also an opportunity to hear others, -
But still not have to interact.
Depending on how we feel.
So there is this one, you usually talk about, almost like you can pull away.
But still is not completely alone.
This is based on the theories that exist around this meaning -
of nature and the impact of nature on our health.
Do you have something where you want to add?
[Åsa:] No, I think it's -
Good things you raised.
And the latest you mentioned, -
There are Kaplan's theory among other things and there are more who have written.
I thought, you mentioned it with the importance of light.
There you have also seen a lot of the importance of vitamin D, which we know is -
Useful in many ways.
[Päivi:] Yes, exactly.
[Åsa:] and may have become even more relevant.
That one has -
Noticed it more recently.
[Päivi:] Yes.
And it is interesting to think, because Åsa addresses this with Kaplan's theory.
They by chance came into this with that, in the 70s and 80s -
It was enough, in the United States.
Were allowed to join when people were taken out -
in the wilderness.
Where through their observations discovered that, it is not all nature -
And all the environment that is, if says, restorative you talk about, -
But recovery.
Without it also had a meaning -
If we could turn off stimuli from the surroundings.
And there in the wilderness can feel that you relax.
And allow to be fascinated by the environment that is around us.
Here you have to remember that it is not always that simple.
For example, if we come alone into a forest, it is not so safe -
That we are fascinated by it.
So in this context you have also had guides.
So it's not people who have been completely alone.
Which is also part of, the ability to recover.
That you feel safe, in the environment where you are.
Just.
And then we come back a little to them here,
What are the mechanisms behind the impact of this nature.
Here we have written well -being, but health and well -being.
Then we can back back and look a little, the natural environment and its condition.
So size of it, where it is, what it looks like.
It affects what nature contact we have.
Of course, it has significance, -
How far do I have to go to get into this nature.
This, in turn, affects how much time we stay in nature.
So we have a proximity to nature, we stay more there.
We also have the opportunity to carry out these activities, -
As we said before.
Physical activity, interaction with each other -
and so on.
In this picture you also see that you raise this with environmental exposure -
for example.
Obviously, we get fresh air, which Åsa was in before.
We get vitamin D from being out.
But we also get in this context -
Maybe take part in environmental pollution, pollen and so on.
So nothing is that, now we go out and then we get healthy.
Without there are also pros and cons with these parts.
That you think about it.
However, we know it has -
A stress -reducing effect.
For example, if we stay in nature.
Then it is so that it needs to be a certain time.
There you can add that now during the pandemic, it has turned out -
That we have been more outdoors, the Swedish population.
But also many other countries, where we have gone outdoors.
We have been aware that it promotes physical activity.
And been to it with social contacts.
But also another thing.
It turns out that nature contact also increases our immune system.
So there are many positive aspects in this, except for vitamin D.
And it has to do with our nervous system.
We have this stress cover with cortisol and so on.
Or is it that we can dampen it.
By staying in nature, in fact also so long -
That we really take a deep breath and breathe in.
And then sounds ours ... it gets like unconscious actions really.
It is not something we can always influence, we can learn to handle it.
And feel, we take a deep breath and land in the stay where we are.
This is what you mean here, that these mechanisms lead to -
health and well-being.
Here we have just illustrated how you can ...
[Åsa:] I was thinking of tab in, I think it's the Juuso family -
Which is out on the kick here.
[Päivi:] Yes, exactly.
[Åsa:] Something I thought we could bring about this too, -
when we talk about the impact of nature.
It is the specific we have here.
In the somewhat Arctic, in ours -
northern parts and perhaps at all in Sweden as a country, -
As such, also what it looks like.
But perhaps not least -
We up here.
Where we have good conditions and you talk -
Much about the green, clean and stuff.
But we usually in our contexts -
Talk about the white.
So we have something very unique, with the snow -
And the mountain world and that.
[Päivi:] Absolutely, exactly.
[Åsa:] At the same time some challenges with slip, darkness, cold.
Which also affects opportunities to stay, for good and bad.
[Päivi:] Yes, absolutely.
We may all have noticed that too, -
These changes in the climate.
That we may have more ice, above all.
I mostly just go with stitches, it may have to do with age, -
Or it has to do with the weather.
Unclear sometimes.
Yes but then so.
What do you say more.
Is it something we can add.
Like, if you don't have the access then?
[Åsa:] This I think too -
is an important aspect.
That now we say it is useful to come out -
In nature, has lots of advantages and so on.
But, one should definitely not detract from, -
On the contrary, it also makes it very good to just come out, -
For example, on the bridge.
Able to sit outside on a balcony or patio.
Just this proximity to nature.
Also very favorable for health, -
For example, being able to look in nature.
Be able to see trees, out towards water, for example through a window.
This picture to the right is from our sauna and I mean, -
It is so much nicer to bathe sauna when you have -
a window and can look out at the water.
That's how it is.
Then there is a lot of evidence for this too.
There was one named Ulrich, who already in the 80s -
Studied it that, when operated the gallbladder.
He saw that those who had a view of nature, -
Where there were trees and green areas and such.
They were discharged faster from the hospital, they felt less ill and had less pain.
This has been seen in different contexts, that there is, - -
That it benefits to be in this.
You see that, preschools located in very natural areas -
And where there is the opportunity.
So do they have the kids -
Better concentration, also a calm after staying -
And a creativity and stuff like that.
And there are many examples -
on feeling better in different contexts, -
Right with the proximity to nature.
It is also true that you can show that you feel better, are less worried -
before an operation.
Where, for example, you had a poster in the ceiling -
with nature motifs.
Versus that it is white or something else there.
So we don't have to go out into the forest every time, but this is important to us.
[Päivi:] There I can also add, you have to remember today -
in the digitized world.
That you work with a lot here too -
To try to find other ways, to make nature available.
For people who cannot get out at all.
For example, if you are in a hospital or are at a retirement home -
and does not have the physical ability to get out.
And it is through AI and digital solutions.
So it is the future that may show.
[Åsa:] The future that may expel.
[Päivi:] Yes, but exactly.
And we have also had some studies.
And now in conjunction with Covid -19, definitely a major impact on, -
The whole world actually.
Can you tell Åsa, a little about what we did there.
[Åsa:] Yes.
There we have done a lot of studies and interviewed -
Both intensive care nurses, patients and relatives.
In connection with intensive care of those affected by Covid-19.
There is a lot around what they have experienced in different ways.
But what was recurring in several of these descriptions was, -
That was not the focus, but it was the importance of nature.
In one way or another.
This is how it could look inside a Covid-19 hall.
Thus, where the patients were cared for.
And for example, an intensive care nurse -
described here.
So it was just, you worked twelve and half hours.
You were, trapped I was saying, more or less inside.
You did not get out of the building.
And how incredibly important, -
You walked with the mask all day.
How incredibly important it was, to take a walk out.
And could spend the night at IVA, because you would soon be on the next pass again.
And you know here in Norrbotten, you were in Piteå.
It was some who commuted there.
Worked twelve and a half hours and was going up again in the morning.
This is exactly what to get out, get some air and see the other world.
Was incredibly, incredibly important.
Just like what you were in, we have had an increased interest -
Overall, to get to the mountains, to be out.
It has also been the prerequisite we had, that sometimes be able to meet and such.
The relatives who were at home and worried about the person who was seriously ill.
Also described the importance of coming out, taking a walk, getting fresh air.
Someone described, who was not so interested in giant, -
But she said, I went up and down the mountain several times a day.
Just because I would be tired in the evening and be able to sleep.
So it is absolutely important.
In different ways.
Even then when you got home, it has also had, both for -
the relatives and the patient.
Being able to stay in this.
I interviewed a woman, when I would ask about what it was -
Having been seriously ill in Covid-19.
She told us, among other things, that, -
Yes it was very busy and you felt alone.
She had her family -
Very far away.
She had been transported helicopter this way.
And, as I said, they were not allowed to be there.
So she was there herself.
Then she told me that, yes it may sound a bit strange, -
But I had a friend.
And it was a pine outside my window.
Well, I thought this was interesting.
She told me that -
This number, it said what the weather and wind was.
If it had snowed and so on.
In the evening I said good night to it and in the morning when I woke up, -
So it stood there waiting for me.
Some night they had pulled down the blinds and the blinds -
And she almost panicked when she couldn't look out the window.
She also described it just like this that, yes probably the staff was kind -
And they came in and so on.
But I was very lonely and then I had my pine.
And somehow she described it as, it was me and the numbers to the world.
I was in continued contact with the woman and still keep in touch.
Then we decided to write an article, I asked if it was okay -
Have had contact, about this number.
And there are a lot of theories about this with that -
Animals, which I have been on.
And even nature, can be important.
And that it can be, the other need not be a human being.
There is something big in this.
When I usually tell you about this, there are others who come and tell you, -
Yes you know when I was lying, then there was a bird's nest outside and a little so.
So it's of incredible importance.
And even in this we discuss against Ulrich and Boberg -
And this with humanity, Dahlberg and so on.
What she tells this woman, so it was, she lived as I said-
far from here.
I would think it's 30, 40 miles or something.
She said, sometimes I want to go and visit the numbers.
Because it was so important and the one that made me move on.
After a while I got a message and then she had sent -
this picture.
I have been allowed to show it.
When she is and visits her pine, outside the hospital in Piteå.
She hugs it.
So she has said, you must never cut down that.
It was her power through this time.
Think it is important.
And I have some of that article if you want -
Bring with you.
It's a short article, there are some there and there are -
Something for a copy if you would like to read.
This is just a quote to draw.
From one of the nurses -
Who worked very intensively, at this Covid-19 IVA department.
And as was sick eventually.
Because it was simply too much.
She also described this meaning of being in nature -
And what it did to her.
This description it is, -
Could be almost in any context.
This with stress -related ill health.
As we are in in many and many -
And what it can do.
I read it.
[Reads the quote on the screen]
[Päivi:] mm, exactly.
And here we get into the climate, suddenly.
I think, I can feedback to this previous one.
That we will come into the parts that also feedback to them.
But now we have to talk about the climate.
[Åsa:] Yes, now we have to talk about the climate.
[Päivi:] And what do we say about the climate and its importance.
[Åsa:] Yes, but we say that the climate is important for health.
What we know here and now, we know that we have a higher average temperature -
than we've ever had.
We know that it brings, -
Storms in different ways.
Floods and such.
This means risks that water will be contaminated.
This means that, for example, we get ticks up here.
These are diseases that may become relevant in a different way.
It affects us in a variety of ways.
And what one can say is that -
None of this as it brings, is good for health either.
[Päivi:] mm, exactly.
And of course, in this context it is, -
And we also know that, it is the weakest that are most affected.
And it is related if you look at a global perspective.
But you look from an Arctic perspective.
Don't we get either -
forget about the importance the climate we have in the Arctic, -
have in a larger context.
One thinks that, when our ice creams -
Starting to melt, what does it mean.
Also for this heating.
Here, but also elsewhere.
In addition, it is also the case that, -
This means a lot in living conditions and living habits.
Can we continue with our traditional way of life and living habits.
Given that the climate affects so much, so that -
the temperature rises, the ice melts, water levels rise, -
The tree line creeps higher up in the mountains.
All of this, overall, has a significance for flora and fauna.
So the animals and plants we have, have a meaning for -
Our effect and being here.
But also on the basis of traditional -
Life pattern.
Then we would like to be that it is, for example, -
for the reindeer herding Sami.
This is also seen in other parts of the Arctic.
Where it is more difficult for people who live according to the traditional way of life.
And maybe have your own animals or need to have, if you think about -
The indigenous perspective.
So this is absolutely relevant, for all of us.
To really take responsibility.
And what responsibility I can take.
Because sometimes we can throw back the question.
So that, yes but, what can I do.
The little I do.
But the little one of us does, is important in this context.
When talking about the climate, it is so that there is a meaning.
There is also a reasoning about, and even a letter -
About this with, how to build sustainable cities.
It is very relevant in Norrbotten.
How to have a sustainable urban environment planning.
To be able to maintain and perhaps reduce transport -
which is also daily transport.
So it has one, what we do definitely has a meaning.
We are also those who may actually do something.
For that, we must remember, those that are the weakest in society -
They do not have the same resources as we do.
To make active choices.
[Åsa:] What one can really summarize this that, -
Good living habits can mean great gains for both climate and health.
So, how we live, really goes hand in hand, -
by doing something about the climate.
So, we would eat better, maybe reduce meat.
Should we move more to a greater extent, it is good for us, -
But also good for the environment.
Thus, physically.
[Päivi:] The active choices.
And of course we can't either -
Knit under chair with, maybe our living habits, -
If they looked different.
Had we not been in that situation -
We have been now, these two and a half last years.
And this is probably not something, where it stops.
So it's hard to say, whose is the fault and where does it come from.
But I think, instead of accusing.
I think we have to take -
to make active choices.
It does not mean that you completely end up with everything.
Without, you have to think a little.
Here we can also lift, -
That there is also research in, how can you make care more sustainable -
And more climate -friendly.
Actually on the basis that it is consumed -
A lot of material and what can we do there.
It is not something that is brand new.
Because it was actually even when I read to the nurse.
But now you have pinpoint it and show the importance of, -
To make these active choices even in these organizations.
How can we maintain a high patient safety, but still not then, -
Actually wasting, on resources.
[Åsa:] Good.
I think we move on.
[Päivi:] Yes.
[Åsa:] Yes, then we have another question here, which we talked about in the introduction.
This with, can really care, care and rehabilitation -
be implemented outdoors?
[Päivi:] mm.
This is an incredibly interesting question we asked.
Given that, -
If we now think that there is evidence that nature and animals -
has a significance for our health and well -being.
Is it also that, we asked ourselves the question, but why is implemented then -
All care, care and rehabilitation mainly indoors.
We did this together, you see down here, we are four editors in a book.
Which is written, thanks to very great help from others.
And where we aim to describe and fill in -
These knowledge gaps available.
Related to these aspects.
Can we conduct care, care, rehabilitation outdoors.
And how can we increase knowledge about how it can be done.
With that also enable and make available, precisely nature -
And its health promotion effects, to patients.
Or persons -
that cannot go out.
We have been to it before.
If you think practical examples, can be for example, -
That we are usually rehabilitated back after a stroke.
Then we go indoors on flat floors.
While you can ask for -
Those parts could be done outdoors anyway.
That one had had, care, care and rehabilitation context, -
Thus, the care business near nature, constructed.
We can also see it sometimes in hospitals that it is built.
But some hospitals we can see, where it has grown again, it has not been used.
But in this book we lift these parts.
But also describes a little -
About the theories we have described before here during this lecture.
And take off from there.
To show, what can we do.
So it becomes a bit like a guide for how to implement -
This, in its business.
But is actually aimed at, we must remember that, -
Actually to the general public that is curious.
But we also think, to students.
And all, really organizations.
[Åsa:] We can say that too, -
It is not then that everything should be outdoors.
[Päivi:] No.
[Åsa:] Without it is the proximity.
What we have been in before, to be able to look.
Natural and for example, -
Access to garden and things like that.
[Päivi:] Yes, exactly.
Exactly, because you can also ask, all calls need to be done -
in a closed small room.
If we think I'm in need of conversation.
Can we actually make the calls outdoors or during a walk.
Prevention factors can be sound and so on.
But think you can -
Look on the basis of the patient's or person, or the user.
As the elderly are usually called, their needs and conditions.
Maybe being able to move outdoors.
Related to sound and weather, of course -
We must think.
But here we would like to, -
We actually want to flag for this book, it will have release this fall.
It is in collaboration with student literature.
So there are two physiotherapists, Liljegren and Lundgren.
And then we are two nurses, who have written this.
With the help of all them here.
Now I don't even remember -
How many they are.
Many authors.
[Åsa:] To the right we see, June, only to be called June and Stand -
for the health care of the future.
Maybe then outdoors.
If you are wondering what she has for the title of that, then it is coordinator.
I think that is also something for the future.
To get ours together, -
Both professions and so on.
So yes.
[Päivi:] mm, exactly.
You had an example here, it has been just recently.
I don't know if you have others, but Åsa may tell you a little.
[Åsa:] Yes.
This one was just recently in,  Dagens Medicine.
This is also something we discussed and noted, -
Even when we have written this book.
Anna and Helle, as visible in the picture here on the left.
Have also  -
contributed to the book and writing in it.
What they have raised is a debate article in, Dagens Medicin.
It is about giving patients the same right as inmates.
It is so that, it is actually enrolled -
in law.
That as internal in prison -
So you are entitled to outdoor living, daily outdoor living.
You do not have as a patient, user or accommodation, -
in care, care and rehabilitation in general.
That's really what the article is about.
To notice -
To have these opportunities, actually.
What they propose as a recommendation.
Is that principals and decision makers in healthcare and care.
Takes care of the knowledge that exists, about health -promoting outdoor environments -
potential in care context.
That we have a holistic perspective, which is taken into account in the construction of -
Hospitals and healthcare institutions.
And that both inside and outdoor environments -
Available in planning from the start.
Finally ... [Reads Text 3]
Then we will talk a little about a project.
As we had together -
And as you have been driving from the Swedish side.
Called, Nordic Nabs.
What is that?
[Päivi:] Exactly.
Now it is 2019 in January, which we received funds from Interreg Nord.
Thus, it is EU-funded funds.
To implement projects where we actually investigate this.
How do we take were on nature's values.
This is a project that has been implemented and we are in the last month.
In collaboration with SMEs, here in Norrbotten -
And Västerbotten.
On the Swedish side.
Then we also have three regions in Finland.
Where they also collaborated with small and medium -sized entrepreneurs there.
And then there are public actors.
Here, among other things, the Region Norrbotten - has
Also been co -financed and co -actor.
During this project, of course we have also looked at, -
How could one use the natural resource industry -
Competence and knowledge, as a complement.
Because as we mentioned earlier, it is not that everyone should just go out.
Now everyone is going out, we all solve the world's problems with it.
Without, how should we make sure the resources are enough.
If you think based on what health care looks like today.
What is it that are recovery measures, rehabilitative action -
and so on.
Here we have looked at a little, just those parts.
How can these small, medium -sized companies that have businesses -
in the natural resource industry.
As too, some of them are -
Trained healthcare professionals, others not, as it looks here.
But like the rehabilitation garden in Alnarp.
These could promote health among customers, clients.
In our projects, customers, clients have come from various public actors.
During projects, of course, on a voluntary basis.
But we also have this.
Really had follow -up research.
We have a doctoral student, -
who consolidates the area and studying, what do we get for -
Contribution to the research base on this.
What is it like to be a person who gets to test them here, in the northern environment.
If you think, we still have a large part of the year winter.
And how could one imagine that these so -called -
The green areas do not work in a white context.
As in this picture.
It is actually our loggo image.
I also want to, under this picture flag because we have -
a website.
Which will be open until 2024.
There you will find links to Youtube and so on.
Various lectures that exist in Finnish, Swedish and English.
[Åsa:] There is also a Facebook group.
[Päivi:] There is a Facebook group.
Until the end of the year, where you can go in.
It goes under the long name,
New Nordic Nature Based Service Models.
It's a very long name, so we got to find a short name.
So we don't slip with the tongue every time at talking about this.
But here I can also say that it is Vasa University.
It is Lapland's vocational college and Oulu vocational college, -
Who has been with us in this.
Except we from LTU.
[Åsa:] I don't know who -
Knocks on here.
[Päivi:] No, I've also listened.
What is it that knocks?
(someone knocks on the door)
null
[Åsa:] Yeah.
[Päivi:] Yes, yes.
[Åsa:] Yes.
It is good.
[Päivi:] No, it's quiet.
I actually started to think, what if someone locked in to the toilet.
[Åsa laughs] [päivi:] my practical thought only, -
Now we have to go and help someone sitting there.
And we all just sit here -
And do nothing.
[Åsa:] Yes, it thought.
[Päivi:] But good, then we know it.
Yes exactly.
And during the project we have done such pilots, -
As we call it.
Actually test attempts, with these contractors.
Where people on a voluntary basis, from the public actors -
has been able to carry out nature -based activities.
It is very interesting to see, how have they experienced this.
Here I have only put in three very short, quotes really.
About the experience of these stays.
Then it is that you have -
Got to be on five occasions, three hours per occasion.
So there are no long processes.
Then you can also understand when you say, -
[Reads second quote screen]
Here there have been slightly different client groups that have participated in -
These activities.
And one person says, "I've felt safe."
Then we will come back -
To that feeling of security.
And also appreciated.
Which is so incredibly important to our self -esteem.
“I feel safer -
Before starting work training.
For I have seen here that there is the opportunity -
that it can be good. "
It is also part of this context that one is strengthened in one's self -confidence, -
But also his self -esteem.
To be in nature and take in with different senses, to still the senses -
in everyday life.
Is a great help in dealing with life and one's stress.
Then we have to remember that, under these pilots.
Have you not been -
alone with the animals.
All the farms have had animals, -
Where we had a pilot ... no not really everyone.
There has been some garden -
And some animals.
But there have been several who had horses, among other things.
As in the picture here.
But remembering that, it is with the help of a guide.
So it's not that you are driven to a farm, so you have to manage yourself.
Without having a support there.
Which is really very important -
in this context.
And with that we want to, now it is in English this text.
Based on Bengtsson and Grahn.
Who has looked at, this is a theory.
If ... it's called Set in English.
It is really the one, the environmental theory of supportive environments, -
Can you say it is in Swedish.
If you think of the box at the bottom.
There is really when the person feels the worst.
I think that is very interesting really based on this theory.
Because here you show that, you are quite inward.
You can't cope with contact with others.
I have met people who have -
Been sick for stress -related ill health, who says that, no but we ...
... they could nothing, they couldn't even be with animals.
Without it just being in yourself.
That it starts there.
Then it will be more emotionally engaged.
To eventually become active and also outgoing.
I now see that it is, one minute we have left.
So I think I don't stay here.
Yes, it is interesting this.
We will see then if any questions are related to that part.
[Åsa:] Should I browse?
[Päivi:] Yes, I think so.
Because I see that time goes by.
We also want to flag a little because there is -
Publications in selection, in this project.
And that it comes -
A final report, natural values as a source of well -being.
It will be in Swedish and Finnish.
So it will come soon, during the month of April.
Then it is like a PDF, to download or print.
How to do.
There are additional publications, also related to indeed, -
This form of activities and business models.
Like a social innovation.
But we can't delve into it.
[Åsa:] No.
[Päivi:] We continue.
[Åsa:] Yes.
But if we were to sum it all up.
Then we take the questions here again.
[Päivi:] mm.
[Åsa:] that with animals and nature has a positive impact -
on human health.
Would you say that is true?
[Päivi:] Yes, absolutely, that's right.
Let's see if I answered ... yes that is true.
[Both small laughs] It's always exciting when one -
Complete before and ... [Åsa:] if they end up right.
[Päivi:] Yes, exactly.
[Åsa:] it has any meaning -
which nature we stay in. Is it better to be in forest or near water -
Or does it work in a park?
[Päivi:] It works in a park.
So the important thing is that we get out.
So it has some significance what it is for the environment.
But, -
Don't forget the park's values.
Because that's what we often have urban.
[Åsa:] This with the importance of climate for health then?
[Päivi:] Yes, exactly.
Absolutely, the climate is important for health.
[Åsa:] and, this with care, care, rehabilitation outdoors.
Is it really possible to implement?
[Päivi:] Yes.
We flag it.
And that it becomes a complement to traditional care.
So we can have these parts, as part of it.
[Åsa:] Good.
[Päivi:] Yes.
[Åsa:] Thanks for listening.
[Päivi:] Thanks so much.
[Applause] [Someone speaks:] Big thanks.