Several million people have received their electricity support and it feels
powerful that the e-service that I and my team have developed were of importance
For so many.
As always when a new IT service is to be developed, it is important to me as
UX designer to work closely with the developers
So that the solution looks and works as intended.
In order for the Social Insurance Office to be able to pay out money, we have developed a
e-service where electricity grid companies can enter
And enter information about their customers.
An important thing to think about was, for example, traceability so that we have
Opportunity to help the electricity grid companies if any problem arises.
We got free hands to
Create this service, but didn't have to start from scratch.
We have design systems with components and features
Like input fields and buttons that we could reuse.
It was a bit like picking up different legobits, part of a building
Which made it possible for us to pay out SEK 17.5 billion in electricity support.
We'll find out
the needs of users, in this case the electricity grid companies, and which
Technical possibilities that exist.
It should be easy for the user to do
Right and difficult to make mistakes.
Several million people have received their support and it feels powerful
that the service that I and my team have developed
Meaning for so many.
Several million people have received their VR support and it feels powerful to
The e-service that I and my team have developed have become important to so many.
As always when new in service is to be produced, it is important
for me as a designer to work closely with the developers to
The solution should look like
And function as it is intended.
We'll find out the users' needs, in this
the case of the electricity grid companies, and what technical possibilities exist.
It should be easy to make right and difficult to make mistakes.
Creating this e-service was a bit like that
Pick up different lego pieces.
Part of a building that made it
possible for us to pay out SEK 17 and a half billion in support.