Hi, my name is Shevin and I am an administrator at Försäkringskassan.
In this movie we will explain how you do to seek compensation and how
A lot of compensation you receive when you participate in a program at the Employment Service.
When you participate in a program at the Employment Service
The Social Insurance Office that decides on and pays out your compensation.
You shall apply for compensation on my pages
on the Swedish Social Insurance Agency's website.
You apply for the compensation afterwards by the fact that
Report how you participated in the program the month before.
If your application has been received by the Swedish Social Insurance Agency last
The seventh you will receive your compensation the same month on the 26th.
If your application comes in to the Social Insurance Office after the seventh
Do you receive compensation on the 26th month after.
Your application must be at the Social Insurance Office no later than
the last day of the month after the month you are looking for compensation for.
Otherwise, you may not get any money at all.
Keep in mind that it takes a month before you receive any compensation
When you start in a program,
Because you apply for and receive compensation afterwards.
What compensation is there and how much money do you get?
If you are a member of the A-box then calculate
The Social Insurance Office your compensation based on
What you would have received in unemployment benefits.
The compensation is called activity support.
And you have to pay tax on it.
If you are not a member of the a-kassan and have reached the age of 25
Do you receive 223 \ HKRONOR per day in activity support
that you pay tax on.
If you are not a member of the a-kassan and are
For 25 years you will receive development compensation.
You do not have to pay tax on it.
Development compensation is different depending on whether you have completed
High school or not and the amounts are updated every year.
On our site
you can see the current amount for development compensation.
If you are part of the establishment program and meet the conditions
you can receive establishment compensation of SEK 308 \ HKR per day.
You can also receive compensation during your mapping time.
The amount is then SEK 231 \ SEK per day.
You will pay no tax on establishment compensation.
When you apply for compensation, you should report what days you
have participated in your program and what days you have been absent,
For example, if you have been ill or been home with a sick child.
When you are absent due to illness
Do you have to report it to the Employment Service.
You must report sick leave the first day you are sick.
If you are sick for more than a week you need too
submit a medical certificate to the Employment Service.
The Employment Service's website contains information
About what you need to do in other types of absence.
You do not need to contact the Swedish Social Insurance Agency immediately when you are absent.
But when you apply for compensation, you must indicate
What days you have been absent.
If you have worked, you should report how much salary you have received.
You do this while applying for compensation.
More information can be found
On our website fk.se.
There you should also apply for compensation every month.
You do this on my pages.
Remember that you leave your information on honor and conscience.
The Social Insurance Office checks that the information has been correct.
Good luck on the road to your new job!