It is February 28, 1986. We are in Sweden's capital Stockholm.
It is 23:15 in the evening and two people who have just been to the cinema Grand on Sveavägen 45 and seen the movie Mozart the movie is now starting to walk home.
These two people were not anybody, because it was Sweden's then Prime Minister Olof Palme and his wife Lisbeth Palme.
They walk along Sveavägen south and when they come to Adolf Fredrik's church street they cross the way and continue the walk.
When the clock beats 23:21:30, what happened that didn't happen.
The couple was now at Tunnelgatan at a store called Dekorima.
Suddenly a man shows up behind the couple, in his hand he has a gun.
The thunder of two shots that go by oaks through the streets this February evening.
The first shot hit Olof Palme in the back The second shot turned his back on his wife Lisbeth.
The perpetrator flees the place up the stairs towards Malmskillnadsgatan and then down the street of David Bagare before he disappears without a trace.
Palme falls lifeless down to the ground, the shot had killed him immediately.
After the shots were fired against the Palme couple, the first call came in to the alarm center 23:22:20.
And the talks continued to roll in to the alarm center during the evening.
This whole event would raise so many questions, questions that people would ask themselves for several years to come.
What really happened?
Why would anyone want to kill Sweden's prime minister?
And above all..
Who murdered Olof Palme?
To summarize the course of events after Palme was shot, the following things happened:
23:24, the first police patrol arrives at the scene.
23:28 Palme is picked up by an ambulance and taken to Sabbatsberg Hospital.
00:06 So Palme is declared dead at the hospital.
His wife Lisbeth had managed with minor injuries, the ball had just turned her back.
00:20 Sweden's National News Agency TT sent out a Flashtellegram with the text “Olof Palme is dead”
00:45 So Sweden's Deputy Prime Minister Ingvar Carlsson arrives at Rosenbad, that is the building where the government is located.
01:10 At night, the music was interrupted in Sweden's Radio and instead the voice is heard by the report Jan Ström which reads the following message to the public:
Since this message was broadcast in the middle of the night, the majority of Swedes were completely unaware of what had happened.
But now the hunt for the killer of Sweden's prime minister was underway.
The day after the murder happened, they began to investigate the crime scene.
Unfortunately, they did not find much trace of the perpetrator, but they found the two bullets that were fired.
One bullet was found in the morning on March 1st the day after the murder on Sveavägen's western sidewalk.
It was the ball that had turned at Lisbeth's back.
The second bullet was found on March 2nd at the Jalusigallret to the stairs leading down to the subway on Tunnelgatan.
It was the ball that killed Olof Palme.
The bullets were of the type .357 Magnum metal piercing from manufacturer Winchester western.
The weapon itself used by the killer is not entirely clear, but the most common weapon used for this type of ammunition
is a revolver from manufacturer Smith & Wesson.
But there are also other manufacturers of weapons with the same type of caliber.
For example.
Colt, Ruger & Co, Taurus and others.
Unfortunately, the bullets were in far too poor condition to determine exactly which weapon was used.
But despite that, there are some theories about which weapon may have
been used for during the murder occurred, there were between 10-13 weapons of the right type that were theft-signed.
And the weapon that is perhaps best known is the Mockfjärds revolver.
This revolver along with 91 cartridges of .357 Magnum was first bought altogether in Luleå by a private person from Haparanda.
The weapon was later stolen in connection with a burglary in 1983.
The weapon was later used at a robbery against a post office the same year in Mockfjärd in Gagnef municipality in Dalarna.
During the robbery, a shot was fired.
When analyzing the ball it showed that the ball and even the ball found on Sveavägen that murdered Palme
were manufactured for one and the same time and were sold in Sweden in the late 1970s.
Mockfjärds revolver was found in 2006 in Djursjön approximately 1.5 miles from Mockfjärd by two private divers
Benny Gustafsson and Ove Jansson.
The revolver who had been a great interest in the police and sought for 20 years was found in about 3 hours
of two private divers hired by Expressen.
Unfortunately, the weapon was in just too poor a condition because you could decide whether it was the murder weapon or not…
Another weapon that was of interest to the police was: "Sucksdorffsvapnet".
The same type of weapon that must have been used in the murder, stolen at home with filmmaker Arne Sucksdorff in 1977
And the man who stole the weapon claims he sold it for SEK 2000 at the "Old Bowler" pub, which is now known as Norra Brunn.
During the investigation, the police have tested 788 different weapons to try to find similarities to the bullets fired on the Palme couple.
Unfortunately, it is basically impossible to know which weapon has been used.
But before we continue I have to
In 1986, the Internet may not exist in Sweden yet, but it does now and as you probably know, the Internet is everywhere.
When you are surfing the web, your internet provider sees what you do and what you are looking for.
Like a small uninvited guest that you have not asked for.
But don't worry - NordvPN helps you keep your internet traffic anonymous and also protect you from going to dangerous websites.
So that you can enjoy your entertainment safely.
Go to nordvpn.com/snabbfakta and use the code quick facts to get a huge discount on a 2-year subscription 4 free months!
Link is in the description!
You can also use Nordvpn's service to virtually change which country you are in.
This is good if, for example, you would like to read news or watch a movie on a streaming service that is not available in your country.
Go to nordvpn.com/snabbfakta and use the code quick facts
Then - back to 1986.
After the police interrogated all the witnesses who were around the crime scene that night, a description of the perpetrator was sought.
The murder must have been committed by a man who was between 175-190 cm long.
The man should be between 30 - 50 years old.
The man had a dark jacket or rock and a cap or a hat on his head.
According to some witnesses, the man moved clumsily and limped forward.
According to other witnesses, he moved smoothly and easily.
Okay, so we have a description of the perpetrator.
On March 6, 1986 - thus about 1 week after the murder, the police had produced a phantom picture of the perpetrator.
After the phantom image was published in almost every news magazine throughout the country, the tips began to hail in to the police.
The phantom picture gave between 7000 - 8000 tips to the police.
However, this phantom image has afterwards been very questioned.
It is based on a testimony from a person who was in Smala alley, about 350-400 m from where the murder happened.
According to the witness, it was between 23:30 - 23:40 when the witness saw the possible perpetrator.
Since the murder took place 23:21, this time span between 23:30 and 23:40 is, according to a later police investigation, far too late for it to be likely.
Today, you don't even think the Phantom image represents the killer.
Anyway, the police have followed a lot of different tracks over the years to find the one or those who murdered Olof Palme.
Remember that this video is a summary so I will not go through any possible perpetrators and tracks,
But we look at 3 of those who have been highlighted a lot in the media and they are:
"The 33-year-old"
“Christer Pettersson”
"Skandiamannen"
If we start with the 33-year-old.
The 33-year-old was a man named Victor Gunnarsson.
He really hated Olof Palme.
He was a member of the "European Workers' Party" - an organization that was very critical of Olof Palme.
He also liked weapons.
The tip about the so-called 33-year-old came to the police the day after the murder.
One woman told me she had been to a cafe named Mon Chéri on Kungsgatan at 22 the same night as the murder happened.
During the time he spent at the cafe, the man had talked loudly about his hatred against Olof Palme.
Several other people must have also advised the police about the same man and they have also mentioned the "33-year-old "'s Palmehat.
On March 8, 1986, he was picked up by the police and taken in for questioning.
He was released the same evening but already 4 days later he was taken into interrogation again and now the police began to become suspicious.
He told me in the interview that he was at Mon Cheri the same night as the murder took place.
In the cafe he had talked to 3 different women and even 2 men.
After that he had gone to the cinema Rigoletto to watch a movie and after the movie was over he went to McDonalds on Kungsgatan.
The two men he had talked to at Mon Chéri stated to the police that Gunnarsson left the cafe between 23:00 - 23:30.
The police also found tracks on Gunnarsson's jacket which indicated that he had recently fired a weapon.
However, you do not know if it was the same type of weapon used against Palme.
He was arrested on March 17, 1986 for about 3 weeks before he was on the loose again.
There was no concrete evidence.
In July 1988, the preliminary investigation was closed.
Then we come to Christer Pettersson.
Christer Pettersson was known to the police since before.
He was an addict of, among other things, amphetamine who was sentenced to closed psychiatric care in 1971 for a knife trail.
He had stabbed a person to death on Kungsgatan in Stockholm.
He was declared well after 1 and a half years and released.
He was questioned by police on May 28, 1986, 2 months after the murder of Palme where they wondered, he was during the murder night on February 28.
According to Christer Pettersson himself, he had visited a club on Oxtorgsgatan called BK Oxen.
He arrived at the club around 19:00 in the evening and went home at 22:00.
He went to the Central and took the commuter train to Rotebro.
He was at home in his home at 23:30 and went to bed.
In the morning he went and picked up the newspaper and then got the knowledge of the murder of Olof Palme.
However, the police were very suspicious of Pettersson and about 1 year later, tips began to fall into the police that Christer Pettersson was similar to the Phantom image that the police had previously published.
He was called in for questioning several times and on December 14, 1988, Lisbeth Palme pointed out Christer Pettersson as the perpetrator in a recorded testimony.
A witness confrontation is a measure that the police can take when investigating a crime and has a strong suspected offender and wants to investigate whether a witness can recognize the perpetrator.
Then you can, for example,
Set up several different people in a row without saying which of them is suspected of the police.
Then it is up to the witness to point out the perpetrator.
After Christer Pettersson was designated by Lisbeth as her husband's murderer, Christer was arrested and
In July 1989, Christer Pettersson was sentenced to life imprisonment for the murder of Prime Minister Olof Palme.
And there the mystery of Olof Palme's murderer had been resolved…
.. at the moment anyway.
Pettersson appealed the verdict to the High Court and on November 2, 1989, Christer was released due to weak evidence.
It came out during the court proceedings that Lisbeth had been told before the witness confrontation that the suspect was an alcoholic.
Everyone in the witness confrontation was also police, except Christer then.
And that all police officers had black shoes, while Christer had white.
Lisbeth had then said - "Yes, you see who is an alcoholic."
Then it was so that ...
There was no technical evidence showing that Christer was even at the murder scene.
And one could also not show that Christer had had any motive to kill Palme.
And then we come to the third offender in this video.
Stig Engström - Skandiamannen
Stig Engström was a graphic designer and advertising consultant at the insurance company Skandia.
He was a member of a shooting club and also knew a weapon collector.
Skandia's head office was at this time on Sveavägen 44, right next to the murder scene.
Stig was interrogated on March 1, 1986, the day after the murder.
His description of the murder night is as follows:
He had quit his work for the evening and went home at 23:20.
When he was on Sveavägen south, he hears a bang about 20 meters away.
Then he sees a person lying on the ground and blood on the ground and that there were people around.
When he arrives, Lisbeth tells him that the perpetrator had a dark blue cover jacket.
Police arrive at the scene and ask "in which direction?"
Stig, who at the time sat down stands up and points with the whole hand towards the tunnel and says "in that direction!"
Then Stig finds that he might have mentioned something about the dark blue cover jacket.
Stig then runs after the police officers he has seen running into the alley, without catching them.
The police were gone.
He then returns to the crime scene.
He himself believes that the signal element left afterwards, that they are looking for a man with a dark rock and cap can apply to him.
Because that's what he was wearing during the evening.
According to Stig, he remained at the crime scene for a while before returning to Skandia about 23:40.
He called his wife, took a coffee and then took the night bus home.
What makes his statement a little suspicious is the following:
According to Lisbeth, she has not talked to a man at the crime scene as Stig describes.
According to the police at the scene, they have no memory of Stig who pointed with the whole hand or even that Stig has talked to one of the police.
And according to witnesses, no one has even seen him at the crime scene.
So what did he really do during the 20 minutes between 23:20 and 23:40?
Many of Stig's friends and relatives describe him as a person with a great need for confirmation.
He exaggerated and often spread his stories.
He spiced his stories a little extra to portray himself as a little better.
So it may be that Stig is trying to portray himself as a bit of a hero in this context
Or could it be so ... that he tries to mislead the cops?
It was discussed in 1986 by members of the police investigation into Stig Engström was a possible perpetrator.
But he was put aside and the suspicions against Stig cooled off while the police focused on other tracks.
34 years later.
The police investigation into who murdered Olof Palme is the largest police investigation in Sweden's history and even one of the largest police investigations in the world.
Over 90,000 people have been in the investigation.
10,000 people have been interrogated and many of them several times.
22,430 different tracks have been examined and 788 different weapons have been shifted.
134 people have admitted the murder, of which 29 of them have admitted directly to the police.
After 34 years, the police finally had an answer to the question that everyone asked.
On June 10, 2020, the police and the Prosecutor's Office held a press conference in which they presented the person whom they suspected murdered Palme.
And it was ... Stig Engström, Skandiamannen.
And how did you find that Stig Engström was Palme's murderer?
It is based, among other things, on the fact that no witness remembers Stig from the crime scene and that parts of his story about what happened during the murder night were very unlikely.
But .. You did not present any murder weapon that may have been used and there was no technical evidence against Stig and no witnesses had also pointed him out as a perpetrator ..
But despite that, he was still suspected as Palme's murderer.
But one could not prosecute against Stig anymore.
Why?
Well, because he died 20 years earlier in his apartment when he was 66 years old.
And you can't prosecute a dead person.
So the investigation was closed down.
The designation of Stig Engström as Palme's murderer, of course, received harsh criticism from all sorts of different directions and the conspiracy theories if the murder is still flowing.
The murder may remain a mystery to many.
Whoever was printed by the revolver at Tunnelgatan that night, there is one thing that is certain.
When the ball left the pipe, the Swedish history changed ..
..forever.
Thank you for looking at section 100 of quick facts!
Don't forget that fast facts are also available as a podcast.
You can find it at podplay.se or in the app!
And a big thank you to all the members on the channel!
Your support is really appreciated.