November 7, 1872 the ship Mary Celeste sails away from the port of New York.
The ship would sail to Italy.
On board Mary Celeste was Captain Benjamin S. Briggs.
His wife Sarah and their 2 year old daughter Sophia
But also 7-8 pieces in the crew.
About a month later, December 5, a British ship named Dei Gratia sails
About 64-74 miles east from the Portuguese archipelago Azores.
The crew of Dei Gratia sees a ship about 10 km away from them.
The ship behaved strangely.
It seemed to sail irregularly.
Like no one on board ruled.
They could not see anyone aboard the deck, which was very strange.
The captain of Dei Gratia, David Morehouse suspected that something must be wrong and sent three of his men to go there to investigate.
As the men approached the ship, they saw the name of the ship written on the stern ...
Mary Celeste.
The men climbed aboard the ship.
Once on board, they discovered that something was not really right.
Many of the sails were broken or in very poor condition.
Some sails were completely missing.
When you went down into the cargo room it was water -filled up to 1.1 meters.
A significant amount of water.
But not particularly alarming to a ship of this size.
The men also found a provisional measuring rod that should probably have been used to measure the water depth inside the ship.
It was also discovered that the lifeboat was gone.
The men continue to investigate the ship.
Mary Celeste carried 1701 barrels with industrial alcohol, but all cargo was untouched and mostly intact.
There was food on board that would last for about 6 months.
It was also seen that part of the navigation equipment was gone.
Among other things, a chronometer, a navigation book and a sextant.
A logbook was found, where it had been noted that Mary Celeste had added to the harbor on the island of Santa Maria, which belongs to the Azores archipelago on November 25.
About 74 km from where the ship was then found by Dei Gratia.
But that note was written about 1.5 weeks ago without any update since then.
There was nothing about any problem or damage to the ship.
There were no signs of violence, injuries or that it had burned on the ship.
Apart from the fact that it was a little wet here and there, the ship was still in a relatively good condition.
The personal possession of the crew and the captain and valuables remained on the ship.
It was like everyone had just ... abandoned the ship.
But why?
Mary Celeste quickly became known as the "ghost ship"
And from that name a lot of different theories were born about what may have happened to the crew on board.
Since no one knows what has happened, I will go through 5 different theories
And then it is up to everyone to decide what sounds most reasonable.
The theories that I intend to go through are:
MUTINY
Pirates
Water thrombus
Aliens
Giant octopus
If we look at the first theory.
Mutiny.
What does it mean?
Myteri means that, for example, crews on a ship refuse to obey the commander's order.
In some cases, this can lead to rebellion and the crew then become violent.
According to this theory, the crew must be drunk by the alcohol on board, become violent
And then killed Captain Briggs and his family.
But.. There are some problems with this theory.
First, Captain Briggs was known for being a very good captain who had a reputation for always treating his crew well and fairly.
Secondly, the alcohol on board industrial alcohol was.
Also called denatured alcohol.
It is alcohol that is undrinkable.
Different chemicals have been added to make it taste bad or even toxic.
This is for the alcohol to be used in other products that are not intended to be consumed.
In today's society this is in hand spirit.
Hence, it is difficult to imagine that the crew would force an alcohol that is not suitable to drink and thus risk their own health.
Third, if now the crew murdered the captain and his family, why would all abandon the ship in the middle of the sea in a small lifeboat?
It does not add up.
If we look at the second theory of pirates, it can initially and be a reasonable theory of what may have happened.
The area where Mary Celeste was found was known for having North African pirates.
They may have been so that a bunch of pirates attacked Mary Celeste and killed everyone on board.
But pirates are known to plunder ships.
So steal away.
But Mary Celeste had all the loads and all valuables from the crew were still left when the ship was found.
This theory thus also becomes unlikely because it is difficult to imagine that pirates would murder an entire crew in "unnecessary" without getting anything for it.
Could it have been that the crew aboard Dei Gratia has anything to do with it?
Maybe it was those who attacked Mary Celeste, killed everyone on board and pretended to find the ship empty and on operation
So that it can make money on the cargo and then the sale of the ship?
It is tolerated to think about.
Can the sea itself be behind the disappearance of the crew?
I mean, it is no wonder that there are natural disasters out on the sea.
A theory points to this.
That it was a water thrombus, also called sea straw that may have created the flood down in the cargo room at Mary Celeste.
Then the crew may have used the provisional measuring rod to measure the water mass and probably believed it would
continue to rise and that the ship would sink.
Hence, all the ship fled via the lifeboat.
In that case, it would explain why it was so wet everywhere inside the ship.
When rumors began to spread about Mary Celeste, it emerged, as it almost always does with unresolved mysteries, a lot of myths and invented truths.
One of those myths says that when the crew at Dei Gratia boarded Mary Celeste
So found them food brought on the tables that were half -eaten
And that there was a cup of smoking hot tea there.
Like everyone in the crew only disappeared in empty nothing.
Like an extraterrestrial ship flown over the ship and absorbed everyone in the crew.
These are false post -constructions.
It is not true that any meal or tea stood ahead.
So this theory we can probably iron out immediately.
After all, the lifeboat was gone, which points out that the crew intentionally abandoned the ship.
The theory of the giant octopus believes that the entire crew, including the captain and his family were taken from the ship
One by one, of a huge octopus.
Although there are very large octopus in our seas.
For example, the giant octopus that can be between 15-17 m long or coloss inkfish that can be about 14 m
So it is still very unlikely that an octopus would have the mental intelligence
Which makes it understand how it should pick the crew members one by one from the ship.
Would the octopus also take the lifeboat and the nagification equipment as well?
Well, this does not sound particularly likely.
What probably happened to Mary Celeste was probably that there was a storm out on the sea.
The storm could possibly have created a water thromble, we can never know for sure
But it can also just as well have been very high waves.
Waves that hit the ship, filled it with more and more water
Then the captain made a decision to abandon the ship with the lifeboat which later tragically sank in the storm.
But of course we can't know for sure.
No one on board has ever been found.
What really happened to the ship Mary Celeste is still ..
...a mystery.
What do you think happened to the ship?
Feel free to share in the comments field.
And as always ..
Thanks for watching!