Avanza and Nordnet, they have received competition.
In this video I intend to go through Leveller, which is a new stock platform where you can buy shares and funds.
And now they offer free trade in shares until March 2025.
So I will go through my thoughts on the platform, how it went, I have deposited SEK 1000 that I bought some shares for.
Will show how it works, what I don't like and what I like with the platform.
Now we drive, roll intro!
Tjena buddy, fun to see you again!
So here it is, Levler is a new savings platform that offers stock trading, they have just launched it.
They have been around for a while, I do not know how long but kind of a year I have for myself or a little more.
They have previously only offered fund trading, but now they have launched stock trading as well.
They then offer a 25% discount on all funds and also interest on ISK.
So I usually say it, if you start saving, start at Avanza, up to 50,000.
If you want to buy more shares after that, then go to Nordnet, then you have up to 80,000 but only within 6 months.
So there you have a time limit.
At Levler there is then no time limit, or there is no amount limit I mean, but the time limit is until March and since 2025 then.
Then it will start to cost commission.
But the commission at Levler will be cheaper than at Avanza.
I put graphics here, compare, here you can see the price of Levler, here you can see the price of Avanza and Nordnet.
First and foremost then, what can you shop at Levler?
Well, you can buy shares on the Swedish stock exchange, that is, the Stockholm Stock Exchange, not, for example, Spotlight.
For example, you cannot buy, for example, Plejd, but on the other hand you can buy, for example, evolution.
Her and Maurits you can buy, H&M thus, but you cannot buy, for example, Spiltan shares.
So that's the disadvantage then.
It is only Nasdaq Stockholm as it is at present, but they have plans to launch it in the future.
You cannot buy foreign shares either, and I have received questions in the group if you can buy Bull & Bear and such leverage products.
No, but this is only pure shares or funds on the Swedish stock exchange then.
And what is really nice is that they offer free commission until March 2025.
So I got into the app and put in a coin to test this.
I bought some shares.
Brokerage -free stock trading simply means that when you buy and sell shares you have to pay a fee.
And this fee they skip, for example at Avanza and Nordnet you have free commission up to certain levels.
50,000 at Avanza, 80,000 on Nordnet.
So this is good, there is no over limit what I can see anyway.
And this is really fun for us who like to save money and not pay so much costs.
So I went in and tested this app and told me what I think, give some feedback to the app simply.
If you want to test at Levler, there is a link in the description and the comments field.
So drive, test if you are a little craving to save money.
So if we start with first and foremost my experience, I put in a 1000-note with Swish and bought some shares.
I bought some Investor, I bought some Lundbergs and I bought some Betsson.
The app works well, but the first thing I come across is that it feels a bit like a webshop or a clothing store.
A little strange, but it is well because you have chosen to nisha against people who may not be familiar with shares simply.
You print add a shopping cart when buying a share or a fund and then it becomes like a checkout.
So that you can click in what you are interested in and then in the shopping cart you have to pay.
And it works, but I prefer the traditional way to say buy or sell, that you press so instead.
So it works to buy shares, a disadvantage here is that you do not get the same functionality as at Avanza & Nordnet.
For example, you have no buying decisions in the graph, you have no technical analysis, a little limited overview when it comes to your total portfolio return.
So far what I can see, but I have just started an account in and of itself, the P/E figure shows a little wrong.
Evolution showed a PE number of 339, so it can be a bit misleading.
The fund discounts are also good, we get into now, and Levler offers a 25% discount on the fund fees.
I have not compared to Saver and Fondo, but the two platforms are also available that offer quite strong discounts on the funds.
So here it is good if you save in funds, so you can check if you have active funds, you can save quite a lot on fees on these platforms.
Now I was going to take some questions that came from the Facebook group then.
Rasoul asks what happens after 2025 with the fee, then it goes over to the cortage, 0.185% in mobile and lowest commission is a penny.
So just over 25% discount against Avanza and Nordnet, so it is cheaper than Avanza and Nordnet.
Jessica asks if there is only a discount on the funds until March 2025 as well, or if they continue after that.
The discount should be the same as I understand it, a 25% discount is as permanent and it is not a temporary thing.
Alaa asks if they have Bull and Bear certificates, if there is a free fee on them too, but no, they do not have it at the moment and I do not know if they will launch.
Isak asks if it is free of charge on US shares, and no, they only offer trading on Swedish shares at present.
But it is something they plan to launch in the future then.
So my honest opinion about Levler, I think it works well to shop at Levler, I bought shares, I came across some bug though when I bought shares.
But first and foremost then what I think of it is that the app or website looks a bit like a clothing store, it feels like a webshop.
So it's probably nothing like, what to say, the design does not appeal to me directly, but the idea is probably more to appeal maybe a beginner who has never saved before.
Who may recognize a clothing store or a webshop online or something.
I know there was someone at Discord who said, shit it looks just like a store, I put a picture here so you can see and compare, it looks a bit comical.
I would like to see that when you have placed an order, because you can enter what price you want to buy a share for and place an order, then I think it is a bit unclear that you cannot find it so easily.
You have to go into account events to find this one, I would have liked to see that it was up to the overview or something so you can reach it faster.
And one thing that bothers me also is that you get logged in fairly quickly, I do not know if it has to do with BankID or something like that, but at Avanza Nordnet it feels like you can be logged in longer.
At Avanza, I know that you can decide that time, how long to be logged in and stuff.
One more thing that I disturb a little is when you press search, at least on the computer it chooses first and foremost funds, not shares.
Here I would instead like that when you press search you get a sorting on both shares and funds.
So it's a bit frustrating, and I got a bug then when I bought or would buy shares in Betsson, then it was like, the order did not go through and then I could not place a new order because the previous order did not have
gone through.
But it was suddenly disappeared, so I couldn't go in and remove it or anything.
There must have been some bug or something temporarily wrong.
So it works to buy shares, it works great.
I have not tested funds in itself, but it may be a bit like that, some small bugs here and there.
But awesome that you get free fees, at least until 2025. It is worthy of gold.
The future plans for Levler.
They have said that they will launch more markets, that is, more stock exchanges and even foreign shares and have said on Twitter that they should be competitive here.
So here it's fun to see what's going to happen.
They also offer an interest rate, I forgot to say, at ISK of 1.25% or something like that.
I put graphics here with how much interest it is.
Here you can see my portfolio, what it looks like at present, with the three shares I bought.
I chose to invest my 1000-note in Investor, Lundbergs, which is a small base in my private portfolio.
So I just tested with them.
And then I bought Betsson too, just for fun.
It showed up and I thought we were driving on one.
So it looks at present.
So overall, the app I think works totally okay, absolutely.
I think it's great that Avanza and Nordnet have competition.
I have gone out on Twitter and said that I am disturbed in the commission classes where Avanza is good so you can change the commission class once a day.
There we do not know how it will be at Levler in the future.
Nordnet gets a boot there, because there you can only change the commission class once a month.
So it is really lousy Nordnet, you have to fix that.
It must be better.
But in general, I hate.
I hate brokerage classes.
Stop it, everyone.
Also Levler.
Try to fix an automatic brokerage class.
So you always get the cheapest fees when you buy and sell shares.
And if you appreciate this video and are considering opening an account where you can use my affiliate link down here in the description or comments section to Levler.
As I said, free of charge until 2025. Go Crazy, shop on.
It is without fees so it is just to drive.
So you can test yourself, buy and sell a little and such.
And thanks to all the members who participate and support the channel, it is appreciated a lot.
If you want to know what I buy and sell in real time, you can do it through the membership.
And you can become a member either here under the video on Youtube, it's the cheapest or Patreon.
If you do not access this button, I am on Patreon with and it is exactly the same content there.
Then you also get access to group coaching and other things you get a nice little star or something, a bubble on your username in the comments field.
Thank you so much for looking and you want to see more about Levler and other platforms, maybe tip about some other platform in the comments field.
So I hope to see you in the next video.
Have a good time, ciao!