Tjena Now I'm back again with a video about my investments
There are quite a few of you who are interested
As many as 3500 pieces are we subscribers on the channel
It's totally sick
And that many of you are curious about how I invest how I think with my portfolio
So in this video I thought I am going through my
Economy type or how I
Structures up
My portfolio
And for you who are new here my name is
Marcus Lindblad
I run sparecash
And sparecash.se is
a website that I started four years ago
And with goals and to teach beginners how to invest in shares, funds,
And much more
And that is exactly what we are going to go into
In this video
I think a little short so I will give an overview
To you about what it looks like how I think
Every month
Around my money simply
So
Every month
I don't have
Stone check on my economy if I am to be honest to
So it is not so fun with money!
So it is fun to have money
But it's not so fun to sit and measure every number
and count on every sausage but what I do
It is that I have a document, a so -called "spreadsheet" as it is called.
And in this spreadsheet or yes
Excel document
So i feed in each month exactly how much
my money is worth
This takes just over a quarter
Much like me
Do every month
Then I feed in
How much money do I have on Avanza
How much money do I have on Savelend
null
How much money I have in my savings account at the bank
How much money do I have in bitcoin
All these different parts they feed in and update
To keep track of what it's worth right now.
So that I get a look at about how much money I have in different places
But also what it is that is increasing and what it is that goes down in value.
Because then I know if I'm going to tinge some more money in any other place
And yes then we come in to
My portfolio and my rules
And I usually have as a small rule of thumb so that
Just over
80 %
Out of all
Money I have
80% of all my money I try to have invested
So that they increase in value or them
May work anyway
And that's then my long -term investment
In, for example
Stocks, funds and cryptocurrencies and such
It is about 80 % of my total personal finances
20 %
The remaining part (20%) is for more short -term savings.
Short -term it means they don't have to lie cash or in cash in the mattress
It might be that i have them in a savings account with some interest rate or i invest them in
P2P loans on Savend or Mintos or something else
And it's simply money
Which is a bit safer who may not have such a high risk if it is that I want to
Put them in
Shares in case the stock market goes down lots or me vetiFan ...
The refrigerator might be broken and then you can have some money there to use
If, yes, unforeseen events simply happen!
So if we start from the bottom
And then we start with the most boring, ie the short -term
Then I run on a
Savings account with interest
And then a complete bank has a savings account
by 0.85 % interest (right now)
per year
It's not so much but it's still more than you
gets on a regular savings account
In other words
At the bank you usually get 0 % interest today then it is good that you use you perhaps for example complete
or Avanza Bank that also has (savings account with interest)
And there you can also unlock the money
on complete so there is no binding time
without
No then it is so you can get the money out
Anytime but on Avanza
so you can also unlock the money but I don't like to unlock my
Savings without
They want me to lie there movingly if I need to take them off
Then i also have a little a little slack in
Peer to peer loan
On Savelend
And at Mintos
And yes it is so that you invest in credit
And myself
Personally consider
Invest in private loans and credits have a little lower risk than the stock exchange
I think that
Where I invest in those there is reliable
And it's not as shaky as having the money on the stock exchange for example
So I consider that as my little
Short -term buffer savings
where I may not need to take off right now
But in case I am urgently need money
So i would rather take from there than my shares
And then we have then
the fleshy bit out of my portfolio
And that is then my investments in
Stocks, funds and cryptocurrencies, & other gut-in-good
So i'm going to jump into my little portfolio here now
And then we'll look
What i have for gut
in Gött
So in my long -term portfolio
It is currently consisting
out of four shares
It's Castellum, Mycronic,
It's Plejd
and it's sink
Then I have some funds
And then I have Avanza World Tech by Tin, BGF World Technology
DNB
Technology
JPM China
Spiltan equity fund investment company
Spiltan Small Company Fund
Swedbank Robur Ny Teknik and Tin Ny Teknik
So right now what will be eight pieces of funds this is my long -term portfolio
The shares I try to hold a little further in
So I don't go in and poke so much
Without being able to lie there and cuddled in if I consider
that they lie in a positive trend or what one says
Thus they go up
Then they may lie there
The funds I try a little with a little more often
I always have a monthly savings of SEK 1000 a month that goes directly into the funds
And sometimes in case I feel yes but now the funds have gone well
And i need to buy some more shares
or i want to buy some more shares
Then maybe I sell some fund that I think has not gone as well as I expected
And so I buy more shares
And then then during the year I put in
a slightly larger sum to that when I buy shares
Yes but then i want to buy
Too slightly larger sum than I do in funds
Funds so are hundreds of dollars that go into every fund
It's not so large sums, but in the shares so maybe I shop for SEK 1000 up to SEK 5000
More than that if it is so that I feel
that I want to
Then I have an experiment account that I started with
And it is my capital insurance called
Foreign equity insurance
And here I have then
thought
That I will invest in dividend shares and that has it kind of become
I have three shares there right now and it's cibus
Innovative Industrial Properties
And Realty Income Corp
It's the 3 shares I have there in
So now we get into cryptocurrencies and
What I have done through the ages so I have only bought cryptocurrencies for fun
Because I find it interesting to keep track of
So i have some slack in cryptocurrencies just because it's funny
And exciting if it goes up or down
And then I have used two brokers called Binance
And coinbase
Coinbase to buy bitcoin on
and binance to buy shitcoins as we call them
Generally speaking with my investments I do most to that
I think it's funny
And money that you don't need them think I should grow
And is it that you have money
in their savings account (with 0% interest) they lose in value because we have inflation and we get no interest on the money
Thus, prices are rising
And the value of your
Sinks when you have them in a savings account
Right in crowns so maybe they don't
Goes down
But because prices increase
and you don't get any interest on your money
So in the long term
Then it becomes so that
Your money loses value
In times like these when the stock market has gone up pretty much even though we have a fair
Shaky year (2020)
Well then maybe i am a little more passive or right now i am a little more passive
I bunker up some more savings money
If it is so that it shakes to a little, so you can jump in and fish a little on the bottom
It is very rare to hit the bottom but it is still good to dare to buy when others are worried
And sells
when it is at its redestest on the stock exchange it is when you are going to buy actually
Because that's when you make real bargains like
And that's how I think
Quite a few complicates to this so much
and make it so complicated to themselves
It's not that hard to invest their money and you don't have to understand everything
Without it enough to have a hum about what
Type man investing in
one does not have to think so much more than that
Without having a savings
As you always activate each month
Powse in money all the time
And that's what I do
late
Don't complicate to it so much but it is more important to
you actually save money
than that you try as well to yes
Bargain and find something
Superb company
Like here and there
that will give you triple the money in a month you do very rarely
Without it in the longer term that you make the big money
This is something I am talking about all the time.
I know it's really boring but
It is more important that you save
than you don't save
so is it that you don't have
Get started investing so yes but I put links to everything that I invest in below
Follow them and like
There are no purchase recommendations that I have invested in but
Many of you are nagging and want to know what I have so
That's why I make this video
Is it that you want to know more about
For example, how I think about the stock exchange
Follow me on Instagram
(Savecash)
And
Great joins in the group 'shares and funds for beginners' in case you are so that you
have some questions
There we can gather and gather
together a community where we learn from each other
So there we can ask questions completely freely no
Questions are stupid
What are you investing in?
I really want to know it please leave a comment below
What shares and funds you have!
and which ones you believe in
And I just want to thank you for now we are after all
3500 subscribers on this channel is totally sick
So it has been so fast
I really want to thank you that subscribe to this channel
So it is great fun
And
long -term I have a small plan for how we can make this channel even better
What kind of material we can publish in the future
Do you have any advice
So feel free to leave a comment below because I write it up and I plan quite far
Ahead
But thank you so much for looked I hope you have learned something with this video
Hope to see you in the next video
Have a good one
Ciao