In this video I will show you my biggest holding of my shares.
SNCH.
The value of sinch shares is now up to more than SEK 200,000.
If I were to sell my shares right now, I would have made a profit of just over 150,000 or 216 %.
Will I sell my Sinch shares?
No.
In this video I want to tell you why I do not intend to sell my shares in Sinch.
And how to think if you have a share that has gone pretty well.
And if you are considering selling.
It is very common to sell your shares prematurely-
-When you are buying and selling with shares.
It is true that the vast majority of beginners, they sell their shares prematurely-
-And you look back after a year or something like that and so think man-
"Oh, I have been missing out on a lot of money."
My name is Marcus Lindblad-
-And it's me who runs Sparecash.
I want to teach you to save in shares, funds and much more.
But enough about me, because now we're going to jump into why you shouldn't sell your stocks-
-Ber how to think if you think and you may want to sell your shares.
So here it is that most beginners, they make the mistake that they sell too soon.
I have done exactly the same thing, I looked back at my stock history and then I found Fortnox.
I sold my Fortnox shares in December 2019 for SEK 26,000.
Had I not sold them, they would have been worth SEK 87,000 today.
So, I sold them for SEK 26,000, today they had been worth SEK 87,000.
And this is an incredibly common mistake that not only beginners do-
-What also professionals, people who have been sitting and acting on the stock exchange for 20 years-
They do the same things.
Have you done the same thing?
Have you sold anything too early?
One stock?
A car?
A painting?
Pokémon cards?
Write a comment below.
I think the most common problem is that you think the share has gone up so much that it will end up.
But it is so common that they just continue up, up, up.
And you think you have dotted the top, though you don't have it.
We'll go through some tactical stuff that you can use you-
-If you are actually considering selling.
Tip number one.
You sell the return, ie what you have gone plus.
So, your winnings.
Just sell it and keep the basic investment.
Then you have secured the profit, so what you can lose at most is the basic investment that you first went in.
Tip number 2, it is that you sell your basic investment and then you leave the profits in the shares.
Then you secure what you have actually invested from the beginning.
If they place the money elsewhere, but leave the profit.
So if the stock continues up-
-Then it's just "free money" if you say so.
Thus, it is your profit that will continue to ride if it continues up.
Tip # 3
That you can sell half of your investment-
-If you've gone with SEK 10,000, yes, sell half.
Then you don't sell everything, so if it continues up-
-So you are still on the train, but you reduce your possible profit.
Then you have secured some money.
Tip number 4, it's not to sell everything at once.
If you have a share that has gone pretty well, as in my case where Sinch is worth SEK 200,000.
It's not that smart if I sell everything at once, but I can go out with a little at a time.
Kind of like I said in the previous tip, maybe sell half or distribute it into maybe four sales.
So you don't do everything at once.
It will cost a little more in brokerage-
-But if it is so that it continues up, you have sold a little more expensive and get more profit.
Tip number 5, do not sell the shares.
You may be convinced that the company will go well or you may be wrong.
Why should you sell?
Really wondering if it's right to sell, because in most cases-
-So it is just short -term noise, that something is happening like viruses in society or whatever.
Which makes you doubt on your investment.
But it is true that quite often you are actually wrong and maybe should remain.
Alright, I'll tell you why I'm not going to sell my shares in Sinch.
From the beginning, it was so that I heard about the company Sinch first in the pod Market Makers.
Then I started doing some research, I started to look at this presentations from Sinch's CEO.
I got a really good feeling.
"That Means that we on average touch every single mobile phone on the planet on average 14 times per year."
And I thought the stock was traded very strongly.
And from the beginning I went in pretty heavy.
And that is why I sold a little shortly thereafter.
I thought I was a little too heavy in this stock, in case it went down suddenly.
Then start reading on a little more and got a better and better feeling for the company.
What I like about Sinch is that they have been profitable since day 1.
They have always made a profit.
The three main reasons why I don't sell my shares in Sinch right now-
-Sum number 1, I know that Softbank, a large Japanese investment fund, has invested a lot of money in Sinch.
They will use this money for acquisitions and the like.
I believe in them as owners of this company.
Number 2, it is that they will make a stock split soon.
The price of the sin chart is quite expensive.
This has nothing to do with valuation, but it is just that it costs quite a lot to buy a share in Sinch.
They will solve it through a share split, which means that you get more shares.
This really has no impact on the company, but psychologically, it is so that-
-You and I like to buy shares that don't cost that much.
Because it will be easier for us to buy the shares.
And I think they can have a technical impact on the stock, which can make that-
-Exmer small savers like you and me, will want to buy shares in Sinch when it is easier-
-be able to buy them.
Then it goes from about SEK 1,700 now to SEK 170.
Which will make it much easier to buy more shares in Sinch.
I think that can lead to the price continuing on Sinch.
The third reason, that's the competitor Twilio.
Twilio is an American company that is currently worth just over 6 times more than Sinch.
I think there is a gap here that Sinch can fill as a good competitor to Twilio.
Or maybe someone wants to buy Sinch or vice versa.
I think Sinch has a lot to catch up with at Twilio.
But I simply like to own companies that grow fairly fast, which Sinch does.
They increase growth and buy new companies and manage their business gallantly.
I like companies and shares that have a good momentum.
The course continues to be printed and more trade and investors come in.
It feels positive in my ears anyway.
I trust my gut feeling simply and it feels good, but this is-
-No buying advice, without this is my views.
Keep in mind if this is how you are considering buying the share.
It has gone up an incredible amount and it might as well go down 20 % in a week.
So take it carefully, don't take what I say as any advice.
The most important thing I want you to take with you from this video-
-It's to try to keep you away from the sales button when you are in stock.
Hold it away, so that you are long -term.
That's when you make money.
I haven't sold anything in shares now in just over a year and a half, I think.
Yes, it has been so much better when I just buy instead of sitting and changing shares back and forth.
On the one hand, you burn quite a lot of commission.
It costs more in fees and then you may stay outside the market and lose out that other companies go up.
It is better that you invest in trying to make more money, save more money and invest more money.
Instead of switching from one to the spirit of the share.
It costs a lot of fees and you lose returns.
And probably you are just wrong.
It is better invest, let them lie-
-Let the winners go up and take it easy.
Don't be so hot.
Take it easy.
Hope you got some good tips this video.
Thank you so much for checking.
And shit, now we are 17,000 subscribers on Youtube.
Damn what awesome.
Have a nice day.
Take care
See you.
Ciao.
This video is Brought to you by Swedish Tap Water
The Juice of Love.
The Juice of Life.
The Juice of Heaven.
Heaven's juice.
Heavenly juice.