Hi Magnus, is it a good idea to go all in with SEK 100,000 in Avanza Global now?
The answer is no.
Let me explain.
I just went through in my monthly overview video that a lot of people have bought themselves into the Avanza Global Fund.
Also this month Global Funds.
And here I see a pretty big risk.
After all, we see that the United States goes pretty strong.
And if you scroll down and check, we see that the most purchased funds are also global funds this month.
What I think is a risk is that quite a few people buy global funds because the US stock exchange is going strong.
What many beginners do is buy the funds that are best at the moment.
The most common mistake beginners make is that you buy on a top and sell on a bottom.
But also let me explain why you should never go all into a fund.
There are a few different ways that I usually tip about thinking about.
And the first is when you start saving, yes if you have saved hundreds of thousands of SEK as in this case.
Then you probably have no experience since before having invested money on the stock exchange.
And then if you buy, for example, a fund for hundreds of thousands of kronor on a top and the fund goes down five percent.
Yes, then it will be extremely hard for you to log in and see your money sink.
Because it is not uncommon for some things that have gone up very much in a short time.
Maybe get a recoil down, maybe five, ten percent.
It depends a little on how things are going in the world economy and what happens on the stock exchanges.
My suggestion instead, if you want to invest a larger amount of money in, for example.
It is that you spread the purchases.
So that you buy a little now and then.
Because on the stock exchange, funds go up, down, up, down.
Over time they are going well.
So the data says that it is always possible to buy a fund or a share, that is, broad, stable investments.
That you can go all in.
But you also have to keep in mind that a stock market decline can last during one, two, up to three years.
And how fun is it if you go all in now and then it falls by 10-20 percent.
And then you should sit on those money for maybe four to five years before you get back to plus minus zero.
Therefore, I usually say, spread out the purchases and then it will feel better for you.
Although statistically, for a long time, it does not have to be the best, it is quite nice for the head.
Psychologically.
I hope you got an answer to your question now Emil.
Or was it?
Eskil?
Or what is your name again?
Yes, I don't know.
Well, Magnus Out.
Thank you so much for looking at this quick response video.
Have the best and have any questions, write a question below.
Have it good, ciao!