Hexatronic has a report today and I was going to draw a small quick report comment after a lot of requests.
So we look and then we see here that the share is currently traded down to minus 10 percent.
Completely crazy and it was one of my biggest holdings, or has been anyway.
Now, it is no longer after this year's decline of 40 percent just over.
And we actually had a pang report.
For we look here we see that yes but it is a record quarter.
The first quarter became a record quarter of both sales and profitability.
Especially North America then, the US and Europe very strongly except Sweden then who have taken a little stop if you say so.
But despite this, the share is down a lot.
For we take a look at this graph that we see here, we see that the turnover is crazy.
They grow on nicely and the margin also up so that you increase both profit and sales.
But there were some words that were reviewed in the report where some may have interpreted this organic growth that has come down a lot.
For example, DI who shared this graph then over organic growth that has fallen down a great deal.
Which may be a reason why the share is traded down so much.
Since the order book also we see that it has come down a lot.
But CEO Henrik Larsson-Lyon himself says they are not worried.
It has been before, for example, Covid, for example, that there have been very long delivery times.
That is, you may have ordered or placed an order 4-5 months ahead.
Because it takes so long then to get material in order to implement the words.
While it will then go back a little more normal 2-3 months maybe so.
And this can be a reason why the market is shopping for the share so much.
After all, it has been very high.
And I scratched some numbers together on sales that have been historically that you can see above me.
And then we look at the turnover as the biggest legs where we see most likely growth in the future.
It is probably North America and the rest of Europe.
For this we have then the United States, we have Germany and we have the UK.
These are the three largest parts if you say.
And we look at historical growth.
Here I have not included Sweden then because you can see here so Sweden is a bit struck and not so extremely high growth potential.
But if you look at these legs, it looks very nice in the long run.
If you think the United States will continue to grow at the same speed as they have done before.
You had a proper growth if you look from the first quarter of 2022 to the first quarter of 2023.
And then we put together the quarters so we see that it looks pretty nice geographically.
Both in Europe and in North America then.
And if you look at the estimates that I have entered here where you assume then you follow these financial goals.
If you reach 20% growth 2023 2024 2025.
Yes but then we get a p/e 17 on 2024.
And falls down to p/e 14 2025 if they then succeed.
One thing that I think is interesting is the itself the package.
As has been presented in the United States.
Which Henrik has actually talked about himself.
And here next door I wrote a little about this bid package briefly
From what Henrik said during previous interview in DI in March this year.
And this broadband if you are going to say bid's contribution then to the United States.
It is, after all, to develop the infrastructure.
It is then called Infrastructure Investments and Jobs Act.
And for broadband, $ 65 billion is budgeted.
And Henrik and Hexatronic estimate that this money will flow out
Or begins to be rolled out in 2023 or the end of 2023.
And there Henrik himself has said that they have a market share of 5-6%.
And there is a major player in the United States who has 70-75%.
And this growth has not been shown in the figures yet.
And since we see such explosive growth in the United States, it is like The Good Times is Ahead of Us.
So it will be better in the United States.
So here I don't think you should worry about it will stop in the US directly.
But here you still gas.
So I actually don't understand why the market is shopping for the share by 10% on a record report.
I think the market is a little too worried actually.
For interest and inflation here for Hexatronic.
So I will stay with my shares.
It is not often that I usually make such comments.
But I will stay there.
I will not buy more because the holding is a little too heavy in my portfolio right now.
So we'll see how it goes.
We keep our thumbs because it may be that the market re -evaluates its views on the share a little further ahead.
But it was a small short report comment at Hexatronic.
Hope you appreciated it.
In such cases, please put a thumbs up and so on.
And if you want to know what I buy and sell for something in real time, you can become a member on the channel.
Thanks to all the members and you who are watching and subscribing.
Have a good time!
Ciao!