It smells really good!
"Psych!"
(jokes)
It was angry.
5 points.
I'm a little pluttis.
Yaaaaaaay!
Hello Hello!
Today we will test ...
Cranky candy!
Yay!
"OUII!"
(candy)
- Laura has already started.
- She cheats.
Fuskis.
- But it doesn't matter, because she's only 2 years old.
- Yes, she is apologized.
But this is how it is ...
We often go to the store and look sweets that look a little cranky and fun.
Yaaaaay, Yaaay!
And then Alma and Harry have asked if we cannot test cranky candy, ie not from any country.
No, exactly, but just cranky candy.
- So now we have accumulated ... - A lot of cranky candy.
Yes, yes, yes!
- We are running right away.
- Yay!
“Lamp spray”
It's a candy spray ... with a lamp in the package.
Uääh!
Sour!
More.
- Very angry.
Do you want to taste, Laura?
- No.
Don't want to taste?
- But it was good.
- I don't know, I've never understood liquid candy.
It's like juice that has not been properly diluted.
There is something about being a spray too.
It feels like you are spraying hair spray in your mouth.
Do you think?
- Do you want to test mine?
- Yes.
- My spray tastes raspberries.
- It's blue?
Yes, I know, but it's a raspberry here on the package, so ... Yes, it's raspberries.
This one should be strawberry.
It does not taste strawberry.
It tastes sour.
This one should be green apple.
You might imagine that it tastes a little green apple.
Do you also want to test now, Laura?
What grades do you give from 1 to 5?
null
- Or wait, 0 to 5. - Yes.
- 5. - 5?!
Me too.
5. I could buy this and have it as a Friday night.
- huh?
Friday night?
- Yes.
- Zero cozy factor with a ... - No, I totally agree.
Very uncommon.
- Is this lamp for the cozy, then?
- No, but ... yes, a little.
I give this 0, but it was a lamp and I like cool stuff, so it gets 1 point for the lamp.
Yes, you changed your mind.
You rounded up.
I give 1 point.
Laura, how many points do you give?
"Um."
One.
One, one, one, one, one.
“Cotton Candy Buttered Popcorn Flaves”
So it is sugar candy with a taste of buttery popcorn.
- So nasty texture.
- Uh!
Is it common to be able to buy sugar candy in a chip bag?
- I do not know.
"Made in the USA," this says.
- Exciting.
Okay.
- Let's go.
1, 2, 3.
Oh!
It really tastes popcorn with butter flavor.
No.
What sick!
- Laura does not seem to like.
- No.
She takes back her candy deodorant.
- I think this was good.
- You like this?
It was something completely new to me.
Not my thing.
So ... I'm shocked.
I don't know what I was thinking, but not this.
I would probably have bought this candy if there was no other candy left in the store.
Not so good store, in other words.
I probably give it 4.5.
(Axel + Alma + Joanna) 4.5?!
Oh.
I give 1 point.
Too messy.
I thought it was really good, but ... it tasted a little popcorn.
- Mm, that's where the score came in.
- Yes.
I completely agree.
I give it 3 points.
Far too messy for me.
Absolutely impossible to have in the home with a lot of children.
But, yes, it tastes as it says it should taste.
- What do you give, Laura?
- Do you eat on a wet napkin?
Blä!
Yuk.
- Laura, how many points do you give it?
- It was pretty much the same.
OM-NOM-NOM!
Yaaaay!
Okay.
It sounds like type a 3rd or a 4th maybe.
- "gango"?
- "Gingo!"
- "Gingo."
- Huh!
"Gingo" is "Cinco", that's 5 points.
"Milka Mmmax Choco Jelly"
It is thus a chocolate cake filled with jelly pieces.
- Oh, this gel was very rubbery.
- mm.
- I haven't got any jelly yet.
- No, I've just been cracking.
- cracking?
- Me too.
It bursts into the mouth, like "Popping Candy."
- Yes!
- Yes, it is filled with different stuff!
MHM!
Yes, it snaps and crackles in the mouth.
This was a bit festive.
Do you think this is in Sweden?
- No.
- Maybe on normal.
- Do you think?
Do they usually have Milka?
- Yes.
But maybe not this kind.
But this is a little fun.
You at home ...
We do not know which of these can be found in Sweden, so you can comment on it below.
Good idea.
Do it.
Do you hear how it snaps and crackles?
- messy.
- messy?
Yes, you get messy with chocolate.
- "uaua" messy.
- Yes.
Laura is messy, yes.
I like this candy.
I thought it was festive and maybe a little fun to offer.
So I give it 3 points because I didn't really like the Jellybeans.
They were a little hard.
I also give 3 points.
Fun with the spray.
Unexpectedly.
- I give 0 points.
- Oh!
0 points, then?
- Why?
- That's why it.
It was disgusting with Jello.
Well.
I thought it was delicious.
It reminds me when I was little and made sweets in the freezer.
I melted chocolate and mixed up with a lot of candy.
I give this 4 points.
It was fun and festive.
"Baby Unicorn Dipper"
It is a diphic club that you can open ... and then you should dip it in powder that is here in.
- It smells a bit "suspicious."
(suspicious) - it smells very vast.
Uh!
Oh, Laura, you turned blue around your nose.
- Yes, it's the unicorn's hair.
- Oh, it only tastes sugar, this one.
- But I can't even get it down.
- Can't it get down?
No!
- How to dip it in "powder"?
- You have to do this, check out.
- Yes exactly.
- Oh!
No, what a horrible sweets.
Wait!
I found out that you can do this ... put some "powder" in it ...
- Oh, smart.
That's how you do.
- The lid.
Äää ...
- This is so disgusting.
- Laura, your unicorn has such big eyes.
It is very cute.
Uää.
It tastes like ...
It tastes like dextrosol.
- Although it's more acidic.
It's sour.
- This is exactly DEXTROSOL, I think.
This is not sour.
Look, mom!
Yes you are right!
Now I recognize it.
It's dextrosol.
It's not like hockey powder, but this is dextrosol.
These are as much quick sugar as it can only be.
Uööö!
!
- I give Feeem, Feeem!
- huh?
- Do you give 5?
5 points.
- "Psych!"
(joke) - meh ...
- What do you really give?
- "Psych" means the opposite.
Zero!
- You don't like it either.
- Noool ...
- Noool ... - Laura too, just ...
"Trolli jelly eyes"
They are packed in a plastic package and look like eyes.
- OH!
There is something sour and runny inside!
- No, then.
Stop it.
Hello, you haven't even eaten by yours!
- This is the worst Halloween candy.
- Yes!
You mean, "Worst disgusting Halloween candy"?
Yes, it was a bit disgusting to eat.
- So, why is it red?
- It's the blood.
"Creepy."
(scary)
I give this 2 points because I love Halloween.
I give the same, 2 points, because it is a good Halloween candy to give to children who want to run bus or sweets.
- eww.
0 points.
- "eww."
He throws eyes here.
I give this 2 points too.
Top pack.
Funny and perfect for Halloween.
- Crazy.
- mm.
- So, how can you like this?
- Concink.
Concink, says Laura.
She wants to open one more.
I think that means she agrees with us.
"Mentos Fanta"
It is quite common mento -caramel that are orange.
- Wow!
- It really tastes Fanta.
- Yes, it really does.
But now you have to put away your eyes.
What does what you have taste like in your mouth?
Fanta without carbonic acid.
Was it good?
Waaah ...
I think this tastes just like regular orange mentosis.
No, it doesn't.
That's why I give this 0 points.
It was just a "rebranding" of an old product.
No, now you're negative.
This tastes Fanta.
It gets 3 points from me.
From me it gets 3 points, the same as mom.
Of me it gets ...
0 points.
- huh?
- Zero!
You don't like it.
“Crazy Roll-On”
It is such a small deodorant that Laura has sat with.
I have "Blue Raspberry" flavor.
- Strawberry.
- Green apple.
Laura has green apple, and this is "Blue Raspberry."
- "Let's go!"
(Now we drive!) - "Yes!"
(Yes!)
- So snapped way to eat sweets.
- Do you think?
Oh well!
The one with green apple was so good.
- Oh!
- Love this one.
Can I taste it?
- You like these, then?
- Yes, I love them.
But it is a useless way to eat.
I also do not take the roll-on thing itself.
It was like there were some deoflases over in the factory.
- And it sounds so unpleasant.
- Yes.
- Laura has a good technique.
- mm.
Although it runs around the bottle if you turn it up and down on it.
- This I think is one that children like and adults just don't take.
- No, exactly.
- Don't you want it?
- No, please.
I give ... noool!
- Me too.
0 points.
- "How could you?"
(How can you?)
- huh?
- Yes.
I give 5 points.
5, 5, 5.
- 5, 5, 5!
- 0, 0, 0!
- 5, 5, 5 ... - 0, 0, 0 ...
- And what should you give, then?
- 0, 0!
- No, Laura!
- Three against two.
It will be 0.
“Milka Oreo”
It is Milka chocolate with small oreo cookies in.
♪ (Laura hums) ♪ na-na-na-na-na-na ... na!
Laura is still keeping his eyes on.
But this one was delicious.
Everyone loves Oreo?
- No.
- huh?!
I don't like Oreo.
I love Oreo, I love Milka.
Perfect mixed.
So, I've eaten this before.
I love it.
-(Joanna) mm-mm-mm.
- I think it tastes dust.
- Dust?!
- You're not like us others.
- You're a little pruttis.
- I'm a little pruttis.
I am a little pruttis.
- I give 4 points.
I give...
(scary voice) ... 5 points.
Five?
Oh, my God.
I give this 1 point.
- Just?
- Yeah!
"XXL Acido Gumetro"
There is some long sausage with ... chewing gum!
- It was angry.
- Great.
Oh, oh, hey, hey, hey!
- Sour?
- Oh!
- Don't you know?
- No.
Yes, now.
It came late.
- Harry!
- Nämen, Nähä, you.
Oh God, what a sour.
Here, you can get mine.
Oh!
No.
- Horrible!
- Ah, I'm crying.
Horrible!
- Eww!
- Oh, my eye.
Eww!
- You get sweaty on the eyelids of this candy.
- You get sweaty everywhere.
I give this chewing gum 3.5 point in terms of taste.
And I actually think this candy deserves "Crazy points."
I give it 4 "Crazy points."
Yes, it was very "crazy."
It only gets "crazy points" from me, 2 pieces.
But 0 for taste.
I give the type 4 "Crazy points," For it was pretty "Crazy."
It looked like shrek-bay.
And then it was like ... The taste of it was not so good, so I give it a third.
- mm.
And Laura, what do you give?
Is it good to clear your toes with?
- Why does she have it around her toes, ewww.
She sits and cleans between her toes with Alma's chewing gum here.
What do you give, Axel?
I give this 0 points.
But I give it 2 points for the package, so it will be 1 point.
"Boom Vampire Extra Sour"
There are small hard blue candies.
So hard.
Woho!
Oh, how angry it was.
- Woho!
- Wohoho!
- Uää.
- Oh!
Oh, you get ...
- It says "Mouth Painter."
- You turn completely blue.
- Giant blue.
- No...
- (Alma) Ääää.
- (Harry) Ääää.
(Laura) Mom, Ää.
Ääää.
Oh, Laura.
- I give this 0 points.
- huh?!
- Yes, I didn't think it was fun.
- But it's cranky.
Yes, it was blue and it was very angry.
- Harry, what do you give?
- I give it 500. I thought it was great to get a blue tongue.
Yes.
I give it 5 points.
I thought it was good, I thought it was angry, and I thought it was fun that the colored mouth.
I give it 3 points.
And do you know what?
This was our last candy and the sun is going down outside.
Yes, so we have to finish and say ...
Thanks for watching this video!
Feel free to leave a thumbs up, or down.
Most thumbs up.
- Comment ... - Ask questions, and have a great time.
And subscribe!
Have a great time until we see you next time!
- Bye!
- Take care, bye!