Hello Hello!
Before we do anything else, we just want to thank all our viewers who have helped us to reach ...
Hundreds of million views!
Party hat!
It's crazy!
It's almost difficult to take in, right?
- Air shot!
Bang!
- Ah!
Today we will react to our old videos.
Yes!
There are many who wanted it.
We are going through your desires now.
Don't forget to push your thumb up if you think this is fun.
Before we start, we should take a question that fits.
Yes.
Thomas Leijon wonders: "How many years have you had Youtube?".
Two and a half years.
Oh my God!
We will start responding to our first vlog.
(- Alma, how does it feel?) (- irritating!)
So small!
(And I've got some direction.)
(- Harry, should we bring with you too?) (- mm.)
Name God how cute you were, Harry!
- Baby-Harry!
- Yes.
God what you were little.
So this was for Christmas and we would go by train to Mora.
(Quickly!)
(- Did you get so much energy from that new swimsuit?) (- Yes.)
(It's so energy-ig.)
- How fun.
- So, you were so small!
- And cute.
- Yes, super -puffy.
And our vlog was so long!
I would never cut like that today.
It is I who cut our videos and at that time I couldn't cut.
- No.
- It's the world's longest movie.
- Not the longest in the world, I think it is a huge card.
- Do you think?
- It's a huge card.
- It's 20 minutes.
20 minutes is a huge card.
- A vlog really doesn't be twenty minutes.
- No.
- What do you think, is a 20 minutes vlog long or not?
- Comment below.
Now we jump 3 months ahead to the first time we went to Malaysia.
Welcome to Malaysia.
Oh, the water.
(Can you spit there on the glass?)
(- A turtle, in the water.) (- Oh, it's huge, Alma! It's as big as you.)
(Almost, or as Harry.)
(There it is!)
(- Do you see, Harry?) (- Yes. It's huge!)
(Put on the swimming goggles, Alma.)
- Ajajaj, it bit you.
- Yes, the bet.
(It thought you were an octopus.)
- How cool?
- Yes, that was tough.
That you continued to swim around even though you just got bitten by a turtle.
Yes, what can one say?
It was fun.
Alma was thus four years on this trip, you would be five.
Harry was two and a half.
- Now we are going to jump to the country place, where we are now.
- Yes, our first summer on Youtube.
(Here's our pool, with a lot of scrap in.)
- Our pool!
- Where is the water?
Alma, your style!
- Check out my glasses, they are round.
- Yes.
(- Listen, what kind of sunglasses are you wearing?) (- They're no sunglasses.)
(- What is it, then?) (- only glasses.)
(Yeah.)
(Hello!)
Can we only take ten seconds and ponder what it looks like inside the house.
- Yes.
- Oh my God!
- New fridge and freezer, other table, other sofa.
- But it's not even a wall, everything is different.
The windows, yes!
There were windows here.
We have been renovating this place for a long time and sometimes you feel that nothing is happening, so this is very good to see.
- Was this a year ago?
No, two years ago.
- Two years ago.
(This is living room/kitchen.)
(Last spring we had no kitchen at all, now it's half finished just like a lot of other things.)
( - Then we have our little Master Bedroom.) - This is your bedroom today.
So, that was so crowded.
It was so hard to go to bed and sleep in that.
- Check out here, we have a wooden board for the window.
- We had a long time.
(Harry is our biggest fan. He is looking at our own clips in bed.)
Aah!
- What did I look at?
- You looked at yourself!
(He got so tired so he wanted to lie down in bed and look at something. It's totally sick that he looks at us.)
(Yes, it's a bit of fun.)
(He has as a thing that he always pills himself in his hair when he gets tired.)
(It's very good, you know when Harry is tired, because he always starts to peel in his hair.)
- Is that our lawn?
- Yes!
Oh help, oh help.
It is so terrible.
That we could live here!
It was a nightmare, that is.
- Yes.
But it's pretty good peep.
- Because it's pretty nice here now.
- Yes.
Now we arrive at the first trip to Kolmården.
(- Didn't you dare to cuddle with the wolf?) (- No-ä, I want to cuddle with you!)
(Yes ... I love to cuddle with you.)
(- I want to cuddle with him.) (- Do you want it now?)
(- Yes-a.) (- Do it, then. He stands there because he wants to hug you.)
(He was very nice!)
(What good that you dared.)
- Oh, Harry.
- "Cuddly".
(LESSPAR)
"He was very nice!".
Oh yeah!
- Little Mini-Harry.
- Little brother, our little brother.
So cute!
We ended that day at the dolphin show.
(God ... The dolphin show is clear and we are very powerful.)
- Do you remember?
- Yes.
I also remember very well how it took in the heart.
At this time we had had Youtube channel for about six months.
Not many people were watching the channel at all.
And then we posted this video, and flips a lot of viewers to our channel.
It stirred up emotions, this video.
You could say it was the first video where viewers started to find us.
Yes.
Now let's look at our most viewed video.
And then mom is a little more like herself.
It's called "Hospital Vlog".
Alma would remove the tonsils.
(Will they cut into my tongue?)
(No, that's what they should not do. They have a tool that holds the tongue.)
(The knife cuts and then they burn the wound surface as well, so it doesn't bleed.)
(What will I dream about? I want to dream that I go skateboard every day.)
(We must not film. See you after the operation.)
(VINKI-VINK.)
Gull kid!
And I was sooo nervous.
- Look, you look like you've seen a ghost.
- mm.
(- You look like you've seen a ghost.) (- Yes but I'm really rally.)
- Nämen ... I can't remember.
- Neither do I.
(- She is on the operating table now.) (- Okay.)
(- There are four pieces in the room.) (- Okay.)
(Two anesthetists, a nurse and an ear-nose-throat doctor operating.)
I remember this as yesterday, I get teary eyed again.
I thought it was so nervous that you would be anesthetized.
It was terrible!
And I don't like this vlog because I think I'm so weird, right through.
From the first box it feels like I'm playing theater, but it's just because I'm so worried.
I even have a strange voice.
I've got it!
I haven't thought about that.
I have to look at it and ...
- But then, it was so nice that everything went well!
- Yes indeed.
- This was so happy!
- And what much better you slept after the operation.
It was completely silent in your room.
Before that, she snored and had a breath break when she slept.
Very high, Harry couldn't even sleep.
- We go ahead and look at our very first challenge.
- Yes.
(Here's next.)
(Not look, not look.)
- Oh, what a little cheat, he tries to watch.
- Yes, he has always been a little cheat.
He is afraid.
It was a little big box.
(- Oh, was it difficult?) (- But Harry, no! You cheat, you should guess what it is).
(What is that? You must not look!)
(- Listen ... Do you now see what it is?) (- What is it?)
(It's a little monster!)
A little monster ...
Oh yeah ...
- Stop, that was not nice.
- No, this was awkward.
- I also feel it was a bit awkward.
Sorry, Alma.
- Harry got a stuffed animal.
Now look how you react.
- You really feel ... - I would look what it was.
- "What is that?"
(- AJ!)
(- No, I'll give up.) (- Do you give up? Try, think a little, what could it be?)
(Ew ...)
(No, I give up.)
(A crayfish.) (*Alma screams*)
- Oh, Alma!
- You were not nice.
- You were really terrified of that stupid cancer.
- Sorry!
We really owe you an apology.
- Yes, sorry for that.
We really exposed you to a test.
- Alma, I can give a crown to you.
- Are you going to give a crown to her?
- mm.
- It was nice, Harry.
- Yes.
Now we will jump to when we had had the channel for a year.
We went on a skiing holiday, and we had 20 thousand subscribers.
- It was so fun there!
I want to go there again.
- Me too.
It is thus the Swedish mountains.
- I Love ... I Love Snow.
(I love snow)
You had never skied before we went up, and you learned very fast.
(- Has it been good today, Alma?) (- Yes.)
(- What do you want to do now?) (- Go into the heating cabin.)
(Okay.)
(Now it's time for lunch.)
(Mom's vegan drums.)
GOD GOD.
It is the worst fire with a grid over.
What do I do for something?
- Sune's dad!
- Worst Rudolf.
- Nämen God, the sausages will turn into coal at any time.
- I know, I got a really burnt.
- Nämen God!
- That was mine!
Note that Axel said "Perfect!".
( - This is a burnt sausage without leather.) - And I got it, seriously.
(- Do you want it, Alma?) (- Never.)
I remember I had to scale the sausage.
(- What? It's really good.) (- I don't want a sn ** P anyway.)
(Nämen stop.)
- Check out what good you were!
- Yes, wow!
- We used to go like that?
- Yes.
- I went under those rings.
Woho!
Now that we have laughed at Dad Axel, I thought you could laugh at me.
Because ... before we started Youtube - long before - I worked with TV.
And I've found an old clip on me.
- huh?!
- Yes!
This is from the program "Wanted" in 2006. How many years ago is it?
- What will it be ... 13 years ago.
- Yes.
Excuse the quality and how compressed the picture was, but then it was at that time.
Mom Joanna is in London anyway and reports on Jack the Ripper.
(The mystery surrounding Jack The Ripper has been raising people for over a century.)
(He murdered and cut up at least five women in London's East End.)
(Axel) Nämen God.
(... and even today no one can say for sure who Jack the Ripper really was.)
Nämen look, there goes mom!
It was a huge card, but I wanted to bid on it.
Imagine what you can find in Youtube's treasure chamber!
- Yes, that was super fun.
- Did you see Jack the Ripper?
No, I didn't see Jack the Ripper for Jack The Ripper died many hundreds of years ago.
- And he's deadly.
- He was.
So here it is, we have hundreds of videos on our channel, we could react more - if you think it's fun!
Yes.
- Now it is important that you tell us what you thought.
- Wait, I know!
We can react to all our slime videos.
- No rather not.
- I've started to follow people who make slime.
Yes, but you can do slim videos on your own channel.
- Yes.
- Right?
Thanks for watching this video!
Comment, subscribe, ask questions and have a great time until we see you next time.
Bye!