Mix, mix, mix.
Chips with hot dog flavor.
Huh?
(Alma screams)
Hello Hello!
In our last video we asked you what you want to see on our channel.
It was a lot of people who wrote different things.
- Kung Fu!
- Kung Fu?
Yes maybe.
(Shoulder) oh.
(Axel) Aj, aj ... Hörrudu!
There were several of you who wanted to see "Challenge".
- "Challenge".
- Yes!
After all, we have done "Gummy vs. Real Food" on this channel before.
But since we are in Portugal, we have noticed that there are a lot of exciting chip flavors, so today we do ...
Kung Fu!
No, not again.
We make chips vs.
Real food!
- Are you tagged?
- (both) Yes!
- Should we get started?
- Okay!
- (both) Yes!
Chips with ketchup flavor ...
... or ketchup.
Here you go.
- Harry, should we drive "mix"?
- Okay, once.
Mix, mix, mix.
Okay, should we drive?
1, 2, 3.
Ketchup?
Ketchup chips?
Yes.
There are chips with ketchup flavor, or ketchup.
Okay!
- Do they taste ketchup?
- A little.
Maybe you should dip them in ketchup?
Then they taste a little better.
- Can I taste?
- mm.
They are very good!
Do not force from someone else's plate.
- Okay, next.
- Yes, next.
Chips with taste of air -dried ham, or air -dried ham.
- "Bon Appétit."
(Tasty meal) - I don't want to mix.
No, Harry.
No, I don't want to mix either.
1, 2, 3!
- Ham?
- ham chips?
"What the ..." (what in ...)
(Alma) So ... Oh ...
"Oh my God."
(Oh my God)
Test.
!
Next chips.
Was the ham good?
No.
Yuk.
This was not a real hit, that is.
But corner, another thing.
A "challenge" must have a winner, and I don't really know how to rate this.
We can make the one who gets the most snacks wins.
Or we can let viewers decide.
- Yes.
What do you think?
- I think most snacks.
- But then you will win!
- How do you know that?
We have lots more.
Yes, we actually have.
We have many left.
We can do so that if you have any ideas you can comment on them below.
Or if you think someone won, then you can comment.
Comment below!
But you have to wait to comment until you have seen everything.
- Yes.
- Smurf.
(Both at the same time) Smurf!
Chips with a taste of pepper, or pepper.
And since there is a little red paprika powder in the picture here, we take some paprika powder on the bell pepper as well.
Here you go.
- No, Harry.
Don't peek.
- No, I smell.
- I want to change.
- I don't want to change.
- Okay.
- 1, 2, 3.
I knew it.
- Paprika?
- With something on.
- What's that?
- something.
Yuk.
What is this?
Pepper with something on.
Test, then.
Okay.
1, 2, 3.
Mm.
They were totally okay.
- Test mine.
- Okay.
Ouch.
Ugh, what disgusting!
Can I have water?
Mom, can I have water?
I also hate peppers.
Chips with the taste of "Pizza Double Pepperoni", or "Pizza Double Pepperoni".
- (Harry) Ah!
- Oh!
Here you go.
Thanks thanks.
- I don't want to change.
This smells like something good.
- Mix, mix, mix ...
- Stop smelling!
- I don't remember what it smells like.
- But should we drive "mix"?
- No!
- Mix, mix, mix ... - no.
Okay then.
1, 2, 3.
- Pizza!
Wait, this must be pizzaips, then.
- Pizza, pizza, pizza ... - okay, should we eat?
- Yes.
- 1, 2, 3.
Mm, they were pretty good, but they don't taste pizza.
Chips with taste of corn, or corn.
- That pizza is probably my new favorite pizza.
- It's called Peperonipizza.
Asagod.
"Double Pepperoni Pizza."
But this is something else.
1, 2, 3!
- (Alma) What is this?
- (Harry) corn chips.
Maize!
They are so good!
They taste like little corn ...
No.
Okay then.
- Do you like corn?
- They taste like little "corns".
"I love corn."
So, these chips are so cute.
They are my new favorite chips.
- How nice!
Are they good, then?
- mm.
Great.
Do you have any control over who has got the most chips?
- I!
I!
- you?
I think it's Harry.
Now that we are halfway in our "Challenge", I thought we would take a question of the day.
Yes!
Where do you want to live when you get old?
Or, not old.
When you grow up.
- Tokyo in Japan.
- MHMM!
- In a high-rise.
- Oh.
Then we have to move to Tokyo all.
- Or just Harry.
- mm.
I think I would rather ... or, I would like to live a little type everywhere.
Like, in different periods.
I don't want any permanent home.
I want to be able to, like ...
You understand what I mean.
- You want to be able to travel around and discover the world.
- Yes!
Okay.
Should we drive next?
- Yes!
- Okay.
- (Alma) Nam-Nam.
- (Axel) Nämen ...
(Axel) But, hello ...
- (Axel) What are you doing?
- I did too.
Chips with hot dog flavor, or ... hot dog.
Mix, mix, mix.
So there.
Mix, mix, mix!
Okay.
1, 2, 3!
Sausage.
- (Harry) huh?
- (Alma) sausage chips.
Okay.
They were very good!
Mmm!
Cold sausage.
Yes, unfortunately, the sausage has become cold.
Hope it does nothing.
It's just mustard on it, and it's because it was just mustard on the sausage on the chip bag.
These were very good!
These are chips I would definitely buy.
Chips with taste of sour cream and black pepper, or sour cream with black pepper.
So there.
No, you have to skull.
- Are you ready?
- Yes!
Yes, we are ready.
Here you go.
Mix, mix, mix!
Mix.
1, 2, 3!
"Voilà."
What was there that flew there?
Well ... I happened to ...
- So ... what's that?
- I do not know.
- Type sour cream and something.
- sour cream and pepper, I think.
Not the worst, actually.
Test.
(Harry) Mmm.
Eww.
- None of this I would buy.
Never ... in my entire life.
- I would buy it and it.
I think both were great.
- For real?
- mm.
Okay.
Next chips.
Large cheeses, or a large cheese.
- Here you go.
- Thanks.
1, 2, 3.
Cheese!
Mom ... You know that Alma is crazy in cheese.
I like this here, anyway.
Mmm!
- aren't these very classic?
These with cheese, and that one.
- (Joanna) Well.
Are they boring?
They are very good!
- Can I taste?
- mm.
- It tastes ... regular cheeses.
- I'll test this one.
Damn*is, what a big bit you take.
I will get cramps in my teeth!
I have to spit out!
No, I was just kidding.
- Now you have almost eaten dinner, it seems.
- Yes.
It looks like you are starting to get saturated.
Those chews were not small, that is.
Now there is only one chips left.
- Shall we drive?
- Yes.
"Moment of Truth."
(The moment of truth)
It sounds like any Thor movie.
Giant cool.
Chips with a taste of red chili, or red chili.
LA-LA-LA-LA, LA-LA, LA-LA!
So, I thought you were like this when we tested sweets, but it seems to be the "Challenge" itself.
Mix, mix, mix!
Mix, mix, mix.
1, 2, 3!
No!
In other words...
I refuse this.
- What?
Surely there is no danger?
- I've tested these before.
They are so strong.
- You can?
- Yes, of course.
We do it together.
- Here.
- Okay.
- 1, 2 ... - But Harry, then?
Here.
- No, I eat my own.
- He eats chips.
1, 2, 3.
(Alma screams)
- (Joanna) How are your chips, then?
- They are totally okay.
Isn't that strong?
No.
I think I'll test.
Will probably bull on the tongue.
Have you tested chili before?
Mm.
- Does it hurt?
- No.
- Is it hot?
- No, there is no danger.
- What is the situation, Harry?
- I ate one.
Oh.
I never do that!
That was so awful!
That was very strong.
And I think I lost the bill a little bit on who has got the most chips.
- My breath is still warm.
- Yes.
It's like the eyelashes curl together like small blinds.
I think I've won for I for that one, and I've been off to myself most today.
Oh really?
I think the viewers should decide who won.
What do you think, Harry?
The viewers I with.
Everyone got a little lever on this strong ending.
Should we ... Nämen listen, I don't want anymore.
No, away!
- Should we say thank you for today?
- Yes!
Thank you for watching this videooon!
Bye!
Oh my God!
Okay.
Bye!
BYE!