- I recognize a real rack kid when I see one.
- No problem.
I'm going to take revenge because he made Harry so scared.
Hello Hello!
- We're outside ... - Green Lund!
It's Halloween in there, and Hussein is with us.
Do you remember when we tested costumes?
There were a lot of people who wanted to see Hussein in his suit, so good.
- Should I try this one?
- What do you think?
What do you think?
- Yes.
Not now, but in there.
- Walk around and scare people with it.
- I don't think it's so scary.
- It's great fun, will look good when running.
Yes indeed.
It will look fun.
But, we have heard that Gröna Lund should be very scary this year.
More horror houses, more ghosts, more witches, more attractions that are open.
Here we go!
- Yes, now we drive!
- Yay!
Check out what a large spider, Harry.
Hussein went to the toilet.
- Are you peppy to see him, right?
- What you jump.
Aaah!
Hahaha!
- Should I walk around with this one?
- Absolutely!
It is absolutely amazing.
Wait, I have to film.
It's so fun!
It is a huge.
And just that you sit like this on it ... your feet just ...
- Welcome!
Do you want to have a piece of candy?
- No, you must not eat sweets.
- Do you also want a candy piece?
- Yes.
Hope they taste.
- It's a cheat day.
- Yes.
Check out Alma.
Should we split?
- It's married!
You can't eat that.
- Oh my God!
No no no.
Just get in.
I can not take it...
- The legs below.
You must have your legs underneath.
- Well, sorry.
I have pain in my legs.
We are not stuck.
You have to down with your legs.
It is only the baby that is stuck.
It is a special show today so there are no queues, but I still did not get a seat on this ride.
- Now we will switch to the big area.
- I've taken off my suit.
- You can't walk in horror houses with a baby.
It's not possible.
- No, especially when sitting on your shoulders.
- What is it, Harry?
- Up there!
Oh yeah, the lousy pumpkin.
Hello then, please the page.
Just right.
Now we go through the portal to the slightly more unpleasant, scary side.
Mo ha ha ha ha!
Are these scary?
No, it can't move.
Come came, my little ones ...
Stop.
Do you see over there on a big stage?
There, the new horror attraction is the sect.
It is the scariest thing they have here at Gröna Lund.
- Should we go there?
- Yes.
- I'm just kidding!
We should not go there.
- It's really scary and brand new.
It is a 13-year limit, 11 years of adult, although it is a recommendation.
If you dare, you can go in.
- Do you dare, Alma?
- No.
- Neither do I.
- You don't have to.
I dare to go in.
It will be me, Axel and Hussein who then test the sect then.
Clearly.
- We'll find a babysitter for you, maybe.
- Yes.
I know who - the two witches that followed us last year.
- Yes exactly.
- Just that, the one who dropped his nose.
They are coming soon.
- Oh, here it's a fire show.
- Do you remember that token?
I get scared!
- Are you scared?
- mm.
- Why is that?
- It is scary.
- What do you think?
- Eeeh ...
Okay, weird.
Behind you!
Look at the teeth.
Oh, what scary teeth!
LOL!
- Run!
- There is no danger, there is no danger.
He is just an ordinary person with makeup, loose teeth and red lentils that make his eyes red.
How quiet you are.
Are you not happy?
I who want happy people here at my circus.
I recognize a real rack kid when I see one.
- Mom, maybe you should check behind you.
- Oh!
Come, Alma.
Did it fall asleep?
- Do you want to shake hands with it?
- No.
- May I do it?
- Yes.
Harry, come.
He is really sweet.
Check out, he's kind.
Shake hands.
How brave you are!
Cool, friend!
Check ... what a scary.
- It wasn't so dangerous, Harry.
- No.
- It was pretty kind.
- It was the one who scared you so much last year.
Yes.
Why so urgent?
Shouldn't we greet a little?
Look, here we have someone who thinks she's safe behind the camera.
As wrong as you can have.
- Who are you?
- I'll take care of you this stay.
Where are we going?
I don't know, you can suggest.
In that case, I think in there, the sect.
There is a nice cemetery with a coffin you can warm up in, huh?
I'd rather not warm myself in a coffin.
You have no choice if you go in there.
Then you have renounced all rights to your own decisions.
- Joanna, don't trust him.
- No, I don't trust him.
- It feels like there are more scary beings in the park this year.
- Yes indeed.
Now we make a break from the horror and go the wild mouse instead.
Come on, Harry.
This is good.
We will go off!
Aaah!
There was some scary type over there.
What did he say?
He told me I would rest in a coffin, so Harry doesn't like him.
Can we go now?
- Where are we going?
- The witches are coming.
Well, oh.
Yes, there we have one.
Check.
Aaahahaha!
In here, the clowns are doing - thus, the actors.
We should go in "Behind the scenes" - that is, behind the secret door - and check out.
Here is the door, turn around.
Super -exciting!
- Will we meet some clowns?
- No, we will not meet any scary type now.
Check!
Here there are creepy clown suits, and so it says the clowns' name.
Here is one that Alma could have.
- Isn't it too big?
- Yes, but it will be quite fun.
- Here is one that Harry could have.
- Yes, it's like the Joker.
- You can wear all the clothes underneath.
Do you want to test them?
- Yes.
- The green has given permission, I not only came to this.
- Should you make up like the joker?
Yes, you can also make up if you go up the stairs.
- Welcome.
- Thanks.
- Is it possibly you who will be scary clowns?
- Yes.
Alma and I.
All right!
- I would have to take off the hat, is that okay?
- mm.
- I'll paint a little white first, on my face.
So, how lousy?
This will be the revenge of the children against all ghosts, circus directors and clowns who scared them in the park.
Thanks, Grönan, for this.
Great!
Drive!
- Aaah!
- Aaaaaaah!
- Scare him, he's scared.
- Aah!
Now I will scare the circus director.
I'm going to take revenge because he made Harry so scared.
What kind of horrible creatures?!
- It has become dark, and it's been time.
- Yes.
- The sect.
Now we drive, we three.
The children are and go with an employee.
- No, but I run the wild mouse instead.
- No no no!
Come now.
- This one will be scary.
- It's much, much scary than last year.
Yes!
It is not possible to compare.
No God, that is a real man.
HELP ME!
Help me!
Over there.
We stand outside the entrance again, Gröna Lund has closed.
It was only open for two hours today.
What do you think?
- Fun.
- Great fun, and scary.
- Scary!
- So scary.
It was so scary this year!
I don't know if it comes out in what we have filmed, but it was so ...
- Not for me.
No one scared me.
- No?
Before you got this and started scaring others, wasn't it scary then?
- I scared people twice.
- Yes.
- But you also got scared.
- You got a little scared too, huh?
Yes.
- The circus director was the worst.
- Yes, he was.
He was definitely the worst.
I thought we should take a question of today, which we have taken before, but it comes every week from several people.
And it is: "Where is Hussein?", "What does Hussein do?", "Where does Hussein live?".
Okay, what should I say now ... I'm plugging.
I don't live with The Swedish Family anymore.
- Hussein has moved away from home, become an adult.
- Yes exactly.
Mom, why did he live with us?
I needed a home, I was homeless.
I found you - or, you found me - I got to stay with you.
- I'm so happy we found you.
- Yes, we really are.
I also.
It is not even possible to describe - when Alma and Harry saw Hussein, run towards him, jump up and ...
- Alma just "he's my brother", from the first day.
- super cozy.
You have really been like siblings.
You who like me and are interested in what I do can follow my Instagram down here.
After the plug, maybe I will start my own Youtube channel.
- Yes, we really hope so!
- It would be fun to see.
- Keep your fingers crossed.
- If you help me too.
Thanks for watching this video!
Feel free to leave a thumbs up, or down.
Comment, ask questions and have a great time until we see you next time.
Bye!