Iceland, here we come!
!
- Laura, was it good?
- Ah ... no!
It was probably not in my taste.
Licorice tastes like burnt car tires, I think.
Okay then, we drive!
Hello Hello!
Today we will test candy from ...
Iceland!
We got this package sent to us by a very nice viewer, called Freya, a long time ago.
Yes.
- "OUII!"
(Candy) - Yes, full of "ouii"!
Then it actually disappeared a little at home.
We lost it in the house.
Then we found it and just, "Oh! We'll do this!"
And what did Alma and Harry say then?
- No.
It's just licorice, and we hate licorice.
- It's not just licorice.
- Yes!
Now we will be positive.
How cute is not by Freya to have sent a lot of candy from Iceland to us?
- Giant!
- Yes, of course, that's cute.
But that's so ... BLA.
They have not been sucked, but now seventeen in me we drive!
Are you ready?
- Yes!
- Yes ...
- (Axel) Woho!
- (Harry) "Ouii!"
- "Sterkur draumur" - (Alma Harry laughs)
It is a chocolate candy with a licorice bar inside.
It is a brine bar that is inside.
- How do you know that?
- It's on the package.
- Oh, Laura has already started.
We have to catch up!
- Yes, now we drive.
- (shoulder) mm.
- (Joanna) etc.
(Harry) etc.
(laugh)
- But he hasn't eaten it!
- You have cheated!
- Haven't you chewed?
- No.
- Take now, Harry.
- Was it good?
- Yes, it was good.
- (Joanna) etc.!
- (Laura) Mmm.
- Laura, you really seem to like it.
- Exciting with a bar in the chocolate.
- Yes.
- Exciting version, you could say.
- (Alma, Slot) AA ...
Alma just, aa ...
- What do you think?
- In other words...
Oh, he disappears.
I've tasted worse licorice, and this one was not so horrible.
- I think the licorice was better than the chocolate.
- (Joanna) etc.
- My!
- Yes yes, okay.
Sorry.
- Laura seems to like it a lot.
- Yes.
It was probably not in my taste.
- (Laura) eww.
- (Harry) eww.
What points do you give from 0-5?
- I give 2. - ooh!
I give...
- Oh no, she vomits here.
- ... a light zero.
- Zero, zero, zero ... - zero, superhero!
- Harry, did you notice what just happened here?
- No.
- She vomits type.
Laura, was it good?
- Ah ... no!
- I give this a 3rd.
- I also give a 3rd.
Gimme, Gimme, Gimme Some Time to Think I'm in the Bathroom, Looking at Me
- Are you ashamed of me a little?
- (Harry) ... is all in need.
Gimme, Gimme, Gimme Some Time to Think I'm in the Bathroom, Looking at Me
"Old -fashioned Lakrids"
There are soft licorice pieces.
It looks like it's parts of a ...
Oops!
... licorice strap.
This will probably be the candy I like the least.
Pure licorice!
Who eats like this?
So, you are so negative.
Lots of people eat it.
I eat it.
I thought we would eat this last!
Meh.
So, it is not good that you have seen the candies since before.
We don't usually do that.
- No.
- I notice now that it was not a good idea.
- But now we drive, I think.
- Here we go!
Okay then.
Oh, sweet chalk.
Or, well ... it was probably a little salty anyway.
That tasted good.
I'll take one more.
How can you dislike licorice so much?
Does all the kids do that?
No.
- No.
Only you are so stupid.
(Alma) eww.
No, I can't do this.
- (Laura) No, Blä.
- You don't like it either?
"No, blow."
But then ... is there a lot of licorice in Iceland?
We can throw out the question to you who come from there, or live there, or have been there.
- There may be a lot of sweets from other countries there.
- Right.
But just the Icelandic candy may be more licorice.
Hello, this is my place!
Musical chairs!
What points do you give?
Zero, zero, zero, zero ...
- Zero, zero, zero, zero, zero, zero ... - ... zero, zero, zero, zero, zero ...
- "Noj, noj!"
I love that you have a big zero on your chest now too, Harry.
- Yes exactly.
Here.
- ... zero, zero, zero, zero, zero ...
"Noj, noj, noj ..."
Okay, the kids agree on a zero.
What does Axel give?
- I give 1 point.
- I give 2 points.
Don't forget to push thumbs up if you like to see when we test sweets.
"Sambó Thristur"
It looks like a very common chocolate praline.
A very common chocolate praline ... with licorice in.
- huh?
- mm.
- I don't feel the licorice.
- Neither do I.
- It's because the previous licorice was so strong.
Harry, eat!
Stop cheating.
- I like the texture.
- I also like the texture.
It is very special.
- This one was actually not so horrible.
- Like middle of a chocolate praline and chewing gum, type.
Look, maybe it's happening now ... They start to like licorice.
- Yes exactly.
- No.
Iceland, here we come!
No never.
Never!
Licorice tastes like burnt car tires, I think.
- But "Iceland, here we come" can you still press yes?
- Okay, I can press that.
- Who doesn't want to go to Iceland?
- Good question.
Laura has put in the pacifier, and doesn't seem so hungry.
Harry.
What points do you give?
- A 3rd.
- A 3rd?
- A strong 3rd.
- Same here.
- Well.
- Oh oh oh.
- Me too.
Hörrudu, now you have to stop with that drum orchestra.
Everyone gives a 3rd.
- Yes.
- Okay then, we drive!
(Harry screams)
"Lakkrís Caramel Superbrees"
(The others laugh)
There are round chocolate beads filled with licorice.
- This one I think can be quite good.
- Why do you think that?
- No, but then, because it is caramel.
- Aah ... then we drive!
1, 2, 3.
(Shoulder) mmm ...
Quite good, Alma.
Pretty good.
Chocolate that tastes dust.
Or I don't know if it was the licorice that tastes dust maybe.
- It almost tastes spirits, in some strange way.
- Yes.
Very adult and boring.
No, not fun.
Not fun.
Fy f*n.
No but...
Sorry.
This is such a candy that is at home with a pensioner and who never gets eaten.
God, now I got a laughing attack.
This one was actually horrible.
Yes, it was very boring.
And then I took another one.
I don't understand why I took another one.
Okay, now Mom starts with: Noooool ...
Noooool.
Noooool ...
Noooool!
- (Laura) NNNNNN ... - (Alma, in English) Very nice!
Very good!
- We take a break to answer today's question.
- Yes.
And it comes from Freya, who sent the package.
“If Laura had been a boy ...
- Uaua.
(Laura) - Yes, exactly.
Uaua.
... what would he have been called then? "
- Great question.
- Do you remember?
I don't think we had any names.
- Yes.
- Leo.
- No.
- Yes.
That was Harry's proposal.
- We talked about Eliott.
- Eliott was my suggestion.
- What was mine, then?
Stone.
Forgive everyone named Sten out there, but to imagine Laura as Sten ...
- No, she's no stone.
She is a Laura.
- Yes.
Or a pupa!
Pupita!
"Nóa body"
It looks like chocolate with bubbles in.
- This is the first candy that does not contain licorice.
- Yes!
- Woho!
- Let's go!
- There were no bubbles.
- Yes, there is biscuit chocolate in there. Like small biscuits.
Yes, okay.
The chocolate on the other sweets was so much better than this chocolate.
I agree with.
- Is it good?
- Aa.
- How nice.
- Laura likes this one.
What points do you give?
I give 3 out of 5.
- And Harry?
- 3 out of 5.
2 out of 5.
- Why did it become "of 5" all of a sudden?
- 2 points.
I give 2.
- Do you need help up, right?
- Yes thank you.
Ouch.
Harry ...
God, you are too snappy.
(Alma Harry) I am a poor peasant boy, but I still live
"Lakkrís Rjómasúkkulaði Með Lakkrísbitum"
(The others laugh)
It looks like a very common piece of chocolate stuck with small tubers on the underside.
- It feels like we've eaten the same thing now and time again.
- Yes.
- Chocolate with licorice in. - Yes.
It is getting a little tedious.
- This one had sweet chalk in anyway.
- huh?
I think it tastes salty.
I seem to have a little trouble with that with sweet and salty, but it's licorice in.
- mm.
Small type sticky squares.
- Yes.
I think this tastes old cheek egg chocolate with burnt car tires in.
I give this chocolate 1 point.
I give this chocolate ... noooool!
Noooool!
Zero.
Nooooool!
(Laura) NOJ!
Zero!
"Djúpur" There are white bullets with ... licorice.
(Shoulder sighs)
(Alma) eww.
Oh no!
(Alma Harry screams and spits and laughs in the toilet)
It wasn't fun.
It's not fun.
It is very sandy.
It's licorice sand.
This one wasn't fun.
But it was not strong or so.
This is the worst liquorice I've eaten.
It like stuck in the teeth.
You just, uää ...
You cleanse your teeth.
It became like a fine -grained dust throughout the mouth.
He stands and pulls out his own tongue.
You know what?
This was the last Icelandic candy.
(All the kids) Yeah!
What do we think of Iceland?
Good!
What do we think of Icelandic candy?
- Bad!
- No, this feels awful.
We must not be so awful.
- Iceland's licorice maybe ...
Exactly!
So we can say.
What do we think of Icelandic licorice?
But...
I get some bad conscience here for kind Freya who has bought sweets for us and sent us.
Yes, it was so nice, but ... It's just that I and Harry really don't like licorice.
- No.
It's not our thing.
Is it your thing, at home?
Is Lakrits your thing?
Comment below!
Thanks for watching this video!
- Feel free to leave a thumbs up, or down.
- Most thumbs up!
Comment, ask questions and have a great time until we see you next time.
Bye!