Hello Hello!
We are in Khao Lak in Thailand.
You should hang on to us for a whole day.
It is half past nine o'clock in the morning.
Last time we were vlogs we were at another hotel.
We had a great time there, but this hotel is a paradise for children!
Yes it really is.
Now we're going to have breakfast!
Quite a little stuff.
A yogurt, a chocolate milk, and scrambled eggs and bacon.
What is the best thing about hotel breakfast?
Yoghurt!
God!
What happened there?
Yoghurt!
You just ... okay.
Harry has always loved yogurt.
- What is the name of this pool?
- The pirate pool.
- Why?
- Because it's pirates, do you see?
Should we take a photo to Instagram?
Of course.
It is so fun for every day when you are at this pool so something happens.
If it is Bamse, or Captain T, or anyone else who comes and greets the children.
Harry, stand next to it.
There, yes.
- Did you get a good card?
- Yes, of course!
- Now Alma and Harry play in the pool with friends.
- Yes.
- They have so many friends here.
- They really find new friends all the time.
Yes.
Today, the children's club has closed, but otherwise in the mornings between 10am.
10-12 goes shoulder ...
... Axel at Bamseklubb!
I go to Bamseklubb, and the kids ... have some home time.
Harry goes in there at the Bamseklubben downstairs.
- Do you see?
Yes, you see.
- Yes.
Up there there is something called 611, all ... thus ...
"Allå", "Allå, so" ...
Sometimes it just gets wrong.
611. 611 club, for children between 6 and 11. It goes on.
They have great fun every day!
- And we get some time ... - ... for ourselves.
- Yes.
They meet friends, they play.
It is great TUI hosts who take care of them.
You can choose whether you want the children to be there in the morning or in the afternoon.
Yes.
There are two hours in the morning, and two hours in the afternoon.
You can choose to be there both and then we would not even see our children, so we do not want that anyway.
No, exactly.
Now we are going to go the blue big water slides!
- Alma, what is this?
- It's a stone collection.
First we dived down and picked them up from the bottom.
Here is the big pile.
Here are white, orange, and black.
This is what it looks like on the bottom.
I love that there is sand on the bottom.
It's so good for my feet.
Listen, should we go and have lunch?
Now we went down to a pool located right on the beach, and here is a great lunch restaurant.
Alma and Harry found their friends directly in the pool, so they just disappeared.
Hello!
- Good with food after all the bathing, huh?
- Mm!
- What do you eat?
- Egg Fried Rice.
I'll dive in the ketchup!
Now we will show our fantastic house!
Welcome!
Here is our very own pool!
Woho!
Alma has invited friends home several times, so we have had a pool party.
Sat on some music, offered fruit and water.
Great!
Now it is newly cleaned in here.
So nice!
Welcome in, in the small office.
Wow!
They have really made an effort!
- Mom?
- Yes?
That is your heart that thumps, and there is dad's heart that thumps.
- And there is everyone's hearts that thump!
- Is this everyone's hearts?
Yes.
Everyone's hearts that thump.
So this is made of towels ... if you don't see it.
- And that is made of stones?
- No, these are small leaves.
It's petals!
Huh ...
It's true!
So this is mine and Axel's bed.
The children have this round bed couch.
- Are you sleeping well here?
- Mm, it's the worst princess bed!
It is quite quick to do a house tour here.
Here the children can look out at the pool.
Here we have coffee, tea, water, and a refrigerator.
And then it's the patio here.
Out towards the sea.
Here we have a bathroom and toilet.
Here is our little dressing room.
It can actually be closed like this ... "Now I'm going to change".
And then you can choose someone here.
- "K"?
- Yes, what will it be?
- "LOK" ... locomotive!
- locomotive, yes.
Good!
We plug in a little.
- Short.
- "Short", yes!
We alternate a little neighbor with pool swimming, because it gets so hot.
- We wouldn't really be here now.
- No, that's right.
This trip is a collaboration with TUI and we would be in Khao Lak for two weeks, at two different hotels.
But when we had been here at Mai Khao Lak for just a few days, we felt we had to stay longer!
Yes.
It was so wonderful to come here.
The whole family came into a holiday loss.
- Yes.
- It was really nice.
We should not be in New Zealand until the first February, so it was possible to solve because it is low season.
Mm.
Together with TUI, we have an offer for those who want to travel to this hotel.
- A thousand SEK discount ... - ... if you use the code "Family" when you book.
You can travel until March 2020, but you have to book before January 28 - ie this week.
All info is in the descriptive text.
Check it out!
We are on our way to the store to buy cashews.
There is a small fishing village ... A very old fishing village located right next to the hotel over here.
- I am very happy that it is there!
- Yes, it will be a small adventure.
Before we had children we had kind of lived in that fishing village.
- Now I can really appreciate teddy bear and resort life.
- Yes indeed.
But it is so nice to be able to go and see something else.
- Yes.
They have a lot of massage here.
- That looks nice.
- Yes.
What many small hermit crayfish.
No thanks.
- What did he say?
- He asked if we wanted to eat there.
- No thanks.
Did you say no thanks?
- Yes exactly.
I didn't want to, because it was a bit boring to eat food and not buy nuts.
Hands behind your back.
Wow ...
Harry.
- Here they have cashews.
- And candy!
Yes, lots of sweets.
But not very Thai.
This is Thai.
- And this.
- Yes.
- And this!
- No, Haribo is not Thai.
But then, corner ...
We have a question for the viewers, I just came up with.
- You know what?
- No.
- Do you want to watch a video where we test Thai candy?
- Yes!
Comment below: Yes or No.
We do as you please!
It is six o'clock and soon the sun goes down.
It is very nice to go here!
We have made ourselves in order for dinner, and I noticed that everyone has been sunbathing today.
- Yes.
- Harry.
Harry, you have red cheeks.
- What are you looking at?
- The water.
Yes, of course it is nice.
You get reassured by the beach.
Now the sun went down.
Do you hear, Alma?
It's all crickets!
- Oh, God what they play!
- Yes!
- They just started playing, after all.
- Yes.
Alma, what do you think about this place?
The best thing I've been to, I think!
I ... I'm kind of distracted by the waves.
♪ Hello Bamse, strongest is our teddy bear.
♪
♪ But he doesn't like to fight!
♪ Dunder honey, Grandma's thunder honey he eats to be strong of course.
♪
- It's show here every night!
- Yes.
- Harry's favorite is Bamse.
- Yes, and Alma's favorite is the disco coming soon.
We are back in our house, and now we will sleep.
Thanks for watching this video!
Feel free to leave a thumbs up ...
... or down.
- Or in between.
- Yes, maybe ... exactly.
Comment, ask questions, and have a great time until we see you next time!
- See you!
- Bye!
Adjoken!
Goodbye!