God, what a fail!
It's just sunny outside.
Give it to me!
Give me them!
Yes, the mood went ...
Alma is a little scared on trains.
You have to respect it.
It says Uaua.
(Laura)
- Is it Laura?
- Yes.
- Let's see.
- Show it to mom.
- No, it says Alma.
- It's UAUA!
Yes, okay.
She very much wants this pink stamp to be her stamp.
UAUA!
We are trying to record this video with a new camera.
Yes.
- A new camera.
So if picture or sound is a little different, then you know why.
This is what it looks like, the new camera.
It's so small.
And soon Christmas is corner, so I have this.
- Hello.
- Hello!
What are you doing?
I play with my toys.
- We are testing the new camera.
- mm.
- Surely it is small?
How is it?
Good.
You seem a little sad almost.
Nah.
- Sure?
- mm.
Could it be that you are a little angry because you couldn't sit with the screen anymore?
A little.
Harry sat and played Roblox and then ended the screen time.
And yes, the mood went ...
We are pretty used to it and I think many families are.
- What?
Speeding of screen disease?
- Yes.
That children get sad when you say that it is enough with screen.
Yes.
Completely oblique dopamine levels.
I think that is very common.
- I think we should try to get out of the house.
- Yes.
- Mom, give me the pacifier today!
- No.
- What do you scream about, Laura?
- Uaua have the pacifier today!
No, there will be no pacifier today.
We take the pacifier fight.
No, not, mom!
Uaua have the pacifier!
- No, no pacifier.
Only when to sleep.
- No!
I don't want to sleep with it!
- No.
- Ugh!
(Proprut sounds)
Wrong way.
(Pip) Yes!
Okay, good.
It is green!
- (Alma) Come, come, come!
- (Harry) Otherwise the doors will be closed.
- No, my turn there!
- (Alma) Shhh.
But Alma is a little scared on trains.
You have to respect it.
She wanted you to come on quickly.
I was so scared.
Can't you help me?
Can't you hold my hand and hug me and say that everything will be fine?
- Uaua have the carriage, then?
- No, you must not pick up your trolley now.
You can do it when we get off.
- We will count on one first.
- A station.
Does your train fear feel something better?
So, not really.
After all, it is still difficult to go by train.
Yes, I noticed that.
But I thought if it has gotten better after this semester?
A little better, because I and Harry have traveled to school sometimes ...
Check out, now you get the shade of the camera straight across the face.
"Sorry" for that.
But I know.
And I thought about it, that we filmed a morning routine when you went by train to school-
-In like September, October, and then you talked ...
- Mom!
- Hello!
... about your traffic phobia.
- Yes.
- And then we got a lot of super nice comments.
It was so nice really.
In other words...
It means so much that when I say something that is hard for me, that you dare say that too.
Because I know like it's hard to talk about.
- Can we buy ice cream and sweets?
- Not right now because now Alma is talking about something that is important.
Buy ice cream and sweets ...
So for me it really means a lot that you chose to write so many nice comments, and just ...
"I'm also afraid of it, and I feel this way, and I'm afraid of it."
I remember it so well, because you sat and read on my mobile and became almost teary eyed, comment after comment.
And so there were so many so we couldn't answer everyone, but we read everyone.
And then you can take the opportunity to thank now, even though it has gone ...
A few months.
- Yes.
Thank you for sharing.
- Really nice.
It means a lot.
- We probably haven't told us where we are going.
- No.
I have put on my most uncomfortable clothes, because we will actually go and buy a Christmas tree.
- Me too!
- You too.
Yes.
Although we will only buy a Christmas tree.
I want a plot.
- A Christmas tree and a plot.
It is enough.
- It is enough!
- Is this the Christmas tree we should buy?
- No, I think it's just too big.
This one cannot take on the train.
This is probably one of those silver spruce too ...
... which certainly holds very well, but I think it will cost half a fortune.
When we were here the other day she had a lot of fir trees, which is why we went back here.
And now it just seems that the most expensive and finest Christmas tree remains.
But we must probably ask.
- Although she has a small deal there, she may have more.
- Yes exactly.
- Should we go and check out?
- We go and look.
(Portuguese) - Hi, do you have other Christmas trees?
- I have it, and one that is closed.
- There.
- Well.
Okay.
This is the only other Christmas tree they have.
It's a bit depressed, it stands here in the backyard.
But it looks very big.
- Yes.
Although it is easier to transport.
- It is very much easier to transport.
- What do you think, Harry?
- I think it looks pretty good.
I like those who are high.
But you buy the Christmas tree in the bag as well.
You do not know what you get.
No, but I had expected a much smaller than the two she has left, I can say.
These have been left behind because they are so big.
No one can accommodate them.
- (Portuguese) please.
- (English please.
- What should we do?
Should we buy a giant fun?
- So, yes.
But how should we get it home?!
But she says she can fix that kind of someone can drive it home to us, though ...
It is unclear.
We do not know.
But hearing.
Those two were in the Christmas tree just recently.
Why are you carrying around on them?
Give it to me!
Give me them!
- "Give me them"?
- God, what spoiled.
Piff and puff are allowed to stay here.
They must not come along.
Portuguese piff and puff.
- They come along.
- No, they must not come home.
They come along!
Oh...
You are a good negotiator, Laura.
But I do not know.
We get to consult with the rest of the family.
We got the Christmas tree home, but not the same day we were there but the day after that.
And then it went another day because it had to stand here and just get used to the indoor climate.
Yes.
And I needed to move some houseplants and so on.
But now this one is and it is huge.
- It's huge.
- Yes.
And Alma and Harry have gone their last school day.
Yes.
- How does it feel?
- Good.
- Do it?
- Yes.
Awesome, that is.
Now I see that you are looking at yourself on the screen.
Axel, help me so he doesn't see it.
That with a new camera ...
Then I have to spin around it.
- Gosh!
And then I have to do this, then.
- Yes.
But tomorrow you have school closure.
- I have to see the picture of myself.
- Nämen, stop!
How does it feel to you, Alma?
So, it is a bit boring and a little fun, because it is like the end of something, but also the beginning of something else.
- Yes.
You finish in this school.
- We get to see how it gets.
- Yes.
- Yes, we really get to see.
Where is Laura now?
Laura is on her crèche, ie kindergarten, so ... and she has barely eaten in the middle.
I know.
So we have some home time without her.
Yeah!
- Are you happy with it?
- Yes, quite.
- She takes up quite a lot.
- mm.
Quite.
- Okay, she takes a lot of space.
- Very much space.
We paid 80 \ Heuro for this Christmas tree.
There is a lot of money here in Portugal, but they do not have fir trees here in the same way we have up the north.
- But what does a spruce cost in Sweden?
- Yes, what does a spruce cost in Sweden?
I have no idea anymore.
- Comment below, or what?
- Yes, you must say.
Comment on what a spruce ...
- Are we robbed with our type of 900 kroner spruce?
- With home delivery.
Yes maybe.
But it is worth it for a little Christmas atmosphere.
Yes, but what about the Christmas atmosphere?
Alma, you who stand here barefood and go in shorts and so on.
So ... like that.
But I don't really think the Christmas atmosphere is snow.
Huh?
It is clear that Christmas atmosphere is snow.
So, it is a big deal, and cold too, though like, the Christmas mood is so much more too.
- Do you have a Christmas mood, Harry?
- No not at all.
And what is it, then?
So ... mostly because we kind of are in a very hot country.
It doesn't even snow.
It's just sunny outside.
It's sunset.
- Hello.
- Hello Hello!
(Alma) TA-DA!
It's the Christmas tree, Laura.
- Gosh!
- Did you get shy now?
Hello ... friend!
Did you get a little shy ... for the Christmas tree?
Or what happened there?
Thus, God what a "fail."
(failure) We thought she would be surprised.
And happy.
- No.
- Didn't you be happy when you saw the Christmas tree?
- Are you going to put your little spiff and puff?
It became one.
Piff.
- Up in the Christmas tree.
- Should we put it up there?
Yes.
You managed to negotiate a spice that lives in the Christmas tree.
- Yes, it was a little fun anyway.
- Give me it, then.
- "Give me it, then."
- Well, now you should start going and picking.
Should you sit in my lap?
You're so funny.
You can check it.
There are many nice lights in the Christmas tree.
And lots of balls and packages and socks.
- What do you have there?
- corn.
It's a new day again.
- And Alma and Harry are at school closure.
- Yes.
- We were not allowed to participate in it.
- No.
Boring, but it can be sometimes.
And Laura, she is in kindergarten.
Every year we get the same today's question from several.
We have already received it on Instagram, and that is what the kids should get in Christmas.
Yes.
We understand that it is exciting.
And since this video comes up the day before Christmas Eve, we can show, because then Alma and Harry will not be able to look.
No, exactly.
Laura does not really have the knowledge yet.
But we can start with her Christmas present from us.
A new "o bebê", and "o bebê" is thus the baby.
Right.
And what happens when you pull out the pacifier, then?
(Baby crying)
No, this is going to be very busy.
(The baby is coping)
- And it can talk a little.
- "Mom. Mom."
- It said "Mom."
That's me.
No, it's Laura!
- Yes.
- And ... do you want to show Harry's gift, right?
- Yes I can do that.
Harry is for a while in his life where he will start to keep track of just that - time.
So that's why I've bought a watch for him.
This is a watch from Swatch ... the watch mark.
But it is a special edition that has been published together with Omega,-
-So it resembles an old classic omega.
And there is a timer and a regular watch on it, so I hope he likes it.
I like it anyway.
Won't he use it so ...
It is such a gift that you really wanted.
I kind of wanted to have this now, but yes ... so it is to him.
Alma has wanted such a set of "rhinestones."
I don't know if you see it through the plastic, but there are small crystals that you glue on ...
In lots of different colors.
... on type mobile shell, or you can put them on bags, shoes and so on.
Here is some applicantor and here is a big tweezers that belongs.
She's a great point on this so, yes ...
It will be interesting to see what her shoes look like later.
- Yes.
These were the three gifts that we feel we can show.
- And now we're going to hit them.
- Yes, we will.
Once upon a time, I was very good at wrapping packages because I worked at NK as a clerk.
But yes.
No longer.
- You lost it a bit.
- Yes, God.
Are you kidding?
We had to take a package wrapping course, we who worked at NK.
- Because it would go fast or be neat?
- Because it would be beautiful.
So, what is this strange picture?
You just see the bed.
- But it was meant to see the packages.
- God, then.
- We can raise a little.
- Give me the tape.
Now it is fully complained.
Yes, but see.
So there.
Oh, the wall looks green, I think.
What do you think at home?
Does it look green or blue?
It is blue.
So there.
They have neither short nor names written.
No its true.
Should we fix it, right?
Oh!
They may well have to guess and think.
They are allowed to sit here and dream away in the Christmas tree.
It is good.
This became a fairly slow and extended vlog over several days.
Yes, and I think it was pretty nice for us to do such a vlog.
It has been quite stressful and hot during the fall.
Yes indeed.
It has been a lot of projects and travel and everything we have had for us.
You have had a lot in school too, and with training and so on.
- And I've written a book.
- Yes!
So good!
And club and Kenya and, yes.
Yes.
So it felt quite right to just slow down for Christmas and just run a little quiet pace.
I started to wonder if it was this camera that made us a little slower.
I do not know.
What do you think who has looked?
Is it "slow"?
You may have to leave a comment about the sound, about the picture, and about the camera and ...
- What you like and what you dislike.
- Yes exactly.
And in conclusion, we wish everyone a ...
MERRY CHRISTMAS!
Yeah.
And of course we see you before New Year's Eve.
Thanks for watching this video!
Feel free to leave a thumbs up, or down.
Comment, ask questions and have a great time until we see you next time.
- See you!
- Bye!