- Oh, that's the way you get sweaty.
- Yes, I also knew it.
♪ zero, zero, zero, zero ... ♪
Hello Hello!
Today we will test candy from ...
Finland!
Where you invent things.
Oh really?
Yes maybe.
In our most recent postal opener video we got Finnish candy sent to us by a nice viewer in Finland, named Ingrid.
She asked if we wanted to test Finnish candy and we said "Yes!".
A short time later, this appeared with "Posti".
Here's a letter!
This is a package full of Finnish candy-
-Which has been sent to us from Liam and Tindra and their parents Sabrina and Robert.
They live in Ekenäs in Finland, and they want us to test this Finnish candy.
- Of course we will do it!
- So fun!
Are you ready?
- Yes!
Here we go!
"Pantteri - Sour Cat"
It is thus jelly candies shaped like the panth faces.
- Should we just choose each color, right?
- I'll take this yellow.
- I take pink.
- I'll take this.
- Orange.
What is left for me, then?
- Green or black.
I'll take a green this time.
- Are you ready?
- Yes!
1, 2, 3 ...
- fruity.
Pretty cute, not so angry.
- No!
"Sour Cat" - I didn't think it was so angry.
Oh...
Harry seems to like it.
No, Harry ...
- He runs one like that ... "Flappity-Flap Man".
- Nämen, Help!
What does this mean?
- Scatman?
- I do not know.
- I flew away.
- You flew away.
Was it so good?
- You must not taste.
Viewers get crazy.
- Oh, sorry.
We get comments about it every time we test sweets.
If you bother with our smoker, I really apologize.
It is difficult to avoid.
What points do you give from 1-5?
Harry begins.
- 4. - 5+.
- 5+, wow.
3.5.
- 3.
“Suffeli”
It is thus a chocolate dipped biscuit.
Oh, it's caramel in.
- It tastes like regular biscuit chocolate.
- Najs!
So, I have eaten so very boring biscuits.
This one is much better than biscuit chocolate, Harry.
This one was much better than those where robbery you can buy in the bag as well.
It was really good.
Ronald?!
- There is something white here too.
- It's something foam-foam, or something.
I thought, from 1-5 ... so I thought ...
Maybe ... oh, I think, I think.
Two fives.
- Two fives?
- Yes.
Oh, wow.
I thought 5+ again, and I thought it was so good!
- Yes.
Me too.
- I thought so too.
5 from me.
4 from me.
- Almost a full pot.
- Almost.
Potters?
- You say "full pot".
- Well, I thought you meant a full pot.
- "Almost a full pot".
No.
- No, absolutely no full pot.
Don't forget to push a thumbs up if you like when we test sweets.
“Pepe”
It is a soft licorice bar.
I ate like this when I was a kid, I know it's really good.
Or, I thought so anyway.
It's sweet chalk.
- Eww ... - It's super good!
It looks like the world's longest cigarette.
- Cigarettes are usually not black.
- And you don't usually blow them.
- Good texture on licorice, I think.
- Super good.
Nam, Nam.
Hörrududu!
Don't try, Harry.
Awesome, Harry.
Good work.
- Gosh!
- So ... what's wrong with you?
It sounds like he spits down my neck, but he doesn't.
We have a sink behind it.
So, how can you not like sweet chalk?
- It was delicious.
- I also think it was good.
I don't like licorice because it's black, disgusting, sticky, long ...
(Harry Hickar)
Oh.
Hick.
It's disgusting!
I don't like licorice because it's like salty and sweet in one, and it's like "berry" and ...
- "Bearing"?!
- A "berry" taste.
Wondering what it is.
Ah ... you have not understood the good of life.
Or maybe a snail ... a slimy snail mixed with pudding.
So, is it only our children who do not like licorice?
How is it at your house, if you have children at home or if you are a child and watch.
Do you like licorice or not?
Comment below.
- Comment.
- Gladly.
Very.
♪ zero, zero, zero, zero ... ♪
Okay, we understand.
We grasp the wine.
♪ ... zero, zero, zero, zero.
♪
Nämen, stop throwing candy!
- I give four.
- I give two points.
"Maxi Pätkis Crunchy"
It is thus a "crunchy" chocolate piece.
- Oh, mint ... - Yes.
Mint, good.
Mmm, it was actually quite good.
- It could have been so much more good.
- mm, if it wasn't mint.
I agree with that, though not because it's mint, but ...
It was totally okay, but it wasn't so fun inside.
So, the texture was boring.
Where did he go now?
Well.
I give 0 points.
- zero?
- I don't like mint, at all.
null
I'm kind now, I give 2 points.
I liked the rice puffs and chocolate, but I hated the mint.
Oh okay.
I also give 2 points.
“Ässä”
There are small jelly candies in different colors and they are shaped as letters.
- I think you say "Ässä".
- But what was I saying?
- You said "Ässä".
- Oh, what a big difference!
- Now we take.
- Yes!
- 1, 2, 3 ... - Kööör.
Good!
Sour and good.
Mmm, I take one more.
- Oh, that's what you get sweaty from.
- Yes, I also knew it.
You get sweaty on the eyelids.
Don't taste, not taste.
- Oh!
They are properly acidic.
Good!
- The yellow, then?
Have you tested the yellow one?
- No.
- Yes.
It was good.
- Not taste!
- Oooh ... so synthetic.
The yum police.
- I give 5 points.
- Oh!
Good.
I give 3.5.
- Five fives.
- Oh!
They roll around in my skull.
I give 4 points.
"Karl Fazer - Maitosuklaa"
It is thus milk chocolate.
Finnish equivalent of Marabou.
- Though a little more boring.
- Do you think.
I think it is a bit more boring.
It tastes a little more type ... hot chocolate.
It tastes a little grandmother for me.
Good.
Nice.
More tasty.
Thus, more taste inside.
It was good.
I give 3 points.
All at once.
I also give 3.
And Alma?
null
I give 3 points I with.
We take a break to answer today's question, and it comes from Liam and Tindra in the letter.
They wonder if we will ever greet in their small town of Ekenäs, if we come to Finland.
- Gladly!
- Absolutely!
It is okay.
- I actually think I've been to Ekenäs.
- Have you?
I think so.
With my dad, for type ... oh my god, 20 years ago.
"Oh my gosh!"
- We are old.
- Yes.
We really want to go to Finland.
So can we summarize it?
Would love to go all over Finland.
This sable virus just has to disappear first.
Yes.
But we will be very happy to Finland and visit you there.
Yes!
"Suffeli puffi snacks"
It's chocolate puffs.
Oh!
♪ Inside it is corn, though it looks like a little poop!
♪
♪ And it looks like a small deer.
TA-DA!
♪
- Now the sugar has gone to the children's heads.
- Yes.
- Mm, it tastes just like corn.
- mm, it tastes corn.
Slightly.
Well, Majpuff.
With chocolate.
I thought the other "Suffeli" was better.
Yes me too.
It tastes a bit like this badly popped ...
Or, not bad, but like this ... Not that long time popped popcorn with type of chocolate covers.
I give this candy 1.5 points.
I didn't think it was so good.
I give it ... 3.
null
"Hedelmä aakkoset"
Thus, it is romb -shaped jelly candies.
Oh, poor my little "h".
- Did you eat an "h"?
- Yes.
There are letters on all these.
They like letter candies in Finland.
I think.
I think this candy was like a boring good & mixed.
I give it 1 point.
I give it 2 points.
- 1. - 2.
"Jim Bites"
It is a piece of chocolate with white filling.
- It's like ... foamy, a little.
- Nämen Fy ...
- It's some strange foam taste after all.
- It's like a really bad foam candy.
- Oh, a little angry, type.
- I think it tastes a little ... almost a little alcohol.
Come up in the wrong place.
Uh-Oh ...
- So, what is happening?
- I do not know.
Now it is tracking out here.
What do you do?
- They spit out the candy.
- Well.
♪ I ... give ... zero ... points!
♪
♪ Zero ... ♪
♪ I give zero, swimmers, swim around ... ♪
- I give 1 point.
- And I give 1 point.
"Gifu"
There are small black pastils.
- To hard.
- It's Viol flavor!
- Yes it is!
- I thought it was delicious.
Take it easy!
You have to feel the taste before you start reacting.
You have to chew on it properly.
I liked the Viol flavor when I was little.
There is a little xylitol in it too, so I don't know if it's a little ... fresh.
- But it's a bit like Läkerol.
- mm.
- Good for the teeth ... is xylitol.
- Candy that is good for the teeth ...
- But xylitol is good for the teeth.
- Yes.
(Harry Banks to something)
- I give 2 points.
- I give 1 point.
- 1 point.
- 3 points.
Turkish pepper.
It is a black hard candy that many Swedes have tried.
But not Alma and Harry.
- You have to chew on this one.
- You have to chew it.
Turkish pepper that is so good!
Are we not good parents, or huh?
- I don't think it's that dangerous.
- I love Turkish pepper!
When I was little too.
Yes, it is very wonderful!
- So, it burns for real!
- But it burns in a good way.
- Did you break it?
- Yes!
It was like a sauce inside with small grains.
No, it's a powder ... just (schhh) in the mouth.
Check out, it's a fire, mmm ... a good fire.
- Harry, did you break yours?
- No.
Lucky.
- Lucky?
Yes ... - then you haven't even tasted it for real.
A pretty funny candy to have on Halloween when someone comes and knocks on.
I give 4 points.
I give 1 point.
I give 4.5.
Zero!
Thanks for watching this video!
Feel free to leave a thumbs up, or down.
Most thumbs up, mostly thumbs up!
Comment, ask questions and have a great time until we see you next time.
Bye!