- Brrr, how cold it is.
- Yes.
- Great cold.
- You have to jump a little in the trampoline so you get hot.
Yeah!
Alma!
Sorry for the mess we are rebuilding.
No, we clean clothes.
It is a positive thing that it has become a little colder outside, that you grab such things.
The children have grown as flowers this summer.
All of this is an outgrown and should be left to the Stockholm City Mission ... charity.
- Hello.
- Your bag is packed.
- Yes.
How luxurious?
- What should you do?
- I'll sleep over with a friend.
Mm.
We'll drive you into town.
- Two nights you should sleep away.
- Yes.
- You have never done that before.
- Have you?
- At Tanja.
But...
It's a pretend grandmother, so that's another thing.
This is a friend-friend.
Buddy buddy.
Along the way, we should actually stop and look for some new clothes, because we have to supplement before school starts.
You don't like jeans, so you need a little more type of tight stuff I think, huh?
- Yes.
- A little cool things.
Harry likes jeans, but he needs a little more soft pants and stuff.
- Yes, he has a lot of jeans.
- Yes.
We will see what we find so that you are good looking and nice, because if less than two weeks start ...
- School!
- No!
It's true.
School is fun with all friends, but ... So, it's not so ...
It is more fun to have summer vacation.
A lot ... a lot ... a lot, a lot, a lot, a lot.
We have a collaboration with Stadium so we will go to their store in Nacka Forum ...
... to see if they have the stuff we are looking for for the kids.
And I would like to buy some new workout clothes myself.
And I would like to look at a pair of new shoes.
After all, I am one such mom who goes dressed in workout clothes most evenly, whether I exercise or not.
- Yes, that's actually true.
But now you don't.
- No, for once.
Yes.
Hunting them!
He chases us!
The best thing is to pick up some and then go and test.
- I want one like this.
- Good idea.
Oh, oh wow.
- What do you do?
- This is our secret place.
Don't tell anyone.
No, it's just ours.
Spring.
- Just our place.
Now dad comes, hide!
- Where are the kids?
- I have no idea.
I saw some light calufs that disappeared here.
Hello there?
What a good hiding place.
I feel like the worst Christmas tree, now we have to go and test clothes.
Check out, here you can buy tents.
- Do you get hungry?
- Yes, very suck.
Tent in the garden.
- I won!
Welcome in.
Oh!
So there.
Thus, my God.
There are too much cool children's clothing here.
Check this out.
She can't stop dancing because she has such a cool dress.
Should we put down everything we should buy in that one?
- Yes!
- Okay.
- Then the idea is that you and I should find stuff too.
- Yes exactly.
Then the children have to look at something while we are looking.
Now I'm also a Christmas tree.
I go in and try a little.
For real, I am amazed at that stage for both children and adults has such a good mix of exercise and ...
- Street?
- Casual.
Casual!
Exercise/casual.
How do you translate it into Swedish?
"Free"!
Exercise and free.
God what strange all this became.
I go and try.
We are finally ready to choose clothes and Alma has got a job as a cashier.
It smells good.
Yes.
It makes it not smell so bad in the summer when sweating.
You can fold this one.
- Here's another alarm.
- Yes!
Where.
- Is it fun, Alma?
- Yes, giant.
So there.
- Alma, you don't say "thank you"?
- Thanks!
You are welcome.
- How good you were at checkout.
- Thanks.
- Is it hard to wear?
Should I take it?
- Yes.
- That went well.
Great.
We have a little while before we leave Alma to her friend, so we will go to our address in town.
Yes.
Me, Joanna and Harry plan to go out and sail for a few days.
In order for us to live and sleep on the boat, we must have sleeping bags, so we will see if we find our old ones.
In our storage room.
After all, the apartment is still rented out.
I guess Harry will have a Bamse sleeping bag, because that's the only thing I and Harry have.
- I want to bring my superhero costumes.
- They are up in the apartment, I think.
Or are they in the store?
- We have to check.
- Yes, we have to look.
- How do you think it feels to be on our street?
- It's nice.
Come, Gullis.
- How do you think it feels?
- Great and nice.
There are several who have asked when we will get our apartment back.
It is not quite clear yet when we are moving back home.
Those who rent would like to rent longer, and we have some plans for the winter that are not really 100 percent set.
But soon.
- And then we promise to tell on the channel.
- Yes exactly.
Do you find any sleeping bags, then?
Maybe here in.
No.
No, do you know what that is?
There are even more grown clothes that we should give away.
I think they are in this old backpacker back.
Check!
Sleeping bag.
- To me and to Harry.
- Yes, to you two.
And sleeping bag for dad.
Old, from the seventies, but works great.
And last but not least...
Supermodern sleeping bag for mom.
My superhero costumes are not in here.
- What an osis.
- Yes.
Can we go to the school yard for a little while?
Yes we can do that.
And then we can test our new clothes and take some pictures for Instagram.
- Yay!
Yay!
- Check out what nicely, we match.
- Look!
Here!
Oh!
Come then, try to take it!
Alma and Harry.
A completely natural situation.
So here we always lie.
Don't all families do it?
- The kids feel relaxed ... - But hello, stop with that!
- Wow, the worst thumbnail.
- Yes, I say so!
Do you feel ready for autumn and school and preschool?
No.
So, I say no because I have thought that the summer holidays have been too short.
Do you feel ready for the fall?
Comment below.
Below...
Now I'm going to swing a little.
Harry wants to swing himself, he says.
I can't swing him.
(Alma) I taught him to swing myself yesterday.
Nice, Harry!
- May I put?
- Yes.
We have answered some questions in this vlog already, but we take a question of today ...
... that is associated with that basketball.
Ebbe Petraeus wonders: "What activity should Alma and Harry go on this fall?"
Good question.
I'll go to riding school and then I'll go to basketball.
- That's what Alma wants to do.
- No, I'll be.
Okay.
- And Harry continues with football, huh?
- Yes.
I'll train as I already do.
Springer, yoga and strength trainers.
I am looking to build my physics more professionally so I will see if I can find a good PT.
Thanks for watching this video!
Feel free to leave a thumbs up, or down.
Recommend, ask questions and have a great time until we see you next time.
Bye!