But it should not be about snuff or coffee or anything else common,-
-Outan about Sweden's most remarkable addiction.
We will do this as a top list.
And number five we find in Sundbyberg.
This section is also in paid cooperation with NordVPN.
- And now we stand here with Alexander.
You have a difficult addiction, you can say, right?
- Yes.
- You seem pretty happy then.
- Yes actually.
- Would you be able to live without doing it?
- Absolutely not.
Every time I wake up in the morning I know that-
-That I will do this.
Whether it will be an hour or fifteen hours.
It depends on what the rest of the day looks like.
- I think it's time to tell you what it is.
What Alexander is dependent on is ...
Miniature golf!
It's mini golf!
You are addicted to!
- That's right.
Now maybe you think, can you really be addicted to mini golf?
The answer is absolutely yes.
Just wait and see.
- How did your addiction develop?
- It was about seven years since I played mini golf with my grandmother and grandfather.
I thought it was great fun.
So I went there the next day, and the day after again and the day after again.
Then that kind of continued.
- How many days have you not played mini golf since that day?
- You can count on one hand.
- How many hours a day do you play on average?
- Up to 15 hours sometimes so maybe the average is 5-6.
- For seven years?
- Yes.
- It's a lot of mini golf.
- But it feels good.
It is not possible to live without mini golf.
I really feel every day when I wake up that I have to play mini golf.
If the mini golf had not existed now after seven years with this addiction, I would not have been able to live.
- It is.
You love mini golf so much.
And I love you because you love mini golf.
And today we will have to hang out with you.
- Yes.
I guess what's on the menu.
- Mini golf.
And then we have some balls here then.
- How many mini golf balls do you have?
- It's up to a thousand.
- Oh damn.
Okay.
- There we have ...
- Oh!
- A part.
- Damn.
- So every ball here is unique as well.
It's not about the look though, but ...
- As with people.
- Yes exactly.
- There we have it.
Let's go!
- Great.
- You initiated a high five?
- Yes.
- It is usually always I am happy to have a guest like ...
- Now I feel that ...
Now its time.
Miniature golf.
Then we arrived in paradise.
It is locked and closed for the season but we step in.
Yes, we come to hole one.
Ah just, on hole four we should have a ball that does not bounce so much hot.
- Is it a ball in the stocking?
- Yes exactly, so that we stop inside the pants.
- Why?
- Because here it is a little warmer than in the ball bag.
- It's like some extra balls there now.
- Yes exactly, now it's really mini golf professionals.
- Thanks.
Cool.
- No, we play mini golf.
- That is a nice blow.
Unbelievable.
- Then there are 17 holes left.
- Yes haha, then we drive!
- We drive!
Ohohohoho!
Nice.
- Was it so fun?
- This is the best I know.
Studs, bounce, and walk in the hole.
How close!
Do we run the next course?
- Let's go!
It's so neat.
- I thought we should take some mini golf - coffee?
- What is it?
- Toast and hot chocolate.
- Do you have with you?
That's what you have in your bag.
- Yes exactly, my cooler bag.
- How cozy!
- I always have it with me.
- Are you the happiest when you sit exactly here?
- Yes.
- Five hours a day, year -round, for seven years ago.
- But is there anything that has been difficult at some point that made you find a security in the mini golf?
- When it started seven years ago, then I might not be very popular in school.
I wasn't the cool guy.
It was probably a reason why I started with this and held on to this.
Then it just continued.
- But somehow you found some kind of security in the mini golf.
And so it was simply developed into a pure addiction.
- Yes.
- For this, my life is.
- Yes, mini golf.
- This is what I live for.
- We will be up with the balls we have warmed.
- Oh, it's tickle a little here.
- Exactly.
I don't check.
- No, you have to check.
It's not private.
- Good!
What a star in the middle!
- Is it like a snus who gets his first snuff in one day?
- It's probably a hundred times better than I think.
- Are you ever sad?
- Situations may well arise in life when you are sad.
But on the mini golf course it is never.
It's like a paradise.
- You did not know that the mini golf course in Sundbyberg was paradise.
- For me, that's it.
- For you, this is paradise.
- Yes.
- My hands have blue of the cold and the rain.
And he just walks around and is happier than any other person can be all the time.
- Do you cope with two more holes?
- Easy.
- Yes, but we drive.
- I've started to get some your spark of life now I think.
No problem.
I get another chance.
- Yes exactly.
- There you go.
- Nice.
- So then we have a track left.
- Yes, an exact same.
- No, but it doesn't matter that it is the same.
It's just as fun for it as well.
- It does not matter.
- No no.
So yes!
- The last hole.
- Nice.
- How long should you stand here?
- Yes, it will be all evening.
- But ...
In other words...
I wonder if we are pulling.
We have to work with something else.
So I can come back then.
- Easy.
- Yes.
Now it has been almost seven hours since we left Alexander.
On the mini golf course here.
Now let's see how he feels.
Probably great.
Check, check, check out.
There he goes.
Alone, in a headlamp.
In a pouring rain and plays mini golf.
So he is completely ...
He is absolutely incredible.
Alexander!
Your amazing person!
- Servant, Mauri!
- I have no words.
When you come here and you just stand here with your headlamp and have not given up.
- No, but it's fantastic fun this.
That's my lifestyle.
- To stand here in the rain in Sundbyberg with a headlamp and drive mini golf.
- That's life.
- Does it take you now to leave in any way or do you feel ready?
- No, I will probably never feel completely clear.
But it's a day tomorrow with after all.
Alexander also played mini golf the day after.
And the day after that and the day after that.
In a time when more and more is about success and money-
-Chusiak more people should be inspired by a guy-
-Which devotes all its time to what makes him happy.
However, we are moving on to the number four of the list.
Now it should be about perhaps the most common addiction that exists.
That is why we have a whole bunch with us.
You are all dependent on the same thing.
- Yes.
- Namely ...
Sometimes the internet can feel a bit like this.
Alert!
But NordVPN, with which this section is in paid collaboration, has a solution to it.
Nordvpn is like a bodyguard for everything you do online.
They, as well as discourage all evil forces so you can feel calmer and safer on the internet.
Let me tell me more.
With Threat Protection, NordvPN's damaged links identify and warn before clicking on them.
Congratulations!
You've won a phone.
Wow!
- AP AP AP.
You can't go in here.
It is very dangerous for you.
And if you want to see series that are only available in other countries,-
-Then Nordvpn can move to a completely different country.
Against the Baltic!
Yes, a little more like this is life with NordvPN.
Quiet, safe and wonderful.
Now you get an extra four months if you sign up on a two -year plan on the link in the description.
It is risk-free and you have a 30 days the money back guarantee.
An objective manner.
Good offer.
Thanks, Nordvpn.
- You are all dependent on the same thing.
-Yes.
- Namely ...
-Nose spray!
- God what a bad sound.
Can we do it again?
- Namely ...
- Nose spray!
- Good gang!
When I asked for tips on unusual addictions, I was shocked at how many are actually completely stuck in nasal spray.
It's like a people's disease we never talk about.
So I chose to gather eight of the country's most nasal spray dependent people.
- You are a quiet, quite large minority in Sweden.
- Yes exactly.
It is only now that we are starting to feel that it is not shameful anymore.
That is why we gather once a week.
And just talking.
It is so common that nowadays you can shout at a party if you end.
Does anyone have?
And there is someone.
- It is so!
In any group, there is one that wears it.
- Everyone has like ...
Yes.
And you have three!
What do you usually drive, Mona?
- Nasonex.
- You're Nasonex girl.
- Yes.
- Nasonex girl we have here.
- You feel like one of those who run the heaviest on nasal spray.
- Yes, I drive pretty hard.
- Yes, you do.
- I've even tattooed Otrivin on the foot.
- huh?
Huh?
Oh!
He has an Otrivin tattoo!
What the hell!
- No, I love Otrivin.
- You know what?
You notice that almost a little.
And I have actually prepared some nice mingle for us.
- Yes, incredible!
Are there canapés?
- No.
- No, okay.
We still drive.
No!
What?
- God, this will be like an AA meeting.
- And how sick you are who bring this to an AA meeting.
- Cheers!
Yes, Satan.
Yes that is good.
Then I let our nasal sprays mingle a bit and have a nice moment together.
But what they didn't know was that I had an evil plan to put into work.
Oh!
- I fill this whole to the last picture when we just let it rain.
- I'm not going to submit mine ... I'm not going to leave my own.
- That's what I do.
- But God ... unless I get this back, Mauri ...-
- It is quiet!
- But what are you going to do with them?
- Should I put it down?
- Yes, it's not dangerous.
- So, I will look out.
Can anyone check if the door is locked?
But wait, now it became a picture here.
- Hello there, players.
The door out is locked and I have taken all your nasal spray.
- We have to break up the door.
- the one who can stay locked up in this room the farthest
- Wins nasal spray worth over SEK 3500.
- Oh!
- Good luck!
- I'm already craving Otrivin!
- Does anyone really feel they will go out right away?
This is the o-scent that ever happened to me.
On the other hand, 3500 bucks worth of nasal spray.
I think I will take this.
I shit in this shit.
Let me out!
But that is an abuse.
- Was it?
- Yes, I will sue you.
- Okay, Gunilla Persson.
- Yes Yes.
- You've got your nasal spray back.
You've got a little goodie bag.
Thank you for meeting you.
- Yes, but thank you.
- It was really nice.
- It was really…
It really was ... MHM
The hours were slowly ticking forward, but one by one our heroes began to fall for the nasal rest.
Now we need…-
-Ah, now!
- Mauri, Mauri, Mauri.
What should we do with you when we get out?
- So, how long are you prepared to stay in this room?
- No, I fight.
I am considering re -booking the air ticket.
- Are you thinking about re -booking the air ticket?
- Yes.
This will be personal now, Mauri, between you and me.
- Then just wait for these people to get out.
- I usually hear that I have a pretty lovely laugh by many.
This is not the first time.
I'm not trying to get it, but it will come when it comes.
Are you hot in here?
- Sweden's best laughter you have.
I die.
Robin's wonderful laughter just kept going.
And continued.
But it turned out to be a winning strategy.
- Do I both of you?
-Yes.
It was the laughter that ...
Everyone became pissed.
This will be a struggle.
- When the two ... - two strong individuals.
- It will last for a long time.
- Yes, definitely.
- It feels hard.
I always have one on me so it's a little tough not to have one in my pocket.
- I'm really, really, really kissed.
But I have a plan that I should try to persuade that we should go out together and take the win both.
I can imagine going out together.
Otherwise we can sit here all weekend.
- Okay then.
- Should we?
- Yes.
- Now are they going?
Now they go.
Now they come out!
Yes!
Oh!
Hahaha!
Bye!
And there somewhere, with a lot of nasal spray, we leave Alva and Robin for the number three of the list.
- And now we are here with Klara.
- Hello!
- What is fun to see you!
- The same!
What are you on the mood?
- I'm so damn happy!
- How long have you had your addiction, ready?
- I would say from the age of 11, but it's probably longer.
But it's like constant.
If I do not, then I can become a huge deck.
- And the clear is dependent on is ...
Chewing gum!
- Is it good?
- Yes, it's great!
Here we have Klara who since she was 11 years old had a chewing gum in her mouth every awake and sleeping second.
One and a half packages a day for 15 years means that during her life she consumed 180,000 chewing gums.
- When you were 11 you became addicted to chewing gums and have now had it in your mouth all the time.
- Damn what sick it is when you say that.
- It's absolutely incredible really.
- Now we sit here with Viggo.
- Well!
- Nice to get a hello from you.
What is it like to have a girl who is addicted to chewing gum?
- The worst is probably in sleep during the night.
I wake up with chewing gum myself on my face.
In bed it is like chewing gum everywhere.
But that's it.
It's serious.
It's not good at all.
When I notice the chewing packages ...
- May I take chewing gum.
It starts to water.
- Wait how long have you been without chewing gum now?
- One minute.
It is watered in the mouth.
- Wait, wait, wait.
Could you help me Viggo?
- I dare not.
- I here more here.
No I have not.
- I just want to see what happens.
- It is good.
She needs this.
We need this.
I need this.
- It will be so unpleasant.
I already know how I start to lose my mood.
- This is very exciting for us.
But Viggo Do you chew chewing gum?
- No absolutely not.
My flora in my mouth is probably good.
- I get it.
- Oom, they were good.
- God, what a nasty.
It feels like this is going to start your poop's need again.
May I say that?
- My stomach is not very good Mauri.
- Do you have to on the toilet?
- He has wanted to poop all morning, but he has thought that they will now.
So then I said it smells too much.
- He's staying right now?
- But you see that.
Honey, go to the toilet.
- Mauri I do for you.
Or I don't.
I don't know why I do it?
- But you, take off the mosquito.
- No, but the mosquitoes should be with us, now we drive.
- Hahaha, now we do this for real.
It's an exciting side track we got.
Short update then, now Klara has been without chewing gum for almost 15 minutes.
- Satan in hell how strong you are.
- greedy hands.
- Oh sorry.
Oh, Mauri!
Press away with your feet now.
-I do not want to.
-Uh-oh!
-What do we do?
No, but ... Viggo!
I say it!
Check out how happy he is!
You are so easy!
-Hey!
Hi Mauri!
-Nice!
Hello!
- Now the moment has come.
- No!
For real?
- Now you should get chewing gum.
Should we sit down at the table and do we serve you?
- Yes !!
- This is going to be so damn fun!
This is so damn good!
Life!
- If she had to choose between me or chewing gum, I go and think about almost daily.
- What would you choose?
- We don't have to talk about that.
It feels so damn nasty.
I can say that I had chosen him, but in practice ...
- I have one last thing I would like to do with you.
It requires us to go away from here.
- Should we buy chewing gum?
- No Unfortunately not.
It won't be so fun.
- Come, Clara.
- I should now tie your hands.
- Excuse me?
-Yes exactly.
- I'm really kidnapped.
- You have no idea what is in front of you right now?
- No.
- In gum would be reasonable.
- I will take off your blindfold.
- No!
No!
It was the sickest, what have you done!
- Sit still!
Hit!
Calm, calm, calm, calm, calm, calm!
- No!
- Here we have your little siblings your boyfriend.
Your family stands here, on one side.
On this page we have extreme amounts of chewing gum.
I just want to ask you to choose between your family or chewing gum.
I will not hurt them directly, but I think your family would like you to choose them in this situation.
Do you want to say something?
- Honey now you have your choice here in front of you.
Choose us now.
Look at us.
We need rescue.
- It's enough there.
- Check, stellas mine.
Stella, you become ...
Do you get sorry if I don't choose you?
- You can ignore those chewing gums.
If you choose chewing gum ...
The family is more expensive than chewing gum?
- So now the question is ready.
What do you choose?
- It's tempting.
But I choose these.
I choose the family.
I chose you.
Obviously I choose you.
Our big hero chose his little siblings and if you make such brave decisions, you are obviously rewarded with a lot of chewing gum.
For us, it now carries on to Gothenburg and the list number two.
- Now we are here with Vera.
Have you ever heard of someone who has the same addiction as you?
- No I do not have it.
I think I'm the worst.
- and the vera is addicted to is ...
... rinse aid.
- Yes.
Now it becomes more unexpected.
Vera has a physical desire to smell of rinse aid.
Remember a hundred inhalations every day for many years.
- What are you addicted to?
- The scent.
But it is not wrong if you lick a little too.
It can also be good.
I haven't started drinking it yet, but it's just lick.
- I get a little ... - you can be.
- But it's good, of course.
-Yes it is.
May I also smell?
- You really want it?
- Yes, I want to smell.
Yes ... you just want to clinch.
- If it was completely harmless, how fast would it be for you to lower it?
- Great.
I get so hungry when you say so.
- Do you know anyone else who has this addiction?
- Yes, my friend Cassandra, which I have included in this.
- Do you have a friend who has become addicted to you now?
- Yes, I have happened to make her addicted.
Should we call her?
- Another rinse -dependent young woman.
- Can you be a little angry about Vera because she gave you this addiction?
- No!
I'm so happy that she gave me that.
It's a good scent that I can't describe.
You don't think about anything but just that scent.
- If I put on some song that you like and then we massage each other at the same time ...
Then you become so satisfied.
And then just inhale.
- mm, so nice.
- Vidar, you are Vera's little brother.
How does it feel to have a sister who is addicted to rinse aid?
Good.
In business if you follow along, you also usually smell.
- She usually open them.
- You have also started to smell?
- Eh yes, sometimes.
- If you want to become addicted to something when you get older, what would you like to become addicted to?
- Enough gasoline.
The smell of gasoline.
- I think that can be a little dangerous.
So I may not think you should.
- Okay.
Can I have a hand?
Rinse aid.
That might be enough.
Then we went to the grocery store to shop a little for tonight's movie.
With the rinse aids.
- How many times have you been here and sniffed?
- For many times.
- Get open?
-We do not know.
But we do it anyway.
- We are about to buy rinse
Now it was time to speed up.
But on the way out I got the idea that the girls would try to explain their addiction to other customers.
- This is the rinse agent.
I wonder what you think about it.
- I can test.
Yes, it smells like detergent.
- What do you like about rinse aid?
- It's not my thing.
- You get a wonderful feeling in the brain and the body.
- No, I've never come there.
- You are Norwegian?
- Fan do you do here?
- Yes, I've been here 40 years.
- Oh, damn!
Welcome.
Do you feel something special in the body when you breathe it?
- You will be happy.
- Surely you will be?
Now we have finally found some who also feel that way.
- But do you usually smell rinse aid?
- Yes!
It's mine ... I usually do it when I'm at Dollarstore and stuff like that.
- huh!?
- But what are the odds that we meet you here ... but god!
What are you doing tonight?
We will have a movie night and smell of rinse aid.
Do you want to ... it became a no from ...
It would have been fun if you could come by.
You are skeptical.
Vidar We found two girls at ICA.
Okay, welcome at movie mud!
- Thanks so much.
- It is her father who calls who wonders where they are.
So they are on film mud with rinse aid theme.
You are so welcome, right?
- Yes, very welcome.
- So fun for you to meet each other.
- Yes, like it's meant.
- I'm getting a little strange.
- Vidar, I think you have smelled enough for tonight.
Vidar now you have to stop sniffing.
Now we have to put it away.
Give back, Vidar.
Do you want your daughters to come home?
We're pushing them home now.
Vidar, final words to the camera?
- Don't forget to sniff rinse aid.
Or do you know, however, do not sniff rinse aid.
Instead, focus on the last person section.
This girl who will soon give a surprise that ends in tears.
- Now we stand here with Molly.
Shall we tell you?
- Yes.
Do you want to tell us?
- I can tell.
I can tell the world.
Sun side!
- Yes!
God, what a nice one!
Of all the dependencies, almost Molly almost fascinated me the most.
She has seen all eight seasons up to 500 times
- And has spent about 10,000 hours of their lives seeing the Sun side.
This corresponds to over four years of full -time work on a job.
- There are as many spa hours as the mick has.
- A small sunny garnish.
It is absolutely incredible.
- There is no one in the world who has seen Solsidan more than you.
- It can't be.
- Is it feeling that you need the sun side now?
- Yes, it is often.
I would say it's a bit like sniffing.
- Should we go up and see some sunny side?
- Love to.
We'll do that.
- You're so hungry.
- This song I usually listen to.
On Spotify all the time.
- Is it true?
- I love that you think it's fun.
- Yes.
Wait, you have to see.
You have to see this.
We do not smoke in here.
But fuck!
Do you think so damn here I will?
I'm so nice.
I am so relaxed.
It's so damn well thought out everything in here.
And it is false too.
As soon as someone goes out, well then the others start to be.
Oh what the mouths go.
It is possible that the saliva sprays around here.
Anna, now I think ... Now it's me to talk here for a little while.
- You can really like the whole script.
Season 1 to 8.
- You might think that I have practiced the scenes like this, but that's only because I've seen it.
- So many times?
It sits so deep in here.
-Where are we now?
- We are the sun side.
- We are not in the sun side, we are the sun side.
This is where they recorded.
Now let's take a while here and see everything.
You notice that you are a little ...
- I'm really fun.
- Why are you annoying?
- Because you recognize everything.
It feels very soft.
Here is the tennis court.
God, yes here it is.
- Now we will soon go into this famous walkway
- Is that it?
I even recognize the gravel sounds.
I just want to go here for all the time.
No, here is the house.
No, but God.
- I actually have a thing left.
Oh, do you imitate me?
I would like to call the producer for Solsidan.
- Ohh, I panic.
- You get like the annoyance of talking to the producer.
- I kind of want to move away from you because I get a little nervous.
- Hello!
- You have a little news for Molly.
- Yes.
- Okay, what's going to happen now?
- I don't know if you have heard that it will be further seasons.
- Yes, I have control over.
I have seen that.
- No!
Now I'm starting to cry.
Yes.
- You should get a small role in Solsidan we thought.
- God.
But we were not ready there so I cheated Molly that I was going to a meeting.
- Is it okay that we just slip away?
- Yes.
God yes.
- Small home run.
We should definitely not have a meeting.
We will go in here and pick up the large sunny side icon Henrik Dorsin, Ove Sundberg.
He will come and surprise Molly.
There we have him.
- Hello.
- Hello, Henrik.
- Mustache.
- Mustache?
Two?
- Yes it is.
Then I know I'm right out if you have it.
We sat and looked at the sun side with her earlier.
- You did, yes.
- She knows all the replicas in all eight seasons.
- Oh, there are actually some sections I haven't seen.
- She has seen them every 400 times.
- It's completely senseless.
What a human being.
I get a little worried that I can live up to her ...
She does not know that I will come.
- She doesn't have a rush.
She thinks we're at a meeting.
- I'm not saying this for fun, but I'm a little worried about how she should react.
But it also does not feel like your dream situation that someone is starting to cry in front of you.
- I'm used.
Many people start crying.
- Wherever you go to town.
- Yes, they start crying.
I don't know why, but they cry and cry and cry.
Fortunately, I am a very good consolation.
What is it?
Was not very set up here, but ...
Are we there?
- Now we are there, Henrik.
Now she will be surprised.
- Allright.
Here we go.
- In here it is.
- Will she see me here now?
- I don't think so, because she sits a little further in.
- Is she unstable?
- No, she is doing the top.
But it will be a lot for her, I think.
But we go in.
- We see.
This will be fun.
Experiment.
- Servant man!
- No!
Now I start crying again!
I'm crying again!
- No!
No, I'm crying again!
- You should not cry.
- Yes.
- Okay.
I hope it is out of joy and not of horror.
- What have you done?
Yes I see it.
I just want to...
- It's fine.
- He must be patted.
- That is sick.
- Had it been easier for you?
If Henrik just stepped into a little more into the character Ove,
-and you talk to Ove.
- Did it have things simplified for you?
- I know, yes ...?
Yes, yes.
- Yes, what fun.
Is that your cookies?
- We got them here.
- So it is...?
- It's ours, yes, exactly.
- If you are not going to have more, we can take it.
Then we just gather here.
- Would you like to say hello with a hug?
- Yes.
- It's fine.
- Is it going well?
- It's going great.
- I say hello then.
- It was so sick.
- Yes.
- How nice you look.
- Yes, but the same.
- Thank you very much, Henrik.
- Yes.
- Do you think you can get a little bag just for this?
- Now he went back into character.
- No no no.
Now I am myself.
- Hahaha!
And thus the section is over for this time.
Five completely different dependencies, five absolutely wonderful personalities.
Thank you so much for watching!