We are going home to him, we will eat with him, we will work with him and we will hang with him.
Just when I say it he rolls in.
- Hello!
- Mauri
- Tjena Mauri.
- Nice!
- The same, really.
Here we have billionaire Johan, who has 50 different companies -
-As in a short time, one of Sweden's richest people has become.
- Wait now, you are parked there?
- Yes, I thought we could be close to the boat club.
- But do you get it?
- It depends on who you ask.
- And why do we meet here?
- I usually have breakfast here.
- At the Royal Mot Boat Club?
- Yes, they have the world's best sandwiches.
- But should we go in and check out?
- I think so.
- Should we?
- Let's go.
This section is also in paid collaboration with Air Up.
- How is the situation with you then?
- It is good.
Is this with you?
- Could it have been worse?
- Yes actually.
Heat day at work.
- Did you work today?
It's early in the morning.
You have been at work already.
How hard do you have to sit still?
- Quite difficult.
At school it was hard.
At school I had problems.
I had to go for a class ...
It's actually fun.
I did an ADHD investigation.
It came to light that I'm just hyperactive.
It is very unusual as an adult to just be hyper.
Hello to you!
- If I asked you now, to just sit and look out over the water ...
So we'll see how long it takes before you can't do it anymore?
- Yes, but when you get these challenges so ...
- Then will you want to win?
- Yes!
- So your competition instinct goes over?
- 100%
- Hyper?
- Okay, thumb war!
- Thumb war?
- You see something in your gaze.
- Yes!
- You wake up!
- Yes now!
Now I'm on!
- The loser swish the other thousand bucks.
- Thousand?
We drive ten thousand.
- Ten thousand?
Ten salmon?
- Ten salmon!
- Lol!
There is much greater risk for me.
It is by far the biggest bait I have done in my life.
- Is that so?
- Yes.
- Are you holding up now?
- Thumb war!
Yes.
1, 2, 3.
- My God.
- Have I just won 10 salmon?
- Congratulations Mauri.
- 10,000
Damn start on this day.
- Really.
And this sandwich.
- Yes, it was so good.
- And this company.
- And this man.
- Yes, this man.
- No, that man.
- That man.
- No haha!
- What then?
- I thought we would take the boat and go out to my country place.
Do you have sunscreen?
So you must not say?
- Yes.
- Sorry
- Is that your boat?
Yes, of course, Serru.
- What a long one.
- Yes it is long and slim and fast.
- Let's go.
- Yes we do.
- Oh!
- Oh sorry.
- Smooth out!
- Yes, serve.
- Now it calls someone.
- Tjena, Viktor.
If there is something you should learn about billionaires, it is that they seem to talk on the phone all the time.
This particular conversation seemed to be a new 12 million boat that Johan wanted to buy in Norway today.
- Should you and I to Norway buy a boat?
- Yes I thought it, how does it feel to you?
- Do we get it?
- We find a good vehicle to go fast in, I thought.
Helicopter I thought.
What do you think about that?
- Hello?
Should we go helicopter to Norway?
- Yes.
- and buy a boat?
- Why not?
- We are going to Norway you and me.
We are going to Norway!
- Yes.
- But okay, first we're going home with you.
- Exactly.
- Oh, now Johan is starting to press a little.
- Yes exactly.
- And then you see how it starts to glide in the eyes.
- Now, now.
- This is fun for real.
- How many knots are we up in?
- Now we are only up to 35.
- huh?
Is this only half?
- Yes.
- Oh my God!
How fast we go!
- Yes, lovely!
- Yes ...
- Are you happy?
- Yes, I'm happy.
But it is this eternal question if you have money you become happier and it is like ...
Yes, it will be easier.
After all, life becomes easier.
I had a great job when I started my company.
I was close to bankruptcy several times.
And lay and cried at home in bed because I had no money.
- mm.
So I know how hard it is.
So, to be short for money.
- Yes.
- It's really hard.
- are all houses here yours?
- Yes.
- Oh God!
- This section is in paid collaboration with Air Rup.
And now you might be wondering why I'm being chased by the police.
Let me tell me why.
It all started with the fact that I completely innocently ordered home Air Up.
That flavoring plain water via the scented mind-
-So you experience flavors such as watermelon, pineapple or apple.
The problem now is that the police think that these are too good to be legal.
For everything else that is good in life, usually cost in one way or another.
For example, if you drink alcohol, well then you become backwards.
For example, if you eat useless food, then you feel worse.
But Air Rup has chopped the system.
Only the advantages, though without the disadvantages.
- There he is!!!
Air Up flavors regular tap water with scent.
As the scent mind accounts for 80% of all tastes you experience-
-This your brain interprets the scent of this little pod as a taste.
- We need reinforcement to E4 northbound.
Mauri gets hold of an Air Up bottle.
-And it works so that you fill bottles with water,-
-S put on the pod with its favorite flavor.
And then just lift the pod to activate the taste.
And then it's just to enjoy.
In addition, there are 25 incredible flavors such as cherries, lime and peach.
With the code Mauri you get a 10% discount on Air Ups website.
Link can be found in the description.
- are all houses here yours?
- Yes.
- Oh God!
- How often are you here?
- One or a couple of weeks in the summer.
- So it's just a summer house?
- Yes.
- How much empty do you have?
- 55,000 square meters.
- 55,000 square meters of empty?
- You look mischievous when you think about it.
- Yes, it's a bit cranky.
- It's a bit cranky.
- Should I try to do something?
- I think I'll try to get this one.
- You don't want help from me.
- Nehehe, you are good.
- Why does no one trust me when it comes to these questions?
- You actively want to be doing?
- Yes.
- Here, I'll help you.
- Thanks.
- And here is the main house itself?
- Exactly.
- Now it calls.
- But who is calling?
- Håkan Guldkula.
- Håkan Guldkula?
- His name is that.
- No?
- Well, for real.
- Do you have a friend named Håkan Guldkula?
It's almost grisly and hot so I think.
- He is an amazing character.
- He is certain, but he can't be called Håkan Guldkula.
- You gas with that.
- Oh, I understand!
Woho!
Do you keep up with or?
- Yes, I'm hanging on.
- You have apples.
- Yes, we have many apple trees.
- Can't we run and pallet any apples?
- Shall we do it?
- Yes.
- Should I pallet on my own plot?
- Ah just that.
- Are you involved in a good challenge?
- What does it mean then?
- I think we crank up a little neighbor and see the one who throws the longest.
100,000?
- No!
- I can not afford it.
- Yes, I know you have.
- Lol!
- But 100,000 is too much.
We can lower it a bit?
Yes, 95,000 then?
- Lol!
20,000!
That is a good.
20,000 that's good.
- I don't know if I'm good either.
Now we'll see then
- It's the strangest thing I've done.
Are you kidding?
That is a good throw.
This throw can potentially cost me 20,000 bucks.
- Or win 20,000.
Imagine what opportunity Mauri.
Come on.
- Does it feel hard?
- A little.
20,000.
- We have to hang out more you and me, I think.
- What is going on now, Johan?
- I think it's Håkan!
He who we talked about Håkan here.
- Is it Håkan Guldkula?
We would just go and have lunch.
Who do you think we come across when we go to port?
Yes, Håkan Fucking Gold Kula.
Look into the camera and say what your name is.
- My name is Håkan Guldkula.
- Håkan Guldkula?
Yes.
What are you doing here?
- I'm here watching the boat.
- Can't we come up with anything with Håkan Guldkula?
- Håkan has his own champagne brand called Guldkula Champagne.
I am also a partner in your champagne brand.
- It's one of all your fifty companies.
- Are you also swine?
- If I am?
- Swine.
- I have it okay.
- Hahaha!
- This is how I want to live too.
- But you do it now.
- Yes, in one day.
It's not enough.
- Yes, yes.
- Happy Thursday.
- Look, the bus here in this man.
Now he is in bus mood.
- Yes you drink far too slow guys.
- Are you starting to get a little intoxicated?
You just sit and smile and look out at the horizon.
- I just enjoy the nice summer weather.
- Håkan Fucking Guldkula.
- Cheers, bowl.
- Okay, lunch!
- Lunch!
- Are you mischievous again?
- Yes, I'm busy.
And lunch we would eat in Johan's wine cellar where his wine expert had picked up some suggestions-
-Or would be suitable for today's meal.
- Legendary vintage 2005 from Emmanuel Roger.
From Le Chebler.
- Located in von Romanias, which is perhaps the world's best Vinby.
- God I become ... Do you understand everything He says?
- No, I don't, but I'm a bit on his ...
- He is in control of the stuff.
There are many references and French names.
- What do you pay for this racker?
- This one may well be at a 60-70,000 approximately.
Depends on.
Can be more expensive too.
Then we get on the next.
Also Magnum, of course.
Roma, stay in chambol with neat.
We find this.
- Now you should choose which wine it will be.
- No, I thought you would?
- Should I choose?
After all, these are for half a million.
- Ole Dole you get to drive.
Hahaha-
- Okay
- Yes drive
Ole doledoff, kinkelakoff, kinkelane ole dole ole doledoff-
What is this host?
- 50-60 thousand.
- Damn what expensive!
- Yes what fun then, now it's time to open the wine.
That we look forward to
- But but...
After all, it is 60 thousand.
- you are so greedy .. you just
There we said hello to 60,000 Johan.
Or we said hello to 60,000.
- Yes Hello!
- Cheers!
Johan, you are the best.
- Do you know how lean it is?
- Yes, damn, it was good.
- It's good.
- It was damn good wine.
Damn!
- Have you ever tried Boeuf any time?
- Are you Boeuf with Boeuf Bourguignon?
- Yes, now we are talking or how?
- Yes, now we are talking.
Now we're up and running this day.
- But when was it so rich?
- It went pretty fast.
In a couple of years maybe.
I have to pinch my arm actually.
Still after many years now.
That I am so good.
Crazy right?
- Yes, it's cranky.
Bowl!
Hello to you!
- Short break to force Johan show all his cars.
What is that?
- The Ferrari 812 Superfast is called it.
- What's that?
- A very fast Porsche Cayenne.
- And that?
Yes, it is a Cayenne but not as fast.
- A very, very fast.
One of the fastest cars in the world.
A Porsche 911.
It is difficult to keep the note.
You have to be careful.
- Keep the note?
- Yes, the driver's license.
- You're a little mischievous.
- I am and I have become because the driver's license a few times.
- How many?
- Oh, I hardly dare to tell you.
Surely a 20 times.
- 20 times!
Have you got rid of the driver's license 20 times!
- Unbelievable!
Congratulations!
- Yes, should you say congratulations?
- No, you should definitely not.
But I'm happy!
- Yes, it's not good, but it's fun.
- Mauri.
- Johan.
Soon we would go helicopter to Norway, but first we got past one of Johan's office to see a little how he works.
- Yes, here we have my biggest company today, Panghus.
- One of your 40 companies?
- Yes, is right.
- There is a ping pong table.
- Yes, just.
Is there money on games soon, right?
- So I am 10,000 back.
- Yes, we shit in it, Mauri.
We are driving now.
- Here comes the kitchen.
Here we have Fredrik who cooks here.
- Do you have a chef?
- Yes, we have a chef at work.
We build entire areas and we make the infrastructure so that the roads in the area draw sewers and electricity.
And then we build the houses from the ground up in the factory.
- How big business do you do?
- In really large areas, you may talk half a billion, up to one billion.
- You do it?
- Cranky huh?
- And what is this?
- Super 10.
It's our hockey agency.
- Do you have a hockey agency?
- Hello guys.
- You are an NHL professional?
- It's Jonte Bergen in Detroit.
- And you are one of Sweden's best hockey players who are just sitting here in your office.
But I got so curious, what did you have about?
- No, but it's a contract year.
- Should he earn more or less than he does on a weekend?
- Where do you aim?
Do you dare to go so high?
- It depends on what a weekend!
Hahaha!
- Here is my office.
This is how I sit in the days.
- Oh!
It was a bent screen!
- Yes exactly!
- What a curvature!
- curvature!
- This is my pressure chamber.
- Excuse me?
- The pressure chamber I lie for an hour every day.
- Do you have a pressure .. an hour every day?
- Yes.
- Cranky huh?
- It's really cranky.
- And why is it good for you?
- Cell division in the body is important for you to feel good and live for a long time.
The largest sports stars in the world are in such a thing.
- What strange this is.
- No, sorry.
Am I sitting on you?
- Hello!
- Hey!
- Then we guys are visible in a while!
- What is this?
- This is the oxygen.
- Okay.
- Surely you feel it is getting hard now?
- Damn, it blows itself up.
- It will be stiff now.
- Is it true?
- Now this is hard.
- What is so fun?
What is so fun about it?
- No nothing, cranky huh?
- It's cranky.
- Wait, I go first Mauri.
- That was great.
- My God, what a warm.
Now we're going to pull.
It goes faster than checking in and going with regular flights.
This is a better and easier way.
- You recommend a helicopter?
- Hot!
- To ordinary people who need to transport themselves.
- Haha exactly!
Oh my God!
Wow!
Oh!
And while we move on to Norway, let's flush the time back a bit to better understand where Johan comes from.
The year is 1977 and Johan goes here at the Vaxmora school in Sollentuna.
- I went here for seven years because I had to go about a class too.
But there are millions in memories.
I had a tough time at school because I had a hard time sitting still.
I had a hard time taking on and learning.
I came after in all subjects and then it was a downward spiral.
- Was there anyone who believed in you?
Among the teachers.
- I had a teacher here and when it turned a little neighbor.
When I went to a new class.
- It was a teacher named Berit Letse.
She took care of me in a good way and understood that I had these qualities.
I had a hard time sitting still.
- How important was it for you as a child to have one?
- It is extremely important of course.
Extremely important.
Guess who arranged a surprise for Johan at his old leisure farm.
- Check out Johan, who is sitting here.
--Wow!
Unbelievable!
-Hello!
How is it Berit?
- Here you come!
--Wow!
- How lovely!
- The same Berit!
- How important was it for you to meet a Berit who saw you better and could handle you better?
- Incredibly important.
It was like a turning point.
Although I continued to have a fairly low self -esteem in the school, it was a turning point with Berit.
- He is today one of Sweden's richest people.
- You can't ... No, is that really it?
- Yes, he is a billionaire today.
- Are you?
- Yes, they say it.
- Are they saying?
- He is.
- Well, what a wonderful to hear.
You can see that yes, how it can be.
If you should not judge anyone in advance.
I had a small card on you.
- Do you have it?
- Look, there you see.
- Wow, incredible.
- And there you really see how cute he is.
- Is it you two?
- Yes, just.
- I have to thank you so much for being so nice to me.
- Thanks so much for that.
I live on that.
After this, Johan jumped off high school to try out different jobs.
He has been a leisure leader, a store worker, a constitutional porter.
He has run two clothing stores in Örebro, opened a bar in the Old Town.
He has started a floor team in Umeå and he has also trained as a pilot.
And the strangest of all, you have also been a football professional.
In the middle of all this.
Yes, believe it or not, but before Johan's successful business career-
-They he was a brilliant football talent that played in AIK's A-team, among other things.
And he was trained by icon Tommy Söderberg-
-Som helped and shaped giants like Zlatan and Henrik Larsson.
- There he stands.
- Yes, incredible.
- He was also an important person in your career, right?
- Yes, he was like a mentor to me and followed me.
He helped me very much.
How's it going?
- It is good!
- Nice to see you!
Hey!
- Hey!
- Mauri
- Hello!
Tommy is my name.
- Oh, it's hug!
- Yes, there are some hockey tackles.
- You give very hard push.
Do you always do that?
- Yes.
Yes, but it gives the design that we are tagged.
- Yes exactly!
- Incredibly.
- What legend we have here?
- How do you remember him as a player?
- You can say that he was a very fast player.
He had a good basic technique.
Then it was such a spraying.
He was a nice devil.
He always had energy in the body and so on.
- He still has.
- I notice that.
You saw that at the time now.
- Yes, you see it.
- I had the offer from AIK.
But for various reasons I refused no two years in a row.
And that's for me ... I regret it.
It would have been fun to see how far you could have gone.
- Thank you Tommy for providing assignments and food with your presence.
- Thank you, it was fun to meet.
And thus we return to the helicopter that is currently on the way from Stockholm towards the boat factory in Norway.
- Now we will try to find a store.
- Oh!
- Oh, Oh, Oh, Oh, Oh, Oh, Oh, Oh, Oh, Oh, Oh, Oh, Oh, Oh, Oh.
- No danger no danger.
You, so long are you not.
- And here is the boat you are considering buying, Johan.
But will you buy it?
- I do not know.
- We'll see.
The hearing has begun.
You feel a small atmosphere between you.
Both of you know you will soon be in negotiation as well.
Should we go out and drive a little?
It is absolutely incredible.
- Do you think it's worth this money or?
- I can't decide that.
It is up to you.
- Are you doubtful?
-No.
- You want this one?
Yes.
I'm not going to say anything.
- Are you ready?
- Yes for the hell.
- Now it gets speed or?
- Yes, I think so.
- Now we will go for 180 kilometers per hour at sea.
Not many boats in the world can handle it.
We will get to know that now.
- There are quite a few boats.
- Stop, let me build.
- It is completely unique to go a hundred knots.
- Don't want help?
- Mauri, the train.
It has probably been.
- Why nobody wants me to help with their boats, Johan?
You were the same before.
- Because you are crab.
- I haven't told anyone.
You are also laughing now, Richard.
- And now, my ladies and gentlemen, it's time for negotiation.
- Hello!
- Bye!
Hello!
Now the champions will negotiate with each other.
The Johan that we have come to know who is out and about boat and chill.
It's a Johan.
The Johan who now sits down and negotiates a 12 million business.
It's a completely different guy.
We others are considering whether to buy a TV for 7000 at Elgiganten.
He is now negotiating a boat for type 12 million.
What has happened?
- We made the deal.
- Have you bought the boat?
- Yes kind of.
- What kind of type?
- No, but I bought the boat.
- Have you bought the boat?
You bought the boat!
Good!
Yes.
What do we do now?
How do we celebrate this?
- No, we have to go to Oslo I think to take a sprinkler.
- Cheers!
Bowl!
Then Johan insisted on running Sten Sax's bag for 20,000.
I won, even though I suspect he let me do it with diligence.
And since I am now 10,000 plus again, so you should write what I should do for the money.
Who should I donate them to?
Why?
Write in the comments field.
Then Johan and I went and drove some Norwegian karaoke.
And I could say that although he has absurd a lot of money and in many ways lives in a completely different world than us other-
-So he is in many ways a very ordinary guy and it makes me happy.
- Now we are on our way home from Norway again!
- Yes exactly!
- What happens now?
- Yes you thought I would invite you to a small party.
- I'll go to a party!
Yes, party!