A news article is an accounting text that describes an event.
The introduction is important.
It should catch the reader-
-And consists of a heading and a preamble.
Then follows a body text.
You can use photos, charts and explanatory facts box-
-which clarifies and facilitates the reader.
Tips to consider when writing a news article:
An interview can create breadth in the article-
-And gives access to the impressions of witnesses and experts.
You shall convey an event-
-W so the public understands and wants to read the article.
Explain difficult concepts.
Avoid personal values and be objective.
You should account for an event, not your opinion.
It is also good if the article shows more than one page in a question.
Follow the course chronologically.
What happened before, during and after the incident?