Trying and re -examining different solutions to problems is part of existence.
In games, you test different ways to get past challenges.
In cooking you try different spices and it becomes more or less good.
Or you may sew a t-shirt.
In school you learn things by trying solutions several times-
-and by finding new ones.
It is impossible to do everything right right away.
It's not exciting either.
When the teacher assesses the quality of your school work, the knowledge requirements are used.
The knowledge requirements can be found in the curriculum that controls the teaching.
In crafts, image and technology, one must systematically try and rethink.
In craft, it is about how materials and techniques can be combined.
You should formulate different action alternatives that lead the work forward.
You are constantly thinking about new solutions.
A student has been given the task of manufacturing some kind of storage.
The material should be reusable.
The object should be created with flat technology.
That task can be solved in many different ways.
It is extra important to systematically test and rethink their ideas.
It would be good with storage for chargers and game controls.
Maybe a wooden box with recycled fabric as a lid?
And with handles in wood.
Or does another material get better?
Isn't a box in wood unnecessarily heavy?
Yes, exactly.
So I sketched a solution with narrow moldings instead.
It becomes like a network pattern.
It becomes more fun to build together but it becomes more useful in the long run.
Good question from the friend.
The student reconsidered his sketch early and above all his choice of material.
One option goes faster but the other gets better in the long run.
Just so you should test your first idea when you make something.
Look at the pros and cons of the material.
Also ask how the finished item should be used.
So there.
I combine the wooden box with a handle of cotton bands.
I can make the bands of old clothes so I recycle some fabric.
Cotton band?
Didn't you have a wooden handle in the sketch?
Yes.
But I braid them so it gets strong.
It will be more comfortable to lift compared to wood.
I made a model.
Compare your first idea with another solution.
So make more sketches.
You can also make a prototype, ie a simple model.
You certainly combine different materials and techniques.
Motivate and explain your choices.
How would you do with the lid?
I tighten up fabric on a frame.
But this fabric may be too thin.
It may not work.
But I have another I can try too.
Exactly!
Plan options before you start.
Thus: you need time to test several solutions and materials.
To try and re-examine something systematic-
-Soping about planning and choosing from options.
Also document your work process and your choices.
It facilitates evaluation and if you want to show that you have worked systematically.
Last we look at the work process.
It is important to plan the work.
In what order should the elements be made?
Can you make a model?
What materials become functional?
Can you combine different materials?
Make several sketches and compare solutions.
How should you go about it?
Which techniques are appropriate?
Which methods and tools are best suited?
Analyze different options and justify your choice.
This is what is meant by choosing and formulating action options.
Finally: Document the entire work process.
You can foot and write notes.
Write why you chose as you did-
-And if you encountered technical or aesthetic problems.
This approach, to systematically test or re-examine-
-Do you have the benefit of in many situations.
Texting: Elisabeth Enström