Resist false rumors
Here you get five good advice!
Listen and read carefully
There is a great risk of misunderstanding
and make your own interpretations
If you do not read or listen carefully to what is said.
To just read headlines,
loose -made sentences and listen with half an ear
can make one misunderstand what is said
And then contribute to false information being disseminated.
Ensure to double -check claims
that seems excessive or unlikely
with sources that can be trusted.
A reliable source is independent, factual, neutral
And can report where the information comes from.
An example of reliable sources is authorities.
We humans are more emotionally entitled than we think
and have a tendency to start from our feelings
Instead of facts when we value information.
"It feels like it's this way .."
We are extra vulnerable when something frightening occurs,
Fear makes us more uncritical.
We react instinctively and want to get into security
And do not think about critically reviewing the information.
No one is completely neutral.
We have all preconceived sentences
That affects us and our worldview.
Confirmationbias, for example
They mean we have a tendency to look up information
Who confirms what we already believe and think.
And unconsciously chooses things that go against our beliefs.
It is important to constantly exercise
on having a critical approach
And constantly question what we see, hear and read.
Especially at dramatic events
Is it easy for rumors to start spreading.
Follow up the claims and find out the facts,
It is important not to be drawn and spread false rumors.