I feel stressed, because I'm afraid I will be wrong.
If something goes wrong in math, I sink down far, and I do not want to.
One cannot plug in to it-
-So it's pretty quiet, though it's still stressful.
It weighs a lot for the grade.
The stress is first.
Then it is also the nervousness.
If I'm really nervous I get a blackout and forget everything.
I'm more nervous about saying something wrong, or I don't remember.
Often I know what to say but it will be: "What would I say again?"
Then it doesn't feel good at all.
It is individual when it comes to the approach to the national test.
Some are stressed, others do not, but there are those who do not care.
One tip is: Believe in yourself!
Believe plenty of yourself.
Believe that you are actually capable of doing good from you.
But also try to visualize the test and the test day and how it goes.
It is a key component.
How is it when you get a difficult question?
How should you attack the problem?
Often you get a blackout, the thoughts may go in another direction.
Then it is nice if you have visualized the situation in advance
-And knows how to handle it.
In addition to visualizing the sample, you can take the help of Provision Strategies-
-If you were to suffer from brain drops.
Start by taking a few deep breaths.
Try to bring down your stress level.
Keep in mind that the test is not the whole world.
Once you have reduced the stress level, it may be easier to think clearly.
If you do not get the answer even though you know you can really it-
-Be about a scrap paper and write down everything you can about that topic.
If you still do not come up with the answer, leave the question and move on.
Maybe you will be the answer in a while.
Read the instructions properly, so you don't miss any part of the task.
Mark everything expected of you.
Then you see that you answered everything.
My top-three strategies are: plug, eat and sleep well before a test.
My teacher says I should take it easy and rest.
Type load me, so I can do my best.
Like sleeping, so I get energy, eat well, work out a little neighbor.
You have to take it easy, think what you say, so nothing is wrong.
Stressing through it is not good.
There are difficulties with reading comprehension.
It is not only to perceive it that stand-
-Or to even start reading and cope with all the text written.
It gets too much, it looks messy.
One tip then is:
Try to change your way of thinking.
Don't think: What a lot of text!
Without: What fun, now I'll read this!
What will I learn from this?
When we change the way of thinking, the brain behaves in a different way.
Hopefully it will facilitate.
It is difficult to plug to the national sample-
-But a great way to upload for the linguistic parts-
-As listening to podcasts and reading books in the language.
So that you practice the habit of listening and taking in information.
Keep in mind that the tests are quite long, so prepare for it.
Check with your teacher if it is okay to bring something to eat or drink.
And perhaps most importantly: believe in yourself and try to take it easy.