Right now, everyday life does not really look like we are used to.
Many of our activities are set
And it's easy to feel abandoned.
The uncertainty can make us both powerless and restless.
Maybe much of one's time is about to think about how everyday life
will look like in a couple of weeks
Or to feel disappointed with what you are missing out.
That we lose energy and get a little depressed is nothing strange.
But with a little creativity we can do about our plans
So that they work even now,
And in this way, get the energy back!
For example, if you play basketball
But that the training with the team is set for some time to come.
Go out and play basketball anyway!
You may not be able to be in your regular training hall with the whole team.
But you might be able to bring someone from the team
And go to a basketball basket outdoors.
Besides being a fun time with your friends
So we feel better when we move.
Exercise and movement increase the levels of serotonin
which regulates our mood.
This means that you will feel less stressed
and happier after you have done a physical activity.
Many people find it really boring to not be able to meet people
which is in the risk group or that has some symptoms.
But it is possible to spend time without meeting physically.
If a friend or grandfather can't go out right now,
Make them with a video call!
- Hello Laura!
- It's good how about you?
To see the face of the one we miss
Can also help us get happier!
It's a weird time right now,
But a good tip for feeling better
and get more energy
is to keep doing the things you usually think is fun.
For example, talk to your friends
read a book,
play video games
Or draw.
And remember to fill with energy by eating regularly.
Try keeping your routines.
Get up in the morning and lie down at the usual time in the evening,
So you get enough sleep.
Then the rest will feel much easier!