When I plug into a sample or homework interview
So I usually read the text once.
And then I write down questions
on what is the most important thing to remember.
Then I close the book and tell myself
Or for someone else what I read.
When to plug in a sample or homework interview
can be used by a method that
is about testing yourself.
While learning something new
Should you test yourself on how much you remember what you read.
The advantage of plugging this way
is that it strengthens the memory and causes the knowledge to get stuck
in a more effective way by forcing the brain
To directly pick up what you have learned.
If I only read the text, it is difficult to remember the important thing.
Therefore, I answer my own questions about the text,
Then it is easier to remember when I write a test.
It also becomes clearer to me
If I remember all the facts I need
When I answer my own questions.
Then I notice if I understand and remember.
If you read a text several times in succession
so will you recognize a lot,
And it feels like you will remember everything.
But then when you sit on the test
Maybe you still forgot a lot of what you read.
Researchers have discovered that one learns better and remembers longer
If, instead of just reading a text several times
Tests on the content.
So it will be easier for you to remember
If you summarize what you learned.
And then test yourself
For example, by answering your own questions.
Then you test your brain on what you remember!
When I will then plug in the test at another occasion
So I start by answering my own questions.
Then I know what I remember and what I need to plug in more!
And when I plugged clearly,
So I summarize to myself what I read
And what is important to remember.
Then it becomes easier to remember when I sit on the test!
When you summarize and answer questions
Do you practice picking up the information from the brain.
It will then be easier to find the information
If you have already trained to find it.