You need to plug in all evening.
Start by thinking about how you can make the evening as good as possible.
How do you plug best?
Alone or with someone?
Do you want someone to interrogate after a while?
Where are you plugging the best?
Find the optimal place-
-When you can concentrate and do not have to be disturbed.
Do you like to sit at a desk or in bed?
You decide.
Make it a little extra cozy around you.
You should still sit there for a while.
Eat something before you start, but also make sure you have snacks ready.
You will need to replenish with energy.
Do you like to have music?
Throw together a simple plug playlist and put it on repeat.
See the evening as a race.
When it is over, you are in goal.
Try to find small ways that can facilitate.
Something to drink or eat and a cozy place-
-Can make it feel a little easier.
Maybe it's good to tell everyone that you should plug.
Then the family stays away and the friends know why you don't answer.
Put the mobile on aircraft mode.
If you need your computer, block pages that you usually visit-
-But that you don't use.
Plug in short passes and take breaks.
You only have tonight, so there will be a little more passports than usual.
But you fix that.
Write down things that you don't understand.
Save them and ask someone else to explain it to you-
-Or try to google for a good explanation.
But was source -critical.
A lot of text?
Write your own summaries.
It is perfect to read through at breakfast or on the bus.
Use the breaks the same day the sample is.
Give yourself a reward when the evening is over.
Maybe you get your mobile back or that you bought some candy?
Prioritize sleep.
Don't sit up all night.
To get the best conditions for remembering, the brain needs sleep.
Then it sorts away noise and unnecessary information.
Sleep deprivation just makes it harder-
-Remember everything you plugged in the night before.
Don't forget the breakfast.
Is the test in the afternoon?
Don't skip lunch.
You need the energy.
If you have kept up with the lessons, you can usually more than you think.
You fix this.