To talk and reason orally
included in several subjects in school
and that is something your teachers judge
when to score.
But how to do to widen
and deepen a discussion
And make sure it leads to a well -developed reasoning?
Here are some good things to think about!
Keep a nice tone
and contribute to a good call climate
where everyone is allowed to speak
and feel comfortable to be with.
And where everyone's opinions are respected.
It is important to let many different perspectives
and ideas come up,
In this way, the discussion is broadened and deepened.
Participate actively and engaged in the call
And adapt your language to what you are talking about.
It might be good to have some extra control
on important concepts that belong to the subject.
Try to formulate your thoughts in a clear way
and was factual by using
Well substantiated opinions and arguments.
Also, be sure to stick to the subject.
Remember it is equally important to listen to the others in the group
Like talking for yourself.
Invite the others in the conversation and ask follow -up questions
In order to further develop the reasoning.
To broaden and deepen the discussion,
Listen carefully to the others' views and spin on!
And if you find it scary to talk to others,
Try to say something early in the lesson.
Often it feels creepier the longer you wait.
So in order to facilitate for oneself
Can you say something small at the beginning!