When you write a debate article, you want to convince the reader of your opinion.
You start from something you think is important and may need to change.
With clear and factual arguments, you want to get the reader to react and act.
The debate article is common in daily newspapers, but also in blogs.
Compared to chronicles and submissions-
-Is the debate article less personal and more factual.
Tips to consider when writing a debate article:
Try to have a brief and interesting heading that attracts the reader.
What do you want to say, change, influence?
Make sure you have a clear thesis to start the article with.
With the help of your arguments you manage to convince the reader.
Choose the best and sort out excess.
Do you come up with a counter -argument?
Good!
By answering them you show that you can see things from different perspectives.
Please refer to sources to strengthen your arguments.
Don't be afraid to arouse reactions and feelings.
It is just fine.
Then you create a commitment.
Summarize your article at the end.
Repeat your tes-
-and use your strongest argument.
You can also leave a call.