You can use different strategies-
-What, during and after you read texts.
Here you get strategies you can use while you read.
The first thing to do is turn off everything that disturbs.
If it is difficult to start or to keep concentration-
-Is well to follow the text with pennan-
-or lay a ruler under the line.
Skim past places that feel sluggish instead of completely stopping reading.
Set a clock and read in short workouts.
Take breaks in between.
Start with five minutes and make the passes longer when you can cope more.
Another good strategy is to divide the text into shorter pieces.
Like reading one piece carefully at a time, and then taking a break.
Then the brain can process a smaller amount of information at a time.
When reading, it is important to ask questions to yourself.
"What was it I read? What is most important?"
"Is that something I don't understand? Is it related to what I read before?"
You can also formulate the text with your own words-
-And this way to increase understanding.
Be patient as you read.
Exercise is required to become a good reader.