Hi, Elza here from Elza's bookshelf.
I get up as you see and that's because I've got a back shot.
It was pretty awful indeed.
I go on pretty strong medicines.
I am still in pain and have a very hard time sitting for a long time.
I usually sit down on the floor and I won't be able to do that during this video
Which will probably be long.
So that's why I stand up.
We test this, we'll see how it gets, how it feels.
I'll probably take quite a few breaks.
You will not notice it, but I will notice it.
I will take some breaks.
But so you know why I get up.
I don't know, this might work to stand up at all.
I do not know yet.
But this week we will summarize my reading month for April, the birthday month.
It's been a good month.
Many middle milk and so on.
And many books that I have liked.
Top three is really top three.
And I actually think, if I am to be honest, that I recommend all these books that I should talk about now.
I start with what I liked at least and end with what I liked best.
But I like them all and recommend them all.
So it's been a good month that way.
So you know what, there are quite a few books so we start at once I think.
The first book I want to talk about is an audio book.
It is my series that I keep going through, but which I have taken a break from.
The Haunting Danielle series and this book is called The Ghost of Halloween past.
Is that what?
Yes.
By Bobby Holmes.
It is still, we can accompany Danielle who inherits a house somewhere.
And the thing about Danielle is that she can see the ghosts.
And people die a little here and there and become ghosts and she kind of has to fix things.
It happens a lot, it's cozy ghost history, easy -going books.
I like this very much.
Maybe this one was a bit tough, I must say.
But I liked the whole.
There were some new characters you got to know and I liked the whole.
And I like Danielle even though she is a little weird sometimes I like her.
I gave this about 3-3.5 something and I like it very much.
But now I have taken a break from this series.
But I miss Danielle and her Shenanigans with the ghosts actually.
Then I want to talk about the bullet who didn't hit Richard Osman.
This is probably the third book on Thursday's murder club series.
Where we get to accompany a couple of pensioners who solve True Crime.
Every Thursday they go through a True Crime and then it's Cold Cases.
So cold cases, so they go through and will solve.
Then some people die here and there at the nursing home and then they will solve real murders in real time.
It is difficult to explain but here it is the same.
You have to follow the characters.
These are new cases.
She and Elizabeth's background come up quite a lot.
You get to know her a little more.
I think these are so damn good these books.
These are not typically Elza books.
I was not at all impressed with the first book.
Everyone loved it but I thought it was meh.
But the second book I liked very well and the third book as well.
But the second book is actually still my favorite.
But this one is totally okay reading too.
I have a lot gave in this one.
I think I gave it type 3.5 too.
This is something that you in that style recommend this series.
Very charming.
Okay, I want to talk about Saga about the ring.
I have listened to the first book.
What is it called?
The ring and the brothership.
Something very male.
The ruler may be called.
First book anyway.
This is the reason why I chose to pause the Daniele series.
Haunting Daniele series
Because I want to go through the fairy tale about the ring.
In April I listened to the first.
It is a listening.
The first time I read it.
20 years ago.
It was 20 years since the first time I read it.
And now I've listened to it.
And I like it just as much.
I gave it in four.
It is a ring to rule them all.
And it's a really dangerous ring.
Our Frodo finds it or has it.
And he should get through.
He must ruin this ring.
And then there are a lot of things that happen.
You who know and have seen the movies understand.
I think this is really good.
Although I actually think the films are better.
But this one is really good.
The first book is absolutely great.
And I'll try to get through the second and third book.
For summer.
IM not in a hurry.
This is calm listening.
And I like it very much.
So I've listened to it.
Yes, 3.75.
Four very large adventures.
This is this epic fantasy adventure.
This is like The Mother of Fantasies.
I think it was the one who paved away for all other epic adventures.
Yes, eternal, eternal.
It's a bit good anyway.
Now I want to talk about the month of world literature.
I go to Japan and read breasts and eggs.
By Meiko Kawakami.
Here we have ...
Here we can accompany Natsuko and her sister and niece.
All these three women are in the middle of one of their own female thoughts.
There is a lot of breast enlargements talking about if her sister wants to do.
Natsuki himself is thinking about sperm donation.
Her niece, now I don't remember what her name is,
But she thinks very much about the first period she has not yet received.
What I think is very good about this book.
It is very long, but what is good about this book is how
This female perspective may arrive.
Kawakami, she like, she doesn't excuse anything.
She is not trying to beautify anything, but this is straightforward
About what many women go through.
And I love the liberating feeling of talking about the women's body in such a normal way.
So these things that a women's body goes through with the thoughts
without being objectified.
I gave it a strong four.
I thought it was a little too long.
Some scenes felt extended, some scenes felt a bit like why is.
Why am I as a reader?
Why am I in this particular event?
For it, the story does not continue.
At the same time it was fascinating to read, because we get to know a Japan
Which is a little different from the Japanese literature I can read about.
Here is a little more misery, it's poverty, women's vulnerability
Which I haven't really read in Japanese literature before.
I really like this four.
Four I definitely get it.
Now it's time to talk about one of the "dust off" books.
Because I have traded three pieces "dust off" this month.
I'll bring this out.
Now I am not really going to wear heavy
But now it gets a bit like that.
It's heavy.
Life after life by Kate Atkinson.
It feels so unusual to get up here, but I hope you keep up.
It just feels so strange to get up.
Life by life.
It was this.
This is a “dust off”
But this is also randomly chosen this for April.
So two flies in a bang with this book.
I was overjoyed.
You who saw the video for my TBR for April
Know how overjoyed I was about reading this one.
I was definitely not disappointed.
I made a reading logo.
I link the reading logging down in the description
so you can get to follow the trip as I read through it
So I don't talk much about it.
I gave this one four.
A strong four.
We can follow Ursula who is born again all the time.
She dies and then she is born again in the same life.
They are the same parenting siblings and the same timeline if you say so.
She learns from her mistakes.
She begins to navigate.
It is a very fascinating read about other chances.
About sixth mind.
Not so much sixth mind as I had hoped at
But a little like this how different choices in life.
How small choices, small events can affect a whole life.
I think it was so good this book.
That said, I gave it a four.
I'm not going to talk so much more about it.
I link the reading logging down in the description so you can keep up with
Step by step how I thought and liked this book.
The book club wanted us to read Daisy Jones and the Six
by Taylor Jenkins Reed.
I have read a book by her before.
Evelyn Hugo's seven genuine men is well called.
I really liked it.
Really incredibly good about it.
I am very curious about her as a writer.
Here is my second book and I am definitely not disappointed.
I listen to this book and it was great.
There were different readers.
Each character had its own reader.
It was almost like listening to a radio documentary.
It was incredibly good.
I was hanging out and enjoyed this very much.
The book is about a fictional rock band in the 70s.
It is their path to Fame and Fall.
Their rise and fall.
What was it that happened between Daisy Jones and the band The Six
When they mashed up and then they broke in.
Something happened and then you have to follow different characters.
How the memory also works.
I thought she succeeded very well with this.
There are so many who have said it is so good
Because you forget that this is an inventory.
This band does not exist.
This has never happened.
But she writes like it has actually happened.
I think it was very fascinating.
I gave a strong four.
I liked it just because I don't like rock.
I didn't like Daisy Jones as a character.
An incredibly unpleasant person.
I would never be able to have such a person in my life.
The rest of the characters were dry.
I did not agree with them at all.
Nevertheless, it was fascinating to follow their lives.
Wonder what happened.
So she succeeded.
It went up and down.
It was a bit tough at first.
But it took off.
I liked the four.
Jenkins Reid still has not disappointed me.
This was very exciting.
I was so fascinated by how she succeeded.
It was a bit the same as Evelyn Hugo.
She told us about Hollywood during that time.
This has not happened.
It feels like I'm reading a documentary.
It is great written.
Daisy Jones and the Six is the same.
I get so committed to something that does not exist.
It feels like it doesn't exist.
It is good positive.
It's time for another dust.
This book is not very tough.
I'll pick it up.
I'm glad it's not as heavy.
This book is not very tough.
Maximum one year I think.
Spring, summer, last year maybe.
I do not remember.
But it's not everything old.
I got so hungry for something easy.
I'm a little craving such mysterious books.
Or a little scary too.
If you have to choose a little.
I do not know why.
I drive on it.
This book.
That weekend by Kara Thomas.
It was a chance.
I saw it.
Thought it seems interesting.
Bought it.
I have not heard of it before.
I haven't seen anyone talk about it.
I haven't seen it on Instagram or on Youtube or on Tiktok
I haven't seen this simply.
I do not know.
You may be aware of it.
But I didn't know it before.
Kara Thomas thinks her name feels familiar.
But I haven't read any of her.
We have to come along this.
Three friends who skip prom.
This is a youth book.
Mystery thriller for young people.
They skip their ball.
Student bale
And goes out to one of the friends' cabin.
And is there.
And should camp.
This is how something happens.
One of them is found but she has no memory of what has happened over the weekend
We have to follow her perspective.
How she tries to navigate.
What happened.
What went wrong.
What has happened to my friends.
What has happened to me.
What happened simply.
And slowly with sure, we get a picture of this.
Very exciting book.
Incredibly exciting book.
Well written.
And unpleasant.
Because I feel so sorry for her.
That has no memory.
You can't trust anyone.
Things come up.
She thinks she knew her friends.
But she doesn't.
How she is treated.
Then when she comes back.
There is a lot going on.
Of course, it's Twists and Turns.
There are some turns.
I liked this very much.
It was close to becoming full points.
Just because it was so easy to read.
And exciting.
And unpredictable a little neighbor.
Be close to getting a full -point.
But something happens at the end.
There is a detail at the end.
Which is so unnecessary.
Which is so boring.
That destroys the reading experience.
Because it just feels why.
So this one I gave a four.
And I was pleasantly surprised.
Because I had no expectations.
It seemed interesting.
I bought with it.
I was eager to buy a book.
And then it became such a full -point.
But it was a positive surprise.
So it's great fun.
Only it's fun.
A four.
Recommend it.
Would like to hear people talk about it.
She has another book.
How maybe I should check her as a writer.
But this was really good.
Except for the closed thing.
Which was completely unnecessary.
Could have gone without.
But but.
Fun.
Okay Hörrni, we're in the top three now.
Very interesting.
But the thing is
That book number three and book number two is the same series.
So I don't really know how to do it.
So I mash them two.
But I'm talking about a good girl's guide to murder.
Now we are in place number three in the series.
I've been able to read two.
I am just listening to the third book.
It's a trilogy.
Location number three comes book number two.
Named
A Good Girl's Bad Blood.
And the first book is then called
A Good Girl's Guide to Murder.
We must bring that with Pipp.
She
do one
School projects.
She wants to be
Investigator in police then.
She is doing a school project where she is to
try to solve an old cold case.
And then so
It happens a lot of things.
It is so good.
I listen to it.
She is a great reader.
There are interviews.
There are recordings.
These are notes.
It is hers
own thoughts.
How she then attempts
dig in this case and try to understand
what happened five years ago
When a girl disappeared
And her boyfriend
Then found
Death in the forest.
Great.
Book number two.
Although she
Solves the case
In the first book.
But it happens so much in the first book
that has connections to things that
she is digging forward that leads
To the second book.
And there it happens
A little same.
But there she has another case
that leads to that
There is a red thread.
This case as she
Solves the first book is after all
a bit like a red thread in all
others also that provide consequences
In her life.
That allows one to follow her
on book number two and then book number three
now.
I have not listened clearly to book number three
But I like these book
a lot.
I gave them all
not all in the third but
These two I gave strong four.
I thought the first book was snap
better than others
and it's probably just because
The case is more interesting if I am to be
honest.
For on book number two
Good girl, bad blood
is the case one
Friend disappears.
She is going to try
Find him.
It is
not as interesting but that is the first case
Which is incredible
skillfully written and much more
interesting.
I am
so peppy on this one
third book to listen to
And like it so far very much.
Four, like this series
Recommend this series to everyone.
Okay, now then place number one
it is a
"Dust of" book.
I forgot to
Pick it up.
Wait, give me a second.
Now
I have this one.
It's a "Damma of" book
a book that I have had
two years perhaps of
A writer I am a huge nick at
and
He didn't disappoint me.
I was talking about
The Devil and the Darkwater
by Stuart Turton.
It is he who has written the seven
The fashion of Evelyn Hardcastle.
This puzzle covers with a sci-fi
Twist.
Everything with that book
I love.
It became a full point.
I do not know
I just died when I read that book.
I love it.
So it is, it's almost like that
It is written for me as well as with one
Pussel cover.
It's Mystery Thriller as well
actively.
And so with a sci-fi twist.
Love it.
This
is not the same but it is still
A puzzle cover.
Here we are in
1600s, yes we are in
1630s.
A couple of people
some privileged than others
more privileged than others
jumping on a boat that they are going from
From Indonesia I believe to
Amsterdam.
And this
is type eight months' journey.
I don't know how much the thought makes me
anxiety.
But they are on this boat
And then people start to be murdered
And they believe
That it can be a demon.
That one of these is obsessed with the demon.
But is it really a demon?
Isn't it just for what is happening?
And so obviously on the boat we have after all
a master detective and his
Apprentice or something.
And so much happens.
What I appreciate most on this book is
The strong ones
female characters.
It is completely, totally sick
how
Strong they are.
I am not
disappointed at any of these
Female characters, incredibly heated.
Without the characters
at all actually is incredible
well written and
credible.
I like them
not everyone, but I'm interested
of them all.
I don't feel
engaged in their fate
as well as.
What is going to happen?
At all to understand
this, what is it that
Hands on the boat?
Is it
Really a demon?
Or is it someone
like, who is
that kills these people?
It is incredibly fascinating and it is well
Background ... So there is of course all
passenger
more or less all of them have as well as
a dark secret that they carry on
and things tilling arrives
Giant, great.
Incredibly well written.
So entertaining.
Thus this one is 500
Plus pages, but it doesn't feel that way.
For every time I brought it up
So just flew the sides.
This was a buddy reading with
Victoria from the War of Book
And she said the same thing.
She just, ie when I just pick it up so just
So these pages disappear.
I was always clear far before
We would talk about it, because we said we would talk about
the one every Sunday, but I was done far before
and it was because it just, that's that
Good, it's so exciting.
This one is 4.5
for the next one, the more I think about
This can be full points.
I think
That, we say full points.
I have released
I think I gave it 4.75 or something
But this is full points the more I think about it.
A little bit in the middle was
maybe a little tough, but who
Bry it is so good.
And the end
And like The Reveal and Man Just
God so good.
Yet another new writer,
Favorite authors this year I have found.
Stuart Turton
You did it again.
Thanks so much
I bend and bow.
Now
There they were.
My books that I could read in April
was my birthday month.
It was really
A great reading
for I have on real
hand on heart, I recommend
All these books I've talked about in this one
The video.
Yes and now i have stood up
It went well, I survived this video as well.
We'll see
How the editing becomes, but
God what funny that I actually
could make it.
I was close to not
record but I did it and now you know
all the books I have read and I am of course
very curious about how your reading month has been
And how April has been.
And of course I want to hear what you think about the books
I have read.
Have you read them?
What do you think?
What don't you think?
Talk to me in the comments field
Then we hear there.
Otherwise we will be visible next week and don't forget
In my thumbs up and subscribe to my channel
If you don't already do it.
Farewell
Now, goodbye!