Hi, Elza here from Elza's bookshelf.
It's time for spring's last video before I take summer holidays,
So I was going to summarize the reading for Juni month.
It was a perfectly okay month, of which the top three is really top three.
I got a positive surprise.
I can tick off some things on my book challenges.
Over all very good months.
So that's why I think we start with, before I say hello then and explain a little how I think before the summer,
So I think we start by talking about the books I have read in June.
And of course I start with the one I liked at least and end with the one I like best.
And let's start with the one I liked at least, that was the world literature.
I went to India and read Visny's death by Manil Suri.
This is some kind of philosophical, touch of magical realism.
We are in Bombay, I think, in an apartment building.
There is a person like Vishnu, his name is Vishnu.
He lives in the staircase and helps those as residents.
He is of a low burden.
And then he or something, he is dying on the stairs.
While lies there for death, in the middle of the stairs more or less,
So a lot of drama happens around people living in the staircase.
And that is different perspectives.
And you can also join Vishnus, in the midst of his dying.
Flashbacks to his life, to his childhood, to his first love.
Even a little Indian mythology is there and we get to learn some gods and so on.
This sounds like a perfect book for me, because I like when it's a little magical realism.
It may be a touch of philosophy and such.
But it doesn't reach me.
I don't think this is good at all.
Just because this magical realism as a writer is trying to tackle, does not work.
It just gets ..
Strange instead.
There is no flow, there will be no good transitions.
The characters also feel ..
Not credible.
Because I get like this, wait, what happened now?
Why did he do that?
Why is he doing so there?
There is a lot that just hangs in the air.
I gave it the second.
It's a dust of book, so I can check it.
It's a world literature so I can tick it off.
But it is also such a book that I have included in the list of 10 books I will read in 2023.
That way it is nice that I can tick off this book.
Then I want to talk about months of random.
For those who have seen the reading logo
So every month I let in chance choose a book.
The book that was chosen for June I dnf-adoled.
I couldn't read it, I couldn't handle it.
So I took a new one in the Reading Log I choose a new one.
And then there were secrets at Sea View Cottage.
Yes, Emily Gunnis, Sea View Cottage.
I had not had it for so long in the bookshelf or in my TBR on goodreads.
But this one was really good, short just relative.
We are allowed to accompany a mother
Who disappears with his newborn baby.
You have to look for her.
At the same time, it is also a journalist who starts digging into this.
And these stories, while all looking for this mother and baby
So you also find out some historical background to things.
And these two stories are intertwined then.
Very good.
I really liked this book incredibly much.
Positively suprised.
I went into it and said I wanted to take this one.
I had no high expectations but I didn't think it would be as dark as it actually was.
It is very dark, it takes up fairly difficult subjects.
And a little mystery there, a little twists and turns.
I liked it very much.
I gave it 3.5 I think.
It was quick to read or listen to in this case.
And I was curious about the author.
So I think I gave it 3.5 close to 4 anyway.
Because it was a little too short too.
But I'm not going to talk so much more about it.
I link the reading logo where I talk and you can accompany me in my thoughts
Down here in the description so you can, if you want, look at it.
So here we have another book that I talk about.
It is also this very good book but
Also, this book I will talk so much about because it is in one of my reading.
This, I'm talking more than you'll know by Katie Gutierrez, I think she pronounces it.
And this book is in this book challenge what I try to get through all the books that are nominated in,
What is it, Goodreads Choice Award in the category Mystery Thriller.
I'm not going to talk so much about it.
This is about a woman
who have two men.
One day, one of the man finds out that she is married to two men and kills the other man.
And then it's a blogger, journalist who is digging in this and yes,
Things happen then.
I'm not going to talk so much about it, I liked it.
This one was not short, this one is normal length, 13 hours approximately.
I'm not going to talk so much about it, I liked it very well.
It was an interesting perspective but it went up and down.
My reading went up and down, it's not even but
Over all I like it.
I also link that reading logo down in the description then you can, if you are curious about my thoughts you can look at it there.
By the way I would say that the kids down there are over there
So that you heard my background, apologize.
But so it is, I did not find otherwise, found no time to record.
Okay, the next book.
The years of Annie Eernux.
This is one, this book, during the summer we had to choose an optional book to read in the book circle and I chose the years.
I liked this book, while I also didn't like it.
It is skillfully written, here is the next autobiographical.
Annie writes for a whole lifetime as well,
So she goes through various historical events in both individual perspective and collectively.
That's how.
Very difficult to explain this book, but I liked it.
I really did.
While I was also measured.
Because it is, I was quickly measured even though it is not so thick.
I think I gave this one four, three and a half four like that.
And I am a hugety pike at Annie.
I understand
That she is a skilled writer, extremely good and I like her take on things.
Telling a whole life in this way is very fascinating.
Both me and no, but I'm glad I read Nobel Laureates, so I can say.
Then we have another pond of book, one that has been really dusty.
I think I've had this book since 2015-2016.
2015 it must have been.
Yes, 2015. I'm talking about Game of Thrones.
Here is the first book called Game of Thrones.
The series is called
A Song of Ice and Fire and the first book is called Game of Thrones.
And I've listened to it.
33 hours.
Over 33 hours was this one.
But God, what a good thing this was.
Unfortunately, I remember a lot from the TV series, because I have seen the TV series and I like the TV series very well, but I remember too much.
But it also feels fun that some things differ from the TV series, so it will be like I discover this world again in some parts.
Four, strong four, what an adventure.
I am doing book number two called A Clash of Kings.
I have this series to get through.
It went much faster than I thought, because I can't stop listening.
I have fit constantly.
That's the worst adventure.
Incredibly interesting characters.
It is well written too.
And so damn interesting only.
How intrigue it is and everyone wants the iron throne.
It is dragons and magic, but at the same time it is just pure politics as well.
This book has everything.
I thought this one was really really good.
Then I got a surprise item not so long ago.
It was a book that I have really been looking forward to reading.
Everything else had to wait.
I jumped on this at once.
I talk about the snake salt of Johan Rundberg who is the fifth part in Månvind and Hoff.
Mika and Constable Hoff are good partners in crime, I intend to say.
They solve crime for Hoff is a police officer.
We are in Sweden.
It is the 19th century.
Mika lives in orphanages.
Things happen.
The two help and solve cases.
So, so good.
This one was just as good, but what I like about the book is that they are dark and that the author Johan trusts his readers.
Because it is still 9-12 years.
Trust their readers, let them take hard topics and can handle it.
He does it in a good way.
He writes it in a good way.
Strong four, of course.
And then we have one to dust off.
This is not just a dust off, but it bends in some.
This year was the year I would read Dona Tartt.
I own three Dona Tartt.
I posted a picture of the three books on Instagram and let you vote which Dona Tartt I would start with.
And the secret story won.
I'm super happy about it because I was most craving for this one.
We have to come along ... This is probably such a storytelling style.
That narrator is Richard.
I think he uses something.
Richard Pap may be a pronounced it.
He starts at a prestigious college.
Hangs with the elites there.
But everything is not right with these elites.
It's a lot like ... Yes.
Then you have to keep up with this gang anyway.
When they find some shenanigans.
It is dark.
It's so sick.
Well written.
Very thick.
Over 700 pages.
I swallow this one because it is incredibly character pity.
And the character is ... they may not be ... I don't like them.
I don't sympathize with them.
But I'm fascinated by them.
I want to know more.
Tartt has a way to explore man's innermost darkness in such a skillfully good way.
This was better than I thought it would be.
I had high expectations.
Be really nervous.
But wow.
I swallow this book.
It's very thick.
I wish I had it in another.
I wish I had the black cover.
This one is good looking.
I do not complain.
The black is a little better.
Mysterious.
I can't explain more than this one is so good.
It deserves the hype it has.
I'm glad I can check it now.
Now I can tick off the dust off.
And a Donna Tartt book that I said I would read.
A strong four.
Yes, a strong four.
My absolute favorite this year.
This month.
I have to say that it was a book that took me by surprise.
I was so surprised.
I did not have very high expectations.
I had no expectations at all.
I thought I would like to read it here, it's a dusted AV book, the classic.
I'm hungry and curious.
I had read another book by him and liked it very much.
I thought I have it at home.
Animal Farm by George Orwell.
Listen.
Listen what masterpiece this is.
This is the satire's satire.
It is incredibly smart, incredibly skillfully written and so damn spot on.
Okay, we're on a farm.
The animals do revolt against the humans.
This is about barley and pigs and horses that make revolt.
This is a satire.
This should make Narra how light power can corruption, how easily it can corrupt power.
How things, how it all started so well.
The animals should only support ourselves.
We know how it will be late to a dictator.
Very written, incredibly well written.
I am so impressed and it was much easier to understand and read than I thought it was.
I liked this much more than 1984, which I liked.
I liked in 1984, but this one is so damn good.
There is a new translation and that was the one I listened to.
So I didn't read it and I listened to it.
Wow.
I just say wow.
Now I want to know more about George Orwell.
Now I am very curious about him.
He is well sharp, incredibly good at putting words into things that I find difficult to describe myself.
Very happy that I can dust off this.
Now I want to know everything about George Orwell.
Who is he?
How did he think?
What happened?
That's how.
There we have the books that I have been able to read during Juni month, which you hear.
I am very peppy and recommend many of them.
Except for a book, Vishnus' death.
You know what?
Are you not interested?
Don't read it.
Do you think it sounds interesting?
Test it.
But I was not so impressed.
The rest of these books I have read this month have been absolutely fantastic and I recommend them, which you heard.
Then we got it clarified.
Now I'm going to take summer vacation.
I'll be back at the beginning of September sometime.
But I probably won't be completely gone.
Because I will do some reading blogs.
I have chosen ..
Random has selected a book for July.
Romanov.
I thought I would do a reading logo.
I had planned that anyway.
Then we have August left too.
I might come back in the form of reading vlogs a little now and then.
But I don't know when.
I do not know how.
I can't promise I do.
But who knows.
Then I have another thing to tell and that is that I have started to make subtitles for my videos.
I have tried.
I have found a great program where you upload a video and it generates the text.
But you have to check and read and look.
Which makes it take a long time.
So to all the language police out there.
Take a deep breath.
Have you done it?
Take one more.
And turn off the subtitles if you disturb it.
Because I can't guarantee it's 100% right.
Because I can't cope.
It's so very funny.
I don't have that time.
But I still want there to be an alternative that I can give.
For those who want it.
So I will try to do.
I will prioritize my wrap ups.
So these videos there where I tell you what books I have read during the month.
Because it is the ones who have the most views.
These are the ones that are popular.
So then I think it
Is good to be able to provide that service if you say so.
So they will prioritize.
But as I said.
It won't be perfect.
There will be some knots.
I apologize.
But there is so much pill and job.
But if you see something crunchy, I say so to and I'll try to fix it.
Then you know it too.
I try to.
I fight with subtitles.
When I get done.
Who knows.
But I'm trying.
I try to.
Now.
Now I have told you what books I have learned and liked in June.
I have also talked about my subtitles.
Adventure Experiment I am doing.
And then I have told me that I take summer holidays now.
But maybe come back in the form of reading vlogs.
Who knows.
I want to say nice summer to you.
So we will hear in September.
And take it easy out there.
Farewell.
See you.
Bye!