Hi, Elza here from Elza's bookshelf.
It's time to summarize May month's reading.
It's been a totally okay month.
The best thing about this month has been that I have finished three series.
I am not such a reader who has many series going on and has not finished them.
For those of you who hang out here know that when I start a series, I would like it to ...
So I swallow them at once and I don't start a series.
Or it happens, of course.
But I prefer to start a series that already has an end.
So it's not like this, oh I've finished three series of such.
But it's fun to finish a series anyway.
And I have done three pieces.
It's been a totally okay month.
Many of these books I have to say, they have given me very good reading experiences for the moment.
But in hindsight, I don't remember much of them.
I don't remember much about them.
So you know.
But do you know what?
We start, we start a couple of books.
Start with the one I liked at least and ends with the one I liked best.
The first books I want to talk about are actually three books.
Because I think I merges them here in some way.
And it is actually "dust off", a couple of books that I have had for any length of time.
Very long.
And I have grazed these three books in a series.
It's 6-7-8, numbers 6-7-8.
And I have grazed them.
Now I don't really remember how they come.
But I think this is ...
Here is number 6.
In the company of Muntra Women by Alexandra McCall-Smith.
And then I think happens and a pair of blue shoes.
And number 8 then it is the good husband on Zebra Drive.
This is Botswana's first women's detective agency.
I think the series is called the Women's Detective Agency.
Botswana's first female detective.
And MMA Ramotswe, I think she pronounces it.
And she solves cases.
This is a cozy deck deluxe.
And I think I've read some cozy books nowadays.
And I feel that now I'm up here with them.
I feel now.
For several reasons.
This series is really a cozy deck.
Where the cases must not take place so much.
Without it, it is more about those who work with her.
And Ramotswe himself.
MMA Ramotswe himself.
So I know I liked them very well.
But I haven't thought about how babbbar they were.
And how little of her rocky is.
What I liked a lot about the first three books I read.
Was that she was so smart.
She thought in her own way.
She solved these cases that were very fascinating and interesting.
But here it does not come out at all.
I will not read on this series.
I am very measured on this series.
So I think I all gave them to 2.5.
3 Max.
So there.
We say 3.
Rounds up a bit.
Thanks but no thanks again then.
Now I feel that I do not want a cozy deck.
Another book I want to talk about is The It Girl by Ruth Ware.
I will not talk about this very much about this.
Because I'm about to make a reading logo about it.
Because this is one of these books I do in my reading series.
Where I read all the books that are nominated in Goodreads Choice Award.
And select your own winner.
Or what I like about the winner.
If the right book won.
But here we have to come along.
This is also such a book.
Very exciting for the moment.
Mystery Thriller.
Classic mystery thriller like that.
And I don't remember the names.
I remember what it is about but not the names or something like that.
We can accompany two girls.
They become best friends in college.
One of them is rich and fancy.
And one is a bit like us the other.
They become best friends.
One day she is found murdered in her ...
In their room.
And ten years after or fifteen years after so ...
It is a man who is allowed to be convicted of this murder.
But ten years later, he may not be the one who did.
Twist Turns.
I liked the end.
I liked Twist-ish.
But the road there was long.
I'm not going to talk so much about it more.
What I think comes in a reading logo very soon.
Within the next few days.
I hope.
Another book that was also good for the moment type.
But as I also kind of forgot.
Are heart lines of wide Bennett.
I listened to it.
Also such a book that is very good.
It's about two sisters.
Maybe twin sisters.
I don't know the names.
One can be taken .. It is in the United States.
African American family.
Two sisters.
One is so bright that she can be taken too white.
While the other is a little darker.
They are very tight.
But something happens in their lives.
They are separated.
We must follow their lives.
It was a long starting distance.
It was long.
It was very tough.
Incredibly tough.
When I think back, I remember scenes from it.
They were totally okay.
It is good.
It is well written.
But it was like ...
I experienced it as extremely tough.
Just so scattered.
I didn't know what it wanted to tell me.
I gave it a third.
A weak one.
I'm glad I read it.
But give me a month and I don't remember so much of it.
Unfortunately.
I've read this month.
One of the series I have read.
This month is Saga about the Ringen triology.
Last month I read the first book, Saga about the ring.
They are so good that I swallowed the rest of the other two in May.
The one I want to talk first about is number three.
I have it in this edition.
Really heavy.
All three books are here in.
This is so heavy.
It's kind of a thousand pages, 950 plus thus, I don't know
All three books are here anyway, with illustration.
I actually listened to them, I just have to show
Here we have an illustration.
This one is really nice anyway
Of the three, I liked at least the story of the king's return,
The reason for this is that there is a lot of fight scenes.
It is very politically a little bit.
Fight scenes I think you look at.
But I don't like to read about them.
So it was a lot so I just yes, yes, okay, they fight, so okay, yes, yes.
So that's why.
I gave it a third, a strong, strong third.
Of the three books, I think that the king's return is the weakest.
Then we have the world's world literature.
And I really want to like it.
But I don't.
Not as much as I had hoped and actually thought I would do.
I actually thought I would like it.
I'm talking about the shadow king by Maaza Mengiste.
Maybe, you pronounce it.
Fantastic edition, so fantastic cover.
We may accompany Hirut, maybe her name is.
I don't remember that much.
We are in Ethiopia.
It is in the 30s.
It's fascism.
Italy comes in.
And so we can accompany a bunch of female soldiers most often.
Soldiers or those fighting against the Italians.
And this should be the focus on the female.
I think it was tough bit by bit.
The language is amazing.
I can't complain about the language so much.
But I think I feel it is a little too thick.
So for the long step best.
This poetic painting language is very beautiful.
But it gets too much when the book is so long.
Then I wished I got more female characters.
We may have three, four women who are portrayed.
I wanted to have more focus on these female characters.
And then you jump a little here and there.
And I have a hard time keeping up.
But on the other hand, I have learned an incredible amount of this story.
A story that I did not keep in mind at all.
And I started to read something else.
It gave me a craving for other historical novels.
Or historical books about this time for Ethiopia.
I gave it a strong third.
Because it is still important.
It is still readable.
And most importantly, it taught me something.
But I wished it would be easier to read.
It was difficult to pick it up.
I couldn't motivate myself to pick it up.
Then we have another book that I am reading about.
It's The Night Shift by Alex Finlay.
Here we have another one like this in this reading logo.
As I go through all the Goodreads Choice Awards nominations for best mystery thriller.
So I'm not going to talk very much about it either.
I hope, as I said, the vlog will come up soon.
I have another book in the reading logo that I am reading.
As I want to include in it.
This is also like this mystery thriller classic.
In 1999, a guy comes and kills a couple of young people in a blockbuster business.
Then it happens the same thing in the same city but in another deal.
Then there is a blogger who sustains this and wants to know more.
I thought this one was better, quickly sharper better.
Partly because it is much shorter and gives a rap in the language.
But also that it was a little smarter written.
The resolution is smarter.
It's a little faster, it's going fast.
It has some tough sequences.
I think what, who, what all the time.
But I should also be honest.
Give me a few more months and I will forget this book.
It is fantastic at the moment.
For the moment it was fun.
It was quick to read it, I liked it.
I gave it a strong third.
But I will also be honest, I will not remember it.
It's not mindblowing.
But I liked this one.
It was quick to read, it was fun.
It was a trip like that.
Lovely trip like that.
But mystery thriller simply.
Now I have to talk about a book that helped my TBR.
As all other books had to wait.
I jumped on the train at once.
I'll be honest.
This is a book that the whole world has been waiting for.
At least I waited extremely impatient was me.
But when I got it, I swallowed it pretty much.
But, there is a men.
I talked about Atlas.
What is it called?
The story of Pa Salt by Lucinda Riley.
And her son Harry Whittaker.
Whittaker?
Harry.
This is the last book in the seven sisters series.
This ends everything.
All questions receive answers.
All all the mystery is only served to you.
The answer to this great mystery.
Who and what and how.
In this book.
It delivers absolutely.
At the same time, I'm a little disappointed.
Because it is still a brick.
Shall we see.
Over 600 pages.
So it's very tall, it's a brick
Despite that, I feel and I feel that it is accelerated.
It goes so fast.
Such pink shimmer around this.
How hard times they go through.
Pa salt goes through.
You find out about his whole story.
How it turned out.
All what happened.
I have to say that I think it was just too cute cute.
It was very easy.
It went too fast.
None too deep.
There was no depth.
I'm disappointed with it.
I almost wished it was ...
I don't know what I would have liked.
But I would have liked more depth.
I had wanted more depth.
Everything else is great.
It is still fantastic.
We get answers and good answers.
It is an incredibly good ending.
We get an end.
It's really nice.
Adventure.
He travels all over the world.
Descriptions.
Environmental descriptions are fantastic.
This is still a readable book.
But I think the strength of this series
are the strong female portraits.
Not on salt.
To think about it.
Is that what makes me not fall?
I gave it in third.
A strong one.
It is still readable.
I think the whole series is fantastic.
Do you like historical novels with strong female characters
So this series is for you.
Absolutely.
Me who has followed this about
Expectations and hopes
and all that
Poor this book.
It had so much on its shoulders.
Of course, you can't fulfill everything.
But totally okay.
Absolutely okay.
Fantastic ending.
We got an end.
Top three now.
In third place I wanted to talk about
Oh what is it called.
I just have to read inside.
Oh I have it in Swedish.
The peculiar event with the dog
by Mark Haddon.
So this was a month's coincidence.
Random was that I would read this book
by Haddon and I have a reading logo
I link it down in the description
So that I should not talk so much about it.
But
I feel that I am stressing through
sorry.
This book was very good.
It's about Christopher
Which then has
a diagnosis.
I guess some kind of
Autism spectrum.
One day
Does he find the neighbor's dog murdered
so he decides to him
Solve the murder.
Who has killed the dog?
This starts with some sort of
We are inside his head.
Here one begins
a little of one
mystery as he solves
leading him to
things within their own family
which is revolving to him.
I gave it a four I think.
Three and a half, three and seventy five maybe.
I'm not going to talk so much more about it.
I link the reading logo
If you want to know more about my thoughts
So there is
The link down there in the description.
The journey I took through that book.
But I liked it
Although I have some thoughts too.
And there we have
and just yes, sorry
This one is others
The series I finish
this month.
And
we go back to the story of the ring
so we have this one
and in second place
will the story of the two towers
And I think
It is fantastic.
God what trip it has been.
I think it's great fun.
It's just so one
Classic adventure
with the hobbits
With the sorcerers
with the king
With the world building
It is incredibly good.
Long books, they are big and thick
But very easy to read
and
less song than I remember
thought it would be
And positively, I think.
No but i think this was
very good, i think they are great
I gave it a four
And want to see
about the movies, it's been a long time since I saw the movies
Actually, so I want to see them.
This is great, much much better
than I thought it would be.
For I read the first book
When I went to high school, it took a while
To take me through it.
I started
The second book, thought it was so tough and
But so about 20 years later I devour them.
No but this was great
What adventure was exactly what I wanted.
I wanted an adventure, I wanted an epic
Saga and world building
and no this was great
Oh what a good thing this was.
And in the first place we have
The third series I finished this month
As good as the dead by Holly Jackson
and it's third and last
The book I.
A Good Girl's Guide to Murder
I am not going to tell you so much about what this is about
but there we can follow along
Pippa is her name?
Beep
which will then resolve
First book
Her school project
is to solve a five years
Old case
that happens in her city and this
first book and what happens in the first
the book has consequences and drawn
out in two books and now this is the final
As good as the dead.
I know this is a water divider
either you like it or you don't like it
because it takes one
other turn than what one first
Believe, it takes a darker turn
And you who hang out here know that I
prefer dark, deep
Complicated books
and this one is deep, it's dark
and it is sickly complicated
It's like gray zones
Deluxe and I love it
God what good this series was
I know I call it a four
But wholeness as a series I want to
give a full point
Great ending
I am really pleased
and that is so exciting
no but then it was
great, which, that is enough
really the only book
as really like this in a long time
As I was
for it is so smartly done for things
and ting is connected together
yeah that's good, it's great
I don't know why but it feels like me
stressed through, I hope that
I haven't done it, tell me in
comment field if there is anything else
you want to hear from
my thoughts on these books I have read
I pray so much about excuses
I don't know why it was more stressed
I felt it might not be like that
But of course I am curious as always
About these books I have read, about what you think
about them, so tell me in the comments field
and also tell me what book
Be your favorite in May, do you have any such
Was there any full point in May
Talk to me in the comments field
so we hear there
We'll see you next week, I have no idea what's going on next week
But we'll see you next week
Don't forget to give me a thumbs up and subscribe to my channel
If it doesn't already
take care bye