Welcome to this training which is about open access.
Open asset is a concept that has become current-
-In the research and library world in recent years-
-And that will increase in importance to the entire society in the future.
Simply explained, open access means that it should be possible for anybody-
-To free of charge take part in research results-
-For example, scientific publications, by searching the internet.
This might not sound so remarkable-
-But the fact is that the open asset means a major change-
-For both the research world and the libraries that make the research available.
Open access is part of another current concept, open science.
In an open science system-
-In open access to scientific publications and research data
-But also such as open learning resources and citizen participation in research.
The government has decided that scientific publications and research data
-while the result of publicly funded research-
-Do be openly available.
Whether you work at a library such as kb-
-or any other research library or if you are a scientist-
-Will you be affected by the movement against open access and open science.
The transition to open access and science has been going on for almost 20 years-
-But is still under development.
This means that we do not have all the answers to how open access will work.
In this training, which takes about 30 minutes-
-will you get a broad introduction to what open access is-
-and how it can affect you in your work.
You get to meet colleagues who talk about their views on open access from different perspectives.