- Thanks so much.
I am also curious about this task.
To lead a research circle and discuss digitization in libraries.
I was going to tell you about my own research and why it is exciting to be here
And discuss your texts in a way that I have not worked with much in teaching form.
Is it okay with the sound?
I have no powerpoint this time.
What have I researched in recent years?
You mentioned some popular concepts: automation, algorithms, digital media.
What does it really mean?
When I try to describe my core interests in my research
I always return to a concept that may not mean much anymore - democracy.
Participation in society, and how it is related to media.
All my research has been about it - how do we feel involved in society?
How can the media contribute to or limit the feeling of participation?
A concrete study that I have done in connection with it looks at various political movements.
One can think about participation and attitudes to the media in different ways.
One can think of ethics, emotions, physicality, sweating.
But you can also think about political issues.
What kind of politics?
How does it limit citizens?
To relate to some with media ecologies.
There I have taken a historical perspective and over time tried to follow the change process.
From the 30s and the labor movement.
Their printing press, their own flyers, and what role such expressions played,
Until the 2010s, and the digital present we are moving in.
What it makes you have to relate to media infrastructures
Which constantly requires content production.
You may not have so much time to think about the content and message.
A kind of time change that comes with the media we use as political activists.
It was a project I was doing for a few years.
Right now I have two projects that can be linked to this discussion.
The first is a project that started with an interest in the digital imperative.
We must all relate to digitalisation as private individuals or at work.
As Jonna uses the philosophers in the past to contrast the present
So I want to explore the digital imperative through environments that are perceived as non-digital.
What are the environments today?
Are they at all?
Prisons, I thought.
There are no digital media, right?
The inmates have no access to the Internet, and so on.
Then I began to approach this environment, which to me feels far away from everyday life.
I have no experience with it, but I am beginning to be able to see the digital imperative
Through an environment that from the beginning feels far away from the digital.
There are ideas about smart prisons, both regarding surveillance, data -find the inmates,
monitor them and try to predict conflicts.
There are different ideas about prisons where new technologies can be developed.
Some restrictions that exist in society at large are not found in prisons.
There are also questions about access to digital media
as a rehabilitation opportunity for the inmates.
It's a way for me to approach the digital imperative.
By looking at environments that may be perceived as non-digital.
There I can clearly see change processes that apply to society at large.
Another project, which is linked to the library environment and digitalisation,
is about automated decision -making in the public sector.
Automation in the public sector where you delegate different decisions
to algorithms and technological infrastructure.
I am conducting interviews with people working in the public sector.
Specifically, I interview people at the Employment Service at different levels.
In the leadership, in the group that develops artificial intelligence and algorithmic solutions
To be able to delegate information to the robots.
But I also talk to the administrators.
I am trying to approach a digitization process
through concrete stories from their everyday lives.
How does it feel to work with some infrastructures?
What are the restrictions?
How can the organization get better?
Where do you lose in interpersonal contact?
When talking to the administrators, they say it is no problem.
It is a logical consequence.
We as bureaucrats should not think ourselves, we should be algorithms.
We must follow the rules and not see the individual in our work.
It should not make any difference if I meet you or you.
I'll always follow the same rules.
An algorithm is ganke much better than a human
Which has judgment, emotions, and sweat.
Who has problems, and sees different things at the same time.
It is perhaps this process that Jonna has talked about that you experience.
Actually, the algorithms may be better than we are.
It is interesting to see how they wrestle with it.
On the one hand, the administrators have an idea of themselves with values.
They have democracy in the self description.
They understand as mediators in a democracy, between the state and the citizen.
What happens if you perceive yourself as rule -controlled, and the information is then delegated to the machines?
What happens to the relationship between the citizen and the state in the automation process?
That's what I'm interested in.
In all my research I have with me the citizen's perspective.
I try to approach the clients.
How do they experience the change process?
How do they feel that the relationship with authorities changes if they meet a digital interface?
If the meeting is about guidance remotely?
On Melja, having phone calls and attending online courses remotely.
The Employment Service strives to have as much as possible at a distance.
There it is difficult to find a way to approach the citizen perspective.
I interview associations that help to facilitate government contacts.
Help build trust in authorities, and so on.
Last week I interviewed the process chain, where prison and automation meet.
Process chain is an organization that helps young
which is about to end up obliquely, or who come from different institutions, out into society again.
One step in their work is to help with government contacts.
How they handle extended digitization, and how it changed over time,
Be interesting to talk to them about.
For them, it is a lot about trust that is built through personal meetings.
Which they perceive as difficult to manage through digital meetings and interfaces.
Library becomes a place where many aspects must be captured.
Building trust is a long and intense process that requires many exchanges.
The first contact usually starts with BankID.
They must help with such simple first steps.
It is not really their core business.
But the first contact with authorities begins with the Swedish Social Insurance Agency or the Employment Service,
In the stories I have taken part in Mirror's aspects of something that may feel greater.
A sense of participation in society that breaks down to a first step
Which can be BankID, which opens access to other tracks.
It will be exciting to discuss more how the role of the library has changed.
In the same way that the process of the chain's work has changed with digitization.
There has been a shift from core business to something else.
How can you incorporate it into a larger project that means more than downloading BankID?
Thanks so much.