Hello!
My name is Fatima Klanco Al Mulki.
I work at the Royal Library.
I will now show how to primarily catalog a book with non-Latin alphabet.
The described approach applies to version 1.19 of Libris cataloging and may change.
I have chosen a book that is in Serbian with Cyrillic alphabet.
I will now search for the Serbian translation of Christer Karphamam "judges in lawless countries".
We are looking for here in free text on the ISBN number.
And we get no hits.
I also search for a pregnant word in the title and writer, and I get no hits either.
Now that I have assured that it is not cataloged, I choose to press Create new.
Here I will get a menu of different templates and I choose printed monograph - RDA.
And before I start by filling in, I can briefly tell you about this menu on the right.
The tools include: Expand everyone, minimize, enrich from template and here you can choose different types of templates eg.
Book.
Plus signs in case one would miss any trait.
It is not relevant in this case because we are already based on a template.
Here is the Undo button and here is the Save button, or create the post button.
We can also see here that the entry is divided into an instance part and an Admind Datel.
In the instance of works, one is related to the work as agents, any preferred title, classifications, subject words.
The real instance begins at the identifier.
Here.
And here are the descriptive characteristics and information to them we retrieve directly from the manifestation.
But we start from the administration.
The first thing that meets us here is bibliography and most libraries do not have to care about this,
But within Libris there are some bibliographies that we register and such a bibliography is the national bibliography
Another is Suecana, it is Swedish material that has been translated into other languages and the Royal Library has the task of collecting and preserving.
Since this is a translation of a Swedish work and I catalog for KB, I want it to be included in the Suecana collection,
Thus, the collection of foreign material with Swedish connection that KB preserves.
And I am entering here
Suec, which stands for Suecana, instead of Sigel.
Then we have the description level.
Most libraries need to settle at library level, or choose the library level.
Post status changes automatically when we save.
Cataloging rules.
Here we see that it is an RDA post and that we use ISBD interview.
In most cases, the information should be divided into different and underlying properties.
In some exceptional cases, it is necessary to use ISBD interview within a property, to separate data, so we leave it.
Cataloging language is Swedish.
We don't change that either.
And the cataloging body is what applies to Libris library.
What we should add and that was not included in the template are two things.
One is Systemtekinsk Note and the other is modifications.
In System Technical Note, we specify which romanization home we will use when we transfer non-Latin signs to the Latin alphabet.
Within the Librian collective, we largely use the Library of Congress Romanization schedules
When transferring text with non-Latin writing to Latin writing.
Exceptions to this are made for church writing and Greek writing.
In the case of Cyrillic, KB/libris practice is that Slavic and most non -Slavic works with church writing should be translit according to ISO 9: 1995.
Instead, those libraries that need it may choose to transcribe according to KR76 (Kjellberg) and, if necessary, supplement with ALA-LC Romanization Table,
Non-Slavic Languages (In Cyrillic Script) for the extra characters that may occur in non-Slavic languages.
Exceptions make up Mongolic where the extra signs ө, ө are romanized as Swedish island, island and ү, ү as ü, ü.
And then we have exceptions for Greek which is:
Old Greek follows transliteration schedule established for scientific libraries in Swedish cataloging rules 1980 (SK).
Nygrecian texts follow transcription schedule stated for Swedish public libraries following the library service's practice for public libraries.
You can find more detailed information including links to the various schedules in the Metadatabyrån.
The important thing is that in this case you specify which table you use.
And since we have a church alphabet here, we should state it.
We will first produce systemic remark.
Like this.
And then we specify transliteration schedule.
So there.
And the other thing we should put before leaving the admin meta is modifications.
Like this
And here we choose the last in the list: Non-Latin characters are available in both original and translated form.
And now we are done with the admin meta and move on to the instance.
Now I start with the bibliographic tasks I find in the book.
The ISBN I write here.
Distinctive addition.
Most libraries do not use this field.
But here you can write about the book is stapled or hardcover.
You can also write other tasks that belong to this particular manifestation.
I choose to write here, stapled.
Late publishing method: Monographic resource.
When we catalog a regular book, it is always a monographic resource.
Media type.
Wear type.
It is right.
It should always be unedated and volume.
Then we arrive at the title.
And here we start from the title page and I write here the translated form of the title.
They look like this.
And I do not have other title information, but I will develop a variant title to put the title in original writing instead.
Like this.
So
And I have no filing values to take into account.
I also write the origin information in translated form as it says on the title page.
Next is a circulation task and there is rarely information about editions in new books
But if there is information then we will take it as it looks in the manifestation.
And here I actually have, and it looks like this.
So there.
Publication.
The first feature of primary publication is land.
And since we start from a template, Sweden is already managed
But we know that this manifestation comes from Serbia.
So I change it.
We write the place as it says.
Thus, the place of publishing.
Sometimes it says in the publications only publishers and not the place of publication.
If it had not been a place of publication we would have to have it anyway, but then we would cling to it.
The following trait is an agent.
Here the publisher itself should stand.
If the name of the publisher appears in the source in more than one language or in more than one writing, indicate the name that is in the main title's language.
If this criterion cannot be applied, specify the task that comes first in the source.
We follow the title page and write: Medija cents ...
As it stands.
If the task is not on the title page, then we take the charge from the place where the publisher is most highlighted, where it is most evident.
Then it's years and date.
Publishing time is a nuclear element for published manifestations
Year may only contain four alphanumeric characters.
It is not uncommon for the actual publication year to be in the book.
The publication year can be based on the print year or the Cophyright year.
We have a print year and copyright year which is 2019.
Date is used if we do not have a secure publication year in the book and then need to specify characters other than those that are allowed in the capacity year.
In this case, we base the release on the print year and therefore need to enter 2019 within staples.
So
Then we have manufacturing.
Since we have based the publication on the print year, we need to specify that year without staples in manufacturing.
We don't really need to fill in the place and agent, but we do it now.
So, here it should say ... so.
But as I said, most libraries do not have to care about the manufacturing tasks.
Range
Then we enter the last paginated page.
Dimensions do not have to care either.
But if you were to do so, you round up.
If a book eg.
Is 21.2 cm then you round to 22.
It is not mandatory but you can fill in if you want
Other physical details.
Here you usually fill in illustrations, maps.
In this manifestation we actually have illustrations so I fill in here.
This manifestation is not included in a series.
To see how to enter series membership look at the instructions in the help texts.
Remark.
Here you can put in something that you think may be of interest to the end user and applies to this particular manifestation.
Now I'm going back to the instance of works.
Eventually, the works will be broken out and you will link to them from the instances but so far they remain as a local entity in the instance
And the work information is repeated in each entry in the same way as in Marc posts.
The title in instance of works should be the preferred title for the work and since this is a translation it should be the original title
And we should therefore check how it says in NB's post.
Then I put in here as it looks in the Swedish post.
So.
Now we have checked that it looks right.
And we have no filing values to take into account.
Here I have participation and function and here I enter the author's name.
We check that the author has an authorized name form and we link to it.
If we are unsure of the person, it is possible to click on the name and the entity will open in another window.
Then we have the opportunity to check that it is really the right person.
But here we already see a judge and we are sure it is right.
So I link.
And the function is already filled.
It's a writer.
Participation.
Here it can be a translator, illustrator etc.
Right in this manifestation I actually have no information about who the translator is.
So I skip it.
Now we come to language and since we are based on a template, the language is already Swedish here and we should change that.
The language is Serbian.
Genre/form.
Under "genre/form", different types of codes are collected such as the literary genre, and genre/form terms.
This is a translation of a Swedish book.
There is an original to be based on which is cataloged by the national bibliography.
I can therefore look for it and link to the same genre/form term and subject words.
It is not possible to copy linked entities so I can look for them and link to them.
First genre/form the terms.
Like this.
First.
And then I have ... Now we have linked the genre/form the terms.
For more information on how to add genre/form, subject word and classification, look at the instructional films: add genre/form,
Link subject words and primary cataloging of original works.
Lets see.
Here we have two different parts.
We arrive at classification.
We have two different parts.
One is Dewey and the other is SAB.
SAB rating we do not do on KB so I will only do this dewey part,
And here I write lawyers - judges.
If I had chosen to leave this one, it would not disappear when saving.
Usually, if these fields are not filled, they will disappear when saving the mail.
But in this case, I actually choose to remove and just leave Dewey.
I am on topic and here I add according to ...
This is the right one.
And then I also choose
So
And finally I choose the person myself.
So there.
Now follows a note of language.
In this field we can add, for example, something that is important for the end user such as
That the Arabic that the text is vocalized, it is Serbian with Latin alphabet etc.
It is the catalog that assesses whether any remark is needed.
This is appropriate because there is a complaint about language.
Because this is Serbian and Serbian is usually written with church alphabet, and I have just one in my hand.
So I choose not to write any special note about it.
We should not forget that this is a translation and we develop that property via the plus sign here.
And chooses translation of.
Like this.
So.
And we choose the right language.
It is translated from Swedish.
For translations in several stages, use the property intermediate language to translations.
It is not uncommon for the work to be translated in two stages: to ex.
From the Swedish original to-English and then to Arabic for example.
Here we choose intermediate language by using the property ... like this ... and click on the plus here.
Then an entity is created.
And we choose works.
And then we put the intermediate language here.
We find now, English for example and with this we had said that
This is a translation from Swedish to Serbian, via English.
But I remove this now because it does not match my book.
So, now we are done with the cataloging.