This step is about how you can help your group become more secure.
When a new group is formed, the members naturally are not very secure with each other.
As the group spends time together, security usually emerges.
A well -functioning group is characterized by, among other things, great confidence and security.
They dare to fail, dare to share ideas, dare to give each other feedback and help each other.
Here is a metaphor that highlights the importance of helping others.
A farmer grows lots of fine corn on his farm.
Every year he reports his corn to a competition for the area's best crops.
And every year he wins.
One year he was interviewed by a reporter who wanted to find out the secret behind the award -winning corn.
The answer made the reporter very astonished.
The farmer told me that he always shared the grain with his neighbors.
"But how can you give the grain to your competitors"
The reporter asked.
"Oh," the farmer said.
"It's not that hard to understand"
"The wind captures pollen"
"And for the one from field to field"
“If my neighbors grow substandard corn, cross pollination will make my corn gradually deteriorate
It too ”.
"If I want to grow good corn, I must therefore help my neighbors".
How you can help others feel safe
Encourage ideas from others and try to avoid getting into a defensive position.
When others make mistakes on training or competition, the most common thing is to do nothing special and just drive on.
However, some choose to bark at the person who made the mistake.
However, given how people work in groups, we need to be careful about how we choose to act on the faults of others.
In fact, most people feel insecure when someone bark at them.
Which often leads to more mistakes.
So the opposite of the effect they really want.
That being said, it is not always wrong to bark or mark when someone makes violations.
Especially not when it comes to things that the person can actually control.
It is, for example, under the person's control how it behaves towards its teammates.
But less under the person's control whether the pass goes to the correct address or not.
As a teammate, it can therefore be good to be extra supportive when someone makes a mistake.
Or get tired and underperform.
How you yourself can challenge your insecurity
If there is an opportunity to be selected for a competition or match, you will surely want to show off your best side all the time.
It can lead to you starting to act safe.
And do not carry out actions that risk going wrong.
Which, paradoxically, often leads to a worse result.
In the skill acceptance
You were asked to challenge yourself and make mistakes.
It can also be about daring to ask when you do not understand anything.
Such as asking for help from coaches or from your teammates even if it feels like you then show
you weak.
Make sacrifices for your teammates, although it may inhibit you in the short term.
In team sports, it can be about working home even though you may be able to cope less in the next attack.
In an individual sport, it may be to take the time to help others in their preparation.
Although you may want to focus most on yourself for a while.
Why it is good can be explained in a few different ways.
As in the metaphor about the farmer and the corn, it can be directly favorable for you to help others.
If others get better, you will be better too.
Which is a particularly simple conclusion to draw in team sports.
By helping others also increases the likelihood that they will help you back.
When you have worries.
Finally, it is also about emotion and courage.
On the one hand, usually creates a good feeling inboard when we helped others which can lead to a better performance.
When it comes to courage, it is about daring to be vulnerable.
Being able to be in insecurity in the short term,
In order to achieve greater security in the longer term
both for yourself
And for others in your group.
This week's training tips
A secure group where members are happy also has a better opportunity to perform well.
Help others become safe by supporting, comforting and encouraging ideas.
And that the members challenge themselves,
Although it leads to mistakes on cards.
Challenge your own insecurity this week by doing what you are uncomfortable with
and sacrifice you for the team.