How to fund your growth.
We will now talk about financing and financing options.
Is it that the business does not finance itself
or that you want to grow faster than with your own profit-
You may need to find other ways to finance growth.
Often there is a combination of different forms of financing.
We at Almi are experts in putting this financing puzzle.
We will take a closer look at loans, development funds and ownership capital
And their respective advantages and disadvantages.
We start with loans.
Here is a selection of the banks and loan institutions
found on the market today.
Depending on the type of business form you choose
the amounts can vary on how much you can borrow.
Almi has a market supplementary role
and lends out together with a bank or other loan institution.
You can also borrow for the ongoing business
To smooth out tops and valleys in your company's cash flow-
And create an extra security.
There are different options when your business
need reinforced liquidity-
For example, to manage expenses before you get paid yourself.
The advantage of loans is that you keep control of the company
But the company needs to have stable revenue-
To be able to pay interest and amortization.
The second way is to look at development funds.
Competition for these agents is often great
and here we recommend that you talk to your adviser at Almi-
So we look at what different opportunities are for you.
They have regional business support, checks from the Growth Agency
and vinnova, verification agent from almi-
And EU grants, to name a few.
What one can search for varies
So it is important to monitor the various organizations.
The benefits associated with development agents
is that no refund is required.
However, this type of financing is often detailed controlled
And earmarked for certain efforts, processes and collaborations.
It is therefore important to understand about a means of development
benefits the business and is in line with what you want to develop.
In some cases, counter -financing may be required
Or its own efforts from the person seeking this type of means.
The last form of financing that we will go through is ownership capital.
Owner capital means that you as an owner go in with financing
Or that you let part -owners into the company.
Here you talk even about private venture capital
which you can find among other things with business angels and venture capital companies.
The type of company that is usually relevant to owner capital
are those who have a scalable business model-
with international potential.
Advantages of owner-capital-
is that you get external skills into the company-
competence and capital in one person.
If you choose this route it is required that you are willing
to release control and let someone else be with and determine-
about where the company should go.
Here you can see some alternatives on owner capital and venture capital.
It's everything from family and friends
to business angels and larger venture capital companies.
We should not leave owner capital right yet
without we want to highlight some points that are important to think-
when you take in new owners.
First and foremost, choose new owners with care.
It's not just about capital
A new owner becomes your future partner.
You need to find a good combination between competence and capital
In order to benefit the business-
And you need to agree on the goal of ownership.
The next point is about valuation.
There are different ways to evaluate your business
And here it is good to take the help of an economic adviser.
You need to find a value for the company
which corresponds to your and the new owner's image of the company.
Think about what values your business has.
Are there values beyond the financial such as patents
In a negotiation with a new owner
Do you need to justify and describe the assets in the company-
that make up your valuation.
The last point is about structure.
Structure is extra important when you become several owners
So you can work towards the same goal.
In a limited company there are some formalia
that facilitates your joint work.
These are documents such as owner directives, rules of procedure for the board and the CEO.
Formulate owner directive together
so it is clear what the owners want the company to work against-
as well as the rules of procedure for board and CEO
to ensure that the board works towards the owners' goals.
In the in -depth part you will find a link to Fredrik Sjövall from Hemcheck
And how they reason around external capital.
As an entrepreneur, it is easy to feel alone.
You have to take help as the company grows.
A coach or mentor and in the long term a board
can be a great way to get external skills-
that engages in the company.
Having an external ball plan can relieve many of the questions
Which you go and think about.
When looking for external skills-
Do you have to find people who complement yourself-
And the people who are in the company.
It is easy to be drawn to someone who thinks and thinks as you yourself.
A board person, an Advisory Board
Coach or mentor does not have to be a long -term commitment.
Each phase in entrepreneurship needs different skills
and it is important to identify skills and networks-
Which is good for the phase in which the company is now.
A mentor acts as a ball board
that guides you forward to facilitate your business-
Development and growth process.
A board member has personal responsibility for the company's administration.
There are also other actors and organizations
who can relieve, of course, as consultants, advisors within accounting-
and auditing, as well as various public actors.
Now it's time for you to work on your own.
We have talked about wanting and daring.
Decide, where do you want with your company in 35 years?
Let the passion control.
Set clear and smart goals for the way there.
Keep focus and build simple systems and routines from the start.
Then you lay the foundation to expand your business.
Make the staff participate and motivated in the company's growth.
Take the help of financing experts.
There are different types of funding
depending on in which phase you are located-
And sometimes it can be difficult to find the right one.
Big thanks for being with us this moment.
We hope you got some inspiration and new ideas
For how to take the next step.
One way might be to look at our other seminars
which you can find on the website.
Good luck!