The space industry will intervene in everything.
The problems with resources and quality of life here on earth are the same as in space.
When we get something to work in space, it is useful here on earth as well.
Space research requires sustainable systems - which can be used here as well.
The main product is called Solein.
Solein is natural, for our organism is an unmodified gift from nature.
Nature has given us this.
The nutritional composition is also reminiscent of the one we naturally get in us.
You get a powder that corresponds to dried meat or dried carrot or soy.
Manufacturing requires electricity and air.
Electricity is found worldwide, both as wind power and solar energy.
With direct air capture we also get water and carbon dioxide everywhere.
There we will have an apparatus for direct air capture.
We capture the carbon dioxide and use in food production.
In the future, we can also achieve this in, for example, shopping centers.
Singapore is a place where new food technology is welcomed.
It is the place on earth where new technology is taken in commercial use first.
It is also Singapore's goal and stated strategy.
The situation is reminiscent of that in space.
You are short of space and have to streamline food production.
And we can literally produce food in the middle of the city!
We use waste products that are already in the space environment.
For example, the carbon dioxide we capture.
It has breathed out of the astronauts.
The powder will probably not be the end product.
A powder is difficult to handle in microgravitation.
We are thinking of a mixture of water and solein, as in a protein shake.
Space research can also be important for the earth.
We can create self -governing appliances, perhaps in container size -
- For use in refugee camps and in places with inadequate logistics.
-How does it taste?
- Top!
This is also important -
- For a third of our greenhouse gas emissions depends on what we eat.
Food technology can solve the biggest environmental problem here on earth.
Mushrooms are fascinating!
The sponge pest is huge!
Therefore, there are so many different types of fungi.
Here we found a nice resistance!
These are Pleurotus mushrooms.
Such are decomposers.
So they break down organic material.
It makes them a good space candidate.
If they receive nutrition, it is converted into protein and nutritious fungi.
When we have picked mushrooms we usually take a spore print.
Mu Mycology came into being when we started growing mushrooms.
In a farm you have a place and can grow a lot of mushrooms.
Waste can be composted.
But say that you are in a food desert or in space.
Then the space becomes very important and the waste becomes crucial.
Mu Mycology was a way -
- Getting mushrooms on a very small surface.
It went up a light for us:
"We can increase the return!"
Then we started growing in the garage.
This is another reason why mushrooms are good space food.
They are constantly different.
There are many different varieties.
They taste so different, but still give the vitamins, minerals and amino acids -
- As the astronauts will need.
- How old is it?
- Four months, type.
-Seriously?
- Yeah!
We do not eat as much fungus in our society.
But it would be valuable, because it is an overlooked food group.
The substrate is the same as for everything else.
You can ignore the smallest.
They have no ...
It is interesting that the mushrooms have been around for so long.
It is an old kingdom.
We know some really old colonies.
Some are around 5,000 years old.
They must be quite resistant, so they may grow even in space -
- The solar radiation and the extreme environment.
Have a nice meal!
Pretty good, actually.
IAEA's plant breeding takes place with the UN Food and Agricultural Organization.
We will help member states with the return in agriculture.
The plant breeding takes on grain production.
The return of the crop must be improved or stabilized.
And climate change and illness must be opposed.
If you want to get different varieties -
— Which in any way is better than before-
- You have to evoke mutations.
Then we make selection for the desired property.
We also try to preserve all the good qualities that have been there before.
It is only when there is a development pressure on an organism -
- As it will develop.
In the end, a variety has been produced that the farmer can grow.
Our colleagues in China have been doing this for a while.
They sent seeds from hundreds of species ... It was in 2008.
The satellite revolved around the earth for 15 days and then returned.
They use the seeds.
But the big breakthrough is a wheat variety grown in China now.
It is the second most common variety in China, and it is developed in space.
Something that is important in this context is -
- That we should have abolished hunger by 2030. Is it possible?
We all strive in that direction.
This applies to all countries.
Techniques such as mutation processing are important, because they are so available.
And they provide the genetic variation that an improved variety requires.
He asked if, when I doctorate, I could help poor farmers.
I promised him to do it, to help the farmers.
I have never regretted.
Radiation, microgravitation and vibrations ...
Everything affects plants - and spring - biology.
We investigate whether it can provide benefits, especially in inhospitable environments:
Salt, warm or dry.
We want to take advantage of it.
We want to turn to the desert spread and secure our future here.
The United Arab Emirates are looking ahead.
Although the oil has been helpful, you look forward -
- And wants to understand which industries will be important in the 50-100 year term.
This region is also expected to gain the world's highest population growth.
This is also the largest in the cities -
- Where you have far to agriculture.
Therefore, space was interesting.
The United Arab Emirates have reached a long way in the space area.
These green beans have grown in simulated Mars soil, these in ordinary soil.
They look the same, although the control plant in plain pot soil is a little larger.
It has much bigger roots.
You can see that clearly.
Ordinary soil gives greater harvest.
But this one also gives nice beans.
However, the harvest becomes a little smaller.
We want to improve it and get the same return.
We can grow over 25 different species right now.
The potatoes are doing really well.
It looks like regular potatoes and does not differ at all from it.
It does well, as long as it gets fertilizer.
Fertilizers are needed, because the soil lacks both nitrate and ammonia.
Requires.
But as long as we can provide it, everything works well.
The regional on Mars lacks things like nitrogen and phosphorus.
We were going to bring it with us when we are going to colonize Mars.
But then space goes to other use.
Instead, we take advantage of something we already have - in our urine and stool.
They are full of nutrients for the plants.
That is the idea of the experiment here.
We will use our kiss and poop.
I remember grandfather doing it.
Once a year he gathered everything and spread it over the horticulture.
We saw what he had done, because it stuck out pieces of toilet paper.
Own vegetables on your own kiss and poop ...
Hope we can apply lessons from the Mars and Moon experiments here-
- And make agriculture circular again.
It is an important goal for 2050.
Now it is not circular.
We use resources from other parts of the world.
We end them over there.
It also causes problems here, because nature is suffering from it.
I hope agriculture will be circular again by 2050-
- And that we should know what it takes to get rid of it.
Growing crops is not enough.
You never eat everything.
You only eat the tomato, not the leaves and roots.
They must be recycled and allowed to be included in the cycle again.
Nothing may be lost.
It is about 9 milligrams per liter.
Every square centimeter aboard a space shuttle is a major investment.
We are the ones who can offer a solution -
–So that astronauts can minimize the space required on board -
- And also the amount of water and the lighting.
A settlement on Mars must be completely enclosed.
Then the space must be utilized optimally.
We let the system provide each of the four astronauts -
- With 150-200 grams daily of leafy vegetables and leaf shoots.
The average production is 16-20 kilos per 28 days.
The one who is allowed to work with plants and touch them-
- Keeps closer to the planet he lacks.
Outside in space, the earth is hardly getting closer than this.
This technology requires no long -haul supplements from coast to coast.
And you avoid pesticides in the food.
You know what you have grown.
Most people live in city apartments now and have no garden -
-So this is a solution for the 21st century.
-One week to go.
- Yes, then it's harvest.
- I don't realize that they survived.
- This is higher up.
One week to harvest.
The head is really beautiful ...
The last few years have been a challenge with all the rain.
It has forced us to rethink.
We have changed variety, to compensate for the climate.
It has been too wet or cold - and too hot and dry during the dry season.
These plants require a predictable climate.
Climate change affects food safety.
How should we support the population after the population explosion?
We have had to use the earth.
After all, we had to survive.
But in the future, we must try to make ourselves independent of the cultivation land.
Then we do not waste on non-renewable resources-
- As fertilizer, work and soil.
In this way, we get more of a circular economy, rather than a linear economy.
The products should no longer become waste but be seen as raw materials again.
In space you have to use what you have.
Same thing here on earth.
When we get something to work in space, it is useful here on earth as well.
Agricultural technology and space provide a product that gives us food safety.
Take a look at the appliances you use.
Start with the microwave.
And so the GPS and the mobile.
Everything was meant for space, but then it came into use here on earth.
This is how the technological development works: it is enough for space, it is enough for the earth.
In Thailand we have used this plant for a hundred years maybe.
In northern and northeastern Thailand it is used as a vegetable.
No other plant grows so fast, so you quickly get a large volume.
It was seen that the plant contains everything we need to need.
Good!
The omelette gets some texture from this.
If you tell us what dwarf food is and how nutritious it is -
- So it can be popular.
The goal is to understand ... If in the future we want to grow a plant on a giant plane -
- As Jupiter, we must understand how it reacts to hypergravity.
We have great diversity among the plants and a good set of varieties.
If we select a certain plant that fits in space context -
- Can Thailand become a leader in space cultivation.
Space research provides innovations, because it makes it impossible.
We have to think new to survive in space.
We must find ways to grow plants on other planets.
And they can be adapted to places on earth -
- As a desert environment or extreme places like the South and North Pole ...
Then we can produce food there and people can benefit from space technology.
We insert the cells into a bioreactor, a tank with the right growth opportunities.
You do not need to breed a whole cow.
You only grow the parts that you will eat.
Climate change affects food safety and vice versa.
When you need more food and consume more resources -
- Then you get problems with things like deforestation and water use.
It affects climate change.
It becomes a vicious circle.
To put a stop to it-
–Com by reducing resource consumption in food production -
- Should reduce climate change.
Singapore is open to innovations and new technology.
The reason is that you need to find alternative solutions -
- As a result of the limited area for meat production in Singapore.
Growing meat is just the right technology.
They can use the cells we send from Israel-
- With some ingredients from Singapore, without having to breed the entire animal.
Aleph Zero gives us the opportunity -
- To work for closed cycles and the abolition of waste.
We can bring with us lessons and start growing meat here as well on earth.
We install the stem cells in the chip -
–And agree with the right nutrients and temperature -
- For the tissue culture from Aleph Farms.
The equipment will fit in this little box.
Everything weighs 3.4 kilos.
There are actually a number of fossils confirming ...
... that the first plants and even the animals here on earth ...
... originates from microalgae.
How about that?
The microalgers are the origin of all living organisms.
This means that all the necessary nutrients can be found there.
Who?
Fatty acids.
Omega-3: DHA, EPA.
All essential amino acids.
The body cannot synthesize them.
Lutein.
Chlorophyll.
Astaxantin.
It is also about vitamins.
When growth is over, we make them a powder.
We dry them.
It works just like a protein powder on earth.
It is possible to have milkshake.
You can make tofu of it, on board the vehicle, with the right equipment.
A bioreactor agrees with an environment where the microorganisms can grow well.
In our reactors, for example, we control the temperature -
–And how much oxygen and carbon dioxide are available.
What you see here is how we imagine -
- The astronauts should be able to grow our microalgers with such a bioreactor.
If we can grow food even on another planet and in the small spacecraft -
- How would it work to grow food here on earth?
Here we could make it extremely sustainable and also effective.
Singapore is small.
Food research and biotechnology will outweigh the lack of space.
Given that, we have devoted ourselves to proteins and microorganisms -
- To gain access to proteins in the future.
My family has been Buddhists for four generations.
We have cooked vegetarian food for three generations.
Much of the processed food would be able to make healthy.
That is definitely the answer when it comes to getting space food.
Because you can't send up a whole chicken series with the craft.
One must use new technology -
- As for fermentation or for meat cultivation.
The more challenges, questions and problems, the more meaningful my work.
And therefore...
... I founded Sophie's Bionutrients.
That's why I have devoted my life to this.
The city is located by the sea.
The residential area was behind it.
Everything was destroyed by the tsunami.
Many in the locals were affected, and they were allowed to stay in shelters.
No one had foreseen the disaster.
In one hand people had a rice ball, in the other a piece of bread.
Everything revolved around carbohydrates.
In the shelters, everything was about calories, not about a balanced diet.
Life Stock-Gelén must undergo a pressure test.
It is a requirement that is placed on all space food.
It must withstand the pressure on the way out into space.
One wonders if only the gel can give enough calories.
In fact, a single package contains 200 kilocalories.
It corresponds to the amount in a rice ball.
You must also keep in mind what it is in space.
The astronauts have a lot to stand in and they are in a hurry.
This product lets them refill energy with just one hand.
Space is an extreme environment that it is difficult for people to live in.
It's like living in the shelters in disaster areas.
We develop techniques for use in inhospitable space.
With the technology and knowledge we retrieve from there -
- We want to offer solutions to the problems the earth is facing.
We get feedback from children now that the product tastes delicious.
Emergency provider is often not associated with the word "delicious".
But this is really delicious, and the kids want to eat it every day.
- It's messy.
- It tastes - orange and red.
- Where do you want to eat it?
-In heaven.
The efforts in a disaster area are reminiscent of them in space.
It is our job to produce food for both space and rescue efforts.
Space technology is a forward -looking use of the technology to solve problems.
If a disaster were to occur -
- Calls the water and electricity supply.
Then no infrastructure works.
If we can solve these problems in space -
- Then we can solve them in disaster areas.
The space industry intervenes in everything.
It is important for creating transformation in many sectors -
- As the transport, energy and agricultural sector.
It provides sustainable development.
It also provides innovations and paves the way for the technology of the future.
As I see it, Singapore can act as a hub.
Geographically, it is located in a strategic location in Asia.
Here we can exchange ideas -
- Discover challenges and find new areas for collaboration.
In the future, NASA will continue to develop its international contacts -
- To make the flights successful.
International cooperation is needed.
Otherwise, the flights will not be successful.
-Hello Alex!
- Hallå, Wieger.
I am fascinated by space, but especially by the planets - and Mars.
A great adventure this century becomes to bring people to Mars-
- To explore how the planet is structured.
I became interested in space as a kid.
I looked up all the books about the planets and read about them.
It made me interested in researching them.
Now it has become a reality.
If you want to stay on Mars or the moon, you have to eat.
You can't do without food.
Already the first March travelers will have to grow vegetables.
Otherwise it is not possible, I think.
And when we want to build a settlement such as international space station on the moon -
- We will grow our vegetables there.
It's the future:
We create our own food where we live.
The goal of our experiments is to achieve something for Mars and the moon.
But we learn a lot that can be used on earth.
We think new about agriculture.
It must be circular.
Translation: Roger Wiberg Swedish Media Text for SVT
When Vaasa left the harbor, a salute was shot.
When the boat got the impact side ordered the captain -
- Closing the cannon gates so that the ship did not bring in water.
In texts about the archaeological history of the 20th century, there are some things that are always addressed.
Vaasa is one of them, because it is something quite outstanding.
It is exceptionally well preserved and gives us lots of information about the story.