-Go on!
Go on!
Oh, so good!
Burning mountains in the background and a windy Kiruna.
I make a hit in the city that one decided to move
in favor of a mine.
Here you see the heart of the new Kiruna:
The belfry from the old town hall next to the new town hall.
But I'm going to Kaalasjärvi, some miles outside Kiruna.
I will go on a rip hunt.
But I'll make a stop on the road.
Thanks so much!
Bye!
So there, a little pure meat.
Now I'm completely ready for the mountain.
In the small village with only 34 inhabitants, chef Johan lives with his family.
Here he runs what may be the world's smallest restaurant.
In it we will cook dinner with Ripa.
Hope we get hold of birds and what a lucky thing Johan is a hunter.
- Are you doing a lot of rip?
- Not as much as before.
We hope we get some dinner.
Everything hangs on you.
Everything hangs on me - that's good.
This is nice, then.
What do you think about the chances of Ripa?
Right in the area we are going to, Ripa has been good.
It's just to hope that it lasts.
I feel as embarrassed as the dog.
Tell me, what happens now?
She is well peppered.
We will hunt a little rip.
These are a little difficult conditions today, not so much wind.
I feel a little breeze from here.
These are very nice places for rips, they have water, food and protection.
Then when she sets the bird beeping it in my GPS
And then we go to the dog and Johan is completely open to shoot.
Search!
Okay, now she stands.
The dog has set a bird and the hunt is up and running.
Wait there, now.
Now it is exciting.
Yes Yes!
Come on!
Oh, so good!
Oh, how good you were!
- It was almost food in the saucepan.
-It was close.
It became a boom on the first attempt.
But the dog Tundra works on.
Soon she stands for bird again
And this time Johan gets a perfect shot.
Great!
Great, there!
- We will see if we find the rip.
- Here it lies.
- A nice shot, Johan.
-Thanks.
Check.
What a hunting day.
We got some birds.
- We got that.
- Fun to see the dog work.
So powerful.
But we don't have time to stand here and enjoy.
- No, we have some guests waiting.
- I feel a little stressed.
I have a plan, but no finished plan.
It probably goes brilliant, I think.
Johan has an idea of making a variant of a classic ceasar salad.
It becomes cabbage and rip instead of chicken.
He removes the cabbage from his own greenhouse.
Because it is possible to grow vegetables so far north.
- This looks like physalis.
--Physalis ...
And a little tomato and cucumber, of course.
Heaven!
We sit outside your nine square meter restaurant.
It sounds crazy with just four seats.
How did you think?
It was a period in my career where I felt it was time
To do something other than work for others.
I still wanted to work with food, but not run a large restaurant.
Then it became, it is today.
I cook a more rustic right over open fire:
Forally grilled rip with a broth that I made on the hull.
We can only accommodate two guests in the tiny restaurant.
Hope they like what we have cooked.
A well -stocked cheese from Vuollerim made from milk from mountain cow.
Rotated rip.
It goes pretty fast, one must be careful with the heat
Not to exceed the rip, but have some nice pink color.
You have to turn a little sometimes.
- Hi, welcome!
-Hello!
Welcome!
This way.
Come in!
Now it is packed in Johan's small restaurant.
- Thanks so much, what a wonderful.
-How exiting!
I could never have imagined ceasar salad with rip.
Great!
-It was really good!
-So good.
Thank you so much.
- It's really a tasty meat.
-Yes.
- But it doesn't take over.
- No, it balances well.
Johan's right was super successful, now I feel an immense stress.
What should they like about my slightly more crazy serving?
But, uh.
It's just going on a gut feeling.
Here we have a roasted rip
Served with a hot broth flavored with quanne.
It is a chanterelle chill and fire -baked root vegetables
A little sooty mangold and apple.
- Fantastic.
- Speaking broth.
What a deep and lovely broth you got.
-Very exciting.
-How fun.
Anyway!
- You may come back.
-How nice!
Then we should know when you are here, and we will book in.
- They seem satisfied and satisfied.
-Yes.
- Now we will end with waffles.
- I usually do, yes.
It is such a wonderful feeling to bake waffles on an open fire.
I think it may go a little to ...