I saw several different movies about laying a footpath before dealing with my own.
I still managed to find a number of mistakes they did not include in these movies, so
I was going to show a little again what five mistakes I made and which I avoided.
One thing that is easy to miss is to
The chipboard has an upside and a downside.
I don't know what role they play, but it's just as good to do right.
A near death experience one can avoid
If you think about it - is that the slices are glass -backed when you have them lying on high.
Don't try to jump down on a pile of slices
Or take a big step between the rules on such a pile.
It can end badly.
One of the first and most important elements
When you put a footpath, it is to get the first row completely nail.
If it started to skew a bit, in any direction then you get an error coming
to reproduce throughout the floor and you will also have to fight it
Each new line you start with and the error follows
With all the time and you can't get rid of it.
To get the first line straight you can
lace the floor and above all make sure that the short sides are tight against each other.
Are they completely tight so they don't glide anything.
So the lines will be straight they just need to be adjusted sideways.
A mistake I made here, it was that I started with the wrong side.
As you can see, they are spontaneous, these chipboards.
And if you see then they are
on one side is a spontaneous one lying
Close down towards the rules while the other comes as a lip from above.
Of course, one should have the lip that lies down against the rules outwards all the time.
Then you glue it directly to the floor and you do not have the problems that I happened to
That you should try to get this lip under the previous disc.
It makes you, when you have screwed it and glued it.
Have you waited a day so it can lie
Lim residue or other in between that makes it completely hopeless to get it there.
Therefore you have to check every disk you put so that
It's free before you start to hit it.
For have you put on glue and start knocking in
The disc so it is not easy to remove it and correct it afterwards.
And above all, even if it succeeds, it is very messy with all the glue.
So start with the right side out.
It's not very hard, it's just
that you have the right side up on the disc and make sure the lip downwards - is outward it
You put against the new discs.
A moment I missed in the chipboard movies I saw
Be how to get the corners together.
To lay a long side to another long side.
It's just pressing and it usually works quite easily.
But what they don't show
How they do to get both long side and short side to be tight together.
For the pros it just seems to be that
Throw the slices there and maybe stomp kick a little on them so they end up right.
It has not been so easy for me.
I have therefore manufactured a hangover
the same feature that one uses when laying
parquet or click floor.
And this hangover allows you to knock the disc there.
It is not possible to knock on the real sides of the disc because it is chipboard.
It is very easy to ruin the edges.
The sponge on these chipboards and you have to think about that even when handling them.
If you set them on the short side when you
Tumps against, you immediately destroy this little chipboard spontaneous.
Another mistake you can do as man in and
Indeed, learn quite quickly and avoid it is to put on the glue in the correct order.
If you start by gluing on
All the spontaneous edges, then you will hold on and scratched the glue on your hands.
That's why I put the glue on it
that is fixed first and then I glue on the disc that
Should be added there.
And you do it in the right order.
This is how you don't have to get so much glue on your fingers as well.
And when to press the disc there
So you also have the glue under the rules that make it slip quite easily.
If you pull it a little back and forth so
Spreads out the glue and then press it there.
And as so often in the case when I lay they
Here the discs anyway so it will not be directly in place
Without that, when I pick up my little hangover.
The hangover I made from a piece of wastewood from another chipboard.
Corresponding fals on the one on the disc and then I have nailed on
Or screwed on a piece of chipboard and a block to knock.
One does not have to take in, one should not take in
Especially hard without it is just that you have power in the right direction.
It is quite hopeless to gain power
In the right direction otherwise with these discs if you are going to try hand power.
And, as I said, you can't turn on the clean
The edge as it is because it destroys it.
And the goal is to get in
The slices so tight together that it penetrates glue in between.
And finally make sure to get the short side tight.
Here you can see that it
does not go fast, but it comes so slowly and slides in and then
Finally, you see the glue penetrating when it is in place for real.
There comes the glue.
Another mistake you can make as I have made here and in the past
is that you do not have a damp cloth to wipe off the glue.
If you do not wipe the glue.
Then you will need to grind it away when it hardened.
And do you as I do here, use a small piece of spill to
Pull off the glue so it is easy to happen that you are satisfied.
At the end of the working day you leave the piece of wood and then it is glued to the floor.
Mistake number five as i made some
times I trust a little too much on my eye measurement.
I screw up the chipboard to the rules.
Three screws in each rule except where you have a joint.
There should be four screws in the chipboard on each rule beside the joint.
And if you trust the eye measurement, you think that here is the rule
and then it turns out that when the screw is the idled it spins
only in the air.
It's not a disaster
But you should not do as I did here.
To guess that “the rule is enough on it
This page “Without doing as I do on this movie.
Have a right disc of some kind so that you
Can post so you know where to sit.
Because it is easy to miss out on where the rule
Is somewhere and it is unnecessary to be annoyed.
By putting the wrong put the screws wrong.
Have you got anything out of this video
At all, please give me a thumbs up, it is more fun to make a movie.
And do you want to continue
Learn from my mistakes so be happy to subscribe to this channel.
Have a great time and we will see you again soon!