The slope of a staircase should actually be a maximum of 46 degrees.
But it depends on what area of use is.
The most important thing is to get the angles right.
I do this so as not to make mistakes during the transfer from a drawing.
To get the right angle at the bottom, I use the same dimensions of rule and floor as on the top of the stairs.
Then just cut to both angles and test that it has become right.
And here's the spot on.
When the first piece has become right, I over the angles to the other side.
So they become identical.
The best step height is 17-18 cm and here I make a template to make it just right.
It is important that the steps become as high so that you do not stumble into the stairs.
I have measured the height from the floor in the machine room to the floor of the attic.
With twelve steps, the step height becomes 18.3 cm.
And that's so wide I saw the template.
Then I make a jig to get the steps just the same.
I start by attaching the template by the step height so that it has the same angle as the underside of the piece.
Then I have a piece of sacrifice and a piece of support that I attach so that it becomes a sledge that can slip on the piece.
To get the right distance, I use the circular saw plus a rubbish piece of the same thickness as the steps.
If you want the exact pass, if it is to be really neat, then pull away the double thickness of the blade.
I build a staircase for the machine hall and it becomes much easier with some play.
That's why I ignore the fin.
The depth of the saw blade I set to fifteen millimeters - one third of the thickness of the vang.
The sacrifices can be thrown away.
I am now making a beginner's miss that it takes a while for me to discover.
See if you discover it before me ...
It's now I suddenly realize my mistake.
You may have noticed it earlier.
Look here you'll see:
I have crossed what is to be cut away.
But sawn on the wrong side of the line all the time.
But since one of the pieces is clear and I have come halfway with the other, I do not intend to start over.
I adjust the error afterwards.
It can be solved, I have calculated that.
A little frustrating when doing an instructional video and making the most basic mistakes yourself.
But - you may not do the same thing now.
So the mistake fixed.
Since the distance between the steps is right all the way, the stairs just need to be adjusted to the top then.
Then I pre -drill for the screws that will attach the steps.
And recesses the holes for the screws to sit against the wall.
While the color dries, I take the opportunity to cut the steps.
I use the same thickness on the steps as for the pieces.
I think it will be the nicest - and it will be a lot too.
Also, I do not have to count on the width.
Thinner steps do not withstand wide stairs.
Now I drive 75 cm wide steps and then the thickness is no problem.
As you can see, the top step is a little too far, but I saw it so it fits perfectly.
As you can see, I have attached the stairs with just one screw in the side that faces from the wall.
Why should I show just soon.
To secure the stairs, I attach it with two screws on the top.
The stairs in place but not yet finished.
I will look for it by changing the screws to wooden plugs.