Good morning
Welcome back to the talk show
To the Psycho Mukbang talk show.
It is a talk show we should have maybe
I saw that it was blinking in your head right away.
Ding, ding, and then drrrrr.
Should you have a Redbull for breakfast
Fuck what disgusting.
I never drink Redbull but today I am tired.
It was you who asked me to buy fruit.
But can you remove that in the middle first how do you cut?
You may well remove when you eat human
This is removed by spoon first
Not on my plate.
Where should I put it then?
Armin ..
Babe stands on mine,
Babe
On my then, you totally rules.
What does it mean
Babe, that means "you own".
Can't you English
I thought Rule was the Rule Model.
Rude I thought otherwise it was.
Pretty good, I also have a large vocabulary
Swedish is actually not my strong side either.
Something that is actually my strong side, you know what it is
It's not to shut up and let me talk in a Mukbang once.
Right.
Just
No now you should look boring it is when I shut up.
What am I a sack of potatoes or?
I love potatoes though.
Klara talked so much in the last Mukbangen and many asked why I was so quiet.
You have to learn to let other people talk so
*Interrupts each other*
I'll keep quiet huh. - Yes.
You ask a question, you answer it yourself .. you are type ..:
Do you know what I have ... and tells yourself to yourself.
You have a mukbang with yourself.
It might just be better that I have them myself.
Or you get out of here.
And I have them myself.
Should you have bread or - yes.
Yeah
Quiet I said
What have you done last time
Antonija has been angry .. What the hell does Lapplisa where they patch them my car then I will f*cking kill you.
You see them orients
Yeah..what is not school end
I haven't put parking on my car.
Haven't you done that
No .. Armin
What have you had .. should we hug or should we bowl
Wait, wait, hug .. I felt a bit like a thunderstorm when I came in here.
Why does this apple juice taste
What have you done
Now she starts again.
Yes anyway.
It's just you and you.
This I think we should taste.
Choco Blanco.
I asked what you have done lately
So .. now ..
We can talk .. The weather is something we can talk about.
Hug.
I like you.
I liked you too.
Can we talk about this being the last mukban we do when I'm 29.
Yeah, when are you turning years tomorrow?
I am celebrating years on June 11.
No it's not tomorrow
No it is the day after tomorrow.
So that you are not aware ..
She says who didn't even invite me to her 30th year party.
What are we still there?
I'm hurt
You were damn in fourth place
*ruffles*
Can you stop cutting it on .. wait a stop.
Now I have no plate.
This would be the slash plate.
You have taken the slash plate on my ...
Now you have spilled on my trousers too.
I am actually celebrating years.
Yeah
In two days.
How does it feel like you turn 29
Can we talk about that my plate is now wet - Häääär, Häääär, Hääär !!!
But stop I'm not done
Then it becomes it ..
How are you darling
Thanks for the question, it only took 15 minutes into the intro until you asked.
Them will get a wrong picture of me, am not i nice
I think the right picture.
Hello is not me a nice girl
Can't we take our college level to a new level?
Yes but then you can actually let me talk.
Hello how does it feel to fill 29 quite seriously now.
However, I turn 30.
You said 29.
This is the last time I am 29 I said.
I mean 30 you take well.
Oh my God
I leave the 29yr decade.
I realized that now.
Or 20 years of decade.
It feels crap.
Do you feel old
Because that's you.
I know I often hear that I look like 14, Armin said that this morning too.
But ... if this ambulance shuts down ..
It goes to pick up my old life.
If you feel adult than type when you were 15, you felt "when I turn 18 then I become an adult".
Same with 25.
Do you still know the adult or do you just know no
Do you understand what I mean
So I would say this: I understand exactly what you mean.
When I was 22, I felt that I was type 15.
But now I'm an adult.
I can manage myself, I know how to cook pasta etc.
I mean life.
Well
No I still like to tramples just as much.
So, for example, when I have children ...
I will tramp very much.
I will be the one who just "should you have melon cheated!"
I will be that person.
Still, I never think I will grow up.
When people ask me how old I am:
And I will have to say thirty so I'll just ... Do you start feeling sensible?
No.
So sensible is something I really do not.
Choco Blanco.
Although I think you are.
Yeah ..
Do you know what's a bit boring with you
Mail is something I actually like.
ME.
You're okay.
You don't understand anything from what I'm saying.
If you like me mail, I like.
No love here.
I will actually write down my bank account here in the description.
"Swisha an optional sum."
Label it with Klara's birthday.
It would have been fun if you swish any sum, my number is on Instagram.
Congratulations then.
Thanks.
Now summer is here.
- Yes, speaking of summer, do you know what I heard on the internet this morning?
"I read on the internet that ..."
No now I have grown old for real.
It wasn't even the internet I would say.
Something I heard on ...
I read the magazine this morning ..
No, this was News Morning.
Do you know what they f*cking is discussing
To shorten the summer holidays.
I've heard about it.
What the hell is that about
I say no
Why do you care you have summer vacation whenever you want.
True ..
You go to Ibiza a little here and there.
It's true.
They said that the summer holidays should not be 10 weeks but it should be type 6.
You are not affected by it.
I felt like this .. If there is something we need more then it is f*cing leave.
More money ..
*mumbles*
As we talked about in the last section.
I just thought it is probably not good to shorten it too much.
I think people feel good about having 8 weeks of vacation and taking it easy.
I think it's important, you understand
I became really upset and sat there ..
It is important for the children
The sandwiches came in the same vein, I was very stressed.
Why are them so blonde, the sandwiches
They are so extremely bright.
There is a lot of pollen here.
Do you feel the pollen
For the first time in my life I do.
I've never known it.
For the thing is like this.
I was sick a few months ago and went on the shit that everyone else had.
And I was stuffed in connection with that.
I was stuffed in connection with that.
It was several months ago.
After all, I was cold and thought "my nasal congestion goes over soon."
When I'm healthy.
It still lasts.
It has lasted several months and I take nasal spray every day.
And I have begun to realize then that it is clear as hell that it is pollen.
It's pollen 100%.
I have never felt that ever
I still stand by being a pollen allergist.
I'm pretty proud to say that.
You have 30 different nasal sprays.
One in the car, one in the bag, one in the other bag.
One in the backpack ..
Do you know what it is called .. an addiction.
You should actually go into rehab now when you turn 30.
I don't like when the butter melts so I usually stand like this.
You want it to go fling down and forth.
The bread is like this *screams *.
Oh my God.
I think it is damn nice that it is summer for all plans.
I'm going to renovate all summer.
Right.'
It goes so well.
I'll get the keys next week.
Hallelujah.
The keys next week
Fun
We set off right away
Do you want to tell me a little then
It's an apartment, a third.
On 77 ..
Expensive
13 million.
20 million ..
Mine costs 50.
It's totally okay.
I tried to go pretty cheap anyway.
I have 5 more ..
The thing is that I should buy another one.
The thing is that I bought the whole house.
I bought the entire property.
So we will build a big fucking house.
We will have three balconies and five outdoor pools.
Out towards the horizon, they should go.
Do you have a room for me
No
Shit what I shudder when I talk like that.
In all cases.
We will start the renovation.
We will move in mid -September type.
Oh..
Or yes...
Where are you going..
Home to you I thought.
Well
Okay..
There have been many this past week.
I would move out, held on like that.
I thought more, how many will live with me
Open house is it at your home.
I should have spent 20 million instead of 15.
A few rooms extra just.
How are the love life going to date something?
Have you snapped something lately
Cleaning .. Type just an orange.
For real, do you have it
Nah
Not late.
Have I snatched no I haven't cheated anything.
Not late but it's 100% easy.
Last, when was it
It may surely be that I have palled an apple or something.
Pall an apple from a tree, they are free.
Are you the way that goes in the store, opens a banana and eat on it
No, but when I'm with the kids and they say * I'm really sucking * I say type "Eat."
Then I always pay.
I save the banana peel so they can scan it.
So you can't do iofs.
Do you like the apple powder
Wait they weigh ..
They do not scan the track.
Just damn, I don't know how they solved it.
This way, it weighs nothing, they have chewed it up.
Forgive me but bananas are about the same size.
Yes
Had sex
No
Not
It's Sahara down there
More than Sahara, it's kind ..
Smalls.
It really is, yourself then.
Located a lot
Aren't you out on tinder
No
Why
And you
Do you think I should it or
Aa
Åfan
Is it true
Yourself then, you lie or - yes
You are really nice today
I was just waiting for you to say so.
Quite frankly now, do you get so much attention from someone than me
Or by me.
No one actually.
If Jack sees this, I don't think you understand what you have to work on.
Everything sits and looks at me where it should sit.
Compare me then, my stuff sits like this.
Mine is looking up.
Yours sits *ding *
Gooood morning
Do you know what my tits are actually good.
Is it something I really like ..
In addition to money
And my tits.
Well
That too.
It's risifrutti.
It's something I ... but it's actually a little fun.
When you go on an excursion with school
That's exactly what I would say.
No you shouldn't say what I would say.
Nehe.
Now you are talking to me.
Yes for once.
Yes.
But what I would say was that my friends always said: "I have rice frutti" like this luxurious stuff ...
My family was always like this: "I make egg sandwiches or pancakes"
There you sit with like wet ballerina biscuits.
Yes exactly.
I also want Risifrutti as well.
I didn't get it.
You know them here the peanut rings
Yes.
I always had such, always.
But what it is like snacks
Yes my parents happened in.
Did you get a onion as well next to like a real jug
A little meat and onion in a lunch box.
Would you think i was a jug
No.
Nehe
Well, a Serb maybe.
MHM, why
I do not know.
What do you bases that on
Tell.
I do not know.
Can you stop looking at me
Croat or Serb.
Maybe pole, i don't know
Yes, but because you do not look Swedish for five cents.
Liberal no wait what is it, Libanes?
Svenne
No.
No
What will you do this summer
So Croatia opens its boundaries now on the 15th.
No
Yes.
For Sweden
Yeah, it's Croatia and another country that has allowed you to go there.
I'm so damn craving me and dad talk about it and he just: "Anto will we go the car"
I am really tough, you should have more
No.
Only me is going to have more.
So I can say a thing, I am also so eager to go down to Marbella.
But I also like this, you can go I do not think that Spain will open to Sweden.
So the thing is yes there are flights that go to Spain now.
Mm.
But the thing is that I think nothing is open down there.
So it will be closed, half closed.
It's fine for me I live in Jannie and Jon's castle.
Yeah you like sliding on your friends' shrimp sandwich
That's what I usually do.
Like you usually pay my bills and such.
Yes you grew up on Youtube because of me.
Yes we have talked about that.
*Antonija rap*
But do we have to be like a bowl?
I actually became it thanks to you.
A youtube star.
Have i told you how grateful I am for it
You actually have that.
Yes I have.
I have told Antonija quite a few times that I am so grateful that you helped me.
Important.
To what
To appreciate each other.
You know I did a lashlift now.
Do you appreciate me
Yes I talked about it then because I said then that I want it as ready.
And then I went in and scroll and just: "What is this"
She just: "But it's medium bend"
And I just: "What is ready for something"
She just: "Medium" so I said I want as clear.
You are a little in love with me.
Yes it's me.
But you don't admit it.
Do you know what I feel sometimes
That you are my little sister.
Well.
Or is it i who is your mother maybe
Yes great fun ...
Or if Antonija posted like this "inspo bathroom" the other day.
Yes it is my bathroom you have described.
But it was actually she who decided.
Yes but you have probably said what you want.
You just: "So I think a little you know gray walls, black taps"
It was exactly the same disc cone with bud.
I think it's great fun.
But you can never give it to me ever.
Why can't you give me, I like you.
There they came there too.
Equally stressed every time.
It's like when the invoice for the rent will be asked no!
Not again!
So I'm so damn tired of paying invoices.
It's something I don't want to do when I'm getting big.
Pay invoices.
So it's really like this: "Damn what a lot of money I make now, come in as much cash as possible and then just"
It goes like this.
No it goes like this and then just down and then just up.
Yes but how fun is that
How long should I have to work because I have no fucking Medelström who goes on this situation.
No no you know what it is about
We have to withdraw more money.
Why are you shaking
Is it money that starts it
We have to be strippers I feel.
Yes..
But god what I shudder, feel
But what are you shuddering over
It's because you are sitting here.
No but do you know what the only solution to this is
what
Earn more money.
Yes
Is it something you feel you want to do.
Yes God yes
Do you take out a good salary
Yes I do.
What do you charge in pay
Salary
SEK 45,000
And you
SEK 55,000.
You don't do that at all.
Well, I do.
Then you have done it now.
No I have been doing it for a few months now.
But shut up because I know we take the same salary.
Yes but after that I have taken out more so that I will fucking get an apartment.
Oops.
You know that .. Yes okay ...
I call the auditor and only: "We have to raise the salary"
Oh
He was in the sun for a long time.
Now we have to stop talking money.
Because then these are the ones happening.
Burnt brains.
Do you know what I feel too
I will probably actually go now.
I am burnt out.
This is what it looks like in my brain when I'm burned out.
I'll say a thing.
I have gone into the wall.
Hello after this, I just want to say it when this one has come up.
Then my other has come up because after this we will eat dessert.
Cake
Because it's my birthday.
I like to be kissed like this.
Did you know that these numbers are minutes.
Well, no I didn't know.
That is sick.
I thought it was level 2.
Level of burning.
It's minutes.
This is totally sick.
But who wants it for 7 minutes then it becomes like a damn brick.
Do not understand.
What do they even mean
No clue.
Do you think I'm finer without fringes
Much finer, it was a bit trashy before.
Yes.
But I think you are very nice.
But what I don't understand is why you don't have mascara on the lashes
Because I kind of think it weighs down my eyes.
Yes I understand.
You are very nice now overall I think.
Thanks.
But there is something with the lip
But I have emptied now and then I'll start over completely.
Yes I understand.
Because I told Antonija it looks a bit like you are sniffing
But also that you have inserted your lip.
This is because this upper lip was emptied but not the lower lip.
So I walk around like this.
But I think the upper lip is very nice.
Well
Yes I don't think you need to fill.
This was just that it was unfamiliar I think.
Woah.
But why should you have burnt out sandwiches
*Antonija screams*
They have entered the rust not into the wall.
But now Antonija is enough.
Can i eat this one
Yes and then you do this.
I'll give you a lifehack.
I know..
Because when this one has been released on Antonija's channel, I have turned 30.
And in order for you to see when we celebrate Klara, I think you should go down in the description and press the link for where it will be cake party!
There it will be a party!
See you in a few days.
No but in a few days
Should you exit this vlog
Yeah okay.
After all, you have learned your homework with shutting up.
Thank you for you, what is this section 9?
It is more.
No.
I promise.
So we are so damn awesome, thank you for following us, thank you for sitting and jawing with us.
See you next week maybe.
We'll do that.
It sounds good to say so, see you next week, kiss pussy, bye
It sounds like we have a TV show, so we should have that.
So TV contact me, or us.
TV, Internet.
Internet.
Internet Contact us We want a talk show.
It's something we should have, think about taking guests and grilling them in the hot chair.
If you want it, I think you should write to TV and say this ...
And then you tag type #TV4.
100 %