He is fucking your mom, wtf
Uh-oh..
It is difficult.
I'm mute, i am puff the first time in my life but i am puff
I feel like a little cock.
*Jack cough*
It smells...
Smells
Incredibly much sweat.
Wow.
I said what I've been in the laundry room.
Smell.
No
Listen we solved your problems separately last.
And it went so damn well, it was fun.
I actually thought so.
And on the video we came up with a suggestion that we would solve your problems with other Youtubers.
And now is the time
We are 5pcs today.
Right
Yes.
Who are we
It is me, Antonija, Anis, Jasse and Filip Motherfucking Dikmen.
And what is so fun for this time is that they are actually not where they have recorded this from home, from their offices or from their places.
I don't think that is fun, I wanted everyone to have been here and had the worst party.
*Rave music*
But we do not have time to party now we will record Youtube and make money.
We have developed 10 problems that we all respond to separately this will be swine fun to see.
What you think, what I think, what Filip thinks, what Jasse thinks, what Anis thinks.
Yeah you smell in my armpit, but seriously
It's incredible indeed.
I'll go and take a shower.
In over 3 years, I think this is Top10.
Is it true
Yes.
Have you run marathons this morning or
Yes I ran to the laundry room.
Okay, we're getting started
We start 5 youtubers, 10 problems now we run woho !!
Ouch
Okay so hello Antonija's channel.
*Stretches*
Hello on you all.
Hello my name is anis, I'm still baking from midsummer, I hope you are doing well.
The first problem we will solve now.
*Filip reads the problem*
*Jasse reads the problem*
*Jack reads the problem*
First, if they are naughty then drop them, throw them.
Secondly, how are you interested in 2 at the same time old man ...
Can you decide on one and after you have decided who you are interested in, throw him and his friend too.
First of all, I never think you should take shit from someone.
If you become uncomfortable about something that another person tells you, I think you should say away and put your foot down.
Although it can be hard, I definitely think you should do it.
You should always tell if you feel that you are being treated badly and if you see someone else who you think is badly treated then you should also say.
Throw them how can you be interested in someone who says: "No one likes you"?
You have to respect yourself and others have to respect yourself.
You may stop hanging out with these guys and finding friends who respect you for who you are and like you for who you are.
And that is not awkward to you.
And say as it is, say this way: "You treat me like this and I don't think it's okay, I'm sorry for it"
It's okay to dare to say.
If you still find it fun to hang out with these guys, I would tell them: "could you stop making such comments"
Otherwise, unfortunately I have to stop hanging out with you.
Oh what fun I am.
This can go to hell the sickest thing I read.
*Filip reads the problem*
WTF
Wtf!
*Filip again reads the problem*
WTF
*Filip continues to read the problem*
Is there more to read what is the problem?
*Reads the problem*
Firstly, your guy is with your mom.
-—-—-
He sends private pictures to her.
"But I love him what should I do"
WTF
Ehhh ...
Either you let him and your mom flee the country and live the flea.
No, but really ask him to go to hell.
This is totally sick.
Your mom is even snapper like ... so ...
This situation is fucked.
Dump him fast as hell.
You my psychologist her name is Gunilla and I send her number to you so you can, your mom and your guy call her she is actually damn good.
So no, no, no, no.
Stop loving him, talk to your mom and say, “Mom what fuck are you doing”
You have to talk to both and then say that you don't think it's okay and say away.
This is so damn bad as it is the same snoop for two generations, I can't.
I'm so sorry i can't help you, someone else may take this one
Hello hello I give up someone else may take this one.
Seriously, Leave Him, ASAP
It is a difficult situation.
Very unusual situation.
You have to dump him
My God you have, like black, seen that he sends private pictures to her.
"But I love him" no he doesn't love you!
Brother.
Old man.
This is unfortunately ... I can't help you here.
This requires C.S.I.
This requires Fucking Private Investigator.
Firstly, why is your mom lying with your guy
Excuse me to make you uncomfortable but what is it that is going on here
Secondly, your guy can go to hell.
Thirdly, I don't know, I'm mute, I'm a puff.
The first time in my life but I am a puff.
We go on I got fucking darkened by that assism what sick people there are sometimes out in the world.
*Jack reads the problem*
*Anis reads the problem*
Why are all the dating issues Antonija?
Is that what the video is all about?
?
Your followers obviously have dating problems.
I also think this is a hard choice for him because he gets you and the children in a package, you understand what I mean then
It may be a little harder for him to run a commitment because you have two kids.
It is more responsibility to take on and he may need the time to melt to dare to take that step, it is a pretty big step.
To become "pretending father" as well.
If you don't even know what you are waiting for, it gives you a strong indication that you should not wait anymore.
So I think that first and foremost you should sit down and talk to this guy.
"It's been 4 months and I don't have time to wait for you, my kids don't have time, it looks like I have time to wait for some tired guy who can't decide"
So it has been 4 months and you have dated and obviously he has an interest in you.
So I really think you should sit down and talk and say this: "Do you know what has been 4 months now you want or not?
I don't think you should end it if this good between you it would have been very boring.
It may be good to give him some time because just because you have children it will be a very large committee.
Becoming a part of it is like no little thing.
As I said, I think it takes a little more time to commit to someone who has children compared if it would not have it, especially if you do not have children yourself.
Because it becomes a completely different kind of responsibility.
So goodbye, Bybye, Arrivederci, Adios, Auf Wiedershen, goodbye.
Okay we move on.
*Anis reads the problem*
*Filip reads the problem*
*Jack reads the problem*
*Antonija reads the problem*
It will never be better between you, so sorry.
I have been in this situation where I met a girl who had been unfaithful before and a little such stuff.
And it's hard and I'm not saying he's right because he doesn't have it but it's hard.
So that here I think you have to make an effort if you really want to be with him to build trust.
You don't really have that commitment, but it can be good if you really want to be with him so to speak.
If he is so controlling then it will not be better between you.
If he wants to check who you spend time with, what you do, one and the other.
See you, goodbye, goodbye.
I'm not here to be a fucking robot that you fucking controls.
After all, you are not his property as it does not work this way.
This will be very busy for you if in is entering a relationship.
This will be going on for several years as I know, believe me, I know.
Leave him before it's too late, find a guy who can give you the love you deserve.
Point End Mother -Herpacker.
This guy has problems.
He got way to many issues.
You got to let him go.
Being jealous is a very bad and ugly trait, I am also a very jealous person.
And I think it is extremely difficult to be a jealous person as well.
Because ... however, I do not know if I have ever been as jealous as you explain that your guy is.
But I have been in such a relationship myself.
Guys who have a need for control will always have a need for control.
You can't change him, his view of life and relationship and women it is as it is so I'm sorry.
And kind of like this if you are with your friends often mess him up: "what do you" "we do this"
I remember when I had a girl and then I went on a tour a few years ago.
I arrived at this city and then I wrote: "Hello I am now" "now I will have dinner, after I have cooked dinner so I will be soundcheck"
"Hello honey now I have sound checked, now I will gigga, I'll hear from an hour when it's done"
Not because she asked for it but because I would have liked her to have handled the situation if she had been touring among alcohol and girls and it is easy to go to hell.
If you want to check something fuck I know go and check such a Rubics Cube and play with it.
Bye see you.
Buy one for him.
Rubics Cube.
You know that: "CIK, CIK"
Let him check it.
Bye see you.
Farewell.
Okay, we're moving on.
*Filip reads the problem*
"My dad is not a racist, but dad will probably see the guy's culture as a problem"
Which means he is a racist old man, do not try here.
*Filip continues to read the problem*
If I had been you I would have said to my dad: "Brother, dad brother."
Dad says sorry.
"Daddy, my guy is a blatte, do something about it"
And then you will see what he does about it that is my tip.
I say this, this is one, I think this is a fairly common problem.
That you feel that you should live up to your parents' type standard and what they think is okay and so.
And I think that's fucked up because it's your life and if you feel your dad can't accept this guy then it's your dad's problem.
He should not decide who to live your life with.
I have a very hard time for people who have difficulty in cultures in general because I think cultures are the finest we have.
And I definitely think you should talk to your dad that he doesn't ... So your dad shouldn't judge anyone for what someone has for a job or background.
Or what kind of culture or he has for religion.
Your dad should see the guy's qualities in that he wants you well.
I think that is extremely important and I think it's something you should talk to your dad about before you present this guy.
I think it can be very difficult with your dad but the only thing you can actually do is talk to your dad.
Introduce him, your dad gets to know your guy over time to see how amazing he is and that you love each other.
Your dad is a racist, we can start there.
I can't cope, your dad is a racist which is okay, it's not your fault that your dad is a racist.
But your dad is a racist if he sees your guy's culture as a problem or that the guy's culture would somehow limit the guy's opportunities for success.
Okay
Your father is a racist.
But
What you should do is say to your dad: "Dad, my guy is blatte, what should you do about it"
And then we'll see what happens.
That's my tip, next.
*Anis reads the problem*
Wtf ...
*Filip reads the problem*
*Anis reads the problem*
It is very shady.
*Filip reads the problem*
How can he feel forced to life and death or?
If your guy is really not involved in any way.
So your guy should call the police because the guy's cousin shit in the guy.
The guy's cousin totally exploits your guy for his own profit on the expense of your own guy hence the call the police.
Aina, 112.
"Sho brother, fix my cousin"
This ... but god I'm so damn bad at this kind of thing, I'm the worst in money.
I do not know..
How about talking to your guy's parents and with the cousin's parents and explaining the situation like this.
This guy has serious problems he sits and takes loans on the other's names.
You have to sit and talk to him for really otherwise you have to report him to the police I shit in whether it is a family or not, you do not do this.
You can't take out loans on anyone else.
So that person can't take loans later, your guy can't take a mortgage for example what the hell
*Antonija reads the problem*
Damn what money problem it is, wtf
*Antonija continues to read the problem*
*Anis reads the problem*
*Filip reads the problem*
Your friends find it hard that you don't have money and they want you to ask your parents for money for yourself
Okay.
It makes more sense.
If your friends cannot support you because you are not financially stable because of your smoking then they are not close friends.
But if you know that you do not have money or that you spend the money on smoking then you can't join them everywhere and go out to all the restaurants and go here and there.
If you can't pay yourself, then you have to stand for it.
If you put your money on cigarettes and do not have money over and then do them wrong.
But if you know that you prioritize your cigarettes over something else which I understand, it can be difficult.
Then you can't join them in everything possible either and then expect them to pay just because you have problems with your smoking.
So I remember when I lived in Dubai.
Then there was a person who was with us who had a pretty small buffer.
I have always said so here you have to move abroad so have at least SEK 50,000 to your name.
In addition to travel money and stuff.
Because it may be that things are going.
And he wanted to come out and we would do stuff but he could never afford.
And then I said this to him: "The brother, I think it's a shame you can't keep up but you don't have the money, stay home.
Don't show up, I have no idea.
Explain to them, I can't afford, I will not come, good luck, have so good, fat fun, ciao.
It's kind of that tip that I can give you because it was kind of what I took with the whole question.
Ehm ...
Stop smoking and saving cash.
And save you on your beautiful lungs that you have because you have only a couple.
Or do you have two pairs
One pair, two lungs.
Save you on your beautiful lungs and your amazing money.
I understand that it can be difficult with money in the teens, I think it is a great way of thinking you have.
Except for smoking there.
You are not ashamed that you cannot afford.
You say that to them.
But you have to talk to your friends, because I don't think it's real friends if they can't understand a situation.
And ask you to ask for money from your parents.
Here is also the thing about turning on the steak.
You can say to your friends "I had the giants followed and bathed on this bathhouse"
"But I can't afford" and they may accept it.
If they can't accept it, they are probably no friends to have.
*Jasse reads the question*
Old man, then you just say we'll see you
Farewell, rubbish fits debris.
You should see this as a blessing from above.
Then God has shown .. brother, old man, brother
Sister, you are surrounded by junk.
You are naive, you do not understand that the people in your area are pathetic.
They are nasty so I'll give you a homework.
I'll show you that your closest people, your best friend and your guy .. is junk.
Let the debris find each other.
Fyfan what unnecessary friends.
So ush.
The tip up in this bitch and move on.
So you can skip this scrap heap by people.
And find better people later.
That's what this is all about.
Fyfan, both of them are very huge.
I really hope you find some other friends.
They were not your friends, definitely not.
She wasn't your friend, he wasn't your friend, he happened to you.
She happened in you, everyone happened in you.
Shit in them.
Throw them.
Have a good one.
No .. I understand that you are very sad ..
But there is no friend to have, there is no guy to have.
That gets along with your best friend.
*Jack reads the question*
*Anise continues to read*
*Antonija continues to read*
Excuse whose dad hangs at the pub with younger?
It's like my dad is going to hang on Spybar
WTF
*Jasse continues to read*
My God which .. So damn what boring.
That you have had to go through these other things.
I am so sorry for what you have gone through.
I really understand that you are traumatized.
Of course .. and this really doesn't help.
Fucking ... *******************
Number one, there is help to get for you, you have to talk to someone.
I don't know if you have done it, because I don't know your background.
Or this whole history.
You have to talk to a psychologist and process this.
And I understand, what you go through now with your friend's dad is totally sick and nothing anyone should go through.
I don't know how good friends you are or if she knows about your situation.
But if it is that you are good friends and she knows what you have been through ..
And you tell her what is happening at her home with her disgusting fucking dad ..
Then she should grasp.
She might suppress it because she thinks "my dad is not like that".
Well your dad is a fucking disgust.
I get so annoyed, whose dad hangs on the tavern
With people who could be his children
It is very vast.
I do not know how far he has gone, but this can be reported to the police 100%.
Iom the situation you have been in when you were younger ..
With you being raped, I may think you should consider stopping spending time with her here ..
I had distanced from ...
I don't want to say that you should distance themselves from your friend because of.
Such a thing ..
But for your own security, I might have done it.
If it is because of her you are close to this man.
So that he can't do something as disgusting that happened last.
Because this is already disgusting.
It's not okay for him to paw at you unless you want it.
And just there he has done something very disgusting.
I hadn't even wanted to know what could have happened if you were alone.
Do you understand what I mean
I had considered stopping spending time with this friend for a while anyway.
To remove me from this man.
So her father.
*Filip reads the question*
Congratulations
*Filip continues to read*
*Jasse continues to read*
*Jack continues to read*
*Antonija continues to read*
*Anis reads*
Eh, keep the baby.
Primarily.
That's probably the most important thing I can say right now .. keep the child.
Do not think the idea of dropping the child, the child is here.
Congratulations to children, I can be your godfather.
I like you, you can have a shoutout from me kids.
I don't have much control over grants and stuff .. But parental allowance will not be enough ..
But there must be some other contributions you can get.
They are probably not on any mega sums.
There must be some other contributions that you should be able to apply for.
Hopefully in your situation.
I really hope so.
Heres the story, first off .. You're gonna keep the kid.
Second, everything is gonna be fine.
We live in Sweden, everything is gonna be fine.
Number 3, You're Gonna Get Money.
In Promise.
4th, he's gonna get a job.
5, Good Luck.
So, Antonija and Antonija's followers.
That is all.
I hope you like my expertise.
Hope you liked my words.
Hope I was helpful even though I just scream.
Peace.
Corner.
There are all questions actually.
For this little "solve problem video".
That said, I apologize if I was a little tired.
So, thank you for me.
Kiss and hug
It was my answers.
It was my answers, hope it helped someone.
Thank you so much for being able to join.
Kiss and hug, bye
But come
But stop
That was not the point.
It was the 10 problems.
The camera is skits.
It was the 5 YouTubers who helped you this time.
I hope you feel you got the help you needed.
We gave the help we could provide.
Aa we did.
I think we make one more like this with other Youtubers.
So comment below which you want.
I will go out on Instagram Story with new problems.
If you have any problems, you are welcome to write them to me then.
And until then, there will be other videos.
See you, we hear, in your dreams.
I fucking went on Thai boxing.
Stick.