Hello and welcome to this extra posted broadcast on the occasion of the great notice that is happening right now.
Yes, the Coronavirus affects the labor market very heavy and many companies unfortunately have to notify or leave their employees.
Today I have Annika Sundén, Head of Analysis, and Mats Rubertson, qualified manager here at the Employment Service.
You are warmly welcomed here.
Thanks so much.
I thought we might start by sorting out what warning actually means.
Annika, what does it mean to be notified today
A notice is that it is a company that tells its employees
That we expect we will not be able to have work tasks for you so that you can be dismissed.
So it is a notification that it may happen.
And this is because of the fact that as a result of the Coronavirus
So we live our lives in a different way.
We do not go to a restaurant, we do not travel, we shop less.
And then there are many companies that no longer
yes cafes close, airlines no longer fly,
There will be smaller people in the business and then there are no work tasks anymore.
And Mats Lost is a fairly new concept for many, how would you explain what it means
Leave Leave is an opportunity for employers that
let the employees instead of resigning them go down in working hours
And it is for the same reason as a result of the fact that there are fewer tasks to perform really.
So it is an opportunity to go down in working hours.
And what with layoffs right now is that this
is a crisis that we know will end.
It is a virus that will disappear
And then the companies want
What is important is that the companies remain when this has blown over or when the virus does not exist
And therefore it can be good for a company to permit to be able to keep its employees,
To be able to start then when the wheels start rolling again.
Luminals are something that has always existed and
that is an agreement between employers and employee organizations
And now there is also the possibility of short -term work
which is handled by the Growth Agency that makes it more advantageous
for employers to use the instrument layoff.
Yes there is a difference between notice and layoffs.
What does the situation look like right now Annika have any statistics, how many are it that is notified?
Normally if we should only have a comparison a normal month if we take Mars a year ago
Then we had about 3000 people who were notified of dismissal.
During these last two weeks, we have 18,400 people who have been notified of termination.
And just last week there were 14,000 people almost.
So there are very big numbers, so there are very many people affected by this.
If we look back on previous crises, I think mainly in 2008 when the great economic crisis came last.
How many people are notified will eventually be dismissed
Yes it is important to remember to be notified does not mean getting rid of the job
This means that you can lose the job.
If we look at the financial crisis in 2008 then by those who were notified then
It was six out of ten who were then dismissed from their job.
But these were people who found new jobs pretty quickly so in the end
So there were three out of ten who became unemployed.
So it's not that you go directly into long -term unemployment
Just because you have been notified, been dismissed, or not been terminated.
After all, we have arrived until the Coronavirus had a good labor market
And there have been plenty of jobs if you have at least one high school education.
And these people who can now get rid of their jobs are people who have had experience
and that has worked so they are quite close and have pretty good opportunities
that when the economy then starts getting started again
When we start living in our usual way,
When we start going out again at a restaurant, shopping and traveling, these people will be able to get new jobs.
And which industries and sectors do we see the most notice in
We have gone into it a bit before, care is one of them for example.
No care is not.
Sorry, hotel and restaurant
Yes about half of the warnings are located in hotels and restaurant
And this is where they have come first.
But we also see it in staffing companies, travel companies, in the transport sector and in the trade.
If we take care and care as you mentioned
so it is a sector where there is a very high demand
And a lot of people are needed in sick and health care and care right now.
We have seen that more job ads have been received for those jobs.
So one thing to think about right now is that if there is something one would like to do in the future
which you can now educate.
After all, there is a great need in care and care.
So to start thinking about an education within it.
Yes a great point there.
Mats, layoffs we have to go back to it.
Are there any figures on what it looks like with layoffs
The layers have 500650 pieces?
Yes 650 pieces, there are not so many yet but we expect many more.
After all, it is the Swedish Growth Agency that will register them.
It will be done from April seventh.
Are there any specific sectors where we believe the layoffs may increase
One can imagine laying out of layouts can be something that appeals to industries
or knowledge -intensive companies to a greater extent
Where it is more advantageous to get people back to work fast.
Yes this is important, as I said a health crisis
Where this virus will eventually disappear.
We do not know exactly when it is, but then it is important that these companies remain.
The reason why layoffs have not been common in the past is that the companies themselves have been responsible for the cost.
Now the government has entered with powerful efforts
where one then goes in and helps pay the salaries of employees in order for them to be left
And that companies should be able to live on.
So it's a lot about keeping the economy or these companies up
So that they are there and left that we can get started when this virus is gone.
So traditionally, we have not seen so much layoffs
But it has started to increase now, which shows that it is an extraordinary situation we are facing.
Yes you could say that.
And finally.
If you are now faced with being notified.
Do you have any tips on what to take with you already and start thinking about
One thing to keep in mind is that many who also lose the job and not just be notified
are, after all, hourly employees and have had fixed -term employment.
Many of these industries are input industries so there are many young people
Many who are at the beginning of their working life.
This might be a time to think about if I might be educated
I might take advantage of this time to find an education
But also think about what can I do now in the short term
For example, I saw that the Sophia home begins a very short education in three days
To learn the basics to help in sickness and health care, for example in the kitchen.
So to think about change.
Then there are many services on the Employment Service's website
Our digital services where you can get tips on how to think.
Yes, you can create a profile.
Yes create a profile and get ready.
And then you become visible too
For employers and get a faster contact where you are looking for skills for example.
But it is only when you become unemployed that you have to sign up
So you should not do that now that you are notified.
But please take part in our digital services
And other webinars to get tips on how the labor market works and what you can think of.
And then it is important to write in digitally, it makes a lot easier.
We must say that.
It was all the time we had for today.
I have to thank you for coming here and I thank you who sat and watched.
Bye.