Hi, my name is Alexandra Zazzi and have been working in restaurant kitchens for over 25 years.
It is both wonderful and inspiring.
But there are some risks.
Therefore, there are work environment rules to protect those who work here.
Unfortunately there are employers who do not know these rules
or chooses to deliberately ignore them
To save time, save money and to obtain benefits towards their competitors.
It is called unhealthy competition.
Follow, and I'll show you what a good kitchen looks like,
where you follow the rules.
Do you see the lamp here outside the freezer room
It's an alarm.
If I were to be locked up, there is a button to press in there so that the lamp starts flashing.
It's minus 20 in there, so you can freeze to death.
Hey here i am again
This roasting table has a tip cover.
And it is also important that it stands firm so it cannot overturn and cause crush damage.
Hello there
Here at the fryer, there is definitely no running water nearby.
If there is water in the hot oil, it can start to splash and in the worst case start to burn.
And always have a lid nearby.
Here in the counter there is eye shower.
There must be, so you can flush your eyes in case that you have got corrosive detergents on the face.
Obviously there is a lot to think about,
But it pays off in the long run and in the end it is about the health of the staff.
And now we will look at what it looks like in a kitchen where you do not follow the rules.
Look here
The machines are connected to joint boxes.
This means that both bench and machines can be live and it is fatal.
This is just too crowded
And look there.
It really doesn't look good.
Remember to place heavy goods correctly.
She barely has time.
Stress is a serious health problem.
She would need some help here.
Ouch ouch ouch
That could have gone really, really bad.
Think about floors and shoes, and that the dressing box is always filled.
Hope you thought it was interesting to see what ignorance, nonchalance and unhealthy competition
can bring with it and what the consequences can be.
It is the employer who is responsible for ensuring that the staff has a good working environment.
But the staff should also say if you see dangers in the work environment.
Then you can avoid injuries and sick leave
Which is tough for the staff and by extension the community costs money.
It is important that those who work with procurement,
For example, of food to schools, hospitals and elderly homes,
places demands on the working environment of the employers who submit tenders.
Then a good working environment can be a competitive advantage.
It benefits both serious employers and the staff.
bye