There were staff that I could talk to but.
and i had a
a support.
but what I brought up with her as she would take
up with the teachers.
teachers didn't listen to her properly.
but we talked a lot and it was nice to have
as well as conversation therapy almost about school
with someone who also works at school who knows what it looks like.
it was.
i needed that support.
I just wished the teachers like to take her a little more
seriously I think.
I would have liked the others in the staff also just saw that
I exist and maybe ask i felt and not that you are
here when it suits you.
While I was home I had contact, or my
Mom had most contact with school.
but I had the most contact with a single person and it was
Ju with resource teacher Roger that I wrote if I was sick
or if I could not go to school at all and he
tried to pull me there.
he usually told me that man or that i just would.
i wouldn't think so much, i would
just do it.
at my old school I could sit in my place and so could
teachers come into the room without even looking in my direction
or bother me as if I were there or not.
but then when I came to my new school it was always an
good morning and it was always positive stuff they said.
and had you become ill one day they could write
to a direct.
and how are you?
they play a bigger role in young people's lives than they think
and what they do and say will affect more than
they think too.
what Mary did that was good, it was that she saw me and
Like almost took care of me.
like I was one of her children.
it was like.
she.
Yes, she saw that I was among all others who were outgoing
and heard as well.
she still saw that I existed
in a way he saw us was that he did not focus on
we had arrived too late without us being there.