When I think back on my schooling
I think it's been hard,
Hell and heaven
What I see in front of me is incomprehension,
Ignorance and confusion I would say.
Hard, it has been confusing,
And it has been depressed.
Unspoken, tough but finally so
was actually very good
When I think back on my schooling
so has it been like a prison
It's been a waste of time to go
To school, I think.
At the old school the teachers had not really
Check out, or no one control, what ADHD was.
It should have been a clock - ding!
He has ADHD.
But I don't know what put a stop to it.
I was so damn hyper but they didn't take.
and it might be a bit frustrating to think about
That they didn't see it.
I sat for the phase of the ceiling all the time.
I think the teachers had a hard time understanding me.
I didn't say what was wrong with me,
I kept it within me how I felt.
So it was barely anyone who knew how bad
I felt, it was only myself who knew.
I have been set in front of Lego instead of
Get to participate in the English and Swedish lessons.
I was too sluggish to be involved.
The worst thing was my teacher wanted me to
Special school.
It was really the most important thing,
she thought i had some other kind of wrong
I don't know what she really thought.
In the 3-4an, that's when the girls began to be
A little more with the guys.
And they talked about me
"She's really busy, we don't want to be with her"
and it became such a hard thing for me
that people thought I was hard for I
Wanted to be liked by just about everyone.
So I was lying in the evenings thinking “Ok, tomorrow
Then I'll be normal.
Tomorrow I can be
normal 'and I decided to be normal
But when it was the next day and I would be
orderly and be calm, then it burst.
And then I felt even more unsuccessful
Because I couldn't do what I had decided.
Inside the lessons I got frozen and on
I was beaten the breaks.
So the whole school was a black hole.
The teachers did not see me.
They didn't help me.
They were probably only ordinary teachers who thought
That I was an ordinary student.
One of the biggest challenges in my schooling
Have been when I got too big tasks.
If one should choose any country and write
so i have always had a hard time choosing which
Country I will write about, and then get started.
When I get such a great task where man
chooses freely and then should write about something,
Then I just get sitting and don't do anything.
Something more that is difficult are long reviews
and especially on the NO lessons for there
they usually be very long.
The teacher usually
say very much stuff that doesn't get stuck,
It goes into one ear and comes out on the other side
It is extremely difficult.
I might listen
for a maximum of 10 minutes.
Then I can't cope anymore.
When our teacher had a review in our subjects,
Especially no and math ... I didn't understand anything
of what she was talking about.
It was like she
Talked extraterrestrial type.
To let a dyslexic go ahead and read aloud
Or write something on the board, it's really
walked scary like hedging him down in a
Diving equipment with sharks.
It's so heavenly
Nervous because you can't read aloud that way.
I can't write, I can't spell
In concrete terms, with a regular pen.
In high school it is that you have to choose information.
“Here are 20 tasks and you should choose 5 of them.
No one is more important, you have to choose completely freely. "
Then I think "5, but that's 20?
How can there be 20 if to do 5? "
Something that has been difficult in school for me
is to concentrate on the lessons,
sit still and be quiet.
I know myself that
it's not possible.
I can't.
I can do
It for a maximum of 3 seconds.
Then I start walking, then
It starts crawling in my legs.
Can't sit still
Further, then I have to move.
But it is
many times as i have heard my teachers say
"Sit still and was silent".
When I switched from a smaller school to a larger
Was it hard in the classroom because there was more sound
than in the smaller school.
The students talked more.
So I had a hard time concentrating
and the teachers did not tell them they would be
silent without the continued as they used to do.
Although it is large or small class so
Is there always something that bothers you.
For me
has it mostly been big stuff but
there is always something small that can bother me
and I can bother with more than if it
are several talking.
So then i have always had
trouble concentrating because of
Some sound that bothers me.
Another thing that is very challenging for me
is my concentration.
It's always been huge
Hard for me.
Getting a paper ...
while I read, I hear how he farthest
rear goes forward and sharpen his pen and I
counts the yard he sharpen his pen, instead
To read what the headline is.
And it is not going
because there is so much all around me
My head can't switch on a thing,
It connects in a hundred.
A major challenge in school has been me together
with conflicts.
It has been very much
that I can't stay on a normal level,
A quiet level.
Most conflicts I come in
is about injustice.
That I feel
either undisturbed or that I become
unfairly treated.
It will be, I don't know,
It gets black when I get angry.
I'm coming
Hardly remember what I do or what I say.
And then the anxiety comes afterwards instead.
But then when the teacher did not take me after
Then it only got worse, then it was left.
When I look back on my childhood
That it is always me who is the one you blame.
In the second, the third had some children been on and
pushed me down in the ground and hit me
Virtually a whole break.
But then when I
Came home, the teachers had called my parents
and said that I had started noise while it
were the ones who were doing with me the whole break.
And then I got the blame for something like me
Really hadn't done.
Why it was so,
It was easy to blame me.
I was one
a little hyperactive person who wasn't really
like any other.
A simple victim to blame.
Homework, the worst there is.
I'm enough too tired to make them and
I just shit in them.
I was just too tired.
When I got home I just wanted to lie down
On the bed and take it easy.
Why should one get homework, the school is for
to learn one and work, why should one then get
Homework to do at home?
Home is at home,
Not the school.
So I think that is totally unnecessary
That you get.
So I don't usually do my homework
If I get some, then I do them in school instead.
A major challenge in school has been to come
Up on the mornings and get away from school.
Often I went up, ate breakfast and
dressed on me but then I felt “no, I
Can't manage "so I went and lay down again.
For I knew the feeling would come to me
will not be able to focus on lessons and
I am behind in school and don't know if I
Will get help for what I need.
Very early in my schooling I noticed that
It was hard to go to school.
It was
well mostly because I was tired and because
I got up so early so I couldn't cope.
It was hard for everyone, my parents got
almost force me to go to school.
It was
well only a few times that I really felt
"Yes now we'll take and fix this", then went
that to hell that day and then I felt
Not so anymore.
My dream school is the school I attend now!
It is because it is so good teacher, we have so
Good contact with the teachers.
They understand how we
Feels and we understand the students.
Especially in mine
Class we feel like a family.
A really good school for me, that would
be a school that never gets homework.
Where it
Are there teachers and special educators who are
Trained to help students with ADHD and Asperger.
A good school for me would be ... understanding!
It is not needed so much more than understanding
Because from that, the person knows what to do
Also understand that everyone with my diagnosis ADHD
Not the same, we don't all work the same.
You have to listen, you have to be interested.
The most important thing I would say is that one gets
More unique adaptation.
It's hard to
individualize teaching for many students
But that is what is needed.
All students sitting in my situation or
Has diagnoses certainly has lots of different
thoughts about their dream school, but I think
that the teachers instead of giving a great task
So they do less tasks for all students directly.
In the school I attend now we have very much
structure.
We have the same classroom, we sit on
the same place, we have a small sign on our
Bench where it says our names.
Then writes
the teachers up on a whiteboard what it
is for subject, what time it is, what time
We have a break, what we should do, how to do
And why we should do it.
There should be good instructions.
Were the classrooms
Located and where to go.
And clear
Schedules, that would also be good.
Something that helps me in school when it gets
Hard for me is clarity.
It should be
clearly to me what to do, it will
be clear when it is to be finished and
It should be clear.
It was well at the beginning
just a teacher who saw that it was actually
Hard for me.
So when I entered the lesson
so there was a piece of paper at my place where it stands
"Linnea's Schedule", and there stands when the lesson
begins and ends at the top.
Then stands times,
"10 minutes read, 5 minutes break" and so stood
There is some suggestions on what I could do.
Check the mobile phone, go down to the cafeteria or
What I wanted to do.
And what time I would
be back.
This worked so well for me
When it was extremely hard for me before I
Strategies themselves had found.
That I actually
Got help from someone who saw me.
The teachers should cooperate with the parents as well.
It is good that the parents and teachers have
good contact because then teachers can tell you about it
Is something in school that may affect me.
So they can contact my parents.
In order for a school to work well so it is required
That the teachers really see the problem with the students.
If they see that someone is feeling bad, that they really
Grab it and ask.
Only a hello in the corridor can make a difference.
Prejudice about ADHD, they will be away.
They must not exist.