Everything started when Nang ended.
I usually do this [breathing quickly}.
Often it was that he could not breathe, he thought he would die.
So he just collapsed and only
"I can't breathe mom," he was really scared.
I had so many thoughts in my head, so I didn't want to live anymore.
In the four, he worked in grade three, and then grade four.
So he ended up ahead of everyone else in the school work itself.
So I've had many outbreaks.
When I was less .. So it was not good.
It was screens .. broken.
Then when he had nang, then Nang and Timmy trained very much,
That if someone was teased then "go away instead of attacking" and such things.
Then we realized that when he feels he is on and getting so angry, and feels that he is losing control
Then he will "I want to call my mom".
When he said it was a signal, he is getting an outbreak and has no control over those outbreaks.
But when he had to call, the phone got right away and then he had to call me.
Then I talked to him, sometimes I could calm him down so he could continue his day
But then Nang was with him.
Everything was raging there
It is many years of working and struggling and training, it is not just a week.
He does not want to get the outbreaks, does not want to be angry, he wants to feel good simply.
He is the best guy in the world.
He has plenty of humor, my God ...
... so caring.
He is my assistant and my friend.
He is great.
He helps me with a lot at school and how I progressed.
I have been approved on topics when I have Amir and stuff.
So it is really good.
No eruptions, nothing.
Can sit and make ten pages math.
Happy.
Enjoy school ...
And it goes so well and self -confidence is growing, no problems.
Home knowledge is my favorite at school
I love cooking
“How would it be if we started training Timmy to be with other adults
Instead of just Amir ”.
I realized right away, that he will be taken away from him.
I read between the lines, we have been involved in this before.
Directly I took the handset and called the headmaster
Then she said on the phone that they should save money and he should be terminated.
So I just “not now again”
Amir is the only one I feel safe with.
I can't go to school again.
I'm afraid to get those outbursts and everything.
It will not work.
He needs to have that security for schooling to work.
It is proven.
The only time in school it worked is when he has assistant he felt safe with.
It's been twice.
And I know he wants to study and work in school and get good grades and all that.
He wants it and he is capable of it.
He is more than capable of it.
He is very smart.
For them, this does not fit this with the special school,
He should really go in regular class.
So then they end up between the chairs.
Then I do not go to school.
Then I stay home well.