Welcome to international author scene Gothenburg here at the City Library where I will
Talk to Helle Helle!
And my name is Annina Rabe
I am very happy to sit here with you for I
have read you very long
And like your books very much.
As we sat here outside and talked before we started
Said your publisher Lisa, your Swedish publisher, something very good.
We talked about the translations of your books.
I will also say that Helle Helle's books are translated here in Sweden by Ninni Holmqvist, which is a fantastic
Good translator.
Then Lisa said like this:
Seemingly but difficult.
Then I thought, that is something that
somehow
A little sums up your entire authorship, in a way.
Because it is very difficult
that is treated though
Most of it is under the surface.
I thought we'll start by talking about your last book,
“Bob” as
Recently, here in the days, came out in Swedish.
But that we will also come into the book that came before Bob.
They are interconnected in a way and that is the book "they"
that came
for
2 years ago.
This with seemingly
Hard but simple?
Or seemingly simple but hard, is that something you
Can agree with or?
For me
Is it simple.
And not difficult.
I think...
Do you understand me?
I think if it is a reader, when I sit and write,
So I think it should be easy for the reader.
So that the reader will understand what I understand.
But
At the same time I can see that
all that is all about
is not what stands
Without perhaps what does not stand.
It's because I avoid writing about emotions.
It's so hard for me.
That I became a writer
and writes the books I make
is because I discovered that you do not have to write about emotions.
But that they are in everything we do
and says.
I just read an interview with you that you say "all my books are about emotions"
But
At a first read
Maybe it can be difficult to detect those emotions?
But that is why I want you to notice,
Thus, sense what is happening.
The people I write about
Don't know what they feel.
There is a kind of break or wait, perhaps a longing to reach it
you feel.
Which may therefore be difficult for me to write.
But as a starting point I think that
the way novels are being read in is often not the same way as the writer
Looking at the novel, that's how it is for me.
When I write I think a lot about
every
sentence.
Not because I am
Perfectionist, or I am!
But one should be
When writing, otherwise it is pointless
But often it is a kind
Association from meaning to meaning.
It's a lot so I work.
Your prose is also very associative.
Often you are described as a minimalist and this I know that you have been against yourself,
to be called minimalist.
But
If you say ...
If you turn it around, you could say it's very ...
There are prose that wastes a lot with the words and you don't.
You are very frugal with the words.
That you are a perfectionist is very clear,
There is not a single word that is there
By chance, you get a feeling when you read your books.
It may sound a little scary!
It may be a little dead about
Every word, you can almost get anxiety if you are to read something you imagine has meaning and meaning in everything.
And that is not the meaning
That it should be so.
And it is true that I do not perceive myself as a minimalist.
I have never understood how to
Write minimalist books.
I understand better minimalism in visual arts
but
minimalism is not
That you don't say everything?
Is it?
So you see that there is very little and below it is very
But I think a minimalism is often about removing psychology
And my books are about psychology
They are psychology, it feels like.
Yes
And that is very much the case for "Bob" which is your latest book
For those of you who haven't been able to read "Bob" yet can we start by telling it it has
A very special storytelling structure
The main character,
It's one of my questions by the way, who is the main character?
Because it tells about Bob,
This young guy Bob, young man Bob,
but
The one who tells his story is his girlfriend.
So the whole story is told through the girlfriend, even in
Situations that she absolutely cannot have been with.
Tell us a little about how it turned out it became this one
Very special storytelling technology?
The books I write,
"They" and "Bob" but also the coming
ahead,
There I try
To let the language
tell
The mood, explain, tell the outcome.
Or leave the form part of the action.
So that the way it is written on
Also says something
About what the book is about.
So the idea of "Bob" was that if the narrator, his girlfriend,
just tells you about Bob
and not about oneself
So she becomes more absent and at the same time more present.
And that's what the book is about.
That they are on their way apart
but that it is a great sadness
The covenant with it
But also a distance that extends throughout the book.
She's just talking about him,
she distant herself
and I perceive that as
A kind of act of love.
That she does it, that she lets Bob ...
She gives him the stage.
But
she might also manipulate
Because she decides
What it should say about him.
And she decides
What will happen to him when she is not there.
And there you play a little bare all the time a splash
with the reader.
Somewhere in the middle of the book you become ...
How much can I trust this narrator?
Can i believe that this
Is it happening Bob?
We can never really know that.
No, but another attempt was ...
What I wanted was that I was thinking
Can you have
A storyteller who just says
"I"
once?
And the rest of the time she is just like a “we”
Together with Bob
I thought, can you do
A pronoun
full of feeling?
In one place in "Bob" it stands,
“my”
My Chinese shoes, what is it in Swedish?
It is a reference to “they”
but the word “mine”
from the narrator's side
is not in any other place.
I was going to ask you to read a paragraph out of "Bob"
So you can get a sense of the book.
I take from the first page.
It is also difficult in Danish.
I might bring out the glasses ... No, they are gone!
Out Move Bob and I to Vanlöse,
Our home lay on top of the station,
And we had a rod parquet.
Up and down the stairs it went,
Bob wore almost everything.
Cardboard boxes,
Classes and bags.
All the time any of us said:
How much luck can you have?
The apartment was one with a balcony.
In the plant road we had a yuccapalm, a homecoming,
a cactus,
A Benjamin Fikus.
The homemade grew in half a coconut,
A farewell gift from Bob's little brother.
The inventory consisted of a flap table with chairs,
One and forty-bed.
Agency and floor lamp and more.
Nothing to the walls,
Bob thought about hanging up a towel,
A special purple
With braid patterns of tapestry character.
Screw legs
on
Table and mediates on bed.
But we left everything in a single mess and went out and sat in the late afternoon sun.
We sat on the same chair.
Bob saw maybe a tern,
The women's house is just behind.
He put his beer on the back of the hand,
grabbed it in time.
The balcony echoed,
It was the eighteenth of August.
Bob loved
Yellow brick.
Then maybe I, to clarify a little neighbor, can read it all
First sentence in Swedish.
It is very special and when we talked about your translations, this
Is really a challenge for translators.
I read an English translation of just this first paragraph
They had not managed to get this very, very
Special Tempus Switch I would say is pretty
Typical of your authorship.
You work a lot with both tempus and pronouns.
Bob and I move out to Vanlöse.
Our home was on top of the station and we had a rod parquet.
It went up and down the stairs.
Bob wore almost everything.
I can stop there.
It happens as one
Tempus change in the middle of the sentence.
It should not be possible but
but it works!
Yeah, it's great if it does
But I can say that it is also difficult in Danish.
Another plan I had for the novel was
to write a book that was like a palindrome,
thus as could be read from the front and from behind
And you can't!
Then I thought,
the first ........
Should you be able to read
from the front and when the book ends you should recognize them, they are just back and front
They would correspond to Bob's name.
Bob.
So I thought that in the book's half first part everything should go well,
And in the other half, everything bad.
As a rorschachtest,
As a kind of reflection.
But it did not work.
The only thing that went was the first three words.
To make them succeed in the end, the book must start with "Moving Bob and I"
Is that how it says in Swedish?
"Bob and I move", so it can be read from behind.
It will be the opposite at the end.
But now I have revealed how the book ends
.......
Who is Bob?
Bob!
May I say something about the previous book first,
Something about "they" to explain who Bob is?
Yeah but you can do, just for
It's so or ...
We'll talk a little more about it later but I can
say that these books are interconnected
in some ways.
They do not interfere with an absolutely obvious way but they do.
You feel it.
One notices it quite
Clearly when man
Have read both.
But start by telling us who Bob?
Bob is a young man from the countryside,
raised on a farm,
that moves with its dearest to Copenhagen
Because she should study.
And he should nothing.
That's the novel.
He tries to get his life ... He tries to find out what to do.
Wandering around on the streets of Copenhagen
are friendly,
He looks very good,
It's positive vibes around him,
He is a kind of ladies' friend.
But he is very faithful to his girlfriend,
which gradually takes more and more distance from him.
I think of him like ...
Now I have to say one thing about “they”
In “they” is bob
A kind of good helper.
Do you say so in Swedish?
The good helper?
It is a literary concept.
He wants others well.
He is also in "Bob".
He takes it with him from his countryside
To the big city.
He looks at all he meets,
You do not do this in normal cases.
But he comes with the countryside
and he greets the bus driver
He is coming
with a kindness
Which gradually becomes more difficult and harder for him.
He is becoming more and more entangled.
His surrounding existence ends up eventually
Like a snare that is tightened.
Both as with that
one understands that this relationship is about to go to the forest but also because
all his situation becomes
More and more crowded.
Yes it does.
He gets depressed after all
Because he doesn't have ...
Yes, because ...?
Why?
Because he longs for something he can't get.
And because maybe he longs for what he comes from
But he can't get what he comes from.
I think many people can recognize that, I do it anyway.
In many of my novels I have used everything I come from,
My own time, my own upbringing in the countryside.
Not really so much to move
from an environment to
another.
More that
move from one environment to another
Without feeling failing, failing
What you come from.
It really is about "Bob".
Then you could also ask, who is Bob's girlfriend?
It is very much her book.
Yes.
And "they" is the book that came before "Bob" and
where
Is it about one
Young
Woman and her mother.
The mother is dying
and
They both know ...
At first, the daughter does not know, the mother says nothing, but
Gradually she understands that too.
But
somehow so ...
their lives as well as continues ... somehow ...
Despite the knowledge of all this, they just keep living.
After a while you understand
to
The woman with whom Bob lives together is
the main character in “those”
I was very touched by "they" because, as I told you before, that I
was very reminded
My own last time with my mom when she was sick.
I think there are many like ...
you said there are many who have
related just to this and heard of this
to you.
This that man
can
Although something so terribly is happening, one can anyway,
So there is still a weekday that is constantly going on.
Because
It can be so hard, and I think it is,
For the daughter and mother here,
in other words
It is not necessarily
better to talk about the great
The emotions.
So if you wish to come ...
They do this in a way
But not much.
I think it's too
her
Mom's way
to make it easier
for her daughter.
To not
Tell her about all the pain.
She wants to make her daughter smile.
So they smile a lot, they don't cry, they smile.
It makes everything easier and everything more difficult, too,
In a way, also for the daughter.
So often when readers come to me
and said they recognize the book
So it is very often that,
it is about.
If you feel that you should lose someone, you can feel a great closeness by talking about ...
There was someone who told me,
When my brother would die
was the only thing we talked about
Where did Mom bought her bread,
Which tree stood at our house?
The things that tied the two brothers together.
And no one else.
Because that story Vilgot loses when the mother disappears
It sounds like nothing
But that's how my books are
that you talk about a tree instead of talking about death
For both have a relationship with the tree
and there is a dear in that relationship
that makes it easier to talk
about everything else.
This mother is a very memorable figure.
You have said
somewhere that you have based her a lot on
your own mom and that your mom has been a very big
Source of inspiration for you at all.
But I didn't lose my mom when I was 16 like
The girl here.
I was 49
So it's something completely different
And I didn't know if I could allow myself to write a novel about a young girl who
Mister his mother when I didn't experience it myself.
But
It felt like losing one's mother
can make everyone feel like
16 years
No matter how old you are.
So it went.
And that is right that my mother has often been
a source of inspiration for me, in my books
Should I say anything about it?
I grew up in a small community, my mother was single as in "those", with my sister
My mother sold perfume on Rödby/Puttgarden ferry.
I worked with her.
As in the novel "Rödby/Puttgarden"
She had no real education.
My father was car mechanic
And my mother sold perfume, and they were divorced.
But there was a great interest in language and literature.
We read.
I have often thought that I am writing a kind of defense
For people that you do not imagine may be interested in literature and language.
But of course you can.
It is one side and the other side is that my mother was incredibly funny.
And above all self -irrelevant
And in front she had a bright mind.
And in front of full of joy
Even when something was really difficult.
I have often quoted her
In my books.
It was a great joy for her
when she was quoted.
Once it was a quote included in a review.
It was so amazing for her to
she walked around all of her village
And be proud of it.
Yes,
Maybe as a kind of painful ease, I think.
It is very nice to read a mother and daughter relationship that is
Very loving.
For whatever it is, there are often the bad parenting relationships
as described in fiction.
I have tried that but I can't.
I can't rewrite
People who are
evil or ...
It becomes one -dimensional for me.
It's like the books grow if they are full of friendly people.
This actually comes more pain ...
I can not...
There are, of course, bipers who are unsympathetic,
But not many.
No its true.
It's not very bad vibes in my books.
That's my driving force.
You are looking for what makes one write, which gives the right energy.
It is one of the things that gives me energy.
I experience it now because I write on a new novel,
to
each time
I try to create one
A little unfriendly
But then I get to write about
Because it will be wrong.
Maybe because I work with a form of recognition,
Maybe because no one wants to see himself as unsympathetic.
What made you want to pull the Bob story out of this one?
What was pocketing?
Why did you want to tell him about him?
How did the continuation come to?
It is not a continuation, they can be read very independently.
Yes you could say that.
I got the idea while writing "they".
When I was done with this one
I thought I was finished as a writer.
Because I wrote a book about everything that all my books are about.
I thought that
I will never come anywhere
So it struck me that I could write
A kind of continuation.
So something that just goes on.
Then I got started again.
And I wanted to let Bob become the main character
It was that with "the good helper"
I wanted to expand his character.
So it happened to
the young daughter from
"The",
After her mother dies,
Getting girlfriends
Bob
and moves home to his mother and father.
And lives there for three years.
That is also why, in "Bob", in the novel,
It's so hard for her to leave him.
Because his parents
is her family.
It felt I was good
to treat too.
Grief to lose both
The family and their hubby.
But you still had a ...
you let it still just glimpse in
"Bob" that it is related to this?
It is not an obvious continuation?
No, to me it was so obvious!
But I wanted it to stand on the back of "Bob", a continuation of "They",
But no one saw it.
And many read it without recognizing anything.
You can do that.
But
Maybe if there are several books in that series, they will be more closely related.
But it does nothing.
I think you might discourage some readers
If you tell the reader that it is a continuation
Then it gets so difficult!
What to start?
But here you can also read backwards.
You said that when you had written "they" you felt that you had reached some kind,
If I understood you right,
you had reached some kind of finish because you had
written a book about all that
You always write about.
Then I wonder,
What is it, in your opinion?
You rarely ask that.
I have a weakness
Do you understand that?
A weakness
for
teenage years or the young years.
I have had that
A weakness for.
And I still have that.
Because,
maybe because life was so far then,
and because one had not yet ended up in a track,
and to
It was so ...
null
So the kind
suddenness, suddenly one was sitting on a train
that drove to Germany and life got a new turn
And suddenly one is 40 and married
with the wrong person.
Because you went a road.
That openness
found in the young years,
but also
That
be in a standby mode,
one should lose what you come from,
One should find your own way,
its own form.
And it is also often one
impending break -ups of some kind that is just expected.
As
the death of the mother or
Bob and his girlfriend's separation.
You are constantly facing,
there is a break up somewhere there but one is in
Some kind
Limbo mode.
Before the breakup.
Yes exactly!
Yes maybe!
Why are you constantly returning to this limb?
What is it that is so ...?
It is very, very interesting
when people do nothing.
When the people are not
moves.
There is
readers, especially in Denmark
who say they get furious at especially my women
because,
also the men,
they want to give them a kick or a scolding and say, get an outbreak, move, make money
do something!
I write best about those who haven't done anything yet.
Thus those who are there
The road should be selected.
Maybe because it holds so much more
than to write about someone who just goes the right path.
The most exciting thing in life is when one
Don't know the road to go.
That is incredibly simple idea that for me
I feel completely lost,
Although I am a successful writer, so ponder
Me on how can I live about my life?
How can I get better
Or go another way?
Not away from the books, but only as a human being?
What do I do?
That's also how my characters are.
I also think sometimes
All the wait in my books
reflects my own writing process
Because I have so much wait when I write.
I am waiting...
There are so many distractions
and new ways to go
in the writing process.
It is important not to plan too much
And that directionlessness
Maybe reflect in the books.
We have to talk a little more about these female characters.
Now Bob is a bit like that
Figure too!
He is actually a man.
But they are often called for,
I scissors a few words from different reviews.
They are paralyzed,
evicted, jagged,
apathetic and passive.
But
Is they really?
Sometimes I feel that
They get a little unfairly convicted?
Yes, I think it's positively meant
but not necessarily correct.
There is something about this as well as the planless location,
that is all the time,
that you are constantly returning to.
But it is
Something incredibly fun about that too.
And a great driving force for me, in the novels.
Now it sounds boring and tragic but
I'm actually
Very interested in that it should also be fun,
in an absurdist way.
It is the absurd that interests me.
That someone should die but you talk about something else.
Often my characters do not say what they intend to say.
I was thinking of another thing,
In this novel, "they"
I thought
All dialogue should be completely meaningless.
And I have actually succeeded.
But no one realizes it one it makes sense.
It is many times completely pointless
because
We know what we are talking about, if we know each other well.
We don't have to bring the whole room
Because we are in the same room.
In the book you can say:
Do you want it?
No,
I got it yesterday.
No one understands what they are talking about
But that is because they are in the same place.
What is exciting about writing dialogue is that you can make it so alive
to get it to
sound like we talk.
And it really is quite often that it is completely meaningless.
This is the way they communicate.
There is a great benevolence
and an absolute lack of,
on communication indeed, in a way.
Another thing that you are also very, very busy with is details.
There is also a kind of meaninglessness there.
You can stay
you very much at
A broken saucepan handle or a dishcloth hanging in a certain way.
There are a lot of those here
The attributes around as
also very much used to
mediate...
History!
Yeah, it is clearly
How busy I am of details.
But I do not perceive it as details.
Many times when I sit in the mornings and will write, I think
What is going to happen now?
And the books should contain something.
So it becomes that I write very detailed.
Not because it's meaningless
For the details must have a meaning.
It is clearly evident in novels when the details
does not matter.
And they always have that.
That that dish cloth lies like that
means something.
You feel very clearly.
It is a kind of motor skills that moves the story forward.
In a slightly absurd way, I would say.
But imagine how busy you can be of details?
Absolutely!
Yes
They fill up so much
in a pain.
Yes.
And they say a lot
about one yourself
and about the others
and often about how one would like to be in relation to others
And another thing in my novels is that the characters are so busy by
How the other looks at them.
And they see the wrong
When they want to see the real
They have taken on the wrong shoes
others perceive them in the wrong way, there is a great longing for
to be a part of
society,
in an uncomplicated manner,
But it is constantly complicated.
Just that, simple!
Seemingly simple but difficult,
which we started with.
Can you sometimes,
your books the very ... you are very formally consistent in
in your story.
If one has followed your authorship for a long time
you notice it.
Can you sometimes get the desire to break off
Helle Helle-Maner and to do something completely different?
Each time!
Every time I think that now it is something else!
I don't want to write the same way.
It was a Danish
who interviewed me, as you do now,
a woman
Who told me;
You found your style very early,
What are you doing for
to keep it?
The answer is that I am struggling to get out of it.
It is not intended that the books should be the same book.
It should be something new every time.
Maybe that's why I would like to
Challenge the form
Because I can't get away from my own voice.
So it may be.
Can you feel the prisoner in your own like ...?
If I understand you right, it's so I remove a scene, because I think
That it likes me too much.
I don't want that again.
In the same way, for example, there are words ...
Each time I finished a novel I spend a lot of time editing,
In fact, that's what takes the longest time.
I always investigate if I have words I used words over and over again.
And so it is always.
So I use
a feature on my computer,
"Search and replace"
But without replacing.
I have a list of 1000 words
As I control how many times I have used.
I think i have only used them once
But then I have used them 20 times!
It can because there is something
That sounds like myself.
For example, a word such as "maneuver",
Is it called maneuver in Swedish?
It depends on whether it is a verb or noun?
I never remember what nouns are?
Excuse!
Yes, it is a noun.
Maybe I'll take a better example?
Yes, but there are some words, it can be a word that actually ...
I discovered when I wrote "Bob"
that I had used the word “half”
Far too many times.
Half,
as in a half apple or half a glass of water.
So
I looked through all
and many were,
At half past one
and at half past five,
And some were
twenty and a half years old, etc,
But other times it had become a mani
For example, I had written that
Bob did something
Half secret!
What is it called in Swedish when something is secret?
Secret!
Half secret!
He did half -secret!
Then I thought,
How half -secret?
Either it's secret or not!
So it was a mani for me and I have to remove that.
The kind of attempt to be funny.
But for us who read you there is a ...
It is not possible not to turn off ...
There is such a huge activity, creativity
Just in the way you can
Sneak in a tempus exchange or a pronoun exchange in meaning in a way
that should not be possible to do.
Yet you do.
It feels like it's a huge, huge activity going on there all the time.
Yes, but it is a form of association.
You can do everything in a novel.
It has taken me many years to understand.
One can blast scene after scene
And it doesn't have to be difficult.
There is also in your very associative prose, which is quite close to poetry sometimes, you
Have written poetry too, right?
Yes, but very little!
That was before I debuted
I could not control my poet self
I became very sentimental.
I am constantly struggling with, not to cross that limit
I would like to reach almost to that limit
But when did you feel in prose that it had
Found, maybe you still don't feel that you had found your voice?
Here's how I can tell you, this is how I want to tell you!
The latest novels are not minimalist
Because there is
A new kind of ...
There are some shorter episodes that are more poetic
that is highly associative
Yes
And it is so exciting because,
for example
Could it be a section in "Bob"
where I want to ...
It may be so calculating to write novels
That you have to introduce something for the reader to understand that ....
so should I have a sentence that is "it happened in December"
What is it called in Swedish?
It happened in December
But it
What should I place that sentence because the reader understands that it happened in December?
And so I can never find a place to put it in
For all the sentences are interconnected.
It's something I am struggling with and that's the kind of associative
prose
that makes one come from one sentence to another
with a particular logic
Therefore, one cannot distinguish those sentences, such as writing
"It happened in December" between two sentences, because then they break.
In that way
We will soon round our part of the call and let in, if anyone wants to ask any questions to Helle Helle.
I was just going to ask, what are you working on right now and is it something like ...
I can say that because I am in Sweden
Because it's secret but ... can I?
I work with that several people from “those”
gets their own voices
But still it is the same daughter who is the narrator
You're left in this one,
In this group?
I wish an extended “de”
So all the books are a kind of “they”
We look forward to this very much.
Thank you so much Helle Helle for talking to me.
Thanks for getting!
Thanks!