Hi, my name is Johan Espersson
And I have written the novel Kungsbacka Ultras.
And I read the introduction from it.
We would spend New Year in Paris
Unable to change
A compulsive action,
something one must fulfill
Even though we were no longer a couple
During the Christmas days we had borrowed your dad's house by the sea
While he was with his new fiancee in Roslagen
A gray palace overlooking Krokvik's boat docks,
the little bird island, and then the empty, vast, horizon
I stood out at the beach edge and filmed the sea with my iPhone
A documentary film about sand
The house was really far too big for a lonely man
Only here and there were possessions from his past life,
But without any order or system
The walls were bare
In the fridge stood a jar of salt cucumber that had gone out
before he had even moved in
A thick membrane of salt had settled over the panoramic windows
People wandered over the rocks without contours, without faces
We drank off your dad's spirits
When the gin first rose in the body we felt happy
See so gray the sea is
So gray and motionless
An endless smooth surface
One can miss it for dirty steel
When it subsided, we felt a great fatigue come
The empty twilight light
The next day took the flight from Landvetter to de Gaulle
It was a strange New Year
Everything was abandoned
We looked up at the sky but saw no fireworks
Two women showed up around one corner
And when they saw us they screamed and cheered
We screamed back
"Bonne Année"
It felt strange to celebrate the New Year
We knew it was going to take us apart
Make us to other people
Make us memories
We walked close to each other, as children do
We found a photo machine
We drank at a bar by a square
We went taxi
The whole trip I tagged on the driver
If bad it went for Paris Saint-Germain
In the beginning he laughed
But in the end he just stared in front of him
and said “peut —être”
We had sex in the hotel room
To take in felt strange
I saw a documentary about a French man
that went with dog sledding, or what is called,
From Russia to China
He traveled over huge white plains
We drank wheat beer out of can
We must have fallen asleep at last and when we woke up
showed the TV a talk show led by a child
We dressed up and went out in the cold
The business was closed
We had breakfast at a cafe where the waiter got angry
because we did not greet him when we entered
He spoke fast in French and it was hard to perceive everything
He asked if we had a good evening
And when I answered yes he said something about hospital
A man we had taken for an alkis
and that sat and drank beer yellow like juice,
somehow gloomy or pondering,
suddenly got life and began to hand out croissants to the guests
I thought about the women we met on the street,
How we went out on the street to check out
In the empty sky
We left the cafe
We went down Rue Lafayette
Some say it dangerous to fall in love when you are too young
Others say just the opposite
I don't know why love feels like such a wrong word
Before I met you, I was a child
A little kid just
We drank to keep warm
Wrapped in lethargy
A borderland between intoxication and ignition
We walked close to each other, shoulder toward shoulder,
But we had already begun the huge work to forget,
to erase,
to give way to the new one that would rush out of us
Yes, that was a difficult question.
I have said before that I wrote the book
in the explicit and the purpose of
Make Kungsbacka a mythological place.
But I mean that I want to make it a
Literary place in some way.
Then I mean people with upbringing in Kungsbacka
Always experienced when I lived there,
That culture was somewhere else.
That it was not in the municipality, so to speak,
in Kungsbacka municipality.
So this became a way to make it literary, kind of.
A great deal is autobiographical and
An yet crucial part of fiction.
It places itself somewhere in between,
As I think many books do.
But is like
Not completely loyal with any of the so to speak.
It is not entirely loyal with the autobiographical,
But it is not completely fictitious either
Without somewhere in between.
Yes, I have chosen the book's format,
It was not a rational choice really.
I got the most feeling in writing that way.
Maybe because I experienced that I
In it could catch a certain kind of perception
which is partly about the memory
and how memory loads different images
and that also has to do with
anything
Which is not completely arranged, so to speak.
It was a bit that kind of
World and language I want to work in.
Yeah, I may
mention two or three,
You have infinitely many sources of inspiration so clearly.
Many books man
Has brought into one's own literary work.
It has been
Perhaps most inspired by Tua Forsström
and her poetry book snow leopard
from late 80s or early 90's
and then well
the elevated factuality of her poetry as I
is very weak for
that has hit me very hard
As I myself have wanted
write through in some way.
Right at the beginning with Kungsbacka Ultras
so I read a damn against the Pacific Ocean
by Marguerite Duras
which was also such a tremendous experience
Which I think changed worked very much.
And it is well
Type not to weigh for the brutal.
To write very hard
And very violent
but still in it
sensual in any way.
So it was very inspired by Duras.
Another favorite author that I have
Is Roberto Bolaño
that has written some kind of directory text
Over different people
and things like that
And my book is also some kind of catalog of Kungsbacka.
The three I tried to bake into something "west coast".
Right now, Carina Rydberg is actually reading, in fact, reading Carina Rydberg
The highest throw.
It has started well, I have not come that far.
I'm reading it right now.
A book that I have recently read that I liked very much was
Manhattan by Zara Kjellner
Which was really a nice book that has come now in recent years.
The two I recommend.
For your own part, the literature is crap important
I don't know what I would have done otherwise.
I had well been
The material manager in any local football team type.
Yes, World Book Day,
I didn't really know it.
I think the culture has
Overall have a fairly marginalized status like that
anything that can highlight it is probably pretty good just because
I very much believe in art
and on literature as a very specific
artistic experience like that there
As one gets just through books and
that has a lot to give to people.