Hello,
My name is Lydia Sandgren.
I am a writer and have written a book called collected works,
Which came very recently, this is my first book.
And I'll read a small piece out of it.
This story is pretty much about young people trying to become adults.
And how they then become adults and try to deal with the life they get.
And get through it in different ways.
The paragraph I will read is about one of the main characters, Martin,
When he is young and has just taken the student.
And not really, he has a bit like that,
Big dreams that he will become a writer and so he is left alone in Gothenburg.
His best friend Gustav has stuck to France.
And he pulls around and has nothing to do for himself.
So I'll read a little distance away.
Then it turned out that the summer that was supposed to be the beginning of everything was mostly about waiting.
Martin was waiting for letters from France.
He waited for him to be able to cook.
He was waiting for the admission message from the university.
He was waiting for the post -terminals slavery to begin.
He was waiting for his salary.
He was waiting for the new issue of BLM.
He waited for it to be autumn, although it was too depressed to admit to himself.
He was waiting for inspiration.
He was waiting for the postman.
He waited, although he tried not to think about it, for the notice of pattern.
He was waiting for someone to call but didn't know who.
He probably would have been craving if it wasn't because he had given it to write a novel.
During high school things had always come in between.
After the student, he had thought.
Then it's time.
It would be easily autobiographical and sharp.
Shake the old one, wrap all the old cobwebs and crap.
He saw in front of him with a room with floor -to -ceiling and a desk under a large window.
On the desk there was a typewriter and piles of paper,
and reverse a spinning chair, in black polo shirt and
with growth hair and a cigarette glowing between point and middle finger
Sit Martin Berg.
He started with a story about a man and a woman
At a hotel in Pamplona, vaguely inspired by Wallace.
There was an atmosphere of imminent threats in the hotel room that is quite satisfied with,
But the dialogue became flabby,
Maybe because he didn't know what his protagonists were trying to say to each other.
Besides, he had never visited Pamplona;
He had not been further away than Denmark.
He had chosen the city because of its sound of sun -roasted streets, lethargic siesta hours,
bullfighting and vibrating evening under dusty dark blue skies,
and he never got rid of the thought
On what a person who had actually been in Pamplona would say about the text.
Then he was more satisfied with the novel Skansen Kronan at two.
It was more autobiographically held, based on an evening
When Martin was about to get it together with a girl just as her ex went on strike
Of some Örgryte guys with white jeans.
The girl had taken care of her former boyfriend, who seemed strangely satisfied
In spite of its vigorous nosebleeds,
and it all ended with Martin and Gustav sharing on a bottle of disgusting sherry
While they saw the sun rise from the hill where they sat.
In that short story he had
got to a kind of chaotic feeling that was quite successful,
And it had also been printed in the school newspaper.
But it was a short story,
And what was a short story other than a strength test for the inevitable novel.
He had not pondered any intrigue, because he thought it all
would resolve in the meantime.
And by the way, the intrigue was not the important thing.
The important thing was,
Yes, what was the important thing really?
What did William Wallace really write about?
Everything that happened in the stories did not seem very important.
That was not what they hung on.
He thought that the intrigue had to be arranged then and wrote what fell him in,
Which mostly consisted of escapades with Gustav during the fall and spring.
Martin had provided yourself with the cover name Johan but did not come up with anything that really suited Gustav,
So far he got hot G.
Johan and G drove around, went to a museum, ignored the student party and
instead climbed some height, where they sat in the grass
While the sun went down and had philosophical conversation about the meaning of life that extended over several pages.
The phone rang, with Martin just had to write a little more about how G snatched snuff on the attendance set
so that they had to
just run off hell
And how they had taken back on the slope below the Kungsladugårdsskolan,
And how Johan sniffs the first time.
Which was fun for five minutes
Before it took its end in a magnificent spya that got some aunts and glow in a general disapproval.
When he didn't know how to continue, he browsed any of Wallace novels
To see how he had done.
In Patagonia days there was a piece that gave him scams.
The book's main character, the young Bill, had just come to Paris.
He was as determined to succeed as he was hungry, alone and recently rejected.
Bill pulled around on the streets in what Wallace called "the ink malaria fever"
And longed for the desk in the hotel room as much as he feared it.
And this is how Martin reads then in
William Wallace Book.
"Given how demanding the author's profession is, it may seem strange that it exerts a
Such attraction to young souls.
No one, not even Bill Bradley,
could fully and firmly imagine ever -inspired at the desk,
pouring out of sources as never -sitting, possessed, feverish, driven forward by forces he did not understand
and could not control.
No, there was an ever -present doubt.
A balancing on the border of an abyss.
And some evenings they fell asleep at the strip of the depths,
And when you woke up, darkness was the first thing you saw, and you knew:
If I fall now there is no return.
If I fall now I am lost.
Few professions attract happiness seekers with such headings:
It is well gold digging and writing.
Yet they are looking for themselves.
They sit down at a table with paper and pen.
They are looking within themselves for the first sentence,
The spider -thin fishing line they are going to testify.
They understand how long it will take, what work is in front of them, but still they continue.
And why?
To write,
It is to conquer the world.
To make it his and herself to God.
In writing you get free access to all rooms, to hearts and souls, and the most sacred;
The unknown is laid for one's feet.
You get a chance at eternity.
To write is to refuse die. ”
Early when I started writing this, I was determined that it would take place Gothenburg.
A lot because I lived here,
but also because I felt that
There was also not really a good and great Gothenburg depiction.
A writer that I had read a lot of,
And likes a lot, is Hjalmar Söderberg.
And I, like got to know Stockholm,
via Hjalmar Söderberg's novels, so I
Felt someone missing that there was nothing similar with Gothenburg.
And for some reason, which I don't really understand myself completely,
So I had some kind of longing to explore a time that I myself did not know.
It was easier
and I felt freer when I wrote about
A city and time that was just outside my own experience.
I moved here, I was not raised in Gothenburg,
But I moved here when I was
Teen in the early 21st century.
I somehow wanted to rewrite the city that lay right away
in the corner of the eye or just outside the field of view in any way,
and felt freer with it -
To find out and tell you about something that I had not really experienced myself,
than when I tried to write about my own now and my own environments.
I could do that,
It became easier to do anyway,
now at the end,
When it has actually been almost ten years since the book's now.
It takes place in 2012, it is the "now" year, or the contemporary plane.
It was much easier to write now that I have worked with the text
At the latter part of the writing
for some reason
so it is a bit, when there is distance both to the place
And at the time it is easier to find I think.
My entrance to the psychology profession and my entrance to the literature
- both reading and writing - have been some kind
Knowledge hunger or willingness to understand me why people are as they are.
I am, like curious basically
who we are and how it becomes as it becomes and
what the human life,
What is the conditions we live under and so on.
I had some kind of humanistic entrance you can say
in both writing and in psychology activities.
So i who consider it as litigrana parallel tracks or
two different branches on the same tree perhaps,
which is in constant dialogue with each other.
I really believe that
reading and writing
Have enriched my clinical work.
That there is a communication
In that direction too.
But all I do -
both my work as a psychologist and my intellectual work -
to the extent that I am doing it - and my writing and the artistic
revolves around the same issues in any way
and to stand in dialogue with people, to communicate with people and that
put me connection with the outside world and other people
and to try to understand something about
how it is
to be that person
And myself too.
It's a little hard to say how I have,
If psychology activities have affected the writing, or if writing has affected
psychology business, without i feel that it somehow
expression for the same desire for knowledge
and willingness to understand and curiosity as I have
Went and been drawn since I was a child in principle.
One thing I have thought of is
something like Joseph Conrad
says or
writes somewhere that is to
The author owns only half the novel and the other half is the reader's.
I think
certain
Some types of books may be easier to as readers
Do something creative with yourself.
For my own part so one of the great
the large stock, and that which also makes reading
is something that I regarded as a lifeliness,
Both to recognize something in myself but also to discover something new.
To the novel
lies there and vibrates between
the unknown and the known between one's self
and the larger world
and that it is at the same time may be some kind of return
And thus also very comforting to read.
At the same time as there is also a kind of discovery journey into something new and unknown.
What it is that makes those as readers be able to get to that kind of creative process,
As you are, a kind of co -creation
Where you make your own book.
There are some works that have read about since the late teens,
Hjalmar Söderberg among other things,
And often I find myself returning to a whole new novel.
I naturally recognize the intrigue and story even though I have often forgotten
how it ends and so
But depending on where I found myself in life and what entrance I had in the reading
So I think I can discover something new there.
Maybe there is something that can happen with all books, I actually don't know but
I believe, I some kind of feeling that
this kind of novel that is quite
that depicts development not only
a fragmented state or
a subjective experience
Without a big life process is what it actually follows
from childhood and teens, development and adulthood
And to have children and to lose people and such.
We humans are always in some kind of development
I think it might be easier in some way hook in
himself not one of the story, in a such narrative
and if
I have succeded
Write something
Like a human being
can one use to make your own story
and do something creative with self
that may be something completely different from that as
I intended to lie there in
or as I myself have thought that I want to try to achieve
Then I'm happy.
If it can get
Brand new novels that arise
with each reading.
Well, that's probably what I might hope for most actually.
Now it is, like finished
now you are not mine anymore now it is after all
Out in the world
So now you have to do what you want with it.