Welcome to International Writers Stage Gothenburg! \ H My Name is Tone Schunnesson and I'm a Writer. \ H \ H
Today I'm HERE TO TALK TO "V", Formerly \ Heve Ensler, About Her New Book \ H \ H \ H \ H \ H \ H \ H \ H \ H \ H \ H \ H \ H
"The Apology" or "sorry" in swedish, \ hpubished at word front publisher.
Welcome V!
Thank you, I´m very happy to be here!
Thank you for being here.
You are Most Famously Known for the \ H IConic Play "The Vagina Monologues".
A Piece that \ h \ h
Explores Sexual Experiences, Body Image and Several \ H Other Topics Through the Eyes of Different Women. \ H \ H
It's Translated Into 48 Languages and Has \ H Been Performed In Over 140 Countries.
It's \ h \ h
Like a cultural fixture and a feministic and \ h Political Groundbreaking Piece of Writing. \ H \ H
The Play Laid Ground for Your Non-Profit V-Day \ H Movement.
The V-Day Movement Raises Money \ H \ h
and Educates People About Gendered Violence and \ H Makes an EFFORT TO STOP IT.
You raised over \ h \ h
100 million dollars.
Besides that you've \ h Written Several Other Plays, Books and Movies. \ H \ h
Among Others "I'm an Emotional Creature", "The Secret \ H Life of Girls Round the World", The Book Made \ H \ H
The New York Times Bestseller List.
You've Also \ H Written "The Good Body" Which Starts \ H \ h
With Your Own Tormented Relationship With Your \ H Aging Body And Then Introduces Us To Women Around \ H \ H \ H \ H \ H
The World Who Have Found Peace With Their Bodies. \ H 2013 You Wrote A Memoir "In The Body of the World" \ H \ H \ H \ h
Which Dealt with You Getting Cancer.
You Also \ H Made A Book Into a Theatrical Performance in 2018 \ H \ H
You Received Numerous Awards, Like A Million of \ H them!
Among Them A Tony Award in 2011. But Today \ H \ H
We are going to talk about "The Apology".
"Sorry" in swedish and the first of your books \ h \ h
Published in Swedish.
I HOPE It's Not The Last \ H SINE YOU HAVE SUCH A BIG AND EXCITING PRODUCTION. \ H \ H
"Forgive" is a very touching book.
It's an apology \ h from your Father, writen by you.
An apology from \ h \ h
Your Father's Point of View That You Waited \ H For Your Whole Life and Never Received.
An apology from your Father's Point of \ H View That You Waited For Your Whole Life \ H \ H
and never receives.
Your Father and Pergetrator \ H WHO Sexually and Physically Abused You Never \ H \ H
Owned up to his Wrongdoings.
When Writing the \ H Book He'd Been Dead 31 Years.
You decided \ h \ h
to give yourself what you needed.
Him Taking \ H Accountability for His Actions and Him Explaining \ H \ H
What led him to treat his oldest daughter this \ h way.
This Book is a Letter to Eve from Arthur.
I was deeply touched by your book "sorry" \ h and it resonated with me in more way than i \ h
would have imagined.
I was \ h so filled with strong emotions \ h \ h
When Reading, it was like \ h a physical experience reading it. \ h
SINCE THERE SO HARD TO READ ARTHUR \ H RECOUNTING THE EVENTS, I WAS FILLED WITH SADNESS, \ H \ H
Relief But Also Anger and Rage.
One thing \ h that Kept coming back to me was the extensive \ h \ h
Emotional Labor Behind Your Method.
To Bring \ H Back Your Father From The Dead and Evoking His \ H \ H
Voice couldn't have been easy.
Can you please \ h Tell me about the process behind this book \ h \ h
And how the book came to be?
Thank you so much \ hor that introduction and for the response to "the apology".
It's funny that you're saying \ hthat about the physicalness of your response, \ h \ h \ h
Because Writing This Book was so physical. \ H it was so physical in so many way.
I Never Had an Experience \ Hlike that, Writing Before.
I'VE WRITTEN A LOT OF \ H \ H
Books and a Lot of PlayS But it Felt As \ H I WENT INTO A Kind of Trance State. \ H \ H \ H \ H \ H \ H \ H \ H \ H \ H \ H \ H \ H
My Father, My Dead Father was very, very present \ h through the whole thing.
In Really Learned \ H \ h
a lot about the dead.
The Dead Are Always With Us. \ H they're Always Around us and often they Long to be \ h \ h
In Communication with Us to Help Them Understand \ H Where they are and to help them get free and other \ h \ h
Zones Where they live.
But the Experience of \ H Trying to Climb Into My Father, to Live Inside \ Hhim.
The Book is a Conjuring, \ hit's fiction.
I don't know if \ h \ h
A Lot of It's Even TRUE BECASE MY FATHER REALLY \ H NEVER TALKED AND HE NEVER TOLD ME About Himself. \ H
But it Feels Like It's TRUE BECAUSE HIS PARSENCE \ H AND BEING INSIDE HIM FELT SO REAL WHILE I \ H
Was Writing It.
It was excruciating, it was \ h liberating, it was terrifying, it was maddening. \ H \ h
In Had Moments Where I Was Literally Curled Up \ H IN A BALL, just just weeping.
But it was
Incredible Cathartic.
In Always Say, \ H there's a line at the end of the book \ h \ h
which I don't know if my father \ h say or in say because by the end of writering \ h \ h
The Book in Didn't Know Who Was Writing \ H It, But The Line Is "Old Man Be Gone" \ H \ H
When that line got said. It \ h really fault like my father just wet \ h \ h
Into the ethers, like he was gone and to be HONEST \ H HE HASNRY COME BACK.
He is gone from my \ h \ h
Life, Gone!
He's No Longer Possessing Me.
He's no \ h Longer Occupying me.
He's no longer determination \ h \ h
Me.
I'm No Longer His Consequence, which is one of \ h the reasons in Changed My Name.
I FELT LIKE \ H \ H
That name was part of that narrative and that \ h story and I'm now writing a new narrative.
\hrs
We're \ hgoing to talk about the ending of the book LATER \ H \ H
but I absolutely loved the last line of the book. \ h it was very freeing for me as a reader as well. \ h
I Thought a lot about that \ hwhen Reading your book because, \ h
For me as a writer, in Always Think that \ H Writing is a way to connect to the dead \ h \ h
and make the dead a part of the living and \ h so much of writter is trying to reach the dead. \ h \ h
Can you say something more about \ hhow the dead are living \ h \ h
With Alive People and What is Literature's \ H Role or Writing's Role In This Relationship? \ H \ h
I feel like our ancestors are all around us \ h all the time and it's a question of whether we \ h \ h
Tune into their presence.
But i think because \ h i was writing this book in my father's voice \ h \ h
I was calling him in.
I Needed Him To Talk \ H TO ME AND LITERALLY I WOULD BE ASLEEP \ H \ H
and he would wake me up at four in the morning.
I \ hwould wake up and he would say, go to your office, \ hi'm going to tell you a story!
So I would get \ hup in the Middle of Winter I'm Go To My Office and He Would Start To Talk To Me.
And I \ hstarted to Understand, \ hthere's a whole passage in the \ h book, like the dead are all around us.
And if we are willing to open ourselves to them and feel them and to list to them and be in dialogue with them
and embrace them, \ hthey will speak to us.
And they will let us know what they are feeling.
And they will also instruct \ house and direct us and help us.
I feel like they are here and I feel a lot \ h of people leave this world very incomplete.
They leave, my Father for Example Left Very \ H Arrogant, He Left Very Prideful, He Refused to \ H \ H
Look at any of the Things he had done Wrong. \ h so he literally had stuck for 31 years spinning \ h \ h
in this terrible, terrible limbo which was real \ h hea hava to deal with all the undealt things he \ h \ h
Hadn't Dealt With.
I Think by My Summoning Him \ H Here, In A Literary and Emotional Way Give
an Opportunity to Really Work Through What He \ H was going through, wherever he was.
It Certainly \ H \ H
Did it for me.
So that is my imagination. \ H i think the imagination often is so much more \ h \ h
truthful than reality.
In Always Think About Truth \ Hwhen Writing Fiction.
Even when writering fiction you know what the \ htruth is.
You can see what's truth and what's \ h \ h
Not the truth.
So that's interesting, the fantasy is like more connected to the truth.
In Also Thought About, When Reading, because, in was Angry.
I Thought About Two Different Kinds \ H of Anger.
Anger, as the feeling Consuming \ h \ h
The Narrator, Your Father, and Making Him \ H Like A Horrible Person, Impossible To Reach, \ H \ H
Impossible to Connect with.
Like indicates AS Lacking \ H Empathy.
But there is also ankher Kind of Anger \ H \ h
and that's Eve's indicates in the book, fueling \ Hher Survival
duck entering as a maker of boundaries. \ h there's a harrowing scene when she smiles at sky \ h \ h
When He's Been Beating Her.
It's so Angry, It's Full of Rage
But it makes her own.
So I'm curious, what are your thoughts \ h on indicates?
Is it destructive or is it helpful? \ H
It's such a brilliant way of \ h putting it.
Both Those Two Types of Anger ...
I think, as women, we are so often \ h taught we're not allyed to be angry. \ H \ h
Oh, you just anchor woman or \ h the b word, or you're all this.
Men are so trained to be allowed to have the one indicates \ h and also to learn how to direct their indicates \ h \ h
Into Achievement and Into all Kinds \ Hof Things.
For me,
I'Ve Always Been Very, Very Angry.
I'm just \ ha raging person and i think my rage \ h \ h
is what helped me survive.
If I Hadn't Had \ hthat Anger, if I hadn't had that defiance, if \ h \ h
I hadn't had that refusal in me, just the \ h furiousness at heaven, he would have wiped
Me Out.
He would have just run me over. \ H so i think indicates is very \ h \ h
Healthy.
It Fuels Revolutions, It Fuels Resistance, \ H It Fuels Risings and and People
speaking truth to power and refusing to be \ h upssed and refusing to be slaves and refusing \ h \ h \
to be undone.
There's Also A Point When \ H You Have To Start Looking at Your Anger
and there's a line in there where his mother \ h say to heaven, indicates is a poison you mix \ h \ h
for a friend and you drink yourf.There becomes \ h a point where that indicates becomes toxic to you. \ h
One of the reasons in wrote this \ h book, there are many reasons, but i heard myself one \ h \ h
Night just going on and on and on about my rage, about men.
In don't accept \ h \ h
Any Kind of Homogenized or Generalized Monolithic \ H Response to Any Group.
IF AnyBody Said, in Hate
A Group, I would stand up and say, how can you \ h possilly say that?
That's racist!
But Why was in Allowing Myself to feel perfectly entitled to go on about but? \ H
I realized that I did not want to be that person. \ H i Didn't Want to be that person who was going \ h \ h \ h
on about raging at but for my whole life.
That \ hwas one of the reasons in wrote this book.
To just \ h \ h
say, okay let's go in, let's see what what is \ h this controlling rage doing and is it serving my \ h \ h
Life Anymore?
Is it really moving me forward?
The Answer was it wasn't serving my life anymore. \ H \ h
It was keeping me attached to a notion of myself \ h as this perpetual victim.
Which I did not want to be \ h \ h
Anymore.
I was only in reaction to my father.
I was \ h Only in response to my father which meant I was \ h \ h
still in my father's story.
I was still within his \ hconstruct or his narrative.
I WANTED \ H \ H
To be in my own narrative.
That's The Big Wonder of This Book.
It's not an Angry Book.
It's a Book Filled With Understanding, \ HTRYING TO UNDERSTAND OR EVEN AN ACT OF \ H \ H
Compassion.
That is what husbands \ H this book so curious in a way.
Another thing that was so interesting \ h with your Father or the Voice of Your Father \ H \ h
In the book, in your wring, is heaven trying to \ h explain how he became such a violent person.
Early on he talks about how he as a teenager Went to \ h the movies and discovered the american movie star. \ H \ h
And charm.
He decides to become a charming man. \ H to use this charm as a shelter from \ h \ h
The Violence He Heavenly is Experiencing at Home.
And \ h After this he becomes almost this image of a man, \ h \ h
Instead of a real man.
I was so \ h intrigued about this picture, this image.
How is that related to lying versus Telling \ h the truth?
And also this obsession \ h \ h
With the image or the picture in western culture \ h or american culture?
Could Say Something \ H \ h
About that?
From My Father's \ Hearly Years, My Father Was Obsessively Adored.
I Think Adoration of Boys, Adoration \ H of Anyone, is a Devastating and Destructive Thing \ H \ h
because it does not allow them to be a human being. \ h it forces them to be ...
Why is that?
When you're adored for this \ hidealized image of yourself, so you have to always be performative.
You can be doubtful, you \ hcan't cry, you can express weakness.
It's Also Very Lonely When \ H You're adored because you're this perfect person. \ H \ h
And in my father's case no one was good \ h enough to be your friend because you are so perfect.
And I think it made my Father really anxious and \ h Crazy Early on.
And i think he was abused by \ h \ h
His Brother.
So when he found moviestars and images of
Valentino and Cary Grant and All These \ H People in the Movies, He suddenly had this \ h \ h
veneer.
He had this image of himself that he could \ H Portray and Bring Into the World.
But it didn't \ h \ h
Take Care of All The Feelings That Were Underneath It, Which Rage And Which Were Self-Hatred and \ H \ h
Which Never Feeling Loved for \ H WHO HE WAS BUT For this idealized Ida that his \ h \ h
Parents Had of Him.
Nothing Having to do \ h with who he real was.
America \ h \ h
is this place that creates these images.
Then it exports these images, Both \ h \ h
Internally all through the country and into the \ h world of this kind of fantasy idea of ourselves.
RIGHT NOW THERE'S THIS NEW \ H THING GOING ON IN MOVIES HERE WHICE
Feels like wealth porn.
All the movies \ h are filled with these unbelievable clothes and \ h \ h
Unbelievable Houses of the Wealthy.
All These \ H TV Series Are Just Exporting This Notion of \ H \ H
of the rich and what it's like to be rich.
So everybody starts Comparing Themselves to That \ H \ H
and starts look at their own shabby house and \ h feeling like, oh my good, look where in live, it's so \ h \ h
Pathetic!
And it Feels Dimined and Feels \ H Like they are less than, it feel like they are not \ h \ h
Enough.
This is what this country \ h is known for, the manufacturing of fantasy.
We elected this crazy predator in chief. \ H who was the king of that.
He was a \ h \ h
Television show, he was a hologram.
That was the ultimate in an American Kind of \ H \ h
Projection.
SO MY FATHER WAS CHARMING AND HE WAS HANDSOME.
Everybody Wanted to Look Like Him and \ H Be Like Him and He was a Bastard and He was horrible. \ H \ h
This is so true of so many.
Whether You Look Through All Of What Happened In The \ H \ H
Recent Metoo Exposure in Hollywood, if you look \ h at all of these people who are so called charming \ h \ h
and Delightful.
I 'Been \ H Reading Hannah Arendt Lately Because She's One \ H \ H
of my favorite writers.
She Always Talks About \ H The Fact That The Evil Don't Look \ H \ H
Like Evil.
The Evil Looked Banal, The Evil Looked Regular, The Evil Looked Charming, The Evil Looked \ H \ H
Like just like everybody else.
And i think \ h this notion of charm is something that \ h \ h
is very confusing and distorting and crispling. \ h it took me years to be able to really say, \ h \ h
This man who appears to be charming to all of \ h you, is destroying my life.
Even in Couldn't Believe that this person who was \ h so charming would be doing this to me.
Culturally we also have Great Faith in the Charm or in the Picture of Charm.
It's a Spell, Charm Really Means a Spell.
People \ H Put a Spell On You Through Their Charm.
That's very interesting.
There's a \ h Beautiful scene in the book \ h \ h
Where Eve's Father Has Been Dead For A Couple \ H of Days And He See's Eve Sitting in His Closet \ H \ H \
With her face buried in his shirt.
He's \ H Reading This As A Sign of Eve's Willingness or \ H \ H
Her Efforts to Remember some form of Tenderness \ H Between them.
This Made Me Think of Making \ H \ H
Room for Grief When Grief is Not Easy.
How do \ h we grieve the people we hate or have hated \ h?
It's such a good question.
It took me so long to grieve my father. \ Hone, because my father was so ungenerous.
When you have a memorial or a funreral, it's an act of generosity. \ H \ h
You're Allowing the People Who Loved You To Have \ H A Way To Process The Loss of You.
My Father Didn't \ H \ H
Believe in any of that.
So there was no funeral, there was no memorial.
There was no way to grieve \ h \ h
for my father.
He found them petty and he found them loathsome. \ H \ h
Like things that human beings would \ h do.
SO After My Father \ H \ h
HAD DIED AND I WAS AT MY PARENTS HOUSE, I did not have any way to to experience \ h \ h
The Disappearance of My Father.
The Evaporation \ H of My Father.
He was here and he was gone.
But \ h \ h
There was nothing, there was no ritual, there was \ h no process to integrate that into myself.
\ h \ h
So I just Went Into His Closet And I Remember \ H Ha Had This Yellow Cashmere Sweater That \ H \ H
He was all the time.
I just took it down \ h and i Sat in His Closet and I just smelled it.
As a way of at least have the memory of heaven and \ h the loss of heaven all at the same time.
To be HONEST WITH YOU, MY FATHER DIED 31 \ H YEARS AGO.
It wasnnt until in wrote this \ h \ h
Book That in Truly Grieved My Father.
Grieved who he was in life and \ h \ h
grieved the loss of heaven.
Because I was too angry at that time, I was too angry. \ H \ h
I'm happy he's dead.
I was just brusque and I was glib.
In Hadn't Seen My Father in Years.
He'd been \ h horrible but there \ h \ h
Were Layers and Layers of Feelings under There \ H Where I Had Once Loved My Father Deeply.
I was \ h \ h
Once Very Attached to My Father and Through the Writing of This Book \ H \ H
I finally undangled Those Feelings.
I just Dismantled them so that in could go on \ h \ h
Clean.
There's a change in \ hhow he sees what he's done, through the book, in the beginning he tries \ hto give eve as a five-year-wold some kind of agency. \ H \ h
Almost Claiming That She's Been Flirting with \ H Him as a Five-years, and this just made me \ h \ h
Boil!
In Almost Couldn't Read It.
It was so Painful to Read.
But then he \ h \ h
Starts to abandon this idea of Eve's agency and he \ h starts to recognize the truth.
That Eve's Agency \ H \ h
was a lie.
This is When the Pain \ H Starts to Affect Him or the Consequences of What \ H \ h
He did to you starts to affect him.
For me this was a Victory Functioning as an Image in My \ H \ h
Own Life.
There is this small possibility that \ h a perpetrator would admit his wrongdoing \ h.
It was also bitterweet, because as you also \ h Talked About, it made me realize how the apology \ h \ h
is missing in the patriarchal \ h Society.
During and after
metoo there was this big
VOID OPENING BETWEEN ALL OF US.
Countless \ H Women Came Out and Told)
and shared their trauma publicly, which is very \ h hard, with hope that something would change. \ h \ h
For me it was never about cancelling but \ h out, it was about trying to start a conversation. \ H
But now there's like this open wound.
All of \ h us still waiting.
What are your
Thoughts on this?
Why Can't Toxic \ H Masculinity Hold Space For The Apology? \ H
It's SUCH A GOOD QUESTION!
SINCE I'VE WRITTEN THE BOOK, \ H
It's Been Amazing, Because I Am Surprised \ H TO SEE HOW MEN have responded to the book. \ h \ h
A lot of but have had me on shows. \ H i've Received Lots of Letters From Men \ H \ H \ H \ H \ H \ H \ H \ H \ H \ H \ H \ H
WHO HAVE WRITTEN ME APologies.
They have written \ h to their perpetrators, I mean to their victims \ h \ h
which has been really moving.
But what i want \ h to say is that, except for maybe one exam of \ h \ h
A Couple On Ted, I have never heard a man make a \ h public apology in a true way for sexual violence.
Nobody Has in the History of Humankind.
I'Ve Gone Back, Back, Back Centuries.
Never. \ H \ h
What I Discovered Writing This Book is \ H THAT IS ACTUALLY A COLUM THAT HOLDS UP \ H \ H \ H
Patriarchy, The Non-Apology.
As long as \ h but refused, and I'm not going to say but, \ h \ h
As Long as perpetrators, because there are \ h Women perpetrators too.
As long as perpetrator, \ h \ h
But I'm going to say again, that one out of three \ h Women on the planet will be beat or raped.
And \ h \ h
That is by men, so that's a lot of but.
As long \ h as but refuse to apologize \ h \ h
Patriarchy Stays in Place.
Because \ h Once One Man Begins To Say He's Sorry \ H \ H
and he knows it was wrong, then all the but have to \ h begin to say they know what they're \ h \ h
Doing is Wrong.
And one once that begins to \ h Happen This Methodology, which is violence, which \ h \ h
is the thing that keeps patriarchy in its place \ h will begin to collapse.
So in belief it's \ h \ h
Truly Significant, The Apology.
It's a core \ h to dismantling patriarchy, it's at the core. \ H \ h
Because you have to make yourself vulnerab.
You \ h have to say you were Wrong.
You have to acknowledge. \ H \ h
First of all, What Went Into Making You?
What \ h are the patriarchal ingredients that allowed \ h \ h
You and Pushed You To Become a \ H Man Capable of Rape, Capable of Violence? \ H \ h
THEN YOU HAVE TO FEEL WHAT YOUR VICTIM FELT, \ H ACTUALLY Climb Inside Her and See The Impact of \ H \ H \ h
What you did to her.
You have to look at the actual \ h Things that you did to her.
What exactly did you do? \ H \ h
And then you have to take responsibility \ h for that.
All of Those Things Work Against \ H \ h
Everything that patriarchy is.
It keeps \ h its distance so it can mainain its power. \ H \ h
It's Always About The Father Is Right No \ H Matter What.
It's Always Insisting \ H \ H
On Domination Rather Than Cooperation and Dialogue. \ H SO I BELIEVE THAT AT THE CORE, IF WE REALLY WANT \ H \ H \ H
To Dismantle Patriarchy, we have to start \ h to have apologies and repair, processes, groups \ h \ h
everywhere in the world.
It has to be begin \ h to happen.
And I think there are more but willing \ h \ h
To Undergo that process than we think, having see \ h letters that are starting to come in from the book. \ h \ h
I SAW YOUR TED \ HTALK AND I REALLY LIKED YOU \ H \ H
Talking about calling but in after calling them \ h out.
That takes some effort to be \ h \ h
Willing and Able and have the courage to do so.
Can you just explain what calling but in is? \ H
My Friend Tony Porter, Who Runs This Organization, \ H Called A Man and He was the one who \ h \ h
Actually coined that phrase.
He was like saying, \ h and i just loved it because i feel like, okay \ h \ h
We have now exposed, not just with metoo, i've been working 23 years \ h
In a Movement Called V-Day where what \ h have we been doing but calling out but!
Calling out \ h \ h
stories, tell our stories, breaking the silence. \ h breaking the silence breaking the silence telling \ h \ h
The stories.
We've done that.
The Next Stage of This \ H Movement Has To Be That Men Begin To Talk About \ H \ H
What they've done.
Literally why they've done it. \ H what's in their history, what it feel like and \ h \ h
What they are going to do to change.
Otherwise We're \ H GOING TO BE STUCK HERE FOREVER.
One of the amazing things about the ending \ h Violence Against All Women Movement \ H \ h
is that women took this on.
This Actually Isn't \ h our Movement.
It should be a men's movement. \ H \ h
It should be but saying, we are going to stand \ h up and we are going to fight to end violence \ h \ h
Against Our Mothers and Our Sisters and Our Wives \ H and Our Girlfriends and our best Friends and our \ h \ h
Aunts and our grandmothers.
We Care That \ H Women are Being Violated, It Disturbs Us as much \ h \ h
as it disturben them.
And there's something holding \ h that back from Happening Called Patriarchy. \ H \ h
Because as my friend Tony Porter Also Says, there's something called the man box and every \ h \ h
Man is born into that box.
And when you step out of \ h that box you risk other but judging you.
Other but \ h \ h
Exiling you, not being a part of the group.
All \ h i can say is those of us who were feminists at the \ h \ h
Beginning Back Then when It was not popular, when \ h people called you names and threw \ h \ h
Things at you and made fun of you, we took the risk \ h of standing up so that women could be liberated.
Men Need to Take Those Same Risks Now So That \ H Men and Women Can Be Liberated From This Horrible \ H \ h
tyranny of patriarchy which is destroying so many \ h lives and morphs into fascism everywhere you look. \ h \ h
It's the Seeds of Fascism.
I love that \ hyou're saying liberation because
Again in the book, your Father Gets in \ H A Way Liberated When He Admits to the \ H \ h
Consequences of His Crimes.
And the lacquer of \ h Accountability is keeping sky in limbo. \ H \ h
And when he starts writter he's been \ h there 31 years and when he finally admits to what \ h \ h
He has done, he is transformed \ h to something else.
This was so beautiful to read.
I was so touched \ h by it because he's actually transformed into eve \ h \ h
in a way.
It's Absolutely Beautiful Scene \ H THAT ACHED IN MY BODY AS I WAS READING IT.
Can You Please Speak About This Image And \ H How the Sincere Apology Changes Not Only The One \ H \ H
Receiving it but the one giving it?
I don't \ hthink there's anything more transformative than owning your misdeeds truly.
And really going \ hthrough that four-step process that in just quickly \ h \ h
Outlined.
There's No One \ H Who's Done Something Terrible to Somebody Else \ H \ H
Who isn the Direct Result of it.
Their lives \ h have been changed by, it their character has \ h \ h
Been Changed by it, their emotions, their Spirit, \ H their soul has been Changed by it.
You don't get \ h \ h
Away with it.
When you begin to take \ h Responsibility for it, when you begin to process \ h \ h
It, when you begin to own it, when you begin to \ h really let the person who you've harged know \ h \ h
That you feel what they feel something amazing \ h begins to release inside you.
You get to be free, \ h \ h
You get to be reconnected to the world, \ hyou get to come out of, you see it all the time where somebody does \ hsomeThing really horrible to somebody \ h \ h
and then they go on a path in their lives where \ h they start to do more and more horrible things \ h \ h
because they're so possessed, they are so so \ h occupied by the darkness or by the guilt \ h \ h
or by the plague of what they've done.
Apologies are just these amazing roots to freedom. \ H \ h
They give us the possibility of transformation. \ H i don't belief in prisons, in
Believe in transformation.
In Believe We \ H All Are Part of an Evolving Kind of Human Story. \ H \ H
We've all been brought up in racist, sexist classist patriarchy so we're all contaminated and \ h \ h
We many of us do terrible things.
It just happens. \ H How are We Going to Create A World Where People \ H \ H
can do bad things and then change and become \ H OTHER KIND OF PEOPLE?
That's what's most \ h \ h
Interesting to me.
I don't want to hold anybody \ h fixed as one permanent mistake for the rest of \ h \ h
their life or one permanent bath thing.
I'm not \ h Into vengeance.
In Think Punishment is Foolish, \ H \ h
I think all it does is create more bad things. \ H so what are the mechanisms we're going to create \ h \ h
That Allow People to Become Other Kinds of People? \ H ALSO SO MUCH OF WHAT HAPPENS TO PEOPLE THAT \ H \ h
Brings Them to Prison Is Class Situations, Is Not \ H Hajing Money, Is Being Abused Themselves, Is Being \ H \ H
abused by racism, so how are we going to \ h cure Those Things and heal Those Things so \ h \ h
That People Aren't Forced to Do Bad Things?
Once You Begin The Apology Process and You Look at \ H \ h
What Brought you to do that things then you have \ h to address three things so we stop doing them.
As a Last Question I Just Want to Talk \ H About Your Dedication In The Book To \ H \ H
All the Women Still Waiting for an Apology.
If we are not talking about the power in \ h \ h
Giving the Apology, I WANT TO TALK \ H About Power in Receiving an Apology. \ H
What is the power in \ h receive an apology and how did it change you? \ H
What I can say this, I Couldn't Get \ H My Apology From My Father Because He's Dead. \ H
So I Wanted to See IF By Writing His Apology, It \ h would help me.
And maybe by doing that i \ h \ h
Could Create A Path Which Might Help Other Women. \ H and the truth of the matter is, if you sit down and \ h \ h
You Climb Into Your Pergetrator and You Write A \ H LETTER FROM HIM TO YOURSELF, WETHER IT BE A WOMAN, \ H \ H
Man, whover that is.
And you really, really do it.
And then you sit with somebody who will help you \ h \ h
With it, because you shouldn't do it Alone.
Because \ h it's very, very hard emotionally - you can get free! \ H \ h
It is possible.
Lt is possible.
That's \ H NOT TO SAY I WANTED TO TAKE PEOPLE OFF THE HOOK \ H \ H
of their responsibility, but there are cases where \ h you can get an apology from some.
Eiter you \ h \ h
Don't know where they are or whther they're dead \ h or you're too scared of them.
This Exercise \ H \ h
is a very, very powerful Exercise.
I've been hearing from different people, \ h \ h
which is also very moving to me, that they're \ h using the book now with people who are coming \ h \ h
Out of Prison to Help Them Begin to Write their \ H Apologies.
And they're using them in women's groups \ h \ h
LIKE TO OUR OUR CITY OF JOY WHICE IS A SANCTUARY \ H FOR RECOVERING Women in the Congo and a \ h \ h
Revolutionary Center.
They're actually doing this \ h Exercise as part of the program WHERE WOMEN WRITE \ H \ H \ H
Apology Letters to themselves.
It's Been Highly \ H Successful In Women Release A Lot of the Toxins \ H \ H
and rage and that feeling of being occupied by \ h their perpetrator.
Thank you so much V.
Thank You So Much, Such Wonderful Questions, Loved Talking \ H TO YOU!
I Loved Your Book and I Could´ve Been Talking About It For Another Hour.
Thank you \ h so much for all your hard work, it's appreciated around the world.
And Thank you \ hor coming to gothenburg writers Stage!
I love to be in Sweden and my love to all the \ h swedish people, I'm happy to be here.
Thank you!