It's nice to be here and see such a crowded hall.
I am also very happy to sit here with pink, we are not seen too often.
The last time we would see it was nothing because you were sick.
We will talk about
The "river" today or "Väylä" as it is called in original.
We should also talk about other things and I thought we will start
from the beginning because
You have just come from Tornedalen!
I was up there in
Tornedalen
Where I was born.
I have a small cottage there.
It's mine
Grandma's old cabin
Which I bought 5 years ago.
I usually stay there around the year
I have ...
a part of me
Have moved back to my roots.
I was away for 35 years
Now it's a new situation
and i went skiing
10 days and there were
One meter of snow.
Completely white nice snow.
When I left my cabin
It was 28 degrees cold.
It was pretty cold.
The sun was shining.
It was like a postcard,
The whole landscape.
It is the landscape that
Also available in this book.
The river
If we go even further back in time, you have written 20 books.
You debuted in 1985
But as I said, you come from Tornedalen and just from the landscape that you have just described to us.
Then I wonder about
Your background?
How did you come from Tornedalen?
Suddenly
you among Finland's foremost writers
And artists.
It is a fairly long development and long way.
It is a very long way.
And there is a lot of work.
It is.
Namely
the books or book like this one, the "river"
and the “overstinner and“ coupe No. 6 ”
They demand
Many years of work.
When I started,
It was so that I wished I
would become a teacher in Russian.
It was my biggest dream.
But
Life doesn't go that often
that way
You think.
There are different roads.
So I became anthropologist
I studied
At the University of Helsinki, I have also studied at Uppsala University,
Russian language.
But it was only for three months
Before I was told I got a
Student place at the University of Helsinki.
So I left Uppsala
and moved to Helsinki.
I know Sweden quite well because
I was born at the border with Sweden,
Up there in Norrbotten.
My relatives live there on
Swedish side.
When I was young,
or children, so we have all the time as well as
Visited my relatives on the Swedish side.
And we talk meänkieli,
So it goes like this.
But
How I became
writer and artist it is
very difficult to say
Why it was so.
I wrote my first three books
in Denmark.
I lived
in Christiania
in Copenhagen
and worked
In the purchasing center four
hours a day
And i had plenty of time
And I couldn't speak Danish during the first year.
I spoke like Swedish that I talk now.
But the Danes don't like it.
I learned
That the Danes hate Swedes.
So I had a lot of time and I started writing there.
Maybe it was to
I was also a languageless person
And so I had to need to
Express myself.
So I started writing ...
or first I started
Draw series,
Series.
It was the first one,
and then it became like
Stories and paintings.
I made a book of serial pictures in Denmark.
Then I started writing
Short stories
And paint paintings.
And I have now done in
45 years.
I do it every day,
almost every day.
So I like
Learn me all the time my work again.
As well as,
Practice, I do exercises all the time.
Now my books are
very
finely translated into different languages in Europe
And other places too.
But it has not come from heaven, it is work.
Yes, it's a lot of work!
A small question now about this with background.
What did you read as a child yourself?
And what did you have for
storytelling traditions in your home?
There were 2 books in my home.
It was the Bible, as I never read
And then it was another book
As I never read.
So I started reading when I was
35 years old.
Fiction, novels
I just read
Research books ...
... fiction only.
Also at university.
So I wasn't
at all interested in fiction,
novels or
novellas,
Not at all!
But
In my home and in my hometown
is it a very strong
Story tradition.
That is
People love
to tell stories.
And many stories
If people who have lived there once,
in history,
in that rural village and what had happened during
that time.
I have grown up with an oral storytelling tradition.
It is the same as reading books and
The storytelling tradition was so strong,
I have listened to,
All year round, on different stories.
In my hometown was there,
the neighbour
was a man named Veine
He is dead
But he was so amazing
narrator
of the story of the village and all people so
I loved that
Listen to him,
for example.
And my mother was also a lot of one
very good storytelling and
Many, many neighbors.
Such absolutely incredible storytellers!
That's my background.
When I start writing on meänkieli
or Tornedals dialect,
On the Finnish side, we call it Tornedals dialect.
And then on the Swedish side with Meänkieli,
Although it is like the same language.
When I start writing on meänkieli
so it came like fluent
from my body.
For that is what I have
grown up with.
I was 15 years old when I moved from that countryside
Because
I wanted to study
It was 70s
and the first idea
was to study.
To go to university and study.
Almost all children in that village had that idea.
That we want to study and we want to go out of this village, we want to live in Storbyar.
And I did.
I moved to Helsinki
and then to Moscow
and then to Christiania and then to
Texas in the United States.
It is incredible, this longing away from the village and about studying.
I think about this with the story because it is something that is characteristic of what you write,
For what you write, ie the narrator.
How it
lives in the text
We'll get to it soon, to the river.
I just have to
Ask from time to time.
Where does the interest in the Russian come from?
Yes, it is very interesting!
That's a big question.
Namely,
Because I was born on the Swedish side
So Sweden was always the best friend.
We thought in my hometown, all people thought that Sweden
is our best friend.
It was so.
Russia was away, gone, gone.
People who live there on the Swedish side do not like the Russians
Or Russia.
That's all for
different ways of life there and the language is so strange with different letters and
a cruel story that we have had
With the Russians.
We have also had a very hard
History with Sweden.
But we think the Swedes are our friends.
But the Russians are not.
We were part of Sweden for 600 years,
600-800 years part of Sweden,
And only 100 years part of Russia.
But we have had
two big wars with the Russians
not too long ago.
My interest in Russia was namely
that when I moved to Rovaniemi
To go to high school,
and Rovaniemi was the largest
The city in Lapland
There lived
30,000 people.
But I thought it's a big city and I wanted to study there
I moved there and I was very pleased to live in a big city
because
In my hometown there were only eight houses.
But in each house more than 10 children.
Laestadians live there.
Rovaniemi was Storbyn
But it was the 70s and one did
at that time
Vodka travel.
Vodka - slug, glow, glow
Travel to Russia
And the trips went to Murmansk
For that murmansk was the largest
the nearest big village
To Rovaniemi.
One day
did i go to the bus
and traveled to Murmansk.
Murmansk is there
on the bank of the ice sea
And when I saw the town
Was I so surprised
because
At that time it lived
Half a million people there.
There all kinds of
Restaurants.
Food from XXX, from Uzbekistan, Kazakhstan various restaurants.
I had always eaten such food.
And I was so inspired by all of these
restaurants and food and then these strange letters.
Also by people for
They were very young.
The average age of Murmansk was 25 years old,
I was 15 years old, so 10 years older than me.
I went to the disco that was full of young people.
So I started
take
Once a month the bus,
Travel to Murmansk.
And like Baila there,
party there, dance there
Yes, eat such ...
incredible,
Incredible flavors
So I became like
In love with Russia.
I have to say that.
Then I started studying the Russian language as a voluntary subject in high school.
And I have continued to study Russian
to this day.
Once in
week
We are like 10 people, we meet and talk Russian.
We have a teacher who
Leads and teaches, it's like a discussion group.
So we discuss in Russian.
It is fantastic.
So Russia
came to be a part of my life and that is all the time
Today the same.
For what I have friends living in Russia
and I love
The Russian culture.
I have to say that.
And I love Russian people
because
they are
close
Finns.
They are a lot
Direct people
And very full of
feelings
as they show.
And to Finlanders it is like
We are not
such people who want to show
Our feelings.
But we
understands the Russians
Feelings very well.
So it's like
Such a strange situation.
And that is what is interesting.
I think it's amazing that you keep up this Russian group
under the prevailing circumstances.
There are lots of ingredients in your artistry, in your authorship.
And I will think of Tove Jansson who also made picture and text at the same time, you are both bondy
In your art.
Now we have to go to the "river" finally!
There is so much you would like to do here but the "river" ...
Actually, it is best if you describe it yourself.
What is the story?
Where does it come from?
I think that here can be people who have read the "colonel"?
Yes, some
When I wrote the "Colonel"
I noticed
that in that novel
I couldn't
begin to describe the Lapland War
because it gets too much
In a book.
When the "Upper" was finished
had that feeling
that I wanted to write
About the Lapland War.
But I had
Like not found
the main character.
But when I sat in my cabin
in Tornedalen
I got a visit
by my dear friend.
He is 90 years old or 91
or 92 years old
And he is man to my mother's sister
I have known him
all my life.
He got there and he started telling
About that
The trip to Sweden.
What it was like to be
War refugee
You know that when
people get older, not all but many,
that have good memory,
They also start telling about their childhood more than ever.
Each time Pauli came to my cabin
To drink coffee or when I went to visit
with him,
he began to tell his story.
And it was so strong and strong.
I had heard many parts of his story
But not the whole.
It was so strong.
Every time he started telling it
he began to cry.
When I listened to him
I noticed that it is
He who is the main character.
He was
11 years old
when he
went to war refugee camp in Sweden
null
when the Lapland War
Started.
All civilian people, children,
Older people and women and cows
Moved
to Sweden,
for that became war between Finland and
Germany.
CHOR !!
Muu!
It was intended that when the war began, the civilian population was evacuated.
And Pauli could
remember
Details from that trip.
And he told me, he is a very, very nice storyteller.
He as well as became the main character in the book
But I made it
to
A girl.
Because my mother was there too
But my mother is dead.
But she also told us a lot about that trip when she was alive.
So i wanted
A girl
Like my mother as the main character.
In the book is Matti
also
with on the whole trip,
So it's like Pauli.
The model is Pauli
It is the girl who tells, the girl who is the main character.
You could say that this is also a hiking story or a hiking novel for it ...
How many thousands were there?
There were 60,000 people
which was brought from Finland over the Torne River
to Sweden.
There was no bridge
There was only the ferry.
A home -built ferry.
During the war, winter war and World War II
took people to Sweden with
rowing boat.
But one could not
Shipping cows with rowing boat.
So one had to build such
Terrible ferries.
The Torne River is large
The water rushes very fast
so it is very dangerous to cross the river
with such a ferry and with many cows
fell off and drowned.
Nearly 30,000 cows
was brought to Sweden.
30,000 cows,
think about it,
over the river.
It was a hell of a job and it was terrible
because the cows were so scared
to go on the ferry.
But then it was and
They also came back after the war.
So it was.
And they also sat in camps in their own way, everyone.
Yes, it was KO camp, that's absolutely true!
There were many, many cow camps and young women or not women,
Young girls
took care of the cows.
At that time it was so.
The mothers had so many children
that they had to be with the children
in another camp.
So the girls, like,
12 years old
to 15 years old,
Also boys,
they took care of the cows
or milked them.
There were many cow camps,
An estimated 200 cows in a camp.
All that situation
When the Lapland War began,
It was chaos.
Finnish government
asked
Sweden's government
- can you receive
Finnish refugees?
And the government said no,
We have so many refugees here, we have
100,000 from Denmark
and 100,000 from Norway.
And now you ask if we can take
60,000
Finnish refugees
To Lapland?
It is far too much said, the government.
But the king, at that time he had power,
The king said, we take them.
And so it became.
So the king drove over the government and said,
No, we take them.
But the problem was that there was
So little time to build these camps.
Because of that was
All these barracks were old
Summer barracks from
Swedish Army.
But it was a much cold winter
And people lived
In these summer barracks.
And they were packed
with people,
So there was no place, they were packed like sardines.
You can remember, after all, that,
As you said, it was women, children
and elderly.
Because the men in warriors
Be out in the war.
So it was
The weaker part that took care of this and were these refugees.
It has not really been told so much about this in public.
What do you think it is because it has been so quiet?
For me it was one
News with these
The camps in Sweden and so on, that there were so many as evacuated.
What do you think it is?
When I was a kid and teenager
I heard these stories by my relatives.
But it was not popular to talk about that time
Because people felt shame.
They felt shame that they were refugees
It is perfectly normal for people to feel that way.
These are such psychological reactions.
They did not want to talk about it that we have been refugees or
that conditions in the camps were very hard.
People wanted to forget about it
And just start building a new life.
People wanted to look ahead,
Not on history.
It's like behind and now we go on
When we think of history books in Finland,
Also in Sweden,
Don't you write about
this period,
Only with some additions.
About the Lapland War
Do you write very little
For Lapland is so far away,
There are not so many people, so it doesn't matter.
Everyone looks at southern Finland, what happened there,
In Karelia,
where lots of people live.
But Lapland is so far away.
For example, from Helsinki to my home
is it 965 km,
965 kilometers.
From Helsinki
to Europe,
to Paris or ... it's so long way
So man
Didn't want to talk about it.
One has not written about this,
not novels but i am quite sure that after this novel there will be more novels
If this topic of
It's so strange
And that is so
closely, not so
far away in the story
There are people, perhaps here too, people
Who may have lived
at that time
or have parents who
told about it.
It has written as well as
Hundreds of books about
Refugees from Karelia
But no books about
This situation in Lapland
It's true
Then this book is, after all,
I would almost say unfortunately, uncomfortably relevant considering the situation we have today.
There are still corresponding phenomena.
To write this book, you must at least take part in research.
Was there a lot of work around?
I am so pleased that
Researchers and historians
has made
lots of
Finework
In the 80s about camps
Namely...
We know all the people who have lived in every barracks.
All names are there, everyone born in barracks,
Everyone who has died there.
And everyone who died there is buried in Sweden.
We have all the statistics.
And researchers
have done a tremendous fine work,
They have placed all camps
in Norrbotten.
There were camps too
in the Umeå area
Pretty far south.
There were thus about ten camps
The camps ... was because
They were isolated,
they were surrounded by barbed wire
So one couldn't go out,
You were trapped.
When people
asked why they could not go out from the camp,
It was in the middle of the forest, not by the side of villages,
Authorities only spoke Swedish
at the time there,
people who lived in the villages spoke Finnish
But authorities spoke Swedish.
And they said that you have to stay here to
We are afraid that you have
tuberculosis
and other
diseases
As we do not want you to infect
Swedish people with.
They were like isolated.
But there was food anyway.
Then we have to talk about the girl.
Or must and must
Thus the girl is the main character in this novel
It is through her eyes
As we readers get to know this historical stage.
And then I wonder firstly, we never know what her name is?
How did you think, that
Is she who tells us, is the janitor but we never know what her name is?
And it's really nothing that man
reflects on while reading without it is afterwards-
How did you choose to
Leave her without a name?
Well, there are many other names in the book but she
is the girl.
I thought that...
There has always been war here on the planet
And still nowadays, many wars are going on in the world.
And it will be new
war
As long as we humans live here on earth.
there will be war
And there will be refugees.
Refugees have
existed throughout
the history of mankind.
Refugees
And refugee streams or what we now call it.
I'm just writing girl
so it's easier for
people in Albania,
people Slovakia or in
Mexico
Or Brazil
to identify
with this girl situation.
For what I knew it was also translated
Out there in the world.
It's like
A refugee girl
who lives everywhere in the world.
Yes, that's how it also feels when you read.
That it is a consciousness
and it is bigger than if it was fixed
by a name.
And she's there, and she's in 13 and 14 years of age and this one
The story takes place for about eight months.
She is fascinating because she is a child partly
but she
forced to become an adult because of the circumstances.
And then she is also a reflective person, she ponders about
the universe.
She ponders nature, she ponders the starry sky.
And so she is very responsible
Pretty incredible indeed!
What strikes me among other things is that
We have Christianity, we have science
and all that
Is included in her consciousness as she thinks about the world.
And another thing
which is also so fascinating, this is the relationship with nature,
The nature that surrounds her and all the others and how you write this nature it is incredibly beautiful.
You look like exactly,
It is noticeable that you are a painter
For as you reproduce nature through this girl
and relationship with the animals
For that is also all
specifically.
After all, it becomes a value scale, what is it that matters and what does nothing mean?
If I am going to pick something out of this then I thought
The girl's relationship with the cows, to the animals.
Would you like to comment
Something about that?
For it had deep roots in a tradition, how
The animals are treated.
It is such a big question that I have to think how I start ...
Just how to how you treat the cow?
It is very important,
Everything she says is very important in this book.
If I think about relationships with nature ...
First I can tell you a little about that girl.
When I wrote the book and looked at the world
with that girl's eyes that is 13-14 years old,
Which is very eager, who want to know about life.
She wants to know about everything that happens everything that has happened.
She is full of
eenergy and she is full of the joy of life
Although she is in liver in such strange
situations.
But she is not without hope,
she is like the person who knows how to live
in nature,
How to live
together with animals.
She thinks she is part of nature
Like the trees,
Like the earth, as well as the air,
Like all flowers.
So she
does not have a relationship
to nature,
She is part of nature.
Like we are actually.
When we think that
We all people
are animals too.
We often forget it
But we are animals.
Like chimpanzees are
ours
closest
relatives.
So we're an animal.
And we are part of nature.
For when we think about
human history and the history of our planet
Was it
millions of years
Before we humans came here on the planet.
And we forget that.
The planet was here and there was no man here.
And then we came.
And we made the planet what we see now.
When one thinks of man's history
Before we started growing the earth,
All the people here on the planet were
Hunters and collectors.
And we worked
four hours a day
To get heat and food.
Four hours a day
And not every day.
And we could live that way for the 100,000 years.
We lived that way.
And with the lifestyle that we have now
Have we lived only a small part of the time.
10,000 years ago we started growing.
And big cities and this lifestyle
have been here a little more than
100 years!
And all that can disappear,
We have to think about that
It's as little time as
Man has been here
And the whole human race can die away.
And then nature and all animals take over the planet.
If we continue to live this way like that
will people die away.
In this book I wanted to
treat this thing
but in the way I describe
How human can live
in balance
with the entire globe,
all animals, all species
How we can live here with all other animal species
In balance like the girl does.
If one lives on the same level as all other species
As we can live here,
very nice.
It goes.
We usually say that
Nowadays, people are like that
up in the head that
they cannot live here
Without all these machines,
Digital world and whatever.
But it is not true.
If the digital world collapses,
it takes two vecor
And all people can live here.
If the fire disappears we can live after two weeks, it goes well
Man as a species
is very flexible.
It's going well.
So I'm not afraid of
The future.
The digital world and if it comes like anything,
if we want
Can we live here.
Right!
Here I think it would fit well if we would read a bit if it's okay for you
This girl
develops during the course of the journey
And the place we should read from is about when she in her way meets love
for the first time
but also her way of relate to what is happening
In a human being when you meet the one you want to be with.
Yes exactly
This is at the end of the novel and it is therefore about
The girl who has come back to her farm and an uncle who takes care of the yard
After the father has fallen.
Uncle had taken a boy who seemed to be proper a thick -nest bay with rash in
The face I had not seen before.
He asked if I wanted to go out into the woods and look for taxes
The bay went ahead and I after.
I looked at his wide backboard.
We roam in the forest and in the afternoon we found to hide.
We started digging by hand, for pots, boilers, copper, barrels and glasses
Which was buried in the woodland and from the rapids we salvaged a service.
We bent in the ditch that ran out of cold source
Where Dad had hidden a quarter.
In it was the vase Grandma had received in the dowry
and grandmother's engagement gifts,
A coffee pot of silver, cream and sugar bowl.
He had smile pits and his hand felt good.
We walked along Skogsvägen to the lake.
The water chuckled and sparkled.
The swallows piled here and there, very close to the surface,
caught short and long night dragonflies in the beak and swung back up into the blue sky
I jerked when the bay put my hand on my shoulder,
hugged hard about it,
Folded me on my back and rolled over on me.
A shoal small fish swam around in my stomach and constantly changed the direction.
The lungs are on fire, the heart fluttered like a summer curtain in an open window.
I thought now is the right time and pressed lips against his rough lips,
Did he licked sweaty face,
he tickled smile pits and white teeth with my tongue.
He my cheeks.
My stupid arms felt the curled hair on his arms.
I brought my pants down and opened the buttons in his.
He penetrated into my damp pussy and it splashed and irritated in my toes and fingertips.
Life sprinkled in the mouth.
I screamed like a pig.
It felt like the lungs were emptied of air and I fell hover like the leaf from the tree.
He sprayed the liquids into my interior.
I grabbed his head and pushed it down in my wrote and he started licking.
My leather pounded satisfied.
We lay next to each other, we giggled and let lice flies and mosquito suck blood out of the throat and forest locks run over our faces.
Then we were silent.
I looked at his mouth, forehead and clear eyes.
We were lying side by side,
close together,
breasts against breasts,
without words.
And the feeling of joy pulsed all the way into the nails.
Yes, yeah, okay.
Now let's take it at Meänkiel as well.
I have talked that time goes on, so
I read a little here in the beginning.
Ko Mie Ja Katri Olima Koalla Urakalla Saahneet Kyörrettyä Karjan Maantiele,
Taivas Peitty Syksyssen Utuharssoon ja kohta alcohol tihuutahmaan jäähilheistä Vettä.
Kaikki muut lenti Paitti ilona pöästyit teräviä hiutahleita ja haijaanuit.
Sisko, Pirkko Ja Liina Rynnit Ojjaa Pitkin, Kerttu Reistasi Paeta Methään,
Siskon Eeliskuussa vision news Sokkerivasikka Tanssi Paikahlaan,
Soma Kiipesi Kielon Sölkhään Yes Molemat Rääyit.
Reunassa Oli Kuiteski niin tiheä marked ja mustaa onei ker
We have to start rounding here but maybe there is someone who wants to ask questions?
So you get ...
The language is meänkieli
or Tornedals dialect.
The whole book.
But Janina is such an amazing translator that she can like
Make it too.
Thank you yes> "
More?
The original is at Meänkieli and the assignment was to translate it into Swedish, not into another dialect.
I can't translate to another dialect because I know no dialect so good that I can write it on it.
Then i have thought like that
that I try to catch the rhythm
In the original as good as possible.
Of course you should include the message too, but it should float in your own rhythm.
Yes simply so ...
Any of you may have read the translations of
Väinö Linnas "Unknown Soldier"
to Swedish?
And that is, as always, this question with dialect?
What to do with the dialect?
For a dialect is not equal to another dialect.
So it's pretty complicated.
But you write in such a way that even if it is meänkieli
So I hear in my head that here he was told me in Swedish.
I don't know how it goes but ...
She knows me so well!
We have known each other for 20 years
"The Supreme" is also on Meänkieli
Coupbee No. 6 is in original in Finnish
These are short stories that are also translated into Swedish.
Such short stories that I wrote before I started writing novels.
I was 50 years old when I started,
not 50 years,
I was 40 years old when I started writing novels.
But I write
Nowadays, short stories.
Most to actors.
Monologists
to actors.
If you have written about your life in Russia and in Denmark and in the US
Yes, I have written about my life in Russia, Kupé # 6 which is the novel and also the movie.
So it is from my own life that and my first
Trans -Siberian journey that I did
null
First year with gorbatov
Now I work with the book about Texas
But I don't know when it comes out,
not in the next few years
For now I travel a lot with this one
"The river" and I want to concentrate
on the book when it comes out in different countries.
It's my work now but my head is working on
America.
But we will see that how it goes.
But Denmark, yes Denmark!
I have never written anything about
Christiania but i have been thinking
Make a documentary there.
And I have, like starting
Talk to my friends who have said they
Who lives in Christiania now.
Also my old friends
Have promised that they will come.
Now I have made a document film about Marjatta Nenander
who is my Swedish gallerist from Stockholm and she is a
Person in this book.
So i made an hour documentary about her
Refugee story.
And her whole story is very interesting.
And now
I work with Pauli's documentary film.
I have filmed everything and now it is haircut.
But I think Christiania comes on documentary films and not
in book form.
Yes I did.
I traveled alone
twice with the Trans -Siberian railway.
But the third time followed my
17-year-old daughter with.
Yes we met there.
In Krasnojarsk and Novosibirsk
She and I took the trip
by train.
I told my daughter to,
We fly, it was a book fair,
We fly there!
She said no, we take the Transiberian train!
So I've done it three times!
But every time it's been awesome
I love
To travel by train
I travel everywhere by train of course it is possible i love
Train
For it
Life is so amazing when in the train
Yes and that and with the Trans -Siberian Railway
Hope that it is someone becomes possible even in our lifetime but what it is so amazing it becomes your own world when you live
And lots of different people
Yes we have seen many have seen a movie
Out number six i was thinking
A brief comment on how to live it and or are there any other of your books that are going on
Cinema
No it is the only one that has made of my bee
Yes I saw the movie for the first time in can the festival in France
It was the premiere there
And I had not been working in the movie and I do not know
Director Juhokåsmannen
Personal but I had seen his films and
I liked a lot
Movies
And when i was there so first
10 minutes I was, like shocks like no
But then like
I lived this whole this movie
So that I didn't think
So like it took me 100 %
So I then started when I have the goose man you can the festival and now we are good friends and
And we noticed in there may the festival that
Chilin sisters themselves
Not friends too okay
But I saw me but the movie I love movie
I've seen a four times now that we round
Round it toured
Turner
With film
In different countries
So i saw it four times and each
It was like another movie to me
For the first time it was like all that since I started
Focus on dialogues then on clothes and
Darke like that so
And then the music and all these sounds and
Looks the lice and such so it was always a new movie
No but that yes recommended
And the book is like its
And the movie is
Warrior
Many books of
That story for what he was such a child
His
Is it clear here
What is it called
Just
The movie is a lot
There were so many children who
Who was also a war child in Denmark.
But
Cake
I think it's called with answers as well
men 50 years old when he wrote the first book about it
As you get older it is easier
The shame is
Of course
that hinders.
I was so curious your stay in Texas, do you want to tell
A little about that?
But it was very interesting.
It was full of adventure.
You could say that
I want to thank so much for this book about the river
I also believe that one reason for people not
written these stories or told these stories
is that they did not have the language,
That they did not get the language.
My mother came as a four -year -old
And she is not written language.
She is spoken language.
In Swedish only.
So that may be a reason.
But I would like ...
I hear when you tell us about coupe # 6
That you might not have the power over the movie
I would like to ask you
Whether you live or not when the movie of the river
Made in the future, that you retain power and say they may not find a name for this girl.
In order to,
For example, Margaret Atwood has made a book
where the main character had no name and
The film companies have demanded that she get a name and they have said that she is called something.
Keep in mind that there is a risk that they suddenly
Just decide that she is called Seja or what she can now be called.
I keep it in my heart
But I was still thinking about coupe No. 6
For
The girl there
Have only one replica in the whole novel, the rest is going on in her head.
We get to know it through her thoughts, it's related ...
interesting.
Yes it is.
I think I'm such a writer
to the best path
For me, writing long monologues.
So that is the reason for that
I write long monologues.
You have a very fun explanation for why monologue?
And that is, I have thought about why I love to write monologues
It is that in Finland and especially in my hometown
we usually do not discuss.
There are no dialogues.
There are only
Monologist by monologue.
You do not discuss.
It's another culture
than in Sweden.
We know that
Here people discuss
And when I have lived in Stockholm too and I have Swedish friends,
especially with gallerist who has been my gallerist
30 years
So we are friends and I feel through the gallery
Lots of people in Stockholm,
Swedes love to discuss!
It is something very special for us Finns
Who sits still and thinks.
Thanks
because you have listened
Thank you to everyone for coming here and
It was so fun to talk here!
And nice audience!
Thousand thanks
And see you in the future!