Hello.
Today it is Thursday and I miss Thursday fun incredibly much.
So I thought we were running a digital variant of Thursday fun today with a little talk and a little work.
Today I thought we should talk about this.
The hedgehog.
Have you ever seen any such
You can usually have seen them sometimes because they like to live close to us people.
In parks and gardens for example.
The hedgehog could live in the forest but it does not like badgers for badgers can eat it.
So instead it lives quite close to us humans.
In Gotland, for example, where there are no badgers where the hedgehog lives in the forest.
The hedgehog looks a little special.
We all know what it has on the back.
Well, it has its tags.
5000 tags can have it and these tags are really hair that is reformed.
Imagine if we had such nice tags instead.
These tags are designed to protect the hedgehog so no one should come and check it out.
When the hedgehog becomes scared, it cures.
Then it stops all the tags outwards so that those who want to eat them stick their mouths.
The hedgehog has 4 small legs with small claws on the feet, a small nose, small ears and small eyes.
They don't look great but they feel scents great.
That way they chase up what they want to eat.
But what does the hedgehog eat
Well, the hedgehog eats worms, beetles, snails, bird eggs they can take, small mouse cubs, frogs ...
... and even snakes they can eat.
The hedgehog can handle pretty good snake poison, so they can.
What is most amazing about the hedgehog eats beetles, do you know what it is
Well, because what you eat comes out like poop.
So when the hedgehogs poop, it is pooping glitter.
The hedgehog's poop shines off the beetle shells that are in it.
So it actually sparkles.
How does a hedgehog sound
They don't sound like much.
You can hear how they scream around there at night because these are awake at night.
Then they crawl out and look for food in our gardens
You can actually feed the hedgehog if you want.
You should keep in mind not to feed it with milk because they are allergic, instead you can exhibit water ...
... or cat food they can enjoy.
The hedgehog is starting to wake up now in the spring for all winter it has been in hibernation.
It hides in a pile of leaves or twigs and it is almost like dead.
The heart beats only a few blows and it just breathes a little neighbor.
But then in the spring it arrives.
In fact, the hedgehogs are not very common anymore.
They will actually be included in the red list that will be this year.
This means that they are starting to become really unusual.
You do not know exactly why the hedgehogs are getting fewer, but they have difficulty finding good places to sleep.
If you have a garden, it is good to leave some deciduous piles and rice piles where the hedgehog can winter.
But now I think we should have our own hedgehogs.
So, now I've got some help.
-Yes!
We are going to make hedgehogs.
We will make the hedgehogs of witch dough and then we need flour, salt, water ...
And a little like that.
And a little like this oil.
Then we want the magic dough to be brown, or how
For the hedgehog is brown.
Then we have old coffee grounds that I was going to color with.
And to tags, what do we have then
What is that for something then
Ehm, conifer.
Yes, it is.
We have pine cones if we are to make small tags.
Let's go
Now we are going to make magic dough pink.
Then we will have 1 cup flour.
Should you pour in
It's like I'm baking.
Yes, but just like when we bake.
So we should have in salt, half a deciliter.
So.
Then we will have in a little coffee sump, what remains when you have made coffee.
If we get a little.
So, half a deciliter.
Yes, take everything together.
So we should have some water, half a deciliter.
So.
And a little oil.
Splash, splash.
Now we are around it.
So this will be a dough.
Mom, this then?
Yes, it was the one we had before and would show how you did.
I can't bake.
-You can bake?
Now let's see if we can get to this witch dough.
Look here you'll see.
We gather it like this.
Oh.
I want it.
Look now we're going to make a hedgehog of that.
But we should not make such a big hedgehog but a small hedgehog.
Here you get and make a little hedgehog.
Here I can make a little hedgehog.
The hedgehogs they are a little elongated.
So we roll this one and make it like a small sausage.
That's how.
But I don't want to do.
You don't want to make one?
Well but then I do one.
Then we will make a small nose on the hedgehog.
Hello there little hedgehog.
Then the hedgehog will get tags.
Then we have these bars.
But the bars are so long so we cut them into small pieces.
So.
Then you can take here and put in hedgehogs on your hedgehog.
I want to stop in yours.
Should you stop in mine?
Yes, put in my hedgehog.
We can have it together.
I want mine.
You want yours, yes but then you take yours and stop tags on yours.
No.
I do one ...
What are you doing then?
Now let's see, look so many hedgehogs it got and a little strange plut there.
Can you help me stop in hedgehogs
It was me.
Well, was it you who made the little dot?
Look, can you help me
Great
You have to stick them in.
The hedgehog has a lot of tags.
5000, so we have to sit here for a while.
These?
-Yes but like those.
5.6.
-6.7.
It is good for no one to want to eat the hedgehog.
They protect themselves with their tags
But look, now it is starting to be a little hedgehog.
But the hedgehog must ...
... was it sharp
Like a hedgehog.
It must get eyes.
I't was not there.
-No, there were no eyes.
No pen either.
There, it had just hidden.
It was I who didn't find the pen.
So we can draw small eyes.
At the front have the hedgehog small eyes
So it has a black nose so it can feel scents.
I want it.
-Yes, you want it.
Should you make tags on yours too
You make dots.
It is not always that people want to play that you want to play yourself.
I want to do.
-Yes you should do as you please.
Should we build a small nest to the hedgehog
Look here you'll see.
Here we have some paper.
Here the hedgehog will be allowed to live.
Idgehogs like to rest in winter and go to hibernation.
The heart beats very dealing, almost so they lie dead in deciduous piles.
So I thought we were taking some old leaves.
I usually glue like a small V, or one up and down V.
So we attach some leaves here.
Look
Oh.
Look now, now it becomes like a small hut for the hedgehog so it can go in there.
Like that, look what a nice thing.
How are your hedgehogs going