Hello.
How nice.
We would be gathered here to talk about the coming legislation-
-And what it can mean for you who work locally.
The reason we have this session, it is both to capture the ER-
-It's the beginning of a needs inventory of how we should design our support to ER-
-If the future legislation.
It's a way for us to start ...
"This is what we think."
You can give feedback.
How right do you think we end up in our discussions?
Before we start, I'll introduce ourselves on stage.
My name is Charlotta Gustafsson, I am from the Crime Prevention Council.
-To right on me I have ... -malin wiktoreng.
I am here as a national coordinator for the county administrative boards' crime prevention work-
-But I also exist as regional coordinator in Västerbotten.
My name is Greta Berg.
I am responsible for crime prevention issues at Sweden's municipalities and regions.
My name is Håkan Jarborg Eriksson.
I work at the Police Authority.
National operational department.
Where we at a development center, as I am responsible for-
-Works with the development of crime prevention work.
Good.
Now I take ...
I thought we were doing a short recap on the law, which is proposed.
There maybe Greta, Håkan and Malin want to fill up, but I'm starting a bit.
The law does not describe what a municipality should do, but more how a municipality should work.
It is both a strength and a weakness so clearly.
What you print a lot in the bill is that you have to work knowledge -based.
There should be a situation picture, which includes both a survey-
-A causal analysis and an information about the conditions one has-
-To prevent crime.
Based on the situation, one should formulate-
-The action plan, ie how to work with the questions-
-And after every two years do a follow -up of the work.
This should be done with the police-
-But also with other actors concerned.
For this to be off-
-also stipulates the law which organizational conditions need to be in place.
Then there should be a strategic collaboration forum-
-Or a crime prevention council that disposes of these issues in the municipality.
There should be a coordinator feature for the questions, which becomes a contact surface-
-Both internally and externally for collaboration.
It must be signed collaboration agreements-
-With the parties involved, who are important for the crime prevention work.
It is the responsibility of the municipal management that this exists.
-Have I missed something?
-No.
I can say briefly too ...
... that the information I have received from Justitie and Skr-
— will the Law Council's remit be ready before the election-
-And the bill will be completed after the election.
The law is expected to enter into force on July 1, 2023, for those who do not know.
As Morgan said this morning, there is quite a great agreement around this law.
-Over party borders.
-Yes exactly.
Should we start by looking at how you have answered ...
Are you with us, Lars?
... on the survey.
So far you had answered ...
Which was the one who answered at half past two today?
Quite a few crime prevention from the municipality that has responded.
That's 34 percent.
About 30 percent are municipal police or area police.
It is fairly evenly between these two strong local crime prevents.
Then you also see that there are other answers from social services-
-The managers, politicians, officials or something else.
You can have with you when we report the answers that this is how it looks.
Shall we take next?
Then we asked the question of how ready you are for the upcoming law.
You are ready.
Very ready, even.
It's only 13 percent, I think.
I don't see, it's so damn little here.
But 13 percent who say that they are not ready at all.
Quite a few who do not know.
You do not know what requirements come with the law.
Then we take the next one.
You can also see from these pictures-
-That you think you yourself are more ready than the municipal organization is ready.
-Should we comment on this?
-I can comment on it.
Many who have responded are crime prevention-
-And many have many years of experience and are ready to tackle the challenges-
-But you may not have your organization with you.
The municipal management is not ready, the municipality has not cooperated.
One might not get the mandate you wish or money-
-To drive crime prevention work.
Those who respond to the survey are more ready than the organizations themselves.
It is positive and it feels safe-
-That so many at the individual level feel ready.
70 percent we were up in. Very ready or ready.
It was a higher figure than I had expected-
-Also if it is a crime prevention who is here at this conference.
It is still the target group that will be hugely involved in the work.
It feels very good.
Then it is natural in a way-
-That the organization, as a system seen, may not be as far ahead.
But still, 50 percent.
There are good conditions when you see these figures.
I can only agree.
After all, we meet all committed and knowledgeable crime prevention coordinators-
-Ote in the municipalities everyday, in our professional life.
We know how much good jobs are also done.
It is nice to have it confirmed through these answers
That you feel ready to take on this new legislation.
While we have talked, a question has come in.
It is whether the Law Council has commented on the bill.
Here it says "your" bill.
It is not our bill.
This comes from the government.
-But do you know anything about the Law Council?
-The Law Council?
I think the Law Council comments on the law council's remit, and it is not finished.
There is certainly someone in the room who knows this better than I am, but I drive a little volley.
When the Law Council's remit is complete, the Law Council expresses itself, then the bill is written.
No, the answer is.
-You write a question and we answer directly.
-So smooth.
It feels like a heavy system, but it works.
But what good.
Then we can stop showing the charts.
Then we will skip some pictures.
That was the question.
Then we arrive at this.
I thought.
Now.
After all, it's not just a bill that comes.
I don't know if you heard when I talked to Willy.
He asked:
"Does it have significance? Does it become revolving for the crime prevention work"-
-"That a bill was produced?"
I answered yes.
Then I thought I should have explained a bit.
With this bill-
-Have the search lamp aimed at the municipalities.
In 2021, when I looked at national initiatives that have taken-
-Holds the municipalities in a completely different way in these SOU: erna-
-or reports from authorities or the authorities' own writing-
-What the municipalities could do to prevent crime.
There are expectations that the municipality will now prevent ...
In addition to creating the organizational structure, and work systematically-
-There are expectations for the municipality to work with environmental crime-
-Now the municipality will take hold of the violence workers in violence in close relationships-
-And make efforts against financial crime and gang crime.
There is something more, not just a bill.
Do you have any thoughts?
Have you noticed it?
It is clear that a legislative-
-Shid if you need to change your work a lot, it means a lot.
Brå, Skr and the police have for many years supported the collaboration between the police and the municipal
-And develop the crime prevention work locally.
The state has not supported it as much as the state does now.
There was a long period where the state's only driving force was-
-To improve the political result, not the municipalities' crime prevention work.
It has turned in recent years.
Now the state thinks that the municipalities must get on the track.
The municipalities play an important role.
The municipality must help the police.
From the time we have been working on the issue for many years, the state is now a player-
-As is trying to drive this development forward.
A change from a political perspective.
How do you think from Skr?
There is an increased demand for the municipalities that are sneakily on here.
You who have read our referral response understand that we do not like the legislation.
The municipalities can develop their crime prevention work without legislation.
The support that Brå and also the county administrative boards and the police provide to the municipalities-
-would be able to develop.
So you can develop the crime prevention work.
We have been negative to a legislation-
-But it is because we do not like the state controlling the municipalities.
It is more of such a aspect that we put in it.
Now we understand that we do not escape legislation.
Then it is more about how the state actors should support the municipalities-
-And what money will we get for this?
These are the issues we are now running.
From a crime prevention perspective-
-Can it have an effect, and you can get a mandate for the questions in a different way.
The municipalities are obliged to work with this.
Do you see it from a political, organizational or crime prevention perspective?
There are different aspects of how to look at this question.
-See you.
-From the part of the Police Authority ...
... we welcome this legislation very-
-And looks forward to having expectations of the municipalities based on this.
Of course, there are a lot of municipalities in the country that are further forward-
-An the minimum level of legislation, prescribes.
But to get up the minimum level, the low level, get a standard-
-Th what each municipality should be able to do in this crime prevention work-
-We will decorate from the Police Authority is good.
We have a challenge on the part of the Police Authority.
We are now an authority.
We have an assignment to work in a uniform and similar way throughout the country-
-And so we have 297 different municipalities that that uniform will meet.
Therefore, we believe and hope that this legislation will help to-
-When it applies to structures, working methods, working method-
-When we then have in the crime prevention work-
-That we get it as uniform as possible in the country-
-and thus generates efficiency gains and has power and effects due to it-
-In the crime prevention work.
It is a line we will try to drive.
Getting this as uniform as possible.
That we work in the same way in the country.
I think we have to safeguard municipal self -government.
We develop the crime prevention work by based on local conditions.
Speaking of local conditions, we have received a question where one wonders-
-If we can explain more what we mean by knowledge -based.
We say the situation that includes survey, causal analysis.
"Have you had thoughts about the situation image as a basis for priorities"-
-"Out of what should be included? Is it a difference it would be good to have it explained."
From how we previously talked about situation pictures and what is in the legislation.
If there is a difference.
There is someone who says: "Good, Greta."
I'm just trying to be your speech tube.
-Do you want to answer the question?
-It's clear you should check the difficult.
Actually, there is not much difference to what is in the law text.
We have said that a situation picture should contain a survey and an analysis.
Then we have not quite as clearly talked about inventing their conditions-
-Working crime prevention.
I don't know if you can see the spin in front of you.
That it says "initiate collaboration" at the top.
But one has to identify what it looks like organizationally to us.
What are we doing now?
What kind of structures do we have?
What can we use?
How can it flow into the work?
The difference is well-
-That is now the case more clearly into this situation.
-Håkan.
-I might misunderstand the question ...
... but of course situation pictures must be based on the local problem picture.
Is it the local problem picture that is the problems to address?
But what I believe and even claim to know, that's Ju-
-That many situation pictures may not be complete.
You look where you stand, if I say so-
-But there is a lot of information about the development of crime-
-If even system threatening activities that are going on in the country-
-which may need to get into position pictures at local level-
-To create an awareness that these problems exist in society.
This organized crime operates in the country-
-and we may see it not here and now, but it may come next week-
-by a hostile takeover of a business, a restaurant-
-A municipal company, for example.
You have to be prepared for that.
You have to bring that in this.
It may not require an action here and now-
-But all local position images need to be refined-
-with the information that one is necessarily not sitting with local-
-But that now still becomes clear that it must be added to these position images-
-When it gets a structure in this way that you get through legislation.
Among other things, it is the role of the Police Authority to be able to provide for these position images-
-With such information, and I think that is important.
I believe that if we get this base-
-when the legislation approaches, then the idea is that the work we put there-
-Do lead to something better than what we have done before, to the right action.
That is the very purpose of this.
The purpose is not collaboration-
-The position pictures or mapping.
The purpose is to get one step further through the tools.
It takes time.
Many of us here in the room have been doing this for years.
My hope is that we will be able to take the step and get a little better.
Get a little sharper, put in a little better action against what is actually the problem.
The collaboration for the sake of collaboration is meaningless.
We must never forget why we do this.
Not to get the complete position image-
-It is for us to be able to take the right measures.
Cooperation is required, it requires thoughtful work.
This base should lay the foundation so that we can take a step forward-
-So that we can see results.
And we have seen the results of our actions.
This is what is so important and good, to build the crime prevention work on.
That is what we must keep in mind when we read the law's proposal.
We should not meet these base stuff, and lean back.
They will lead to something that makes us safer and safer municipalities.
What Håkan talks about recognizes to where you started, Lotta.
Within the county administrative boards, we also see this complexity and width-
-A of the crime prevention work.
We see how other types of crime categories are starting to become more and more interesting-
-At national level.
It is about environmental crime, it is about men's violence against women, the business issue.
Very interesting in relation to the crime prevention work-
-But also violation of welfare.
This clarifies the complexity-
-In the crime prevention work.
The new bill presses a little neighbor.
Where you really show the importance of the entire municipality working crime prevention.
Many administrations have to enter this work and can contribute in a good way.
Both in a mode of image work-
-But also linked to solving the crime problems.
Cause analysis means to dive deep into a problem.
How can it be part of a situation picture?
I would like to say that a situation can ...
The survey will cover everything you have found.
But in the situation picture you also try to identify more as pattern-
-and make a compilation of their survey.
This means that you can prioritize certain crimes.
"This is what we want to know more about and do causal analysis about."
We do not say that one should do a causal analysis of all-
-An if you can report a survey that has covered a lot.
In this way, I think that the causal analysis will be included in the position image.
I hope I do not say to what we have written in the book.
Based on the situation, it is assumed that the collaborative parties-
-which is identified in this legislation, make its prioritization first-
-When which are our most important problems we see?
This is where the causal analysis comes in to go into depth in those problems.
You got for something you said before: "Good, Håkan!"
Great.
1-1.
We get quite a few questions about this with the situation picture.
There we begin to understand that here there is a need of
-Do we continue to provide support and discuss-
-What is for expectations that come with this situation picture?
As the bill looks like now, it may change-
-Then there is nothing to say what the situation picture should look like.
You should make as good a picture as you can, of course-
-But the important thing is that one does not get stuck in the mapping bit-
-That you don't get stuck in it.
You should make a good situation.
The situation picture can be improved, you can improve that year by year.
The law does not require the situation to look in a special way-
-What is the situation picture that the municipality pleases to develop, which is in demand.
Not everyone can make a situation that is 100 percent right from the start.
No municipality has ever done so.
You start at some end.
You who have made the situation know that you can replenish and adjust it, and move on.
You who start from scratch, there is good support in our collaboration book.
There is no minimum limit for what a position picture should look like.
It is probably a co -condition, maybe.
Several of you have asked questions-
-If what to do with municipalities that do not prioritize crime prevention work?
Isn't that the purpose of the law?
Do you mean how to take them in the ear from the state?
Yes.
"What could be the consequences for municipalities that do not comply with the law?"
The first question that came in, before the session was even in the walk-
-Also traded on what happens to a municipality that does not follow the law?
Do you want me to answer that?
Or maybe the state should do?
And then you look at me?
I can say this.
BRÅ has a responsibility to follow up on how this law works
-And how the municipalities work according to it.
We will follow up on it-
-And I suspect it will be like the annual report we do today.
It may be a bit like open comparisons, which Skr develops.
That you describe how the municipalities work.
But we have no sanctioning authority.
We are not such an authority.
We will only compile this.
There is no sanction, and it thinks that Skr is good.
We also do not think that the state should control exactly what the municipality does-
-Or I think the municipalities want to do right.
The municipalities want to work as well as they can in the crime prevention work.
Then these must be anchored from above.
Some may have views that the municipal management does not prioritize.
It is legislation.
The municipalities are obliged to follow the law, and want to do so.
No one will hit you on your fingers if you do wrong-
-But the hope is that everyone has the ambition to follow the law.
We all want our citizens to be as good as possible-
-And wants to prevent crime.
It will be self-marking if one does not follow the law-
-So I see that the law itself will be self -realization.
You do not want to be designated as the one who does not.
Not MD the priority that the security and security issues have in the municipalities.
Fifteen years ago, these issues were not on the agenda as they are today.
Now almost all municipalities talk about this.
Then you prioritize it differently, depending on what the crime looks like in the municipality.
It will be a cue in to the next question.
We have received a question.
It is in itself good with national unity and structure-
-But are there any thoughts with us about how to support the smaller municipalities?
They often have small resources and limited presence of police.
In the bill, the county administrative boards also have ...
It states that we must be allocated funds to provide operational support to municipalities-
-To reach the requirements of the legislation.
It is a clear signal to us based on how we have interpreted it.
It is the municipalities that may struggle with resources and with these processes-
-And this is where we should receive a resource strengthening to be able to be a support.
What that support might look like, it will look different out-
-Sters, we are 21 different authorities.
We adapt our support to the needs of the local level-
-But we will also return to the latter today.
What kind of support is actually in demand.
Then I just want to say that I would like to say-
-This small municipalities have been given a more prominent role in national conversations in the day-
-compared to earlier.
When I look at referrals and referral responses-
-When often lifted rural and sparsely populated municipalities' prerequisites-
-Sodger than they did before.
It is a joint work that we have done.
We have a bit of a mission to lift all municipalities' conditions.
We work with this on the county administrative boards, but also the police and Skr.
And BRÅ, of course.
We cooperate a lot now, around what support the municipalities need.
Then the focus will be on the municipalities that have not begun their crime prevention work-
-What does not have the structure that the law requires.
In addition to the particular level, which we realize must have a lot of support-
-How should we support other municipalities that have come further?
After all, we will not leave you who have come a long way, to help the others.
We want the support to be available for all different levels.
We discuss that a lot.
We are fully aware that there are municipalities at all levels.
In some way, everyone must be able to develop their crime prevention work regardless of level.
We discuss all the municipalities' different crime prevention levels-
-When we talk support.
There I can fill up, in the annual report I talked about earlier in day-
-That we see a development-
-There of metropolitan municipalities since 2017 have been high and stable.
They have fairly good conditions organizationally to work with the questions.
They have a habit of doing mapping, causal analysis and follow -ups.
Then we have also followed the smaller municipalities, which we will support.
You can see that the curve is going up now.
There are more people who have local advice.
More who have collaboration agreements.
Smaller municipalities may not allocate a full-time service to this question-
-Thaly combines it with several other prevention issues.
You may not have had a pure education for the questions either.
Despite this, you still do surveys.
It goes up.
It is more causal analysis, a little weaker with follow -up, but it is a positive trend.
But you look at the medium-sized municipalities-
-When we barely talk about, but that are still quite a few in Sweden-
-The their curve is more flat.
In some respects, it has now begun to go down.
When we said we need to look over all the municipalities-
-blie the "big city, socially vulnerable areas, gang crime"--
-Or it will be sparsely populated, and so we have lost middle milk Sweden.
It may be coincidences that make it flicker out.
It can be a result after the restrictions of Covid-19.
But we have to keep extra eyes to the medium -sized municipalities.
The county administrative boards' regional crime prevention coordinator-
-Find out throughout the country.
We adapt our work based on the needs that exist in our county.
That communication is important.
Contact the coordinator on the county administrative board.
Have a dialogue about what support you want, what support the county administrative board can provide.
It is also a way for us that, just as Lotta talked about earlier in day-
-Being able to bring up the local level on a national level.
Then we have to get it to us in order to pass it on.
Don't be afraid to contact.
I was going to say that there will be no more questions, but then one came just.
If the prerequisite is that the municipality must sign a cooperation agreement-
-What happens if the municipality is not satisfied with what the police can put up with?
Do we force the municipalities to sign anyway?
An agreement is a form of will.
That you put down on print, black on white, what you want to achieve together.
An agreement is an agreement.
If you are not satisfied, then you cannot sign such an agreement.
Then there is the legal requirement that there should be a collaboration agreement, but ...
You cannot sign an agreement if you are not satisfied.
No, exactly.
This is a collaboration-
-Which is to be based on agreeing on what to work with.
Then you have to file on ...
After all, there are municipalities that do not want to be part of the citizen promises-
-like the police.
Municipalities have broken the cooperation agreement-
-To you are dissatisfied with the police's representation.
Then you have to try to find ... The very basis of the agreement-
-Is, as Charlotta says, a kind of will.
If one cannot agree on one point, it cannot be included in the agreement.
If one is dissatisfied with the police presence-
-Do not regulate the agreement.
What we can do better together in this work, we will work with that.
Hopefully, in a collaboration, one can agree-
-What to be included in the agreement, and not.
If you cannot agree on a particular issue, you should not bring it.
Neither the municipality nor the police can force the other to sign an agreement.
But the agreement is not a legally binding document.
No one can go to court and say:
"Now the police broke the agreement."
This is a will.
The requirements of the law are not so that you should ...
It says that you should document this in a way and you should agree.
The important thing is to have this collaboration and that you try to move on.
Then you have to take a new hold the next time you negotiate or sit down and plan.
Hopefully it is not a document that you hit the other in your head.
It should be a common will, which controls the work forward.
We should be a little better together.
It should not be a bat, a threat or a bribe.
That is not the purpose.
The purpose is for us to get better.
That the municipality and police find the right measures.
The police will take into account the municipality's picture of reality and vice versa.
It's a hard question-
-But the very purpose is not to have it as a bat.
We can't force anyone else, simply.
Before I give you the word I want to say, good Malin!
-1-1.
-Now it's me zeroing.
"Do you do the homework according to the book 'Collaboration in local crime prevention work'"-
-Harms the agreement at the level that both parties have the opportunity to work with.
-Do you say that?
-It was a good answer that came in there.
I have nothing to add linked to the collaboration agreement.
You should be able to agree on that.
These are the issues that are there.
My picture is, and we look over ...
In any case within the Police Authority, we peek over at regular intervals-
-All collaboration agreements that the police do with the municipalities.
The ones we get in and the ones we get access to.
My picture is that there are other things that make you not agree-
-If a cooperation agreement-
-But that is what becomes the symbol because you do not have good cooperation.
One has incorrect or unreasonable expectations of each other-
-And so the collaboration agreement becomes the symbol.
Then do not sign it.
I meet municipalities and police.
Many municipalities are dissatisfied with the police-
-But also many police officers who are dissatisfied with the municipality.
It looks very different, who is drawing in this work.
What becomes more equal is-
-This is that both the police and the municipality have a crime prevention assignment by law.
That's the difference now.
Previously, the police have had the mission-
-And the municipalities have been involved to the extent that they want or need.
Now it becomes a kind of minimum requirement.
Both have the assignment.
It may be able to help us get this balance that both parties weigh just as heavily.
It is very important in collaboration, that it is not the one or the other who has the power.
The police should not dictate the conditions for the municipality.
There are two equivalent parties who will agree and work towards a common goal.
Now that we talk more about the police-
—inst minded going over and talking about what expectations the law can bring-
-On the police and in the local police areas.
A bit like we mentioned earlier today ...
Both Ulf and I were in on-
-That the municipalities often turn to the police for support and help.
With increased pressure and ambition increase with the crime prevention work-
-Alt the local police area also to have to meet it, just as you said:
"You are equal parties."
-I can begin.
-Yes, please start.
It is probably a concern that Skr lifted in the investigation work, and by the municipality-
-That you are afraid that the police will take a step back:
"Now the municipalities have been given responsibility for the crime prevention work."
"Now we can keep up with cool operational efforts."
It is probably a concern that we have had.
- You may want to hook in. What do you think?
You can believe that I want to.
-The fears are true ... -not, you think.
No.
Of course, there may be individuals in this where it is not matched-
-But I think it was clearly stated in what Ulf Johansson told about earlier.
We within the Police Authority, although it takes a long time to build up-
-So we have made a very powerful promotion since 2015
-As the crime prevention work within the Police Authority-
-and now where we are today, this is-
-If not the heaviest, so at least at least as heavy-
-As other important strategic orientations of police work.
I dare to promise that the police are ready and will not back away-
-When the municipalities are given this responsibility.
On the contrary, it is long-awaited-
-Just to get that equal party.
As you said, Greta, we have had municipal police officers since 2015-
-For all municipalities.
That activity is there many regions-
— as now also in conjunction with growth, which was told about earlier in the day-
-Will expand, so we really ensure-
-That it is not a municipal police officer who is responsible for four or five municipalities.
There is a municipal police officer at each municipality.
Then we also want a co-part-
-On the municipality's side, which is a clear entrance.
It is missing in many municipalities.
Where the municipal police can run around to a lot of administrations-
-For the questions are not coordinated in any way.
You cannot turn to a place and have an entrance into the municipality.
So it's longed for this.
We promise that we will stand up for.
-Bra, Håkan.
-Yes.
Good, Håkan.
All you municipalities that have received these indications, this is a fellow
-That police legislation does not change.
They are responsible for this question-
-No like we will get it in the municipality.
You have to take it into consideration, and then you have to have Håkan's words in the back-
-That it's a joint job.
The police should not reverse, but take a step forward.
There you have to be a little responsive to the way the situation looks out-
-And you get to talk to your police locally, and what you have expectations.
We have talked a lot on the county administrative boards.
What we get from the municipalities-
-The coupled to the police, is very much about ...
We believe that there will be greater demands on collaboration with the police.
The municipalities will demand it, more will demand it.
Part of it will be about the statistics, getting statistics from the police.
That police officers should feel comfortable with what statistics they can disclose.
It is a dialogue we have had long before this bill came too.
There, the police are very clear about "that we should get it".
There should be a clarity around it.
Then we also see the importance of the police presence-
-No obviously both in socially vulnerable areas, but also on land- and sparsely populated
-Just to get this continuity-
-In contact with police officers who will work more strategically.
We have municipalities that describe that they have relay police, just like relay doctors.
You get placed there for a while.
Then there will be a new one.
It will be so difficult to constantly start in this.
With future legislation, we believe that this will be important for the municipalities-
-To get continuity in it, so it's great to hear what you say.
In terms of growth and police presence out-
-If mind in memory that it is only at the turn of the year that we have just passed-
-which it is really the net supplement-
-When the police were promised a number of years ago and really got ...
It is only now that it has generated in real police officers.
Recruitment and then 2.5 years of training before the police officers are in place.
It is only now and in the coming years that we will see this growth.
If you say "we haven't seen it yet", no, you haven't been able to do it-
-For they can only be retrieved from a recruitment and a police training.
There has been a question.
Can you explain what Ulf meant when he said:
"The police should focus on situational crime prevention."
What does that mean?
Social prevention against individual-
-Situated prevention against location or problem, to simplify it.
It is other actors in society that have real tools-
-To working with prevention against individuals.
It is the municipalities, not least within the social services, within the school-
-But it is also the health care, which is partly, it is not called county council anymore ...
Regions.
The police have for many years sprung a little lost in this-
-and may have devoted a lot of resource time-
-To social prevention on its own, but without having the real tools-
-As is needed for it to have an effect.
And so we have neglected to work against the situational prevention.
It is more about a displacement in commuter movement.
We have to do what we can actually do, and have tools for within the Police Authority-
-In situational prevention.
But then we will contribute to the social prevention.
We do a lot of work there-
-But it assumes that this is done in collaboration with other actors who are on the tools.
The police must contribute both their knowledge, but the information we have about individuals-
— which need different measures against them, but also help and support-
-Excare etc., to be able to abstain from crime in the future.
It's not about leaving an area.
But the police's internal focus must be on:
"What is it above all we can do on the part of the police?"
After all, we have to spend our resource time on.
We got a question.
"In many local police areas, it is still the case that a lone municipal police"--
-"Responsible for pursuing collaboration against several municipalities at the same time."
"In some cases four to five municipalities or more."
"Is there a need for clearer national control towards the police regions?"
We who worked nationally had that fears and looked fairly immediately-
-That, unfortunately, it was so in some places that ...
It was not known from the beginning of 2015 what this role would mean.
What will be required, so to speak?
One was a little careful in some places to resource this-
-With an individual for a municipality fully, one hundred percent working hours.
I don't think it might have been absolutely necessary to have it that way.
One hundred percent for each municipality, for that dimension is quite different in the country-
-With 297 municipalities.
But there were several local police areas that added ...
... Four municipal police officers in a municipality, for that municipality was so large
-So it requires this.
That was what I meant...
We run the national line that in this growth work-
-So it must be a clear assignment to the police regions-
-As expanding the municipal police operations for now there is a legislative-
-As will set expectations for the police.
We cannot say that we welcomed this legislation-
-Now the municipalities will be given a responsibility and so we will not be able to it-
-For the municipal police have five municipalities that he will cooperate with-
-In this structural form that the municipalities are imposed.
Then I don't sit on it control ...
The control mechanism to decide on this.
It is something we communicate internally in the national operational department-
-In the strategies that are anchored with the police regions-
-That this we have to bet on, this we have to build out-
-To be able to meet the expectation that is on the police.
It became a little politician response, I felt, but ...
I thought we were moving on.
Do you feel ready, because now comes ...
-Now comes the big point.
-Sorry.
You talk, I'm quiet.
-Am I talk?
We asked the question: "What kind of support do you think you will need"-
-"linked to the new legislation?"
This is a question that we have been thinking a lot on the county administrative boards.
Both the type of support we should be able to contribute, when the legislation is in place-
-And even before, to be able to prepare.
But then also, what kind of support is this, then?
What was quite exciting to see with your answers where-
-That that is in good agreement with what we have thought of on the county administrative board.
Or what we think we will have to offer.
What we could see in the answers from you was that you ask for support.
Then it is support from three different perspectives.
Partly support for you who work as a coordinator in the municipalities-
-When it is very much about skills support or competence development.
It is about support for managers to understand what this means-
-And provide the right conditions for you who are coordinators.
Then it is about support for politicians-
-In the form of guidelines, education, be able to interpret the new legislation-
-In reaching a political consensus and a willingness to decision-
-To connected to crime prevention issues.
There were the big features we could see-
-In the answer that is about the type of support that may be needed.
What do you think about it?
It reflects the view I have received when I have talked to different municipalities.
It is that all municipalities say they need support-
-But it looks very different what kind of support you need.
This is what will be the challenge for us at national level-
-Finding the right level of support.
I think the county administrative boards will play a big role in this.
One municipality in one county may need one type of support, another municipality another.
Then you have to be responsive to it and adapt it to the needs that exist.
I think there are different levels, but also in different ways at the different levels.
Everyone does not say "we need support with mapping or training".
It looks very different.
The municipality's work looks very different.
It reflects the multifaceted work that is to be based on the local problem picture.
That it looks different, and that we work in different ways-
-But that the common should be the structure and that we can achieve success.
-What do you think?
-What to detract from that need for support ...
... as crime prevention coordinators and those who exist in day-
-The coordination function prescribed by the legislation shall be available, need-
-So I think the support directed at managers-
-And against politicians will be extremely important in this context.
And perhaps the most important thing, without detracting-
-For knowledge, tools are needed.
A lot is needed around the coordination work and the crime prevention functions.
In order to unless this crime prevention liability-
-Nore the entire municipal administration, for it must do-
-You have to think of crime prevention no matter where you work with it.
The kind of problem that we see more and more of, as unauthorized impact-
-Organized crime that is trying to get in.
Unfortunately, the municipalities are an easy business to enter-
-For it is a breadth of activities that the municipality conducts.
The criminal networks and organized crime try to do so.
Then you have to have a mindset in the entire municipality.
Therefore, it is the administrative managers, but not least the politicians-
-which should actually distribute the money for this work.
I think it's extremely important.
We have seen that.
In the municipalities where collaboration has worked really good-
-There you usually have a management commitment and support.
We see that in these municipalities it works very well.
In the municipalities with a crime prevention without support from above, it works worse.
One can be good down there, but it happens nothing-
-For you do not get the right resources, you do not have the right interlocutor with the police.
I think that is very important, and we have seen that in collaboration.
Now as we look at the annual report-
-When we did pretty simple, it's not called anymore-
-Samvariations, and checked on the county administrative board or
-ger municipal coordinator or municipal police support to-
— to make a knowledge -based work or action.
Then it will have an effect.
In any case, there is a co -variation there.
If you have received such support, the municipal police officers respond to a greater extent-
-That you also do these pieces in knowledge -based work or take action.
It feels like ... I'm drawing a wild interpretation.
A method nerd would say that one cannot do this much interpretation-
-But to me it sounds like we have structures-
-To support your local crime prevention.
They exist, as well.
We have a tradition of working with that and we are pretty good at that.
We need to bring politicians and managers on this-
-and that they understand what the law will mean.
What does it mean to give an assignment to reach to produce a position image-
-So that they really understand what they order and allocate resources in relation to it.
I am so a small blow to Brå now, together with the county administrative boards-
-Vaven Skr and the police are on a corner-
-Developing an education for managers and politicians.
We feel that there is a strong need to clarify this.
Someone has written in the chat and wants to tip about a course at Linnaeus University-
-which is called "Crime prevention methods and collaboration".
That training is open to police, municipality and county administrative boards-
-If you want to increase your knowledge in the subject.
-Is something more we want to say?
-We talked a little about the compensation.
Morgan Johansson said this is to be funded-
-And it will be financed by 200 million.
We have received that sum through the budget plug
-But it looks like it is still to be distributed ...
It should be distributed based on population in the municipalities.
The small municipalities, according to SKR, get too little money to do the work in a good way.
We will push this question hard against the Ministry.
It was an area that was lifted, linked to this issue.
Where is resources needed?
Both in time and in money.
Resources throughout the chain are incredibly important.
From national to regional and late local level.
We cannot bottlenecks in any of the levels.
Then we will not have the effect of the new legislation.
When we talk about resources, it becomes a transition to the next question.
It was then the fears, due to municipal legislation.
Just.
There, the resource question comes again among the answers.
There is a concern that resources will be insufficient.
That there will be a high workload out in the municipalities-
-To connected to the law.
But also that this might not-
-will create some actual difference.
That it will look like before.
This will be a paper product.
There will be quantitative solutions-
-As for some other satisfied.
Here also comes the connection to managers and politicians.
There is a concern that there is no knowledge at the decision-level-
-And that it will make the work stubborn out in the municipalities.
Many of the things come again.
Any thoughts about it?
Many of the fears are interesting, and you have to try to work with it.
But I think too-
-That most municipalities want to do right.
I usually try to say that to the county administrative board-
-When sometimes think the municipalities are trying to throw away.
"The municipalities do not want to throw away. They want to do right for themselves."
This is no exception.
I think you will do after best
-To work this way and work forward on this issue.
We should not get stuck in the legislation.
It becomes in some way like a wall.
The idea is that we should be behind the legislation.
Move on to work.
Get this commitment from management and managers to be able to work better forward.
Just not the eyes get stuck at the law, at this document-
-So I think we can develop the crime prevention work.
It is all of Sweden's interest, to prevent crime more effectively.
It's not just us in this room.
That is everyone's will.
We have to keep it in the back of our minds all the time.
These fears presented in a little more general perspective-
-That it will be a paper product and nothing will happen.
I actually don't think so, for the social discussion today about crime-
-Is so powerful and it happens so much that I am so naive-
-I think you want to do something about this.
Then, on the other hand, these fears that are linked to the fact that ...
We do not get enough resources to do what we want to do.
They should take more seriously and that these may cost significantly more-
-An these 200 million.
Both in the form of support and to build up the ability on the respective municipalities
-Where it doesn't already exist today.
I think we have to bring with us ... If you look at how far we have come-
-In the crime prevention work, without legislation-
-As by having produced support and having a crime prevention counsel-
-And how far we have come.
Almost all municipalities in the day-
-Have some type of cooperation supervision.
We do some type of survey.
We do a lot of work that is in the right path.
We have achieved this without legislation.
We must have that with us - that we do this.
This is not difficulty for us, we have done this before.
We know this.
There is a lot of support to get and the state wants us to do this now.
I see it as there are only opportunities ahead, to go further-
-And develop the crime prevention work.
It was a shame, because that was such a good entrance to the next picture.
I have to say my own too.
Pretty many answers were about not feeling
-That you are fully ready, or that you think that you account-
-Fast you are not really ready.
It is a concern-
-That now the legislation comes and I think my municipality is not ready.
It might be reflected in the diagrams that we looked at earlier-
-When you said, "I feel ready, but maybe not the municipality".
That it was also here in the text answers.
I agree with you, Greta, we've come a long way
-and that we should not lose.
We want it to develop and sharpen
-And then it becomes so easy to get stuck in what remains.
One must keep in mind that the law is not built-so-
-That on July 1, 2023 we will have everything in place, but then the team starts to apply.
This means that we have a starting distance.
We can start our work now.
Even though we start then, we have time to build this work.
No one will hit us on your fingers or hang us in the square-
-What we will have time to do this-
-And there is support and help to be obtained, especially from the parties standing there.
We should not be afraid of this, but see it as a carrot-
-Being able to develop the work locally.
You should not think about the date and feel that you do not have everything in place.
That's not how it's intended.
This is an indication of where we are going.
If you have not come all the way then, I do not think it is the whole world.
It is a work that we have to build on.
They should be better, year by year.
That's the idea.
Even though the law says a certain level-
-We can develop the work.
-An better transition.
-Right?
Then we have the last question we asked in the survey:
"What will be better thanks to the law?"
Just.
There I think we could see two slightly larger areas.
Partly it is about this work with bf-
-It will be able to take a seat in the municipality now.
It will be a clarified responsibility.
You believe can lead to the issue to be given priority, that it gets greater weightdd
-And that the system is getting better.
The second part is a bit about the craft around.
That it will be a more municipal-wide work-
-the horizontal perspective, as we have been inside and touched and talked about-
-As also came here in the chat.
That it is important that support, not only to the manager, but far out in the line as well.
It is something that we think will be important to support-
-Many different administrations in the municipalities because it is so clearly printed-
-That internal collaboration should be available.
Everyone should contribute to work-
-The precise as it says in our national crime prevention program.
It is also very clear in your answers.
That collaboration will be something else-
-Exmen better, both internally and externally.
I thought that if no questions come in now-
-The we thought to end in the positive spirit.
That it can get better.
Collaboration especially, can be better.
Yes!