To scratch, either to sharpen their claws or to highlight their territory,
is perfectly normal behavior for a cat.
But sometimes it can also be a sign of anxiety and anxiety,
and happen where we do not wish,
Most often on vertical surfaces such as door frames and furniture.
Feliway optimum with the brand new generation pheromones
reduces the cat's concern and counteracts the cat scratching where you don't want
Clean the place where the cat scratches as quickly as possible
And get a stable claw tree for your cat.
It is important that the claw tree is placed near where the cat sleeps.
Cat parents who used feliway optimum
Noticed that the cat claw less already after 7 days.
Always use for at least one month.
Feliway Optimum provides more security than ever
And causes the cat to stop scratching furniture.