MORNIN MORNIN MORNIN
Pussies before guys, y'all.
HHHAAAAAAA
What am I doing
Is this rolling?
Okay! Hi! Hello! How are you!
A while ago, me and Keyyo a.k.a Kristina were in Japan.
Phone company Comviq sent us there to record the youtube series "Welcome to Japan" which now is out on the internet!!!
The second episode came out on Thursday, in which we visit a fish market and a very special restaurant.
And this restaurant is the strangest thing I've ever been to in my entire life.
So many strange things were going on there,
so I thought that I'd make a story time today
to tell you about what really happened at the Kagaya restaurant.
I'd actually recommend you to watch the episode first, link in the description,
because what I'm about to tell you is all my own experience
it's some sort of bonus material if you wish,
which we chose not to show in the episode because it's basically too rude.
Yep.
Well, it all starts with us going to a fish market.
We were at the market and found out that we were being sent to a restaurant.
But we eat at restaurants every day, so we start wondering what we're supposed to record, there has to be some kind of content.
So we arrive at the restaurant, there's a frog on the outside of the building,
quite an ugly frog.
It's just like an ordinary residential, there are stairs going both up and down,
and photographer Erik and producer Teo goes down the stairs to the basement floor,
telling me and Kristina to wait on ground floor.
It takes a while until Teo comes back up
and when he does, he tells us that this restaurant is driven by a man, Mr Kagaya, and his mother
so his mother cooks the food while he does the entertainment.
So the thought was initially that me and Kristina should take part in this show.
I went like "oooooohhhhhhh no"
I don't like showing. I'm not a shower. I'm no entertainer.
I like sitting in my sofa, speaking to my camera.
That's the total amount of show I can expose myself to.
So I'm like "oh fuck"
But then it seemed like Mr Kagaya changed his mind in the last minute.
He's afraid that we won't understand his art so he wants to see how we are,
and if he likes us, then he'll allow us to be on the show.
I'm like *breathing out* gosh that's a relief,
there's a risk of us not getting along well, which means I don't have to do the show.
Yaasssss.
Naah. Mostly I'm thinking of how amazing it is to be in Japan and to challenge myself.
Of course. Mostly that.
But a tiny part of me is glad that I maybe don't have to pull off a show.
Anyway, we follow Teo down in the basement
and end up in the tinyest room, like 10 square metres,
no windows because it's in the basement, bright yellow walls,
and a super strong ceiling lamp, so it's not really cozy time.
We sit around a table, people drop in and finally it's full.
And that's when Mr Kagaya enters to start the show.
The first thing he does, after standing and saying "hello hello welcome"
... and he goes quiet...
... and then he hits his hands together and starts screaming.
Something like that.
We start giggling, like, what is going on
he he?
Then he starts singing a jingle. Very monotone. Goes like this:
DA-TADAAAAAAAAAAA. DA-TADAAAAAAAAAAA.
And he kinda squats down
and starts jumping, tiny jumps on both feet, towards me and Kristina
while he does like this.
So eventually he is all the way up in our faces doing like
DA-TADAAAAAAAAAAA
I know that the air is free for anyone but JESUS, MAN
So he's up doing datada in our faces and then, the first act is finished.
Then he brings in the menu, which is a coloring book.
He has written the menu himself.
And this menu, when he puts it on the table, we spot that there's a flower on the front page.
So he starts to...
... he starts to touch the flower.
Damn why am I so shy? He starts fingering the flower, okay.
He starts pulling the menu flower.
Do you understand me?
The flower is a vagina.
And this is just solely uncomfortable.
It's not only the fact that he is fingering it,
he's also making very... sensual noises.
I don't know why I find this disturbing. It may be because I'm kinda shy.
It could also be taht I'm not quite ready to start sexualising flowers.
The flower gets an orgasm. Which flowers get, of course.
I never thought I'd say those words.
So it's time for us to order.
And we have to sing our order.
So spontaniously, I don't feel like singing in a room full of strangers and with Splay's camera in my face.
And Kristina was like "I can't sing. What do we do?"
So we're like "let's do a rap!"
So Kristina does a rap while I go like "uhm chicka aah chicka uhm"
while I hold my hand like this because that's what they do in cool beatboxing movies
and the order is approved!
High five.
Anyway, we get our foods and drinks
I eat tofu and pumpkin and like, it is what it is, but it's actually kinda tasty.
So we have our dinner and when we're finished, he begins his final act.
He walks into his little walk in closet and puts a big piece of cardboard in front of the entrance.
A couple of minutes go by and suddenly, a puppet frog appears.
This frog starts talking to us: "helloooo?"
We're like "hello".
"What's your name?"
"... Clara, Kristina."
"Have you seen my cousin?"
No. We haven't seen your cousin.
"Do you know my cousin's name?"
No. How do you expect us to know what your cousin's name is.
"My cousin's name... is Dick."
Well of course your cousin's name is Dick, anybody surprised in here? Didn't think so.
So this bloody frog puppet starts chanting "DICK! DICK! DICK!"
"COME OUT DICK!" and we're like oouuuuhhh should we really? Couldn't Dick just stay where he is?
"COME OUT DICK!!!" and then when he has shouted this like 75 times
he kicks away the piece of cardboard,
and jumps out wearing a frog suit,
so he puts this frog puppet as some kind of genital
gallops over to our table and starts humping our faces.
Just let that sink in for a second.
dick, dick dick
grwaaaaaaaaaahhh
*humping sounds*
I don't even know.
Mr Kagaya, you're wacky.
Seriously. Get help.
Do you understand what I meant when I said that this is the craziest thing I've experienced?
So like I said, this is what happened at the Kagaya restaurant
which never made it to the "Welcome to Japan"-episode.
That's all for this video, and don't forget to go watch the episode!! I think it's hilarious.
Also if you watch it and comment and like, maybe me and Kristina can travel to other places and that would be nice.
Anyway, this video is at it's end,
Take care and I'll see you guys as usual next week.
Bye!
PUSSIES BEFORE GUYS Y'ALL!!!
Oh god aah iiih ooh help no