Hello!
Do you know what I have done?
I have downloaded all
My old pictures from the picture diary.
All!
Holly ...
... cow!
Forgive in advance that the light changes a lot.
It's a lot of clouds
And the sun outside.
You who are my age - a little -,
I am 23 - you will probably have well -to -do
Colorful memories of the picture diary.
You who may be a little younger
Maybe not at all know what the picture diary is.
However, maybe dayviews call a small clock?
I had the picture diary between 2007 and 2010
So isch from being 12 until I was 16.
You could say that the picture diary was the Instagram of the time.
Although you were not as selective with what pictures you draw.
It was not uncommon for you to go for a school day,
Take Kamran, Foot Type 50 Photos,
Get home and upload everyone on the picture diary.
You had no barrier there.
Or was it so because I went in seven?
Anyway, the picture diary which is nowadays called Dayviews will close down.
Dayviews, the picture diary will not be advanced anymore.
... there will be no more I mean hi hi hi
So that's why I went in and saved every picture from 2007 to 2010.
And today I thought we would look at them.
A, what do you say?
I say we can start.
Ok, first picture.
Huh.
Hello and welcome to my picture diary from 2006 through - I lied to you.
August 16, 2006. Here I am 12 years old.
Here you also get a hint of what a fantastic taste I had in decor.
From being a kid, I had pink walls with big rabbit stickers like a board.
12-year-old Clara thought "No. That is baby wallpaper. Now I'm a big girl. Now I want other wallpaper.
Check this out!
Lime green wallpaper with such large pink flowers.
Fy fuck.
If you easily get sick then you do not want to be in my old room.
On the other hand, pink and lime green were my favorite colors.
I had to choose wallpaper all by myself.
Mama thought it was a bit crisp and encouraged me to choose this.
Since I also raised in a family that does not have so much money.
So the next time I tapyaized about my room then I was 18.
It was fun to bring so cool gymnies or the first date home.
What else do we have?
Hohohoho.
Creshing brills.
13 years I am here.
I have long hair and I have started to get quite a lot of pimples.
So my whole forehead was like a small hot tub.
I remember once when a girl in the class, so damn good, but she just like this:
"Ah Clara, you have something in the forehead."
And I thought inboard:
Ah I know.
Unfortunately, I can't just remove them.
And I then answered aloud:
"I know. My cat tore me."
Kungiiiiii
Ooooohoooooheho
Selfie session.
Here I am 13 years old.
Don't have as much pimples.
It may have been for periods.
I do not remember.
And it is also my acid, Kimberly who is 11.
I don't really know what to say about this picture.
I also do not know what it is we are looking at.
Because at this time you had like ... you couldn't see yourself in the camera.
At the same time, we are and we are very aware that we are footing ourselves.
It is a mystery.
And that is so bad.
I also thought I was pretty good at it.
Here I have made a little, a little more tan in the skin.
K. got red hair and I got brown hair.
We have both got brown eyes.
We also got whose little Kajallinije.
I mourn a little that I still can't photoshop.
I could have learned quite well.
What do we have?
... oooohhhh.
AAAAAA.
This is a bit cute.
God what a little.
This was also the period where everyone was forties.
Except me.
Everyone had bleached their hair white.
Everyone had so here tupped
Brown cream
Remember Those Days?
Ah God, I wasn't cool.
Here I am on my way to a Fridrot competition.
I jumped height and ran heck.
A, sweet.
Ahhh for cute pictures.
To all 13 year olds: It gets better.
So puberty met me like a frisbee.
In the back of a frisbee golf course.
Eij.
There are 13 -year -olds today who go up in the morning and make up it full and then go to school.
This girl did not.
This girl had never even heard of hair spray.
Fun that you are not a teenager anymore.
Yyyyyyy
My mind and interest in fashion have still kicked in.
Lime green Winter Jacket.
Again the favorite color.
And then we match it with an Aik cap.
Did I know what AIK was?
No.
Did I watch football?
Which team am I on?
Sweden.
I tried.
So cool I was.
Do you remember what I said if everyone else were forties?
Everyone else had so tufted hair, push-up bra, started drinking.
I was doing this.
Oh my good ... no what is this?
Charming.
Oh good.
I think I've been like the definition of White Trash when I was 13.
I mean I was pretty cute when I was a kid.
???
Ment the years in between?
Can you like to see there in the background?
Do you see what comes flying?
Yes, it is puberty like a fucking truck.
A. Nice stuff.
No but check!
Here I am at a Fridrot competition.
From the time I was twelve to being 18, I jumped high jump.
And I burned for it.
I loved high jump.
Please note the little tongue here.
I couldn't skip the bar without pray ...
This is Stockholm.
Please note the large Clara grill here and then there is a owed where Clara stands here.
And then Papa thought: "Clara, now we have to take a picture."
What else do we have?
Oh good God what is it?
I remember we sat and played mit you know with such IQ-test-Puzzle,
All pieces look different and so will get it together into a square.
We took these pieces and I threw them up in the air and my sister photographed when they fall down.
And then I would kind of look a little funny.
I look like a five year old on crack type.
Just that, I had an answer period too.
I never think I talked about it but I thought high school was a very difficult period.
In short, my friend and I had a brawl, and it was so much bigger than it had to be.
And our parents pulled in and we stopped socializing.
And then I realized like this "Shit, she is kind of my only friend that I like to spend time with."
Then I have other friends in the class but I do not spend time with them.
And suddenly I was like this.
And like that had no friends outside the school.
And it was really hard.
And then started taking these pictures that I thought showed how I felt.
This was also at the time there as well as such emo pictures
There ... they were either far too overexposed or undexoned was trendy.
I would like to belong to emo.
Here is also fun.
This is the day before I turn 15.
And as we all know, it's a team of having a helmet when cycling and when you under 15.
And this is a pretty grinding description of how strong my teenage revolution was.
Non-existent.
When I was 15 I thought it was fun with - A but it way too bright in here -
Thought it was a bit cool to take some artsy photographs.
The caption is: "I don't know who I am."
* sings* "I don't know who I am but I know I'm yours"
Here I have come second and third in some district championship I believe.
I think I have come second in high jump and third in hedge running.
Wooo, here I cut my hair short, God.
This is right at the beginning of nine.
And I cut off my hair.
This was the first picture I took on my hair too when I was on my way home from the hairdresser.
After all, it's not really a nice frill.
Again: Hair products.
In with some shit.
Because now it just hangs there, Clara, I asked it.
It was probably the same day when just cut it.
The snelog was fucking my best friend through high school.
I loved this hairstyle so hard.
It was damn the best thing I did when I was 16.
Again: Artsy image.
Black and white.
This was also when you started drawing mustaches on their fingers and prayed
Frock coat!
Sacre Coeur!
Je Suis Francaise!
Come over here and kiss my French lips!
Not this a frill that type all image teachers have?
Myyyy.
Check!
Also a hairstyle that is a bit on growth.
Damn.
I see the uncertainty in my gaze.
Did not like being in the picture at that time.
Little did I know that I would live on putting videos on myself on the internet.
If I had known it, I would have received heart fibrillation.
Friends, these were all pictures.
Now I have not shown it all because I have so very boring pictures on my picture diary.
But this was easy and most interesting.
But still fun.
Imagine that these pictures have put out on the internet for everyone's.
Ok friends, this was everything I had for this time.
Thank you for checking.
Don't forget to write comment, subscribe, share this vidon with friends!
So you can take it beautifully and then we will see you just as usual next Monday.
Bye.