Damn!
No no.
Please.
Give me the Ronny bag!
My name is Bosse.
Huh?
Bosse.
Bosse Nilsson is my name.
But it was Ronny I would take the bag off.
I would pick up the bag from Ronny.
Ronny is at home and waving.
His guy has got chickenpox.
I am a substitute today.
Hell fucking.
Are you new to work or?
I am on work testing.
Stefanovich has begun to take in a lot of unemployed from
The employment office and receive support allowance and crap.
Does Stefanovich get money from the state because you are his torpedo?
Just.
Is it really nice that they do so?
I don't have to jiddra with the a-cash and stuff.
And then I get experience and an entrance to the industry.
It is very difficult to get a job!
This could have been a good job to have on my resume.
Well that's right.
It is a tough labor market.
It is.
Is it good cash to wiggle or?
Maybe had been something for me.
No, I don't want to say that.
I have been trying to get a full -time service for a few years
But the company apparently benefits more from not hiring me.
Sometimes it goes for fucking for several weeks without calling.
Oh fuck.
Yes it is not so damn fun.
I have a damn bills and two kids there at home too.
So damn not cheap.
I mean.
Had they said this, that I would keep on
Jock around with the car and that you would come here and…
Now you are going to shoot me too.
Know in fuck if I had accepted this even.
Fixed…
It was actually Ronny that I would "Wasta".
Yes, as I said, he is with a sick child.
Yes but then we can do so I take the bag,
And then I shoot you in the leg instead.
What do you think about that?
Yes it would be fantastic if it was possible to solve it that way.
Damn it was nice.
Thanks!
Yes, oh ...
Ouch!!
You, would it be okay if I use you as a reference then when I do my resume?
Reference?
Yes absolutely, this you did great!
Down on your knees!
What the hell?
What the hell are you doing?
AJ as hell.
Your little pig!
Apapap!
Then we take it damn quiet.
Elin, we do not fire weapons without my command.
How many times should I have to say it!
Can I have the bag?
So, who are you?
Are you a police officer or?
Yes.
Or so ...
I am on internship.
Plugs for police.
This is year class 6, Gripvallsskolan.
They are on prao.
If I get the bag so we come from here!
Hello?
What did I just say?
Do you go on CSN then or?
Sure.
Oh fuck.
Study debt up over the ears.
Damn .. I don't get a job after this I sit in the shit.
We just said that before you arrived.
That it is a damn tough labor market.
After all, there are no jobs!
That's enough!
Put down the weapons everyone!
I will bring this with your Miss.
And we'll see how fun it gets
When it comes to the development talks this fall.
If I get the bag now so we get out of here!
What the hell does the military here?
Turn if we have everything under control ...
No, stop it.
Do not shoot.
I'm only on work testing.
Take the bag.
It must be a-cash for me.
You…
Home service,
Is it difficult to get a job there?
Yes.
There are almost no places left now, after all,
When people have to work until they are 80 years old.
Most people have time to work to death before they get so old that they need care.
But Einar here, he is struggling.
Next year, then there will be a pension.
Nice huh?
What did you say?
It is absolutely fucking incredible that it should be so difficult to get an ordinary ...
Full -time service!
What did you say for something?
A full -time job.
A full -time job?
A full -time job!
And then they struck the last real employment contract.
And my children.
It was the story of the full -time service.
Wow!
Now it's time to go to bed.
But Mom.
Not already!
Yes!
When I grow up, I want a unicorn and a full -time job.
But you realize that there are no full -time services really your stupid.
Good night grandmother!
Good night my kids.
Sweet Dreams.