Yes but exactly.
No I agree.
Just now.
Sure!
But you, what we talked about yesterday?
Just.
Do you have time with it now or?
No I think it feels like we ... I just want to get it done right away.
Great!
Then I come by right away.
Just picked up also wanted so we're at you in a while.
Or by the way, run out and meet us instead and we will pick you up on the road.
Good, hello.
How's the guy?
Good.
Miss told us what had happened and that is nothing to care about, okay?
It is he who is stupid, right?
Have you done any fun in school today then?
Not so much.
We were in the forest.
Cozy.
Did you play and so?
We grilled sausages and Miss read some fairy tales.
Be good with sausage.
What kind of fairy tales Miss read for you then?
Red Riding Hood.
Red hat, is it good?
But is it not a little uncomfortable when the wolf dresses up,
And does the Red Hood cheat in that way?
No, it's not at all.
Dad thinks that is really scary.
"Why do you have such big teeth?"
"It's because I can eat you!"
You old man, we'll just pick up Henrik a turn on the way home.
So should we fix one thing, is it okay?
Okay.
When does Bolibompa start?
Bolibompa starts at sex, we can get home to that.
Are we watching together later, right?
Hello!
How's it going?
Yes, think it will be damn nice to get this done.
Yes I get it.
What about wanted then?
Is it good?
Yes.
"Ville-Viking" right?
Yes, "Ville-Viking".
Yes that is good.
Do you have the address or?
Yes I know where we are going.
It is good.
Damn wouldn't you sell this car by the way?
Yeah absolutely.
I posted an ad on the block as well.
But you are fucking a mail bomb by 7000 Mohammed jihad
Who will buy the car for nothing.
"I buy the car for one and 700 SEK"
No thanks that is SEK 30,000 in the ad.
"I buy the car for one and 700 SEK now!"
Yes it is completely senseless
You know I had a friend who would sell.
He posted his number.
It ended up with him having to change numbers.
They came home to him with their families,
, their goats and camels and all the crap they have.
Stands there and just “You sell!
You sell a friend! ”
Absolutely fucking incredible.
No.
The blators should stick to baking kebab pizzas.
Well, they do it damn well.
Haha, that's damn true.
But what if SD wins the election.
Then there is no more kebab pizza for us.
But damn, wins SD, they are well allowed to introduce such a pizza test.
The immigrants who bake the best pizzas may promise to stay.
And you would sit in that jury then or?
Yes, you have squeezed a lot of pizzas in your days.
You know that!
You know the Thai massage down here at the corner?
Yes.
It can be left, for that jury I would like to sit in.
Well.
With happy endings then or?
Do you like huh?
Happy endings?
Wanted is behind it.
Wanted, you wanted some Thai massage.
You had paid Thai massage Ville.
So nice with Thai massage wanted!
Am i running wrong now or?
Where is it somewhere?
Grästorpsvägen.
Grästorpsvägen?
You know where we looked at that Saab a while ago.
Don't you remember that?
Yes Yes.
It's right here.
It sure is.
Then you turn left there.
So I don't understand why you don't get GPS.
It's great!
GPS.
I can't sit and peel with a computer while driving.
It is not certain.
Yes, but you come up anyway, right?
Lol.
You I think it's time for us to play that game now.
Yes Yes.
Wanted, should we play hide and seek?
Yeah!
Then you must not look now, so you count to 50.
So we will two hide.
Okay?
Should we do as we did last time or?
Yes.
One, two, three, four, five, six, seven…
You don't peek out now huh?
Wanted to?
No, now you have to start over from one again so we have time to hide.
So you have to promise Dad that you close your eyes properly now.
Okay.
Not a peek now wanted, it is important!
One two three four five,
six, seven, eight, nine,
ten, eleven, twelve, thirteen, fourteen,
fifteen, sixteen, seventeen, eighteen, nineteen,
twenty, twenty -one, twenty -two, twenty -three,
Twenty -four, twenty -five, twenty -six, twenty -seven, twenty -eight…
Yes?
You, take and keep your fucking son in school!
It's quiet, it's quiet.
No one is here.
Forty six, forty seven, forty eight.
Fifty!
I see you!
No but?
He found us right away too!
What a little racker we have back there.
You, you will have no more problems in kindergarten with Abdoul.
Should it be, you say.
Promise it!
Mm.
Good.
Good work.
Yes damn well fought!
Henrik: Damn you can let me off at the pizzeria later.
I got so damn craving for kebab pizza when we talked about it before.
Dad: You have earned a good blattepizza.
Henrik: No, damn it was scabbling!
Ville: Blattepizza!
Dad: It is the fyfan those who bake that shit.
Henrik: Are you going home and jaw or?
Dad: Yes, Mom has cooked some pork pancake for us,
So we'll check out Bolibompa tonight together we thought.
Have a little cozy.
Henrik: End good everything good then?
Dad: Exactly!