Having made a movie with Crazy Pictures has been ...
One...
Rollercoaster.
Drive!
UFO Sweden is about Denise, a foster home placed teenage rebel
who lived in the belief that her father died in an accident up in the mountains.
But when she gets signs that it might not be so
If she is looking for this association UFO Sweden.
Then I welcome you all to today's board meeting.
And explains here with the meeting opened.
I think it will be so damn fat!
Although we have had more resources than we ever had
So the ambition has also been so much bigger.
When it is a take there may be a car for 70 kilometers per hour and gossip.
We initially thought there would be very digital effects
But it has become more and more that we could do a lot on the spot.
So that is not possible to fake!
We have wanted to create a cinematic experience
An adventure that one should want to turn off the lamps and sit in the bio darkness to see.
UFO Sweden is really the story of the little man in the great spectacle.
It will be a very different Swedish film.
And that's cool.
This is such a movie that I wanted when I was growing up.
Who is ready for a little UFO hunting?
Born Ready!
Turn on double coffee pots!
This will be our largest field survey ever.
My wish is that people have an amazing movie experience.
That you get to know these characters, that you got to be on an adventure
But also that you come out and look up at the sky and ...
Wonder.
Want to know a home run?
I don't think we are here alone.