Ouch!
No!
Ah ..
It's five o'clock!
No, but I had stopped!
No, my guts!
Oh, coffee stains on the uniform.
It's not true!
No, they don't go away either!
Okay ... A positive attitude reinforces the feeling of team.
A positive ..
We get OB anyway, that's good!
So you get some extra money ..
Ob?
OB, when there is war after five o'clock you get OB.
What, we have no ob ...
Do you have no one .. Do you have no OB?
We have no ob.
Huh?
After all, you should bring it up with the union in that case.
What do you have in hourly wage?
60 ...
60 bucks?
You know that SEK 90 is the minimum wage huh?
We will have a planning day on Sunday too, type how we should attack you and so on,
I don't get any money for that either.
After all, they can't take advantage of you anyway.
You have to get your free days, it's teams on it you know.
Damn what soft you seem to have this.
Yes, yes, but it's pretty good actually.
A pastry, here too.
But you lead anyway.
It looked great when you came running here before too.
You seem to be very good I think.
But what the hell ... Do you have toilets in the trenches?
Yes, we only had pissers before, but someone complained to the discrimination ombudsman.
After all, not everyone has the penis.
Oh fuck.
Yes, maneuver, good!
You?
It has run a little ..
Breast-Bengt here has jumped on the suicide front, so I need you for the evening pass.
AHA okay...
I feel like I'm starting to feel a little bad, so I would love to go home.
But then you have a medical certificate for that?
No I do not have it...
No, but then it is so that if you are going to have a lawful homecoming with
Compensation and everything then a medical certificate is required.
I really have to get this schedule together now.
I understand it, it's mostly ..
I might be able to take that pass.
But you are German ...
Yes good!
But you, then you take the passport.
And remember our motto:
"A positive attitude reinforces the gut feeling".
Requirements ... the feeling of team ...
Yes!
Are you cute since before you go on the next pass, just check the toilet a little neighbor?
It looks too damn boring there, now that we have the coffee table here and everything.
Absolutely ... Absolutely ... I fix it.
Employee of the Month!
Oh thanks!
How fun.
Oh fyfan ...
Sub -text: Alban Bergström