Welcome to the new video on the channel
Today we will deal with LED lighting strips
Circulation LED lists for kitchen
There have been no Ikea products on the channel in a long time, but now that I was in the store I found a campaign (sale) of this model
The default price is around 22 euros
In my opinion it is quite a lot, even if they are real
Ikea has accustomed us at substantial quality at fairly affordable prices
Unfortunately, LEDs from Ikea are quite expensive.
The selling price of these LED strips is approx.
7 euros
So i bought 2 pieces such orbit led strips
Parameters: 60cm / 300 lm / 5.4W
Two such moldings are enough for me to replace the lighting in the kitchen with new ones above the kitchen counter. Think
However, these strips do not require the more common 12V, only 24V tensions
Cent
of such power supplies outside Ikea starts from about 10 euros LED, I had to spend on the power supply
The cheapest 24V power supply in IKEA is connecting (cost about 17 euros)
I saved on the strips, and on power supply no longer ....
But I preferred not to waste time adjusting a power supply from another manufacturer (except IKEA)
Thanks to this I can be sure that everything will match
24V power supply.
The effect is limited to 19W
A strip is 5.4 W, so we can operate up to 3 such strips
The power supply is modular, let's
Connect the ends of the strips
Ikea also has more expensive wireless power supply, but they are definitely more expensive
.
Then we increase the cost of such installation even more
Therefore, my choice fell on the basic model of the power supply.
It is not a very modern design, rather classic, but it is enough
You can't use the switch
The use of a traditional switch is also not a problem in my opinion
.
Such a switch is definitely more reliable than control of external servers
The split itself supports the power up to 3A
.
Remember, however, to limit the power supply to 19W
There is also such information on the packaging.
Therefore, we can operate up to 3 such strips.
What will probably interest you is ...
How does such a circulation light up
I will demonstrate it in a moment.
Let us
See what we get in the sales package.
In addition to the list itself, we also get one
Clip to screw in the cabinets
Screws
included
After screwing the guide we can
mount
The list
with
clips
The
looks much more aesthetic
Connect
LEDs
The plug
is
detachable.
Connect Power Supply Connect LED
-—-—-
Strips to the distributor
LED
However, it turns out that it is completely unnecessary tell
In the comments what you think about IKEA leadership offer
Write what you think
I also ask to like and subscribe