Welcome to this week's Thursday tip in Excel, with me David Stavegård
It's time to get started with an excel file again, and now we've been given a task
Make a histogram over the wage distribution This is, after all, fictional names,
fictional wages, it's just for you to see how to do histograms, you have control over
Take a look here you'll see ...
You simply go into info, choose statistical graphs and choose
Histogram and pang we have got it out.
Histogram works so that it collects a number of different values in groups
and counts how many are
So here we have between 22,500 and 31,300
How many of the salaries are in between right -clicks you and choose add
Data labels, so it also calculates how many they are.
But, it won't be that great, there will be some strange numbers here.
Excel tried to be smart.
You're smarter.
That's why we drive like this.
Right -click and select Format the shoulder, and look at options for shoulder ...
Here's a little luring: Do you see that you can scroll down here
It's not that often you have to do it, but if we open this a little instead.
So you see the values out here from the beginning ...
So you should get to see automatically it is Excel suggests
Interval width, here you can say that we want an interval of SEK 3000 in salary.
Then it turns out all the intervals by 3000 in step length.
Or we can say number of intervals, yes, we may want 3 intervals
It might be a little bit, but maybe eight intervals.
Then it draws out how many have salary in these intervals
Then it is like this, there are some that are at the bottom,
as we may not care about exactly where they are located, and the same
We may not care about them either, because it gets a little plot like that ...
So instead you can say "interval for the highest values" if we were to write
60,000 here, then it takes with everyone who is
greater than 60,000 and counts them in the same bar, and the same 'intervals for the lowest'
For example, if we say 30,000 here,
Then it takes with everyone who has up to 30000 and counts them ...
So it becomes a little easier to understand this, then you can look good for this graph litigran.
Yes, something like this you can get then, and this is how you work with
Histogram in Excel, it's very neat, one can change
You just go in here and say how many intervals you want or
Or what interval width you want.
You don't just have to do this on pay, this is not just a matter of pay,
This can do this on shoe sizes, lengths, ages, I don't know
Go wild, simply
My name is David Stavegård, big thanks for looking at this, we will see you next Thursday, again,
Just as always.