We want Jönköping with its fantastic sights and destinations
should sprout by life and movement.
We also want to use our strength as a meeting and event city
And be the obvious stop for both fairs but also for the tournament of music and culture.
We want to be one of Sweden's best visitor destinations, hang with
A place benefits are about its conditions
And we have identified the situation, nature and our inheritance as particularly important.
The situation and nature may not require any direct explanation
But our legacy is about all those who built the place before us:
Amalia with her polka pigs, Husqvarnfabriken and others.
We have a strong association life and the collaboration between our acts.
We are used to cooperation, we help
It is an incredible strength and opportunity for success,
It gives us a lead on many levels.
Our target groups place ever higher demands that we as a destination company
Works with a big heart for society and the planet.
The hospitality industry plays an important part of the transition to a more sustainable society.
Destination Jönköping wants to help lead the transition to as sustainable place as possible.
What attracts visitors to a place is what you can do and experience.
More and more people want experiences where you feel involved and that are developed.
We work with culture and sporting events, experiences that you do together others create memories.
In our municipality and region we have operations with extensive knowledge and prominent research.
By taking advantage of and enabling meetings within these core areas
Where participants, nationally and internationally, catch the eye of Jönköping
We increase the attractiveness of the place and create the conditions for skills supply.
Travel changes, we go from being a place with strong business travel addiction
To a place where private tourism is taking an increasing place.
We are now working hard to increase companies' opportunities to take advantage of this trend,
Finding new travel reasons for private travelers.
By creating commitment and collaborations,
enable these conditions and identify forces
So we position ourselves as a meeting and event city both nationally and internationally.
Just look like Dreamhack, Oringen, unique music festivals, international bicycle competitions and countless knowledge meetings.
A good hosting is often crucial to how a place is experienced
We must therefore together make sure that inspiration and information can be found in places where the visitor wants it,
Both digital and in person.
We therefore work at the destination very much to train, inspire and develop the host in our place.
We want a program that appeals to many.
We want a close dialogue and a close Samabete with local and national organizers,
This leads to the broad cultural offering offered at Jönköping Theater and Jönköping's concert and congress.
All that we have now told about is a prerequisite for creating a sustainable hospitality industry destination
And we would like that work at Destination Jönköping lead
But we can't do it alone, but we have to do that with you all and your commitment.
Together we will create an attractive place for both residents and visitors.
A place we can feel proud of, Jönköping.