The day I go and buy the magazine it is over in my life.
I have more to give.
Sweden is getting more and more "job sonaries", people over 65 who combine jobs and pensions.
Why?
And what should a pensioner who works think about?
We try to find out in this feature.
A joy in life.
Not only to say thank you and goodbye, but continue some more.
It is above all fun.
Lars Fallgren had a full working life in the advertising industry behind Sig-
-When it was time to retire.
But the sofa cover did not attract-
-Instället was involved in starting the thunderstorm "rents a pensioner" in Stockholm.
In recent years he has written children's books.
I'm probably an uncle who thinks something should happen in life.
Are the children's chefs happy-
-Above my figures, it pleases me.
My ambition is that it will be a theater in the first step.
I hope so.
It would be great fun to be involved and do it.
Figures from the Pension Authority show that the number of "job sonaries" increased constant-
-In the 2010s.
According to a survey from Jönköping University-
-As every third person over 60 jobonar or plan to be.
When you have done something that you may be quite good at, you get huge feedback.
And maybe you can get some crown.
I am absolutely convinced.
For those who want to combine jobs and pensions, there are some things to keep track of.
Of your general pension you can withdraw 25, 50, 75 or 100 % per month-
-Over how much you work.
And from 2023, according to the Employment Protection Act
-do you right to work up to the age of 69 without getting rid of your employment-
-On the basis of age.
Also keep an eye on the income of pension and job-
-Compassed and the limit for state tax is around SEK 52,000 per month.
Working longer is always profitable.
In addition to receiving pay, your future pension is also increasing.
For example, one can sit on boards of the company-
-Lite depending on the skills they need.
Are there any risks to continue working as a pensioner?
Yes, there is, of course.
Especially if you work too much.
How are you treated as a working elderly by individuals and society?
Very positive.
We asked the question to several people:
Why do you use us 60-plus?
"It's so safe. You may be a little long, but it's positive and safe."