He came as a refugee from Iraq to Sweden as a 13-year-old.
Today he is 30 years old and a millionaire.
Mohammed Salih is a savings economist, stock market inspector and Instagram profile.
He is a podder, writer and dad-
-And today he is here to talk about his journey towards the million.
-Welcome here, Mohammed.
-Thanks.
So fun to have you here.
We will hear about your trip to the million today.
-Do you have always been interested in savings?
-Yes, I've been.
I can remember back to when I came to Sweden.
Already then I started to take an interest in savings and the entrepreneurial.
Now it is prescribed, but before New Year-
—I used to ask my dad to buy out a bunch of big rocket-
-And then I sold them pieces.
In this way I made money and I know my family always needed more money-
-So I tried to contribute as much as possible.
You and your family fled from Iraq to Sweden.
Can you tell us a little about it?
Yes, and it wasn't that we took the flight from Iraq and landed in Sweden.
Without it was a long escape route, we were on the run for several years-
-And did a lot of middle stops before we landed in Sweden.
We are incredibly grateful for that.
So a long escape route that resulted in the new home Sweden.
-You grew up in Ronneby.
-Yes, first Rosengård and then Ronneby.
Or Kallinge that is the metropolis for me.
It's just there that I feel at home.
That you have this escape in the luggage, how has it affected your view of money and finances?
This is probably what has made me so interested and constantly want money.
It creates such security.
During the escape trip we did not even have money for food and clothes.
Then Mom got to beg clothes and food.
Although I will never end up in that situation in Sweden-
-So money is a damn security for me and the dependence on money comes from it.
What does it mean for you to be in Sweden?
It is difficult to explain with words.
My love for Sweden is really boundless.
There is nothing that I am so grateful for-
-As Sweden opened its arms to our family.
For after 13 years on escape-
-or 13 years of uncertainty before getting this residence permit-
-It can't describe how nice it felt.
-When did you discover the stock exchange?
-When I was around 22-23, quite a few years ago.
It was through a friend actually.
We were going to MMA training.
I drove a car, he sat next to it.
I'm pretty social so I like to talk.
He was not as social at all so I asked what he was doing.
Then he bought and sold shares on his mobile and earned a lot of money-
-On this short part we drove.
Then I felt that I had to learn about shares if it is possible to make money via mobile.
Before you put your savings goal to become a millionaire, what did your life look like then?
Can you get a snapshot from Mohammed Back in the Day?
Then I had bought my first apartment.
I had no savings goals, and without savings goals it is quite difficult to save money.
Because then you feel that you have nothing to save for.
An economic yet spent Mohammed who did not care very much about economics.
I had no budget at that time, but I took life as it came.
It was probably more before.
How did it go when you decided on the million?
Money is very taboo in Sweden.
No one talks about it, you must never ask what anyone earns, hardly what anyone has in interest.
I wanted to try to change that, document everything I do-
-and become a millionaire before I'm thirty.
How did it go at the beginning of your investment trip?
It went okay, actually.
I went on the big raffle before I started Mohammed's path to the million.
I knew I would buy a lot of investment companies and buy very wide.
I had 150,000 that I did not invest right away, because I had already burned myself once.
So I started by buying very broadly, as if I managed an index portfolio.
Slowly but surely I built it up and the money rolled in, the monthly salary came in.
It felt good.
How did it feel when you really got to see this interest rate on the interest effect come?
It took off after a while.
The money only grew-
-And sometimes they made balance updates two, three days in succession.
I had SEK 10,000-balance updates, but they came more often and more often-
-In and with the stock market just going up and interest on interest was becoming more and more powerful.
It was a great feeling.
You hear about it very often, but it is even more powerful when you get to experience it.
Did you make any changes to your everyday life to increase savings?
Yes I did.
I knew this will not last for any length of time.
Hopefully I would become a millionaire before thirty.
Then I was 26 or something.
So four years left.
Then I felt I had to make some changes.
I earned about 28,000 gross.
Not very high salary, but not very low either.
But I knew I had to start working a little extra.
I waived SL cards and went back and forth to work-
-From Sundbyberg, it takes an hour and a half to go easy.
No outdoor lunches or outdoor dinners, I didn't go out at all.
For any length of time you can't live that way, but it was a short period of time-
-And I felt it was worth it.
Pretty big changes in my consumption ...
You tried to obtain revenue in other ways, you started a "flipping account".
What does "flipping" mean?
Someone sells an ore agency from Ikea.
It is in very fine condition, maybe it is before a move.
The price is a hundred bucks and I know that a new one costs 1,200.
I pick it up, polish it a little with a wet napkin
-To it out and flips ... I put it out for 500 bucks.
Then I flipped this item and made a lot of money.
I did it often and received around SEK 50,000 in 25 months.
-Wow.
And that money you invested.
-Yes.
Above all students ...
... usually ask how to fix extra money.
"Forex trading?"
No, "flipping," I answer.
So good, and you can make a lot of money.
Then you can think that all those agencies and armchairs are part of your million today.
Really, and in addition to the money, you do something very good for the environment.
So it's win-win for everyone, for the buyer, for the environment, and for your own wallet.
Now we will have an overview of Mohammed's savings.
Mohammed, a person who has inspired you is this one.
Who is it?
It is the "stock test", a great role model both for me-
-and all ordinary people who only have a few hundred dollars to start saving with.
He started at SJ with a couple of hundred dollars and finally had SEK 140 million.
-What is so exciting about him?
-He shows that everyone can invest.
Everyone can create a great fortune through the stock exchange.
You did, but it has also looked like this.
A hardship you have had.
Yes, when I bought my very first stock.
The Marketing Group was delivered from the stock exchange-
-So it was a huge hardship.
But some patches on the tracks may come here.
A lesson: "Everyone makes mistakes."
Yes, that's it.
No matter how knowledgeable man is-
-How much you have plugged in, how well inserted you are in the industry-
-I is actually that everyone makes mistakes.
It is important not to make the same mistake.
An opportunity that meant a lot to you was this.
What do we see?
Yes, here you see me lecture, and now I have become quite large on social media-
-But this is my first major lecture, and it is at the Börshajen event in Malmö.
That was where I came when I came to Sweden.
It felt very, very big.
Did it also open a desire to be seen and heard more?
Yes, and above all to meet people and lecture.
It will be a completely different thing than just sitting digitally.
It was a big milestone.
What was your biggest motivation?
A huge driving force behind running the account and continuing with it-
-Ist know that people look up to me, do as I do, take hold of their financial
-Fears their parents to invest ...
It has been the biggest motivation and inspiration for me.
-Getting others to grab their finances.
-Can it not make you a little scared too?
-You get a great responsibility?
-Yes.
Therefore, you have to be careful what you do and communicate.
I am 99.9 % transparent with everything I do, but I buy an ill-white small company-
-I may not own it to my 80,000 followers because the course is affected.
So I have to choose mine ... that 0.1 percent I can choose not to go out with.
-It can be a Mohammed effect there?
-Yes, there may be a small effect.
You started when you were 26. What was most difficult during this savings trip?
To stay motivated, actually.
Sometimes one goes out in snowstorm-
-And know that "today I will go to work because I will not buy an SL card".
To motivate yourself to everything all the time, choose things ...
... don't go for expensive dinners with the poles, or go to concerts with good artists ...
You had to do ... you had to prioritize, so prioritization was probably the most difficult.
What did you see for a dream picture that made you say no to everything that was pushing?
It was that I had so many followers.
I didn't want to disappoint them.
"I'll really go to the finish with this."
The nice was that I know many made the same trip while I did it-
-And when I reached the million it has been transparent with everything.
Then you got in their DM ... "I also reached the million!"
Or "I've reached this milestone".
It was very nice.
The followers have been my biggest motivation, of course.
More than this million.
-Do you what the day you became a millionaire?
-Yes.
-What happened then?
-I bought champagne and celebrated.
A little celebration with me and my partner.
"Shit, what a trip."
She has also helped me, had an understanding of four ore agencies in the hall ...
I felt I had to share the joy.
-We celebrated with champagne and food.
-Gud, what a wonderful.
Now we will have a look at which holdings have led Mohammed up to the million.
Voilà!
What we see here is a selection of the portfolio that you had-
-During the journey towards the million.
We have selected some of your biggest holdings.
You had a very large portfolio.
But here we have then picked out the investment company Kinnevik, SBB-
-Evolution and a fund - MS Asia Opportunity.
What was your investment strategy?
"Buy very much and very wide."
That was my strategy.
Should one of the companies go over, I have 20 others who can back up.
So my philosophy was not that I just have growth or just value-
-Or to buy broadly, and buy in several different sectors.
And I succeeded.
Here we see an investment company, but in your portfolio there were some more.
-Why do you like investment companies?
-They are self -sufficient.
They are amazingly good historically, heavy families behind that have been for a long time-
-Gedigen return historically, good balance sheets-
-Get or approved dividend, so ...
At least the majority of them bends off all my criteria.
Sbb, then?
Yes ... the second most owned stock in all of Sweden, which is totally sick.
And at this time, when the portfolio formed-
-The sbb don't at all be the favorite it has become now.
It was really a start -up.
It sounds very safe: long contracts, community properties, stable cash flows-
-and then quite low mortgaged because they had not started with the acquisition shoulderlomerate ...
Then it was a very nice company that I thought in my portfolio.
How did you reason about funds, then?
There was a greater focus on shares.
Yes, of course.
I think I had two funds if I don't remember.
Asia was one of them I didn't have ...
That sector, or the country, or the continent I did not have much exposure to.
All these are very European and American-
-And I wanted to be exposed to Asia as well.
Then it became Morgan Stanley's very expensive Asia Fund, but it returned very good-
-And has delivered fantastic returns.
-So your portfolio out like this today?
-Two of these four are left.
Evolution is still the greatest possession-
-Kinnevik ends well in sixth or seventh place, or perhaps even further down-
-But Evolution and Kinnevik remain.
There are certainly many who want to make a similar savings trip.
What are your two, three best tips to succeed?
You have to set concrete goals.
If you have no concrete goal, saving will be quite diffuse.
"I'll reach here before I'm ..." both a goal and a schedule.
I think.
Then you become very motivated to follow your goals and can prioritize correctly.
One more tip is to celebrate the sub -goals as well.
At every 100,000 we went out and had dinner.
We did a lot for the trip in general.
And then, remember that it is not the goal but the trip that is important.
Thank you very much, Mohammed, for being here.
Want to hear more savings and get more tips on the stock exchange?
Then go to Youtube, the Efnekonikanal, and follow us on Instagram, Efnaktiekoll.