The best thing that can happen is that the electricity continues to flow-
-And there will be no major power outages.
Even in the best possible scenario, electricity prices will be very high.
The worst thing that can happen is that we get to see some electrical outbreaks-
-In a way we are not used to.
Secondly, we can see very high electricity prices.
Much higher than now.
The consequences that can be almost insultable.
We can end up in new types of conflict-
-With other European countries.
We can also see new types of protest movements.
More and more militant protests against rampant prices.
As a historian, I'm a little worried about this-
-who, that when we look back on the crises of ancient times
-To there is a clear connection between high prices on food and energy on the one hand-
-and radical events such as the French Revolution-
-or the Russian Bolshevitic Revolution-
-So there is every reason to take such a scenario seriously.