Björn, how has the weather been in Vattholma?
It has been an exciting year of huge variations.
Rising fuel prices, sinking grain prices-
-And a challenging weather this summer has set it up for Sweden's farmers.
We are back at Hånsta Gård in Vattholma outside Uppsala-
-To check the situation with EFN farmer Björn Wallin.
Around Uppsala we have probably had a great luck.
If we look only three miles west in Harbo-
-Where crops are under water-
-So it's nothing.
It has arrived 160 millimeters in August.
We can handle that.
The soil swallows it when it has been dry from the beginning.
But summarized: first it was drought, then it came very rain-
-And then came the storm.
If you put the weather season into a historical perspective, where do you land?
In a fairly common weather type.
Here it is early -dry.
July and August are the rainiest months.
Then it may have been a little drier and a little rainier.
LRF has talked about 20 % worse grain harvest than a normal year.
How has it been for you?
That figure is probably at the bottom.
The harvest will be worse than 20 percent loss.
You could say that 6.5 tonnes of autumn wheat is quite normal.
Spring seed ...
Yes, stiff half harvest.
Not much more.
It is the spring seed that loses.
It knows we threshing in July, an early sort-
-Ad the fall figures, bread quality.
The rest is feed wheat.
As if it wasn't enough to dry and rain-
-To the farmers have been able to handle greatly varying prices-
-On cereals, fuel and fertilizer.
It's almost a new position.
It's always on the way up or down.
It's the new normal, so it's ...
-That it fluctuates ...?
-Yes.
It flutters very much.
What you have to do is make sure ...
If the fertilizer is expensive and one decides to buy-
-So you have to sell the grain expensive as well.
Try to time the two, so there is ...
It is no problem to conduct agricultural-
-If the fertilizer costs ... 11 bucks for Kalkamsalpeter-
-And you can sell the wheat for 3.50.
But if you get 2 bucks for the wheat, it starts to be tight.
Then it starts to get bad.
More "back to back" shops.
Despite the uncertain circumstances, no complaint is heard from Vattholma.
It's not a shame about me or us here around Uppsala.
It is a pity for those who have flooding and cannot threy everything.
So it is.