What does the investment climate look like for unlisted companies?
And how do it go-
-Klar CEO Sebastian Siemiatkowski's investment company Flat Capital-
-which, among other things, invested in Open AI where it has been messy lately.
We will talk about that in today's EFN market.
Welcome.
-Welcome Hanna Wachtmeister.
-Thanks.
Fun to be here.
Fun to have you here.
You are CEO of the investment company Flat Capital.
Today we will talk about trends and the investment climate for mainly unlisted companies.
But also about flat capital, of course.
We start there.
What is Flat Capital for companies?
Flat Capital is listed since 2021. A small investment company-
-What is checked and owned mainly by Sebastian and Nina Siemiatkowski.
-It started ... -klar -founder and CEO.
Good.
You get stuck in who they are ...
Nina and Sebastian with their entrepreneurial travel were given the opportunity to invest-
-In other entrepreneurs around 2013, when Flat Capital saw their first light.
They began to invest in, among other things, budbee, or today Instabe, and Truecaller.
Can you tell us a little more about your strategy and why are you focusing on unlisted companies?
Our strategy has its basis very much in mainly Sebastian's experiences-
-When I was in.
Brief
-They we believe that an interesting return profile is-
-In the opportunity to be long -term.
Being a long -term investor in companies.
Because it takes time to build companies.
Not four years.
Klarna ... Sebastian has been holding on for 18 years.
And will last for another 18 years.
Building good companies takes time.
And do you have a fund structure that is common in the unlisted world-
-If the funds often have a lifetime, they are built up.
And there is a possible conflict in how you build companies and maximize value-
-Man between if you are a "venture capital"-investor-
-or if you can be with the whole trip.
We try to be long -term.
We do not take a lot of charges-
-As a company, without we will cover our salaries and keep costs low.
And we will invest through our network, because it is the most unique with flat.
The network that the Board has.
How early do you go into companies?
We have said, and it has to do with Flat being an early company ...
... that we now do not want to limit ourselves to clear mandate-
-As just investing in a particular phase or in a certain type of company.
Then the risk becomes quite high that we must not invest in something we want to invest in.
We started with a very flexible mandate.
In practice-
-Can we can invest in whatever we want.
But what we can, is good at and believe in right now-
-Is companies that have received capital-rich, very good investors-
-When we take back.
Companies that may have found-
-What customer segments to go on and what product or service they really have.
You have still come a little bit on your trip.
We can do startup, but this is not something we generally focus on right now.
And your approach is a bit "hands off".
What does that mean?
We are not active owners in our companies.
We are very small in quite large companies.
For example, we do not have board representation.
We back the contractors and are always available.
We try to maintain good relationships with all portfolio companies.
And in almost all cases-
-We have it.
But we do not actively work with them.
Because then it had not worked-
-with only two employees.
In the picture we see your holdings.
There is any red thread except that most are unlisted.
Unlit is the red thread.
But I think the companies, which come from many different sectors-
-In addition to being unlisted, they have fantastic basic teams that lead the companies.
We really believe in them.
They have extremely capable investors with themselves-
-In its “cap table” that has a history of doing very good return-
-To their investments.
And who believe in these companies, and so do we, of course.
They have a scalable business model and can grow globally.
Right.
Open AI is interesting.
We'll talk a little more about it in a while.
But we can look at a list of your largest holdings here which is invested capital.
Yes.
It is easy when you see this list, to think, which is understandable-
-That this is the largest holdings in the portfolio.
But unfortunately in the unlisted world, or as it works in the unlisted world-
-So they are not noted on an active market-
-What they have their capital raising rounds when setting new values-
-What means that the values ...
They can change a lot, sometimes fast and sometimes not so fast.
So in the Klarna case we have invested the equivalent of 34 million, a little over.
But then they did a round last summer, when the holding was written down-
-In connection to a capital raising as they did.
And we have other examples of this list, type budbee or instabbee-
-Where invested capital is 7.5 million-
-But the company is valued significantly higher today after different rounds.
So you should not see this list as facts on the largest holding.
Then you are listed on First North.
We can look at a graph of the development of the share price.
Is it a reasonable reflection on how it goes for your invested companies?
Yes ... I'm not, which is nice ... I as CEO should not have that much with-
-The market pricing of Flat Capital's share to do.
The market is awarded flat capital.
What you can see ... Then we are a relatively small company with quite a few small savers.
So relatively speaking we have a pretty okay liquidity-
-To be such a small company on First North.
And it's fun that there is liquidity, but it's not huge.
We want it to get better over time, as we get bigger.
The general is that you have seen that it has been very up and down, volatile-
-And it is probably a pretty healthy reflection that it has been a very volatile market.
Then I think we generally have had a small premium to the last reported hub-
-What may be reflected in the fact that our portfolio of companies are companies that cannot be achieved-
-By investing on the stock exchange.
So that's the unique, maybe, in our portfolio.
Right.
Your net asset value, there is a premium on it, on how many percent right now?
I would like to add to this list of companies where you see invested capital ...
I know this is something that has been a bit problematic for us when it comes to ...
We only report our aggregate net asset value.
Then the we-
-When we make an investment.
But we do not have at portfolio level level latest valuation-
-What is something that we obviously think a lot on-
-And is thinking about how we can become more transparent over time.
Why the situation looks so is because we have the opportunity to enter these companies-
-On these premises.
There is a lot of American legislation-
-while means that if we were to go out every quarter and report the values-
-So we would not be allowed to invest in these companies, simply.
The contractors in these companies have for competition reasons or other ...
They do not want their values to be seen too much.
So these are these two scales all the time, that we are considering.
Today, how big is the premium on your net asset value?
14 % I have for me.
But there.
-And then it moves very much, of course.
-We looked at the course here ...
The last rise in November came after information that Klarna should be listed on the stock exchange.
If that happens, what would it mean for your investment in Klarna?
It is a good question, and something that we discuss on the board.
The principle question is ... We are very much associated with Klarna-
-In that Sebastian is the CEO and founder of Klarna.
And flat had not been found without clear, you can claim.
But it is probably about ... "Can we sit on a listed holding in our portfolio?"
And there we probably have to come back, I think.
But that is something that we can absolutely absolutely.
For example, we are still at a post in Truecaller, which is also a listed company.
But our business concept is based on being unlisted.
So I have to come back around it.
Earlier this year you chose to invest SEK 32 million-
-In the shaped American AI company Open Ai-
-which has been noticed to stand behind the chat bot chat gpt-
-And most recently for all tours around their CEO, Sam Altman, who first became kicked-
-And came back.
What do you say about everything that has happened here?
In the name of honesty, I was certainly as familiar with Finanstwitter, and read News-
-like any other.
We didn't sit on any unique channel-
-Where we had a lot of exciting insights, but we followed the news.
Sebastian has good contact with Sam-
-But in this tour, I don't think they have had any special contact.
So I would say it's a bit scary-
-To such a large company with such an important profile ...
That it could go that way.
The whole "Corporate Governance" issue is interesting.
Then it also became clear-
-How important this team, Sam Altman with its nearest team-
-How important they are for Open AI, and how dedicated they are Open AI.
Scary and at the same time a little cool to see-
-The engagement of all employees, and how important it is.
So I think Sam and his team, based on what I've read ...
After all, it feels like he's really "committed" to run this now.
So it feels safe anyway.
Although it has been nervous.
How did you reason when you chose to invest in the company?
We think AI is an inevitable-
-And very exciting and quite scary type of trend, or what to call it.
It is not a sector, but an element that all companies need to take a stand for
-and integrate.
And it's so big and it goes so fast-
-It is clear that we find it exciting.
Then we reason so that it is probably very easy to go wrong and invest wrong.
So our principle is that we think you should go to the winners in this sector-
-The ones that are really at the forefront and who are strong profiles in this trend-
-And that other talented investors think you should invest in.
It's probably the great logic.
And then it has to do with networks, that we actually know them through Sebastian.
Right.
And that they are unlisted.
Unlike Nvidia, for example.
Just.
I thought we should also talk a little about current investment climate-
-For unlisted companies.
What would you say, what does it look like?
I'm still new in this spectrum ...
I would say that if it was difficult five years ago, it is probably even more difficult today.
On the one hand, when it comes to how you value growth companies ...
After all, it has been changed completely, with the macroeconomic position-
-and the geopolitical situation.
It has made it.
But also these structural AI trends, that's what is perhaps the big-
-They if companies suddenly don't need a startup or 30 developer-
-To produce a product, without they may only need two ...
How do you value such a company in relation to the old by 30?
So there is very much values-
-which may be both questioned but also made possible through AI.
So the structural with AI is smart.
And so we have the macroeconomic situation as too ...
This cocktail makes it difficult.
Our way of managing it is basically to keep our valuation pragmatic and simple.
It's "Art Rather Than Science".
But we take back on the larger investors-
-What are good at this.
And we do not put the values in companies that we go into ...
-. without they have already been set.
-Right.
At the same time, unlisted companies can work more undisturbed than a listed company-
-Where there is more focus and so.
There is perhaps an advantage in it?
Yes absolutely.
Ask me.
After all, we are a small investment company.
There will be quite a lot of work to be listed, purely administrative.
Values build over time.
It might not go quarter over quarter-
-Out you can have this more long -term perspective when you think about value creation.
Right.
Then we have a relatively high interest rate position now.
Which sectors do best and worst in the prevailing market climate?
I am not a macroeconomic, but it feels quite reasonable that companies that are capital tongue-
-The also that needs financing and has capital -intensive business models ...
Obviously they get it tougher.
Then I think companies that don't have ...
It is some kind of crossroads now in unlisted, at least in a little earlier company ...
It is almost assumed to survive, even for a very nice company-
-That you have capital -strong shareholders with you too.
But sectors, it's like these "asset light" companies-
-Tech company that is scalable and that are profitable, of course-
-while solving real problems and that can quickly become global-
-or that is not limited to a country ...
They still do well if you have quality in the ground-
-While the real estate industry or highly mortgaged industries, capital -intensive ...
There it is probably clearer.
Is that what you look at a little?
Is it a good location to buy companies cheaper now?
Yes, the only thing you should be careful about, I think, is ... what is cheap?
There are many companies that can look cheap when you look at multiple level-
-or on how they deliver.
So the answer is in principle yes.
The values have dropped.
The important thing is to ensure that you invest in companies that continue to grow-
-So they are not in a giant lame spiral.
Because then maybe "cheap" at multiple level is really very expensive.
So you have to be careful when saying: "Oh, what cheap it looks."
You have to keep your tongue in your mouth, or what you say.
And finally, what are you looking for?
What trends do you look forward?
Where are you looking?
We have had quite interesting discussions.
We really have, especially with Sebastian, but also in the board-
-The insights in large companies and what they take a stand now and what they see ...
We have a great spect of AI and the value risk that comes with it.
Check out all these large companies built on tech.
They need to change a lot.
There are opportunities and up pages with it, but those who do not see it ...
Maybe they should beware of them.
So much discussions about tech companies and the AI angle.
Then we also discussed: What is not AI?
Thus, are there sectors and companies that are not affected to the same degree by AI?
It's a little easier.
So we have many fun discussions.
We will see what happens.
But we have also looked at companies that may not be in the eye of the storm when it comes to AI.
I understand.
That's all we got along today.
-Tort thank you, Hanna Wachtmeister.
-Thanks.
Thanks also to those looking at EFN market.
If you like the program, please give a thumbs up to it on Youtube.
See you.
Bye.