Report Week on the Stockholm Stock Exchange has been pretty bleak
and then the last reconciliation of the portfolios in KomxS30
the share index OMXS30 has collapsed by 5 %.
It has also reflected in the competition participants' portfolios.
Last week, ten of the 13 participants were on Plus.
Now no one does.
Most recently is Jonas Olavi, who is thus a new leader.
This is how Olavi described his workshop -heavy portfolio at the beginning of the competition.
This is a portfolio with a little lower risk
But it includes companies that are in a fairly strong momentum separately.
So these ones they stand and go beat on fine
And has managed to parry economic turmoil so far.
Olavi's tactics have paid off well, none of his shares have lost significantly.
For the cows from Sparreholm, it is time to question the share skills.
They cable a lot down in the last place.
The explanation for the poor outcome is
That they managed to prick the two shares that lost the most: SBB and Kinnevik.
It remains to be seen if it could be a "Komeback".