"The one who is in debt is never free."
That's how it is.
I have to keep track of my finances now.
Mia Ingelström is not only an economist, she is also a personal trainer in economics.
Yes, you hear.
Should we start this?
Welcome to Come in shape financially with you and me.
Section loan.
"Whoever is in debt is never free," I usually say.
-Is that so?
-Yes that's how it is.
-Do you have a loan?
-Absolutely.
-O good or bad?
-I just have good loans.
You could well figure it out ...
Today we will learn about the difference between good and bad loans.
And maybe a little about how to negotiate loans.
-It's a little interesting.
-And many want to know more about tied ...
... and moving, amortization, and how it works.
-We have a lot to talk about.
-Yes, we have to talk quickly.
We start with good and bad loans.
Surely there are no good loans?
Nice to be debt free and bad to have loans.
We start with the bad.
Bad loans are the ones you take without getting any lasting value.
A holiday trip you can't afford.
You have a more expensive lifestyle than you can afford.
Holiday pictures are no lasting value.
Nor a handbag ... to take out loans to finance a lifestyle.
-Is car loans bad?
-They may be bad.
If you can't afford to buy the car.
Then you sit with a large loan that you have to pay-
-and that may be quite high ...
-Is good loans?
-Yes it does.
Those loans provide a lasting value.
You take something to get something that remains.
-Yes, just that ... training is hopefully left.
But if you take student loans to read something you ignore, it's not so good.
Something that gives you the opportunity to do something else.
Or if you take a mortgage you can buy a place to stay.
-Is it a good loan?
-Absolutely.
-The girls get worse interest rates, I read.
-It's about creditworthiness.
Credit rating is a measure of how creditworthy you are.
How much you have the opportunity to repay.
Women often have lower wages.
We have looked at that.
Maybe you are also single ...
Women are more often than men single with children.
Then the entire household gets less economic possibilities-
-And then the interest rate can be higher, especially on private loans.
For girls usually interest-
-Land some interest points higher because of the creditworthiness.
I have home loans.
What should I do about it?
-Can you do something with it?
-Yes, you have to get control ...
... over what you have.
You go online at the bank and look at your loan-
-and your loan parts.
The loan can be divided into several parts.
And what interest rate do you have?
How often do you call the bank?
-I called when I took the loan.
-And how long ago was it?
-17 years ago.
-Then you can probably negotiate the interest rate.
-You have to act for yourself.
-How often should you do it?
At least once a year.
To get control of what you have-
-and that you have received the best conditions.
The house may have risen in value.
You may have renovated or can re -evaluate the house.
Maybe you have got a new job with a new salary.
Or your partner has received a new salary.
Hello the bank.
I want to talk about my interest rate.
I have looked a bit and it doesn't seem great.
"My house has received a higher valuation. I want to discuss the terms of the loan."
Then you have information that the bank receives.
-And then you can have a dialogue about it.
-How often does this work?
Depending on the terms ... Do you have a bound interest rate or moving?
If you have a variable interest rate, you can do so, say twice a year.
-Do I get lower interest rates then?
-It depends on.
You don't know that.
But the ability to do something is 100 % greater if you hear from you-
-An if you don't.
Sure I get lower ... when I haven't heard from myself in 17 years?
You can imagine that.
And it can be quite a thousand dollars a year.
-Do we celebrate with a cup of coffee?
-Yes we do.
-Now I have so many questions about this ... -Yes, drive.
-I drive now, so that time is enough.
-It is good.
-What is list interest?
-The bank's starting price for mortgage rates.
Default mode.
Okay.
Average interest rate?
Interest rates customers have received during the last period.
-The average interest?
-Yes, with a interest rate on the list interest rate.
Comparison sites?
"We're looking up your interest rates."
Or ... "We look up the banks' interest rates and give you the best loans."
-Does it work well?
-They give an indication ...
... on how different banks are located.
And that's good, because then you know about ...
When you call your bank you know what you can ask for-
-And which levels are appropriate.
-The they also have owners?
-If you dial you should be nervous ...
Then it often concerns private loans and maybe SMS loans.
To take more loans than man ...
-What do you like SMS loans?
-Rate shit.
-We should not swear here.
-Then we don't.
-But then you know what I think.
-Yes, it was clear.
A viewing question from myself:
"Hello. Should I start amortizing?"
It depends on your life situation.
We need to know more about your total economy
-To know if it's good or bad.
But can you not save on other directions-
-If you consume what you get, it is better to repay.
-Then you save for yourself.
-Do you know why I don't like to amortize?
Okay, I'm going to repay 2,000 per month.
A lot of money.
They disappear into the million loan and make no difference.
Do you know you can save them, it might be better to put them into another savings-
-which gives you interest or return.
You invest the money.
Do you benefit more from investing?
But then the return must be greater than the interest rate you pay on the loan.
And now, given that interest rates are rising, we have to look more at your economy
-To know whether to amortize or not.
-Fast and moving?
-Fast interest means bound interest rate.
You commit to a certain interest rate for one, two or three years.
-The motion rate changes every three months.
-What do you like the most?
Variable interest rates have been cheaper for long periods.
-But you should be able to sleep well at night ... -is in your stomach ...
And you must afford interest rates as they rise.
-The interest rate queen.
-The interest rate queen ... oh.
You know everything ... I usually say: And what have we learned today?
-For a lot, it's not possible ... -But try.
-I will help you.
-I have learned about loans.
Have a good one.
What we have to remember is that SMS loans are pure shit.
-We don't swear, I said so.
-No, okay then ...
SMS loans are boring.
Call and talk to the bank.
The second thing.