The dull and production -inhibiting summer is finally over
And EFN stock exchange lunch is back.
Today Monday 12 August we have plenty to talk about.
Come along.
Heavy the CEO, a turbulent outside world
And two lead -heavy guests in the studio.
Welcome Fredrik Skoglund and Mattias Eriksson.
Has summer been good
Yes I think so.
-giantbra.
But the stock exchange wasn't the top?
-Very volatile.
No further report period either.
-You have some pictures.
We have technical problems.
The resolution was too low on Mattia's summer pictures from the mine.
But we will talk about it and much more.
First to ABB.
Today's big news.
-Absolutely.
Great for ABB, boring for Sandvik.
The course graph shows today's stock exchange reaction.
I have not figured out how much he is worth.
There must be a few billion.
Does the market count in too much?
-No, too little.
Too little?
-Annatly di.se doubles the course now.
So then 4 % seem stingy.
Surely it was Gardell who thought so?
-Yes.
Finally there is hope for ABB.
The company is right in time with energy efficiency, automation
Digitization ... Now there is expertise in ABB.
ABB is too big, loud, bureaucratic and official control ...
But all that Björn Rosengren can change so that it becomes a completely different company.
Less, more focused, better and more shareholder friendly.
Over to the next course graph before Fredrik takes over.
It shows both shares since Rosengren took over in Sandvik, in November 2015, I think.
What do you think about ABB, Fredrik
Should one wait and see how the spin -off of Power Grids goes
They have a lot that lies in time, as I said.
But the structure is completely wrong.
Björn Rosengren grew up in Atlas decentralized environment ...
He made Wärtsilä more decentralized.
Sandvik as well.
He is really the right person for ABB.
ABB is too big and needs to be split up.
May ABB be so sluggish that not even our foremost business leader can fix it
No, you can solve.
But it costs some during the journey.
Restructuring ... but will surely be good in the end.
A worthy challenge for him.
-Sandvik, then?
Sandvik is probably in good condition when he chooses ...
The fact that he chooses to leave Sandvik is probably not a sign that the company is in poor condition.
He feels he is done and wants a new challenge, I think.
Sandvik flags for some concern in the report.
The business cycle, as Mattias said earlier.
Q2: the orna were bad, q3s get worse
Generally in industry.
Drawings, dismissals ...
We are well on our way into a cyclical fatigue.
Nice to jump off then stop at the top.
Sandvik would be like Atlas to resist the recession.
But it has not been tested.
But the businesses are cyclically sensitive.
The cutting tools, as well as the mines ...
If SMT seems to be different opinions, according to the press.
Should they get rid of what they are finding out.
It may have affected his Belut.
More VDBETTER.
Håkan Buskhe resigned from Saab.
He wants to get a new operational challenge in his career.
That's why he gets off.
-For Saab has not gone as well.
No ... good order book, but worse margins, and above all worse cash flow.
Despite the new issue, the money does not flow into the company.
There may be reasons for greater concern.
But the money flows into an Austrian dog -year government bond.
The graph was previously shown in one of our programs, but I want to show it again.
Fascinating.
Everyone wants to place money in the Austrian state paper
While the stock exchange goes like this at the end of summer.
Some reflection you are both moved ...
Is it to 2117?
-Yes, a hundred year old.
Very exciting.
-Fascinating.
Really.
Concern on the stock exchange ...
Mattias has a bouquet of safe paper.
Companies that perform well regardless of the business cycle.
No one is completely immune to cyclical changes
But companies with structural and perhaps even company-specific driving forces-
Can do well even in worse business cycle and troubled times.
Essity ... Swedish match I look directly in the picture.
Yes.
Essity has the headwind now after long headwinds
And can ride that wave for another time.
An almost unique company for the Stockholm Stock Exchange with its stable products.
Toilet paper, diapers ... It is difficult to find similar products on the Stockholm Stock Exchange.
Attractive.
Grows steadily over time with a marginal improvement trip ahead.
Pay expensive for quality on the stock exchange
So it is on the stock exchange at the moment.
Some "Compounders" ...
Essity may not be that expensive, but some compounders are swindling.
While the cyclical companies get "whip" when there is concern about the brandy cure.
So will we continue with compounders
Or should the cyclical ...?
Maybe there is a valuation bottom.
The hope is that when the stock market drops for various reasons ...
Economic turmoil, Trump tweets ...
When everything goes down, you can pick up quality companies at a low valuation.
Those who are usually traded quite high.
In Georgia, around 200 employees at Evolution Gaming are dissatisfied with their salary.
They earn around SEK 1,500 per month.
Is it a real problem for evolution gaming
In Evolution Gaming, the corporate culture seems to be strong.
They are good at product development, mainly the culture ...
In the figures you can see that much is done right.
The company is growing and is successful.
Surprisingly, they suffer a strike, it is still serious.
We will see what reasons are behind it and how big it gets.
A warning signal.
Over to our summer portfolios that were launched last spring.
Many competitors have had the reason with the return.
Even today's guests.
First to yours, Mattias.
I don't want to sound negative ...
Fantastic companies ... -But it's not over yet ...
August 15.
-Billerud has not had it so easy.
Although the report was good.
The stock exchange is frustrating ... the companies ...
Humana reports on Friday.
The share has gone stable over the summer and also the company's development, I believe.
We'll probably see it on Friday.
Both Munters and Billerud
Have performed better than I expected during the summer.
Especially Billerud with cardboard machine 7 which I looked at now during the summer.
Pictures can be found on Mattias Twitter feed.
-The fantastic movie ...
It has rolled up, as expected.
A long process remains to full capacity.
I think they do 2022 ...
But it rolls on properly.
Sales of the forest, the mountain weight access ...
... got better than expected.
A cash flow of SEK 8 billion, I think.
A lot of money in, good balance sheet ...
They have done everything right and the case is that Billerud goes from a negative cash flow
at 2.6 billion last year to 2 billion plus 2020, and 2.5-3 2021 ...
... feels reasonable.
-What is the market dislike?
I do not understand it.
-What do you think?
I agree with.
The transaction was more than people had believed
And then the courses rose in all forest -related paper.
But now they are below the level-
When the transaction came ... substantial height has been taken for the economic mat.
They are cyclic ... -They talk about price pressure ...
... on some types of cardboard.
Possibly that turmoil ...
A little odd considering the government bond we saw ...
Forest is stable, it also stands for hundreds of years.
It should be valued as a bond.
But the stock exchange does not make that interpretation of these papers.
At least not yet.
Over to your summer portfolio.
This is what it looks like.
First to Stillfront.
The next graph shows the price development for the shares.
Stillfront has backed a bit.
It has gone well for a year, but the summer was not advantageous.
Strange, because they bought the Canadian company Kixeye
That raises EBITDA by 30 %, according to Stillfront.
The effect can be even greater-
on EPS.
They have again raised money to make more acquisitions.
During the autumn there will probably be more acquisitions.
At the end of 2020, they may earn SEK 30 per share.
On rolling forward -looking ...
And it stands in around 230. Stillfront still does everything right.
Surprisingly, it did not gain momentum during the summer.
How is it valued?
-Ev/ebit around nine times.
The cash flow generation is very strong.
Soon the net box will be positive.
They will make acquisitions that drive growth.
They are cheaper than THQ and other acquisition machines in the gaming industry.
THQ has received too much attention.
Lars Wingfors has done well, but ...
Does Stillfront miss a Lars Wingfors?
-No.
Jörgen Larsson is at least as good.
-He may not have the same ...
He is an old consultant originally.
He was CEO of a consulting company.
He says what to do and delivers.
He is good to have in an acquisition strategy.
He has clear rules on the way of working and what acquisitions they should do.
He is not Lars Wingfors.
Lars Wingfors may have the roots more ...
Jörgen is very clear and delivers.
Both are good.
They are different.
Can you speculate on what THQ does that stands out is it a matter of charisma?
Perhaps.
Then they have a different ...
The stock market has a harder time valuing browser and mobile-based games, I think-
Compared to other games.
There is a discount on the browser and mobile games at present.
Interesting.
You also like this company.
-Absolutely.
Very.
You like Husqvarna too.
They were in your portfolio and have not had any dream summer.
In the Q2, they guided a little weak for the robotic lawnmowers.
Otherwise it was totally okay.
I like this partly because I think robotic lawnmowers are beating in the US
the next three years.
The conversion from fossil fuel to battery -powered machines is very good
for demand, but also in a stock market perspective.
Husqvarna learns to get high ESG points.
Then you have the capital market day September 15.
There they will come with new goals for the next five or three years.
They will probably raise the marginal targets and be generally more positive.
Husqvarna, regardless of the business cycle, is a good share in the next few years.
One last reflection ... Munters was on your list.
No huge disasters, but still courageous.
The company is doing well.
The share went up 14 % on the Q2 report.
Since then, Nordic Capital has gone down ownership, so now you have an overhang in the share.
But if you look at it until 2022, when the options
As the acting CEO even today ...
Klas Forsström starts today, and also the CFO Annette Kumlien.
Johan Ek and the Chairman of the Board Magnus Lindquist
Has options that expire August 31, 2022.
The strike price is SEK 45.
It will stand well over SEK 45 in 2022.
Then comes the overhang from Nordic Capital ... I hoped they would keep their share.
But now they have shown that they want a lower proportion, maybe down to zero.
Then it becomes a difficult technical overhang.
But the company itself performs better than expected so far.
Another misunderstood jewel.
So Munters, Stillfront and Husqvarna we put in the portfolio.
How should we top this, then
We do this tomorrow with Carl Armfelt and Oscar Karlsson
And when Karl is here, viewing questions usually tear in.
So go to Twitter and ask your questions or email us.
Gabriel, I missed something
Tomorrow 11.45, as usual.
Have a good time until then.
Fun to be up and running again.
Finally