Hello all legends!
Early serve!
Today there will be a new reaction video
Where we react to what you said last time: Near death experiences.
Shall we do this honey?
-Jump?
-Parachute.
Yes or...
What happened right?
Lord...
Oh, shit.
I thought they would do a trick.
They fly into a plane.
Oh, what?
He is on the second plane.
Oh, shit.
I didn't realize it was so serious with the balloon.
It just crashes.
Then you wonder what is happening to the pilot right now.
Yes.
Look, there you got to see from a different angle.
Oh, wow.
It just burns and stuff.
-It's type seven people in the air.
-It was the plane they sat in that broke.
I think what they crash with are breaking.
Okay, is this any car, right?
It's an airplane, I think.
So, how can you be so stupid?!
-Otherwise, I'm getting angry.
-Oh my God!
Make if he is hit in the head by that.
-Shey, how can't the other see it?
-What jerk cork, that is.
-But what luck he is.
-Yes, what a luck, angel guard.
This is completely crazy.
But okay.
No sharks anyway.
I think it's so scary.
Oh, it's a shark.
I had been so scared!
How heavy he is.
He just lowers the shark.
He struck it.
Yes, but who hadn't done it?
So, what a legend!
So, he just "bam"!
I have read somewhere that you should hit for it to feel that it is not ...
-It's hammer shark, huh?
-Yes it is.
I have heard that they are quite aggressive.
It can't want to eat him, right?
But he may have caught his kid in the thread.
No!
He must think it was a turtle.
Often they believe it.
-But if he hit it hard ... -A big yellow banana boat is a tortoise?
He fights for a long time against this thing.
Yes, it does not give up.
It could overturn his boat so easily.
-Do you think so?
-Yes.
Imagine being the one sitting alone on the sea.
I had been so scared.
This I think is cool but so scary.
Shit.
-What is he doing?
Throws out of a mountain?
-Yes probably.
-Go go, dude.
-Okay.
Can you just, then ...
Oh, no, the man!
Oh my God!
WORM.
Oh my God.
Huh?
How could he manage?
I do not get it.
But that is probably the case that is muted.
But still.
That must have done so much hurt.
Why is the guy just filming?
Oh!
What is happening there?
Or what?!
I didn't even see.
Did anyone flew into a sign?
We will try to understand what is happening.
-Nowing comes flying.
-Oh, wow!
It is such a squirrel costume, I think.
Well, one with fluxy?
I have never understood it.
How can you fly one?
Shit, then.
What a fucking ...
Oh, Lord damn!
-Otherwise, that guy!
-Did you see that tour?!
No, ush, what scary.
Can we rewind and check again?
That was totally sick.
-Oh my God.
-This are centimeters, that is.
Wow.
Centimeter?
He certainly hit the car, but he managed very well.
Ouch.
Huh?
What is going on?!
He is passionate about it!
No, but extinguish the fire!
I just want to extinguish the fire on him.
I love that he just "shit, I'm outa here!"
First he went out and then he just tagged.
He may have seen that the others came to him.
-No, what a cowardly of him.
-Yes, I think it was cowardly.
Thus, understand the tour you have to have for such a thing.
What now?
After all, this wall will not come ...
Oh no.
No, no, it will collapse!
This feels like a game of blocks.
-Oh, no, no, no.
Please.
-So dumb.
Don't do this, please.
Check all the stuff above him now.
Why?
Oh.
So, I'm kind of angry.
You are so stupid!
Stop!
No?!
What did he think would happen?
Oh my God.
Did he die or?
No, okay.
Oh, should he be robbed?
-No, what a nice!
-What is he doing?
-He have this ... -... hair spray and lighter or something.
So, what a heavy!
-But what smart that he just ... -This was a legend.
They didn't even get in before he did that.
Shit.
Pure legendary, that is.
-Gta.
-No!
Oh...
No, but animals must not be damaged.
It's just so.
It's something special.
-He just goes late.
-Ouch ouch ouch...
Yes, he is completely shocked.
Shit, then.
Oh.
No!
So, that is completely sick.
Oh no!
In other words...
Oh, my God how close it was.
Did you see it, right?
No no no.
Oh.
Bye.
No, but God what a fucking cliff it was there.
-Hey hey, skye?!
-I'm good!
Okay, sorry I said hello then maybe.
But wow.
Oh my God.
Running!
You flew!
I flew?
I felt sorry for those standing there.
He flew.
Aj, aj, aj, aj, aj, oh!
He made it.
All guys breathe out.
So, I thought it was Nut Shot on that.
Wow.
God.
What is going on?
Oh!
... it deserves it but then ... yes, you should not pass by ...
Ah men, wow.
It looks like Sweden.
It could be Sweden.
-This is you, honey.
-Yes, it could be.
Wow, what a fucking luck in ...
-It kind of could have been me.
-No, she doesn't take this, right?
Oh!
Talking on the phone and walking across the road at the same time.
-Did she go into the bus?
-Yes, yes, yes.
She was so close.
That is why you should not talk on the phone unless you are focused.
It is fatal.
But you have to check the left.
And so she doesn't even go to the pedestrian crossing either, so she just goes in the middle of ...
Damn what scary, then.
I had just died.
But I felt sorry for the snake first.
But then so ... can't just leave the snake.
Oh, no, no, no.
Beware, beware!
You stand in the way.
Hello!
Oh, did you see how he just threw that kid away?
-This was also Legend Move.
-Yes, what a hero.
Do you see, he hung in the hood as well.
This is just bautafail, that is.
-What do they do?
-No no no!
Oh.
Oh, Lord ... wonder how much it weighs.
It may not be so heavy.
I would guess 100 kilos, but I just guess.
-It's totally ... -Now it's bombs.
-Ouch!
Ouch.
Was he really shot?
-But then, huh?
No, he was probably not shot because then he had screamed a lot, but shit.
Take the weapon from man!
-Such people should not have weapons.
-But why do you turn around?
And then just "Ah, but well! Bam!"
Okay, a little higher, please.
It was all the videos we had for today.
My God, my heart just thumps.
And it doesn't end.
You just "uh, uh, uh!"
continuously.
After all, you are up here.
You get such an adrenaline rush.
You don't get a quiet moment.
But hopefully no one died or was exaggerated injured, I hope.
I thought it was most sorry for that snake.
And those little sheep.
No, my God.
It was great fun to make this video.
Thank you so much you who suggested to react to close death experiences.
A really good suggestion.
So more comments, spam with suggestions.
Don't forget, if you like these videos, give a thumbs up because then we will be happy.
-Write a comment and ... -... subscribe.
-So I hope you have a great day.
-So we'll see you again soon.
Bye.