he has been judged already  .
I found him in the criminal record.
That's why I call and   it was up to me even more.
How should we act in the   here situation?
I'm talking about Emma and Konrad as   Two months ago disappeared from ..
The crime should be judged as gross as the injury was then occurred by an uncontrolled fire.
and the injury was extremely noticeable.
We just disappeared and the situation is still serious.
But we have to tell the truth and we have missed Youtube and you above all, so much heaven.
so we got comment daily on what has happened.
Everything from having raised children, someone has been unfaithful.
or, what you wonder, have we ended.
Watch the entire video because you really don't want to miss this.
What has happened to us is really sick.
Although we have a wonderful job   there is a dark side like many
Creators choose not to talk about by rescue for it to get worse.
What we will tell you about now is one of the absolute worst LVI has been through.
and it all started in 2020.
We started getting messages and mails by a man who said he was religious.
he talked very much about God, but be kind.
for he said he liked our videos and my livestream.
At the same time he began to say that he was talking directly to God.
that he was like a speaker for God.
Here I feel pretty guilty because I didn't know who the person was.
But I responded to one of his messages and it opened a total door to a Madröm that became so damn unpleasant.
Our journey with this channel began in October 2016.
A jealousy filled with laughter, creativity and lots of love.
But as you noticed in the summer of 2021 it became quiet.
We just disappeared without a word and without any explanation.
Youtube means so much to us.
I've been watching Youtube for as long as I can remember.
Already in 2008 I uploaded my first clip.
It is now that you realize that I have gotten rid of my absolute greatest interest, to tell stories.
After several years of streaming, I realized that something important was missing.
I wanted to create videos that were always there for you.
Even when I wasn't live.
I moved to Stockholm to learn all about Youtube.
That's where I met Konrad.
We decided to start this channel.
When our channel was silenced, it felt like we lost a bit of ourselves.
We became compelling.
In his mean he began to focus more and more on Emma.
he claimed that God had created her to him.
Like I was some thing for him.
An object.
he saw all of our relationship as an evil sin.
she was in unfaithful to him.
At first it was so sick.
I just wanted to laugh it away.
ignore it.
But now I started to get really worried.
It only got worse and worse.
Happens enough that the situation had become extremely more serious.
to shop for a video.
In this video he sits.
He seems completely drugged.
Someone seriously wrong with this person.
he sits and talks about all extreme s*xuel*a stuff.
that I have to do with him because he owns me.
he will make sure we will not   be with each other anymore.
If that's the last thing he does.
It was so extremely unpleasant and so eerie.
and just hear the voice of this crazy man.
just give me shivers, only I talk about it.
Here we start by notifying the clip.
But it obviously gets worse after that.
What do you think this person did?
He sits down for ten hours in a car to Stockholm.
Not just that.
He Bo sits in a hotel.
share on the corner.
Right near where we live.
We're starting to get planned when we got to watch this video.
We felt chasing it.
One did not feel safe in your own home.
it's sick don't end there.
he starts filming our house.
he even gets into our gate.
and to then get into our floor.
When it fails, he walks around the house and films straight in through our bedroom windows.
It felt absolutely insane that this happened.
It was like being stuck in a nightmare that one couldn't wake up from.
I was obviously terrified.
We both got this huge and didn't know what to do.
He could be every fan at this time.
and at the same time we had our dogs.
We had to go out to the apartment.
I just wanted to lock myself inside and at the same time I'm really scared something happens Konrad.
Konrad, if you go out and I know what he would do if he finds you.
What is yet scary is that this person doesn't even hide who he is.
He is completely open and you realize that he has no limits at all.
No, he's totally sprouting crazy.
So, something is seriously wrong.
We couldn't even sleep at night.
We were just awake at night.
and every fucking sound we heard we thought it's this
the madman standing outside us with the ax hand or something.
all the more thoughts that come into one's head that you just can't shut it out.
We had probably had enough by this time and just like this what the hell should we get to?
No, so we simply called the police.
Now I have got a clip Send me where a person is looking for me and my girlfriend.
This person is in our gate and looks and looks for our names he tells him in this video.
So that's why I call too.
For it was up to me even more,
otherwise just thought it was a strange fan.
- What does he say then?
What is heard is that he is looking for us and he is looking for us for three, four days in the area where we live.
and we had, as I said, called the police and they took this seriously.
Thank goodness.
But here comes the next bomb.
This man has been sentenced several times since before.
so not only the disgusting videos and s*xuel*a messages and crazy god stuff.
so our safety was really in danger because he
actually did the crazy things he had also talked about.
Police told us.
to block him, ban him everywhere.
Give him no attention do not respond to any messages at all.
and whatever you do, don't talk about this out in your social media.
Because we don't know how to react if he would be angry.
and if he were to get angry what he would do then.
We got to sit there and just pretend, be happy that everything was peaceful and joyful.
It was great, very busy.
and at the same time it took a lot on our relationship between us.
for we walked around and was nerve wreck and worried.
and we couldn't sleep at night, and the smallest sound as we
heard or movement felt like he would break into our apartment.
and I think you noticed it more and more, to
Videos are getting smaller and smaller and my streams also.
and guess if we had a bad conscience after this.
We were forced to lie to you.
or it felt that way, at least, even though we did not make sense.
But being loosened that everything was just as usual when it really wasn't.
It was above all extremely difficult for me as a live streamer in the days.
I am sitting live stream at TikTok and on Twitch.
and have lots of people every day asking why we don't post as much videos anymore.
From the beginning, people start asking why I didn't join the videos as much.
and it is also to not trigger him, appear as little as possible.
I had no answer to any of the several questions.
We just sat there trying to pretend like nothing.
and this man was since previous criminals and was convicted
Several times for, among other things, serious violent crimes and murder.
so now this idiot was then obsessed with my girlfriend.
- Emma !!
*censored*
xxxx ... I know where you live.
Through the police we got a contact with a person on the personal protection group.
they work with people who are exposed and who are in such situations.
We were asked by them.
Do you want to move to protective accommodation, because we can fix this for you?
until the situation has resolved.
The problem was only that if we had stopped doing so, we would have had to stop all our social media.
and basically go below the ground.
Which is the last thing we wanted because we actually love our job.
so it was extremely difficult and it was really something we
had to think through.
It was no easy decision.
After much about and but then we finally decided to
move to a separate apartment themselves without the help of the police.
may not be the best choice because since we did, we have had to move three times.
because we wanted to be able to continue with our job that we loved.
We had to do anything to feel money and pay the rent.
We really tried to keep up but motivation and
The love of creating was completely wiped out after all that has happened.
and he did not give up.
I just felt that in the end I wasn't wrong and I was depressed.
and videos came up more and more rarely.
I just felt such incredible stress and pressure.
I didn't have the whole energy to keep up both Youtube and Stream.
If we are thinking that he seems to focus more on Youtube
than twitch so I chose ok but I continue with Twitch.
Then we have any income anyway.
There I can sit and sit like I don't understand anything or try.
i modder in this point so incredibly bad.
I just felt that I was betraying you and I betrayed myself when I can't cope anymore.
youtube was your life.
hard to talk about?
very hard to talk about.
Youtube has been my life for so long.
Yes.
It's all Konrad talks about.
youtube, youtube, youtube all the time.
It was in the summer of 2021 that we finally made the difficult decision to okay.
He still hadn't stopped by this time and as I said we moved around like just that.
a j*vla lots of shit it happened.
Now we take a break, a real break to see if it can make him quit.
We were just hoping that he could lose interest in Emma.
Then the time went more and more and we have managed to heal, build ourselves and focus on our lives again.
We probably realized it in the end so enough is enough.
Now we want to live and do what we want.
I refuse to let someone j*vla ganning once again control what we do and do not do or get.
It has taken therapy for us to arrive at the point we are now.
I feel so ready to continue with Youtube.
It's all Konrad talks about.
i'm legit.
I'm the world's largest Youtube nerd.
I cure holes in her head with video ideas.
Look at this.
i love this.
or we both love this but I'm extremely nerd.
you are extremely nerders.
Yes, he is really extreme.
Every day there are new videos here.
In this point you have thought that hundreds of video ideas are what you want to do.
I just feel think about what fun when we post a video.
Yes, think what a good thing it will be and God what fun we will have.
I'm just glad we are sitting here now and can tell the truth.
It has been such a sick thing over our heads for so long.
I've been able to sit here now and do this.
I'm just so damn happy.
Yes, 100%
Now we really hope you want to accompany us on our journey back.
and you finally you at the truth.
to the big question that everyone has wondered.
are we still together?
Yes.
I didn't know what JI would do ...
Yes, we're still together.  *Laughter attack*
and you probably wonder what happened to this madman.
and apparently he should not even be in Sweden anymore.
We have not been able to confirm it.
But that's what his relative says  anyway
It ended up with, unfortunately ... I can say that I am not surprised.
to be laid down.