Hello! Today we're doing a Story Time about this crazy thing I encountered.
You guys encouraged me to tell this scary and crazy experience.
I just started my first year in high school, about 5 months in cause we had winter jackets.
It's not summer it's kinda dark at 9-10 PM.
Me and my friend Tim was in Åkersberga (Swedish suburb in Stockholm)
We just had recorded a music video for school for Britney's Toxic.
Pretty random but my classmates choose the song.
The shoot when really well, our mood was on top. "We're getting an A+" we we're thinking.
When we arrive to the station next train leaves in 30 minutes, which kinda sucked.
It's a very boring and plain station, there's like 5-6 other people on the platform to our right.
It's not very crowded in other words.
It's two guys in their 20s and some older people about ten meters from us.
Tim light's a cigarett and we're trying to kill time.
Out of nowhere a guy comes up to us.
"Hey can I get a cigarett?"
Tim pulls upp his cigarett pack.
It's pretty usual that smokers ask each other for smokes, I think to myself.
Right when Tim hand is stretched out with the smoke package.
BAM!
He grabs his arm and twist's it.
Men and Tim is like "WHAT, WTF ARE YOU DOING?"
Right when we're shouting two other guys comes up behind us.
One guy rip's the cigaretts's out of Tim's hand
The other guy pushes me away from Tim.
In this moment...I get really shocked.
This stuff doesn't happen to you open on a train station.
It's such a crazy thing to go down.
Right away I'm starting to move back to Tim.
Two guys a wrestling Tim.
As soon as the third guy sees me walking towards Tim again.
He grabs me here (showing where), and throws me into a waiting booth.
A waiting booth with a bench and walls around it to protect from the wind in metal.
I remember the pain I felt when I hit the metal wall.
When I open my eye's again.
The two guys are standing 10-20 centimeters from my face.
Now i'm super scared.
I panic.
I feel my pulse raising.
I feel empty.
I see the two guys trying to talk to me in someway very aggressively.
But I can't hear a thing.
Everything is going in slow motion in my head.
Suddenly...the silence breaks and I hear a tinnitus sound in my head.
I just got struck right over my ear.
It's like I'm waking up from the panic.
Now I finally hear what they're saying to me.
I hear..
"This is a robbery".
Then I feel something something sharp against my throat. Really uncomfortable.
Then I see a kitchen knife, which the guy in the gray hoodie puled out.
It's shifting between a few centimeters and touching my throat.
He repets himself saying: "This is a robbery".
"Give me your phone".
My brain collapses.
The only thing I want to do..
Is to give this guy my phone..
But my body..
Doesn't want to move how much I wanted it too..
I wanted to dig through my pockets.
My muscles and arms doesn't connect.
I see how the guys get's angrier and angrier.
Cause I don't answer them or do anything. I'm just standing there frozen.
It's like being trapped inside your own body.
Then I get woken up from this state with a punch in my stomach.
I remember loosing my breath and starting to cough.
It really hurts.
My brain is such a mess right now.
I'm starting frantically going through all my own pockets.
In reality I always have my phone in my right pocket.
But right now I have no idea where it is.
After I've gone through all of my pockets..
I give them my phone, keys and bus ticket.
He took my phone and shoved the rest to the ground.
I see my friend laying down on the ground...coughing.
The two guys starts moving towards him.
The only thing I want to do..
..is to drag them away from Tim.
Now it's 3 v 1.
I only got one thought in my head..
..what if we DIE now?
I might never meet..
..my lovely mom again,
My family.
My cat.
Or Tim.
I can't move.
I stand there frozen in a spot.
Nothing works or responds.
After a while.
They drag Tim up on his feet.
Puts him next to me.
They start debating whether to steal our jackets or not.
I feel so humiliated.
They end up laughing at us.
The brand on our jackets isn't fine enough for them.
We both had jackets from a pretty common sports store.
So humiliating.
They just robbed us and now they're laughing at us.
Fuc*ing pricks.
The guy in the gray hoodie approaches me.
I can see him holding the knife in the pocket.
He says:
Don't tell anybody.
We got our eyes on you.
Don't call the police.
Don't do anything.
We have somebody watching you on the station.
Just go home.
He says ice cold.
Then they starting to leave like nothing happened.
They disappear around a corner.
I feel such a relief.