Apparently, this powder should be able to replace our future ..
Is this our future?
When I see something like this, I become skeptical.
Is this Bulls*IT or not?
There is only one way to find out ..
I'll live on this powder only, for a full 30 days.
So we see if I survive.
I really have the worst eating habits right now.
You know ... when you really slip with everything.
I have ended up in an army, so it always feels like I am behind and do not have time to make food.
So in other words that solve my problems with eating quick things.
Candy.
Chips.
Junk food, yes you understand.
Sugar and fat.
And sometimes I completely forgot to eat at all.
So I started talking to Emma (girlfriend) about my problem with the food.
Hin posted it pretty simple.
"Controls it up they make a lunch box, making your food schedule" a normal person probably thought it was a good idea.
But I think the step further.
I'm starting to think: "Why is there not a pill"
Future food that solves me being measured.
It's useful and good, no shit.
Type like Kalle and the chocolate factory where Willy Wonka makes a chewing gum that simulates a three -course meal.
How brilliant is not that idea and why is it not?
So with that idea in my head, I go to Google and start looking.
I scroll and scroll, find nothing.
Google
Facebook they are sick in the head
Then you come up with ads just for this.
Chocolate taste.
We will live this for a whole month.
Now we start, cheers.
Not bad.
I expected it to be worse.
The taste is totally okay.
Tastes a bit of a mug ..
A little coconut some flour and chocolate.
The mutton-porridge consistency: d
Thought it would be much worse.
Think I made my a little too thick ...
The funny thing is that I'm measured now.
How fast I didn't get a whole meal now?!
There I'm done!
I've been playing for 4 minutes.
I guess 2-3 minutes went to lots of shabel when to talk ..
I easily think you can eat a whole meal in under a minute.
It's crazy that you can eat a meal so fast!
At the same time, I feel very useful, when I get everything I need.
Now I'm "fit for fight".
I thought you should say this but I'm pleasantly surprised, you actually get measured
I've been running now four days and I thought it would be much more difficult than it actually is.
But wait a bit now !!
You have no idea if that is useful or not, you can't say that straight up and down.
Blood test day.
We need an expert too, so it is not just "what I think".
Now she has chosen to focus on functional medicine, ie she knows much more than you and me.
Is this the future?
You avoid all the cows, the meat and the environmental impact.
You solve everything with a powder instead.
So my own personal opinion I don't think so.
Maybe a shorter period.
I don't think that's the future, don't jump.
Good food is what we should live on.
You have looked at the contents of the bags, what do I get in me?
I see that they contain the necessary vitamins and minerals we need.
..So you survive ..
Okay *haha *, so I survive?!
So we take a blood test now and then an experiment is clear.
But how you will feel ..
You may go on your ketones.
So you burn fat instead of sugar and I can do some "high"
Clearly thought :)
I feel evenly measured, nothing up or down.
It is very stable.
All levels are stable and feel happy.
Andreas here sits and eats pizza.
This is so good.
What do you have on the pizza?
A Vesuvius with bacon.
Is that ham from the beginning?
Yes, I added bacon.
So what?
Just, that's the same thing: D!
Andreas: That's why I looked at you..when you said bacon
But I thought..yes..ya..ying will probably be good anyway.
I will continue and not give up.
I don't know why I felt as bad as I did.
We are past it anyway.
Then you may be prepared that when you get a little run out of sugar then an abstinen's situation can occur.
Headaches, you get low.
Which can be pretty hard to get through.
But it happens because the body gets rid of the sugar.
Now I have found something bad about the powder.
It feels clear with the mask ... the breath.
I forgot brushing my teeth and it's not nice ...
But I talked to a polisher about, that and he said that protein powder could have the same effect.
What do you think I have done this for a while now.
You smell for J*crazy :)
Routet ... his breath ..
Will we see you test this?
Have no hopes.
Thumb up if you want Emma to taste.
Do you think it is healthy to live like this?
No, not for a longer period.
If you are going out and camping or similar, I think it can be smooth.
I hope many people like the video now, as he put more a month on getting it together :)
Stop
I sleep next to him and the breath ..
Continues with the shake, it's 2 weeks left.
I regret to do this in the summer.
I am very hungry for real food.
It will probably go well anyway.
The worst thing is to be around "regular food".
Had I not seen it would probably have been a minor problem.
We would just back with the car ..
I don't know whose car it is.. it just stood here ..
J **** bang
You get a perfect energy level.
Another disadvantage is that you get crazy hungry quickly.
Quickly
If you chew regular food, you first become hungry, more hungry, crazy hungry.
Here you get the next a little deceived, then it is panic.
You are hungry now
So my stomach screams at me ..
Today I have eaten just as I should do ..
Would pick up some things for Emma and see the chocolate ..
My brain says directly: "That we have to take!"
But we didn't..I just pulled here ..
When my brain says something now ... then I'll do just the opposite.
I haven't been in this refrigerator for about 2 weeks now .. Thanks to this one!
I sit and make a food list that I will eat when I'm done!
Here you have the dish, I think I have seen a red thread in the whole.
It is flour in everything I apparently miss.
I'm so hungry at natchos..omg
Am I bitter or am I bitter?
7 days left ..
It smells so good in here.
How crazy is it that I didn't have to think or cook for so long.
It is so nice to avoid it.
Cooking then "Yes what should I cook today ..."
God what fun
Finally you cook the same s*it anyway (: uninspiring!
I am feeling very well!
It's not long now
Instead of just seeing me with a shake every day, you should see my friends taste instead.
What is that?
Dinner!
Strawberry!
It wasn't that dangerous, it was good!
Porridge..Type: D.
OATS!
Jerre: No!
- huh ??
After all, there is a little lumps in..but it is so with protein powder and the like.
It's his food ... not protein powder.
I liked it.
What do you think if one has different opinions and thoughts
That is, everyone who does not eat the ones you eat.
A chew, doesn't it look nice or?
I can not!
The brain wants to take the easy route.
You train your discipline reached incredibly.
3 days more
It is really nice to not have to cook.
A bit of that money and over a month
Even if you drink Cola Zero?
It is not good for the liver, then everyone knows that at home.
Instead of sugar, there is some other crap instead.
Exactly, so it actually got a little better.
Also
And then I saw that it was going down a little bit
Finally get to eat
WHO How good does this not look like
Thanks
Wow