An employer can terminate an employee due to.
lack of work or personal reasons.
This video will be about termination due to.
Lack of work.
We go through how it goes and what applies according to the labor law.
This video is useful for both you as an employee and you as an employer.
What is a lack of work
Lack of work is a reason for termination.
It is actualized when the employer must terminate certain employees for economic, organizational or similar reasons.
The concept of lack of work is a collective concept.
The term encompasses all situations where a dismissal does not depend on the employee as a person.
If there is a lack of work in a workplace, there are factual reasons for an employer to terminate one or more workers.
Some examples of lack of work are:
1. Lack of tasks.
2. Lack of liquidity, ie
that wages cannot be paid out.
3. Transliness as a result of a reorganization.
4. Other business change.
For example.
A change in the business that can lead to a certain competence being no longer necessary.
A dismissal is not objectively based if the employer can offer the employee any other work with him.
It is called the employer's relocation obligation.
If the employer does not examine the relocation possibilities before a dismissal,
there is no factual reason for the dismissal.
Notice that it is not that the employer must create a new job for the employee.
Thus, there is no right for an employee to be relocated if the employer is not able to do so.
Termination due to a lack of work takes place in accordance with a turnaround.
The turnaround is based on the employee's period of employment with the employer.
Employees with longer periods of employment have priority over workers with shorter periods of employment.
It is called "Last in the principle".
Note that there may be exceptions to your workplace.
With the new Employment Protection Act, all companies can exempt 3 people from the turnaround rules.
This means that employers with factual reasons may terminate 3 people
Without taking into account how long the employees have worked at the company.
This applies whether it is a small or large company.
But what happens if the employer is wrong, the employee may then claim damages
If employers terminate staff without factual reasons, breach of the turnaround rules
or does not comply with the rules on preferential rights for re -employment, the employee may claim the employer for damages.
The general damages in the event of an incorrect termination normally amount to approximately SEK 100,000
Thanks for watching
Like the video if it was useful.
If you have any questions, you are welcome to put them either in the comments section on Youtube,
Or by contacting us at simplejuridik.se.