Good morning everyone.
You who saw our latest vlog saw that Hailey would have a little party.
So listen now definition party but she has girl friends at home and sleep down
In the Lilla Hus.
The heading read Hailey moves to the Little House and this was a little test at
If we could live in the little house.
So she is 13 years old.
It is clear that she will live herself in a purple house, but thus,
She will never solve it.
Firstly, this is the case when you live alone or live in a house, then must
You keep some order, some order and ready and so on.
Alina Knäppkök stop running!
But when I came down this morning I didn't panic
And think about I can cut.
I cut in here next to me now.
A movie sequence that I filmed when I came in and just to the matter I hear that
today my parents come home again and then I have to make sure it is like
Nice here.
So yes, we have little to work on you can say.
But they have started and that is good.
And I've started the dishwasher.
But now I will take and wash because, to say the least, it is needed.
And I will also fill up so we can get.
When mom comes home they just come oh my god, how have you managed to get it like this
fine.
Yes, I'll tell you that you.
We have cleaned up for happy life, but
Even in here they have not been so.
In here it is quite nice to turn on the underfloor heating a little because it is a little half raw
out.
But I'll start the dishwasher, the washing machine and clear a little so it will be
Order of this torpedo also time enough.
Even though it takes some time, I can imagine so it can stand there.
So now it is.
Quite so cleaned here again anyway.
But yes, it was an experience you can say.
Now I have difficult cleaning mania so I have said you can clean up after you.
Now I mean some cleaning.
This one needs to be lubricated with a little 5:56.
But now we should at least go and fix the horses.
We will take a walk with all the horses.
Oh no, it's hugs.
Oh a thousand wonders if it is possible to climb the hill without getting stilts?
We may try.
Maybe it goes.
I have to bring the court with me and scratch the hoofs.
It is quite soft in the forest.
I wonder what it is that sounds, but that's my phone.
But you feel it is plus degrees or it is
zero and plus.
But it was so damn good for their bodies to go climbing round and sometimes
is it actually good not to ride without walking next door because then they get like
Using the entire body.
But working in a free way.
If you understand what i mean.
So we drive on climbing round.
We hope it goes.
Here I stand waiting for the kids to go and pick up the horses so we can go out and
The Vafasen never got ready but picked up the horses.
We're going to go out and walk in the woods and I leave the camera at home because it will
Not something fun to film anyway so we'll see you afterwards.
Now Robin and I will go down to the car business.
I'll go down, stay there to
The car dealer for my car has been inside.
It has been sick.
No, it has been in service so will pick it up now and then we will go to
KC and buy some more Valentine's Day things or more.
I have bought some and now I think I have to tie the bag and get in
order on it.
Because it's actually.
Hi there are not so many here.
Well, so it will be.
There at Beckis Yes, it's small, but it's a bit bad with sledding back here actually
And down here, there are not so many people.
No, it's not.
Yes, so now I have picked up the key to the car and will go home again.
It's a bit of a scary weather outside, but I think.
For now the snow is going away and I think hopefully there will be no more
Snow now because I am moderately tired of snow, the gods should know.
But home again and now the car is serviced and nice.
God what good, then you can drive a few more miles with good conscience.
What a thing we will see when you drive away.
Perfect.
I think you can take it by hand.
Hi Gumman e so cuddly, so cuddly.
Oh you will have lunch soon so now I'll take and drive home again.
It is very fun now it is perfect ground to run kicks for the snow
Am so packed and I'm so happy.
I bought that fired last year and we just loved the little Calypso.
Big and when you.
No, very, very good.
You who know me know that I kind of never cook and robin do all
Cooking here at home which is so grateful.
But now I have their girl friends here and Robin is doing lots of important
Things I don't know what.
And then I got to be the person responsible for cooking and it can be fun.
Said myself very funny that I stand here
Yes I understand it.
But I now make chicken.
I can't decide if there is enough chicken, but I
Think so.
So it will be chicken, rice and so I will make my own sauce that is very, very
Tasty.
It is
creme fraiche and chili sauce.
Then if you want.
If you feel like this that you don't like creme fraiche then there is also
bearnaise sauce and it may not be the best combo in the world, but it is still a
Okay combo.
But it's like this chili sauce and it gets super great and it's also very
Fast lunch and you hip a little like this
Kind of like that.
Is it.
it runs water somewhere
Boils.
Chicken fried chicken cook rice.
No water flows.
You should not be worried when I stand here
And waiting.
Yes I know.
They are.
Four pers.
Four a little smaller.
Although this is food -happy children, I think.
After all, it is gymnasts they have to eat properly.
Yes, as long as I should eat too.
So we're five then.
You can also eat.
It's chicken.
I do a little extra so we can take what is over
I think.
We go.
What is the name of mussels yesterday?
Makes you not get so measured.
But you are gratefully measured.
But you are not like when you eat type tacos and are measured for four days.
So it's done.
I think I pour on a little more chicken.
This is rose chicken
As we have received from my brother -in -law.
To test.
This is frozen because I want to hectare Robin's tractor pan because then could
You have let it stand and put it so there will be heat from above too, but I did not get
Borrow it.
So now this will be.
Will take a while.
Oh what it boils here so
I season with salt, garlic and pepper.
There are three spices I like very much myself.
It is important to spice up what you like.
Then I also like chili, but I think we're not going to
Konstra to it too much.
And now I came up with one thing.
She was allergic to nuts.
Now we have no nuts here, but
May be good to keep track of one of the girls to not tolerate nuts.
But otherwise.
Yes.
We meat here.
So now we are starting to show up here.
It is still very cozy when you can do and usually we always take our food
in the kitchen.
It's not that it's super long here but it will be.
So the food is getting ready anyway.
Which feels good.
Koelikok
I just got a bid for the post that was also opened, but it is, I think
from.
Prime
which is.
Super fun.
I have not ordered anything from Prime, but I have received.
A lid with prime.
You see what this was then.
Prime Energy Drink Icepop.
This is not allowed to taste this.
We got Prime the other day but then it was not energy.
So this one.
If you have tasted this, please comment on it and comment on what you like
Which prime you like.
I have never really tasted them.
Oh, it tastes like a mixture of probably the Red and the Blue.
I'm probably just taste the red, but very cute.
I rarely drink energy drinks, but thank you very much prime mmmm.
Yes can drink a little neighbor or so.
Give it to someone I know likes Prime very much.
But I think it's fun to get these stuff because it's fun to test new
things.
But then I don't drink very much.
Or not at all energy drinks because i don't think it is i experience when
I myself drink energy drinks that I become very good then of course.
But then I also get very, very tired.
So the question is whether you become as well.
That it becomes a negative effect of it.
But then it was another delivery here.
But it was to Robin I think because it was a
Electric car charger.
After all, our company has both my company but also Robin's company.
We have the company together, among other things and what it looks like here.
I am going crazy and then there may be deliveries with things that are not to me
Sadly without him.
But that's it.
I'll go into Haley's room and twist one thing.
After all, I've been the world's opponent of snail mucus.
Think it's so disgusting.
So just the thought of scratching killer snails in the face of myself getting
me to want to start crying.
Type.
Now I say hello.
Ah but then I get a psychic
This then we have Hailey's solution to all the world's concerns and that is that
Throw everything in and of itself.
Maybe I should take on, but you see here, I panic.
However, I think I might be able to take on a bit of that it looks like it does on
her room because i called her ba can you go out to chloe and hang out with
Her and then I think she released everything and went.
But this is no exception and something she uses right on
Took too much.
It is such pads makeup pads and that is because she.
So really, I will buy this.
So to really lose it.
And that's because she.
I can't talk more now because I get so annoyed.
She is so sloppy.
What is it about children today to be so extremely sloppy?
Or is it just mine
Children for now I am losing it.
So difficult to be parenthood.
Help me please.
I'm so tired.
What I would say about snail mucus.
Now that I've threaded myself out of Hailey's bedroom it is that I try that
The other day.
Because in my flow everywhere, it shows up how good.
Snail mucus is here.
Or this snail it's just this one.
So I had to try and liked it kind of.
Which character in me.
Went in and ordered three for these products.
I'll show them in another video because they haven't come home yet.
But feel free to comment if you have tested snail mucus in any form.
And feel free to comment
What you liked about it, because I have been opponent because I think that
it is so rough and think the idea of getting snail mucus in my face considering
That I hate, does not hate, detest snails.
At least the mucus.
But if you think they could be named something else they could named the super
Power Serum, I hadn't thought about it.
But is it so snail in.
But feel free to comment on what you think and
If you have any product.
I have understood that there are a few different such products, because there is, after all
This is like this.
And then there is some face cream, some eye cream I believe that I
Ordered it was face cream and eye cream.
But then I saw.
There is another brand of this as well.
So yes, there is little to choose from.
But, as I said, many people feel many that follow us is a little
in the same generation with bitch tok and other
So yes.
I must also say I use Charlotte Tilbury Flawless Filter.
I really like that foundation, or it's more like a serum foundation
But it is yes.
I like a lot and even hudas baking powder also superb much fun,
A lot of fun.
That's a lot I can say.
But Tik took to have learned or got a lot of tips on some fun products
to use.
Especially as my makeup routine has become completely different which is super fun.
As a surprise.
You haven't filmed Robin Robbans Kitchen
It's a little dark in Robban's kitchen today.
But then thought.
I'm not so much.
So then it will be at Robban's kitchen today.
Then there is so much as pork, stew and more.
Not so advanced, only with mushrooms and shallots and cream and good.
What are you going to eat then
I'll eat type.
I'll eat chili its carne.
And it will.
Yes, it's chili without meat.
Chili con carne, without minced meat.
Without minced meat, mince and.
Beans too.
Or I will start, I
and.
Benna and I may see what is there.
Kidney beans and white beans.
Yes, and I would hectare with a small one so it gets easy like this.
And have i crushed tomatoes
And pepper
Should I share it for you I can run it in my mixer.
No I do not know.
Have something I missed.
Well Janne.
I like my pieces.
You are boring.
Greece is a success.
I didn't say it was bad.
I said I like my pieces.
Now finally my dad has come home again and they come up here and eat so I
is about to
slightly.
Hello we have a friend left.
We will be as many as the table.
Yes the table full, seven.
It gets cozy.
I still think it's nice.
And now it is praise for us who live on the west coast but who live in Västra Götaland.
But it was so strange for no, just Kungsbacka but not Varberg.
It's weird.
Gothenburg.
And also Skövde and Trollhättan and these.
But the strange thing is that not Orust, they were portrayed from LOV.
They follow the promise the week after that.
But yes, then you have to take the opportunity and have some nice I think.
Yes, so damn cozy.
What dinner do you know amazingly!
We go mussels.
Mussels yesterday.
Well, if you like it you get to taste Robins here.
And Dad doesn't like mussels.
Not salmon anyway.
I can't.
It's not salmon.
It was good it was swinging.
Robin is awesome at cooking and other side.
Now it will be food.
I go around looking for my mobile and pray what have I put it and so
it is next to the coffee cup.
Good check.
God it flows so in my eyes and I look really tanned again.
But I'm not.
Or yes, on cheating.
It's time to finish today's vlogg and i kind of got some reaction of
Something so I've kind of swelling up on one eye during the night.
I don't know if you see it, but it's like.
Or the eyelid is completely swollen.
But thank you very much for looking at this blog and thanks too
To everything else you have looked at our channel.
And one thing to this vlog we did before this blog that was about that
We have been to funeral and that we would make a video where we pay tribute
everyone, all, all or someone we know or someone we miss or if we have
lost does not necessarily have to be a person.
That video really has east with such fantastic comments.
Feel free to go in and look at it and just be filled with love because it was so nice.
And even though I sometimes said oh it was fun and you wrote something, everyone took
Really opportunity and did, which I thought was incredibly beautiful.
So thanks for that but now it is so that we will end this video and now so
Also starts our sports holiday.
We should not do anything special than we should go and compete, probably in
This weekend at Grevagården Thursday to Sunday.
So we really go forward.
But hope you have a great time and that you are doing well and if you have sports holidays,
Hope for a very nice holiday was afraid of you and we will see you again soon.
bye