Good morning
Oh, were you there, you should we pull?
Good morning, welcome back to a new vlog, it's Monday.
It is 9:30.
I just left Selma at preschool.
Svea is home because she was a bit snotty last week.
If you have symptoms longer than 24 hours, you should be home for 7 days.
Think Svea was a bit snotty for 30 hours, or something.
She must be home.
Selma we also thought of having at home, but she very much wanted to preschool today.
She may be there for a few hours anyway.
Can be good to hurt them sometimes too, they really need home time.
I don't know why I'm in such a bad mood today.
First we sleep and then I get stressed.
I usually get a little angry when I'm stressed.
Then I think the children got angry that we were sleeping, they have not been in a good mood.
No, okay ...
You are happy now anyway
Good
Elsa is a bit grumpy today too.
I'm just trying to turn on the day now.
Today is such a day as I feel I just want to sit at home
Sit on the couch and scroll on the phone.
But we shouldn't do that yet!
Yeah, we'll have a coffee
I haven't had breakfast today, or I actually forgot about it.
Me, Svea and Elsa are going to Sunne now.
Still, we can't be at home, for Oskar to insert the last window.
Last week we started with it in the vlog and since then we have not been able to move on with it.
We have had a hole in the wall for a week because I have worked
Oskar has been with the children who have been home and been "sick".
So it has not become anything more, so now he will try to grab it.
We leave the house.
Going to Sunne.
Svea
Svea: She looks at me -aTtars Elsa at you?
Yeah!
-Yes, she's looking at you!
Now we run
Spring Elsa
Svea
Svea: Little sister.
Is little sister better why then?
Svea: Because she's very cute of them?
She eats milk
Do you mean Elsa
Dad smells ...
...toothpaste
Well, but it was better than fish sticks anyway.
Aa, are you
Mmm
Ugh, what a weather it was, I was going to plant today.
Thought I would prepare a little nice on the porch, with the flowers I bought.
Then we go and pick up Selma, in the rainy weather.
I have a question for you, Selma.
Selma: Why that
Selma: I don't know.
Nothing?
-Nää.
Am I not good at anything?
-Joo!
What am I good at then?
-I do not know.
What do you think I'm good at
Selma: A Pepsi
Bake.
Selma: These monks that were Greta pig.
Well, though I had bought them.
What do you think dad is good at, then
Cook.
Huh okay ...
Is he better at cooking than me
Yes
Just because you always get meatballs and macaroni when making food
Woho
Svea: I want her to sit on my back
Oh
You must not go away, Svea.
Selma: a snail that takes me
Are you also a snail now
Selma: Now I'm a human being anyway.
Well, you are a snail, jump down on the floor and be a snail.
God, what a tough day we have at home today.
I get a little stressed, but I try not to be it and be able to take these days more often.
So damn nice anyway not to do so much.
Which we have not done today.
Selma and Svea watch some TV, eat some fruit.
Elsa and I have slept on the couch.
It was also great.
I've been so tired, feels like I could sleep every day now.
Think that is because I have pretty bad blood values right now.
I was with the midwife 1.5 weeks ago.
I took blood tests and then she said that the limit on these values is 117 and I had 115.
So i'm going to eat on with food and keep eating iron tablets
And then I would come back after a week and take a new blood test-
And make sure it goes in the right direction.
I think that's why I'm tired and energyless.
We have to take some dinner.
Thought I should take and clean the hall.
What is the matter with you then, Elsa
Have you woken up now
The name, the name
Oops you lie here and box in the air
Mmm, good.
Lose the pacifier.
Good you are.
We're going to make dinner.
We have some cheeses left from the weekend.
Goat cheese, blue cheese.
Maybe cheese paste with walnuts maybe.
It became cream, blue cheese, leaf spinach, salt, white wine, walnuts.
My God, what a luxury.
Selma: If you were spilled, then you would have had to dry up ...
Oskar: I don't know.
Oskar: Maybe.
About how long then in that case
Oskar: Was it a follow -up question or did you continue the question
Oskar: Or is it you who asked the question -I was the one who continued the question.
You are so curious you
Near
Oskar: Not in a hurry at all.
Well, maybe you will start to wonder in three years.
Or?
-Yes.
Then you get to know, in several years.
Crafts, carpenter or mason.
Is it the dream profession
Yes I think so.
-Not blacksmith, or anything?
Yes, it would have been fun.
Imagine forging full time, to feed on it.
It would have been fun.
Or type ... -... Youtuber?
Or small farmer.
Get some cows and grow a little bit of everything possible, sold a little.
If there was an economy in such things, I would have easily tinkering with it.
bye
Hello then, Elsa
It is so bright outside, can't believe it is 20:30.
The children sleep.
Oskar just went away and should watch football, he brought Elsa with him.
So now I have some home time.
Now I'm going to take and clean the hall.
And insert new boxes.
After I have taken the dishes and removed a little neighbor.
I'll take and clean our hall.
This is what it looks like right now.
I will ... maybe not today when I have to screw, do not want to risk the children wake up now at 21.
We have this one that we have put together, with boxes.
They are already smoking.
Should clear from winter stuff, hats.
Put down swimwear, bathing rings and all that it may be.
Sun creams.
Clean through this cabinet.
We have bought new boxes.
When I ordered these I ordered the wrong boxes, or we got wrong, I don't know.
Probably it was me who ordered wrong.
The boxes we have are not as deep as you see.
They continue in a little bit more, the ones I have happened to buy are type 30 deep
And we have room for 50 deep.
This means that we have room for much more and we need it in this hall.
I'll replace them so we get deeper boxes.
I'll clear there and clear a little here.
Clean a little, dry a little.
Listen to a pod.
I love this, listen to pod and pill with things.
Clean a box.
It is soothing for my soul.
Finished
So nice, now it feels like new again.
Does it go well for you
After leaving the dining table for three minutes to take care of Elsa ...
Good morning.
I try to hide that I am and look like a zombie today.
I'm so tired.
Oskar and I fell asleep around 00:30 yesterday, watched a movie in bed.
The children went up 5:30.
They were so nice then, so it was just to get up.
I'm so tired
Now we are going out and taking care of the animals, it blows so much today.
So it will not be possible to film anything outside, I think.
Our animals were castrated last week.
So we are going to take care of them a little neighbor, look so they feel good.
Wonder if it's time for them to move out now with the others.
Hello the animals
Hi
How are things going with the pungs
What good you are
Oskar: Do you grab the horns Svea: Aaa!
Oskar: Take hold, do not release.
Hold hard.
Oskar: Try Staffan.
Good Svea, hold on hard.
Oskar: Just right, good svea
Oskar: A horn in each hand.
Take the other hand there.
So Dad can spray in the back.
Svea: Good
Oskar: Hold on.
Oskar: Now you are strong
Svea: Staffan Oskar: That is Bengt.
Svea: Staffan
We have, as I said, castrated the goat boys.
We got a honey spray to spray.
Now they will finally be allowed to go out after a week.
Oskar: Go behind and scrap them out.
Svea: Schas, Schas
Good, svea, more
Schas, Schas
Out with you, there is food out there.
Elsa is lying inside and sleeping, so we should take the opportunity to cup the potato land.
So that the weeds stay away from our potatoes.
We'll have lunch, will be the same as yesterday
pita bread with salad, feta cheese, tomato, red onion, cucumber-
And a quinoa and sweet potato steak.
Yes
Svea: Oh, my shoe
This vlog is so damn messy, I understand it, we have no plans today
Otherwise it is "Today we will do this and this."
Right now we just go around, we see something that needs to be done and we will.
I have revealed all the outdoor furniture again because now it will not be sunny I was about to say
Now it should not be rain in a few days.
Wondering if I should pick some dandelions.
A little weed.
Oskar is stopping the last windows.
Elsa sleeps again, we have been inside and cooked lunch, mysterious for a while.
I wonder if I should change water in the pool as well.
Yes, you see, I come up with new information all the time.
There is much to do here.
Oh, my poor flowers.
We have a box in front of the basement, where I thought to put those tall flowers.
And they a little lower.
Then of course I bought Rosenskär, although I found yellow.
I think whites are by far the finest, but the yellow ones were also fine.
I bought them for another pot.
The idea is that this will be a big bush sometime, an oxygen hydrangea.
It should be huge and bushy I had thought.
Around the entrance here, but it didn't turn out so well.
It's not going so fast.
Don't know if I said it in the last vlog, but the goats cooked up our plants.
And the hens sand baths so that the soil disappears.
Therefore, our plants do not feel so good.
Nämen, a white rose -cut in the middle of everything comes up as well.
A little finer outside the guest house.
If the bushes go sometime, then, damn ...
Will go and pick up Selma.
As yesterday she was at preschool, she has been there for a few hours today too.
You, you
Should we take and buy an ice cream?
-Yeah!
We cheat today, it's only Tuesday.
You want it, Svea gets the same.
Check out what just came with the post.
New lane to the chickens.
Now Oskar will clean them up and pick them up.
Or we should build them together.
Don't know if you hear me now, this has been a problem because we have been out all day
And it has blown like seventeen, I haven't been able to talk.
I have been allowed to wait for the wind, now it has calmed down, now it does not blow as much.
"Okay, now nothing is blowing" and so I've talked and then it starts to blow.
This whole vlog has been fast forward largely.
I may well call it the fast flush vlog.
There are many who like those sequences in my videos.
This is a vlog for you
Should you get it tidy and nice now
New lane.
You have shit down so damn.
We have had problems with chicken mites.
But we bought some type of killer malway.
I don't know what it is called, but a mite that eats up such mites.
You buy them in a pipe, release them in the chicken house, they eat up these mites
And when the food ends, ie the mite, they also die.
Or they die when it gets too cold.
So then they also disappear, finally.
She refuses to leave
She just "nah, i'm not going to leave my eggs"
So damn scary when they ...
Oskar: It doesn't hurt, but it's nasty ... she never knows when I come so just:
Can't you try, then
So
bye
It is also for one to be able to
Pick out the preparation and clean it easier.
The others are in wood and stuck to the wall.
Selma: Klara, finished, go
Selma: I will win
Selma: Yeah, I won
Svea: I won Selma: Nah !!
Are you drunk
I might have this to you then, because I have just done wrong
Oskar: Maybe it's just as good.
I have built together and Oskar redesigns.
I just told Oskar that the top of the most boring thing is to go to the dump, order.
Throw glass and metal.
But this fuck everything, build something together, make mistakes and can rebuild it again.
Right?
-Mmm.
What a lucky thing I came here now and did not have to join in and build the wrong
Just
Now I have the energy to do this.
-Yes exactly!
Tacoti day
Selma: Näee -nähä?
Selma: I want sausage.
Now it's tacos.
It's even better.
Hello!
Do you chew up my spices
Buttons
So there
Have you lay down in there again!
Little hen.
She has been in the box again.
Ah
Thought I would do a little thing to the hens now that it is so hot outside.
One thing that can make them cool off a bit was actually one of you who wrote and advised me about this.
You should have a swap.
Maize.
And water.
You freeze it, the ice block puts with corn in when it is hot outside
Then they get some cold water.
A little ice cream.
The children are sleeping now, or they have done it for a while, it is 21:15.
I am damn tired today, but I think we should replace the boxes, that has been my goal today.
It is already 23:20, I sit and do the last job.
Right now, you are responding to your comments on the last video.
Something that I think is so much fun is when you time tags things in the video that you thought were extra fun.
Something that you like a little extra, like this one to show an example.
Here Susanna has written "Hahaha, love".
21:05.
Then I can click there and get right there.
"Selma is so grumpy" "she thinks you are grumpy today too"
"She's so grumpy"
"You with" "Näe"
Many people have been tagged just that sequence when Svea heavens with their eyes.
And thinks Selma is grumpy.
So I think that is great fun, also think it is great fun when you write what you thought was interesting and good in the video.
That's how I can design my vlogs and develop more of what you like.
Feel free to write what you thought was good, fun or interesting.
Or whatever you want more of.
So they became more as you want them.
Of course, I do not change my everyday life, but I may be able to get more fast flush if you like it.
Or more question time or more that I sit and talk, yes you take.
Now I'm going to make this clear.
And then I'll go to sleep, now I'm very tired.
Yesterday was very tough, the day today has been better.
Now it feels good.
Thank you for looking, good night, see you soon
Kiss puss, hi hi