Day 37.
In the Gospel of Matthew 7:14, Jesus says
that the road is slim and the gate is crowded
And few find it.
As long as one is busy by oneself more than by Jesus
So you never get up on the road.
You will constantly lose balance and end up aside.
It's like when I was going to the boom.
My feet were far too big
and the boom far too narrow,
it wouldn't go
But as soon as I stopped looking at myself
and instead attached the gaze to the wire in the wall
That's how it worked.
The biggest problem that many have when they become Christians
is that they become too busy by themselves and their own failures
Instead of being occupied by Jesus.
The road is really slim
and the gate is actually slim,
and there is only one way to walk on the road
and get in through the gate
And that is by looking at Jesus.
Spiritual exercise:
Do a five -day experiment:
Try to start the day with a moment of prayer and Bible reading for the rest of the week.
Evaluate this and see
If it is an order that suits you.
God bless you.