Western philosophy was born in ancient Greece about 600 BC.
At this time, Greece consisted of several hundred different city states,
Also called police, where Athens and Sparta were dominant.
A city state was a self -sufficient area ruled by a king or a tyrant -
- the latter only a term for a ruler who conquered power
(often with some popular support) instead of inherited it.
The Greece of the time was also considerably larger than today and included parts of the present Turkey
and colonies along large parts of the Mediterranean.
At this time, a number of thinkers appeared who began to question the prevailing truths.
They no longer content themselves with trusting myths and gods tales
Without the help of reason to understand the world.
In the past, knowledge of the myths had been what made the people meaning and guidance in life.
Drought and illness, war and accident, birth and death - everything was due to the belief in the power and influence of the gods.
These myths would be managed and were not allowed to be questioned or changed.
Wisdom was long to be able to reproduce the myths correctly and interpret them so that existence became understandable.
But now a slowly began a shift from mythosis to Logos,
That is, from myth to reason, in the Greeks' thinking.
This change was first noticed only in a few, but soon it came to permeate Greek culture.
Of course, one wonders how it was that it was precisely in Greece that this change happened.
Perhaps an explanation may be that the Greeks, who were a seafarer people,
Had extensive contacts with other cultures through trade and shipping.
In this way, they gained perspectives on their own myths and explanatory models.
Furthermore, there was no strong central power and no organized priesthood that controlled the area.
Greece was an Örike that together with the colonies formed a loosely cohesive civilization
built on freedom and agreements between the city states.
In the older centrally controlled Babylonian and Egyptian cultures, the priesthood had in a completely different way
dominated cultural life and thus made it difficult for free and critical thinking.
As the power of the myths weakened, reason entered into its place.
One was now trying to see the world as an interaction of forces and laws
And wanted to find natural explanations even on things that seemed mysterious and difficult to understand.
The first thinkers, the so -called natural philosophers or pre -democrats, tried to form a worldview
which was not based on divine influence, a first step towards Logos.
The term philosopher is used during antiquity as a collective name
For anyone who devotes themselves to describing the world scientifically.
Many of the first philosophers therefore devote themselves to what we would today call science.
It is only later in history that we have come to divide the sciences into different categories.
An example is the father of healing, Hippocrates, which meant that human diseases were due to
The environment she lived in and the food she ate, and that no divine powers or demons were involved.
This was a radical thought for its time.
The historians who recorded the fate of the people
began to refer to human decisions and natural circumstances
- It was no longer the gods that decided the fate of man, it was herself.
Eventually Greece developed into an economic and military superpower
with Athens as the dominant city state.
Here, culture and free debate flourished in a way that was unparalleled in the ancient world.
To this cultural center, thinkers sought from all of the Greek civilization
And now the city ended up in the philosophical eye -catching.
Old traditions and performances were questioned and abandoned - but what would come in its place?
How would one shape the new society and how would man know
Which way she was going to wander now when the gods no longer ruled?
The conditions for philosophy were now in place and it would not
Lasting long before Socrates, Plato and Aristotle take place on stage.