Zenon from Elea (about 490-430 BC) was a natural philosopher best known for the way he argued.
He did this mainly by constructing paradoxes
And some of them have puzzled people ever since.
He developed these paradoxes as arguments, for example, because movement was impossible
And that the reality we perceive must be an illusion.
The most well -known example is "Achilles and the turtle".
Zenon uses logic and a method today called Reductio ad absurdum
- If a reasoning leads to a contradiction, its opposite must be true.
Most interesting with these paradoxes is how a strictly logical reasoning
Seemingly can lead to an incorrect conclusion.
Through his paradoxes, Zenon showed that philosophy and science require more of us than what we first take for granted
- And that's why he deserves a place in philosophy history.
What happens if we let a well -trained runner (in Zenon's example Achilles, the protagonist of the Illiad)
Compete in a 100-meter race against a turtle?
Of course, the runner wins.
But wait a bit, says Zenon.
Let me show that strict logic claims the opposite.
And the logic does not lie, which is why our perception of reality must be wrong.
We set up the contestants, but to make the competition a little fairer (and for the paradox to occur)
we give the turtle a certain lead.
In order for Achilles to win, he must first pass the turtle
- And this assumes that he will first catch it.
But this is a logical impossibility, Zenon says, explaining:
During the time it takes for Achilles to get to the place the turtle was based on
Has the turtle has moved another distance.
At the time it now takes for Achilles to run even this stretch, the turtle has moved another piece.
So can continue to reason until the given conclusion becomes
That Achilles will never catch the turtle.
The distance that separates them over time becomes minimal but never zero.
If you clean the reasoning in the paradox you can show that nothing can move at all.
Do you see the problem, and how could you respond to this argument?