Yesterday it was really hard to say hello to you all
But now I'm finally on the way
And should go.
After a long education.
We will soon board the aircraft.
I thought you would be able to go, so you will see how I have it down there.
Against Afghanistan.
Sometimes you come down as a foreign soldier and want to change the world
During the small six months.
But there is very little you can do during that time.
Still, you are a cog to get something in the right direction, hopefully.
I think it feels like we made a difference when we were there.
The impression you got from the locals and those we talked to
When one made things that got a concrete difference
So it felt like one created security
And made it better for the population, they contributed to a development in the right direction.
My name is Niklas Wikholm and I come from Holm
A village five miles outside Sundsvall.
I work on the ambulance in Ånge.
Here is Ana's healthcare store and there is very good stuff here
Which they may not really know that they have.
Ked-vest
TRACTION SPLINT
More than we have on our ambulance.
FS14 and FS15 I thought I felt pretty well.
But it was winter on FS14, a very cold winter with Afghan dimensions.
Otherwise, they were reasonably equal to tasks, what they did and so.
When I got home after the FS15, it was two years before I went down again on the FS20.
Then they experienced that it became
a clearly more strained position
and more sharp tasks
to try to influence what happened
More than just watching, observing, as you may have done before.
Preferably one was in southern Afghanistan
at the larger conflicts, at first
And then it also spread to northern Afghanistan.
It's been a tough night on the mountain top at the mast tonight
First we had a post at the top of the top
Then we were forced to regroup
Down to the Compo Round in the middle of the night.
We had to wake the Ana soldiers so they would not freeze to death.
Now we have camped here instead.
We came down on the FS20 in December.
We were a unit that would follow the Afghan Army
And be embedded in it, surrounded.
We didn't have much to do with the larger Swedish units.
For most of the mission.
The Afghan army would go down and look at an area south of Sar-e Pol.
We would get there there had been a lot of unrest
And warlords who had disturbed the locals.
Initially run man in more low -lying areas
Then we came to a mountain passage
with high rock walls in a valley
A bit like the Grand Canyon, though the mockery narrower.
The rock walls were 300-400 meters straight up on each side
When we were to pass that passport
We were shot.
I remember that before we went in
In this valley where the insurgents were found
became it like a stando
where one was waiting for their turn to go in
On almost like a railroad track.
The feeling when going into this shooting area
was that they tried to be calm and focused.
What is my task, what should I think about.
Right then and then, do their best and try to do their task.
We tried to call on flight support
But we had no coverage then.
We sat trying to call it
So it was approached that you would go into this area.
Where you are most likely to be shot.
The task was that we would reach the village of Jarghan.
When we got out where the valley opened a little more
where the insurgenets had taken fire
So the Afghan policemen had taken shelter under some stones.
They had thrown themselves out of the cars, which were not split protected.
At the same time, our Swedish Galtar had arrived
and driven past their Afghan police cars.
We started to answer the fire and push back the insurgents.
As we passed these cops on the side of the Galten
To take shelter as we get through the valley, along a mountain wall
So three to four policemen hang on the side of the Galten.
Any of them throws up the bullet on the hood
To avoid carrying it.
They look exhausted and sweaty
While I was driving I tried to send out water bottles
Through the small grenade hatch found on the box.
Deport PET bottles so they could drink.
We tried to support them the best we could
And went through this mountain pass with 20-30 vehicles.
We made our way up to the village of Jarghan where we could collaborate with the population.
Half town is here and welcomes us.
Here is the village where we have our location
Where we opened our base.
It looks like an old cowboy constellation
Where you put the tensions in ring.
The village is called Jarghan.
Here next to Ana lives in a compound.
They are building a building, a school maybe.
Very high mountains here.
We wanted to try to establish a presence of the Afghan army and police
In order to regain this area
to the Afghan government
which we support.
I remember when we arrived.
Then you would not have talked to so many other units directly
Without the most talk on the radio.
You didn't really know what it was like with everyone else
If they had managed fully -skinned
Or if something had happened you might have missed.
Someone who had been injured or so.
But once we arrived and could talk to each other
saw that everyone was full -skinned
So it became a pretty excited atmosphere.
That everything had gone well, you were very relieved.
One was not satisfied and happy that
It had become a dangerous situation or that you have been shot.
That everyone managed was nice.
One was somehow prepared to
It could be dangerous this time when we came down to Afghanistan.
Then you were also relieved that it went well this time.
I think there are many lessons you bring
from the missions that are difficult to put into words.
I am convinced that one is formed as a human being
And experiences are tied here at home.
You get some perspective on things you are through.
One may not complain about the same everyday things
When you get home as you did before you left.
With all the missions in the luggage
I feel satisfied with what I have been through.
I carry a chair with me that I have been involved in and contributed
to helping other people in the world
But also help Sweden make a difference in other countries.
It's something I will always have with me.
My name is Niklas Wikholm and I am a foreign veteran.