Hello!
Here you can get help doing your cases at Försäkringskassan digitally by using Mobile BankID.
With Mobile BankID you can use your phone to log in to My pages on your computer and to log in to the My Page app on your mobile.
In six simple steps that only take two minutes, we show how to do it.
Go to your internet bank and order Mobile BankID and download the BankID app for your mobile.
Go to My Pages and click Login.
Click Mobile BankID.
Complete your social security number - twelve digits in a row - and click Login.
You will be asked to start the BankID app on your mobile and then you should identify yourself with your personal code.
Now you are on My pages and can apply, report and sign your cases.
Thank you for doing your cases digitally with BankID!