An ordinary day starts with me looking over
What orders have been received.
Then we jointly go out and control the systems.
There are two types of techniques at an airport.
Those who screw on the aircraft
And those who screw at the airport.
I belong to the latter.
My systems never leave the ground.
They are attached to everything from air traffic controllers in the tower
to the pilots.
We make sure the airport can be used.
I have always had a technical interest
so it is perfect to work with a great variety
of systems.
I get a good mix of the technical and military.
And in the role of officer get a job
With leadership and education.
What the Armed Forces means to me
is hard to put words on.
It is rather a feeling
that my job makes a difference
For myself and others.
My name is ludvig
And I am a management system officer.