Right today is a special day here at F 7 Såtenäs -
–This we have received Finnish F-18–
- Without the Finnish clarification crew.
We came to Såtenäs to work with the F-18 plan as part of Aurora 23.
We teach our Swedish colleagues how to work with F-18-hunting plan-
-And in turn we will learn how to work with the Gripen plan.
It has been very good to work with the Finns.
They have been very accommodating and pleasant.
They have gone through how their airplane works.
We have had to try different handles, -
—The tanking, secure robots, -
—The Airplane, lay a block, -
- Creating things we do on our machines.
We speak different languages, but our countries are so similar that everything just flows on.
It will be great fun to work more with the Finns.
I think we learn from each other and -
- During Aurora 23, I think we can grow stronger together.