As a tactical UAV pilot, I see qualities as accuracy, responsible and even curious.
We have a very unique expertise in the Armed Forces.
A competence that will be relevant for many years to come.
My name is Johan and I am a tactical UAV pilot in the Armed Forces.
If we start from a flight training period, then the day begins with a weather brief.
The flight service manager goes through today's passport and then you go down to the place to fly from -
-And carry out all Pre-Flight checks and really makes the flight system ready to fly.
For me, it is interesting and evolving when I get to solve sharp tasks.
It can be anything from obtaining intelligence as well as the exercise of fire management with sharp ammunition.
I like to join and work with the current system.
What I also like is to be able to participate and drive the development forward in terms of future systems.
As for the development of UAVs in the Armed Forces in its entirety.
I am proud to have been given the responsibility to be a representative of the Armed Forces.