Hi, my name is Vlada and I did my military duty as a sea surveillance operator.
And my name is Calle and I did my military duty as a wagon manager at Grenadeklarspluton.
What does a sea surveillance operator do?
A sea surveillance operator is located either in a central that I did.
Or on a vessel and lake monitors Sweden's borders.
And ensures that no unauthorized, vessels border on our Swedish waters.
What does a grenade thrower do?
The grenade launcher pluton do -
- Is we shoot grenades at longer distances.
No short hand grenade.
So it's grenade launcher in a tube.
As a carriage manager-then that system is on a 90-wagon.
And then I decide where to go and take care of the crew.
So I'm the manager of the carriage.
Today we will answer some questions.
And for that we have an iPad to help.
"Is there any trait that many people think you have to have but that is not really that important?"
Here, the cliché will be big, strong, bite.
But you don't have to be so big and strong.
Nah.
For most positions I would say.
Yes, so I still think that some kind of fitness and want you probably need to have the foundation to cope with it.
Because it gets tough.
- Yes, it gets pretty physical.
But you don't have to be the biggest and strongest.
You don't have to be an elite athlete.
Well, and you're there too to learn all those things.
"What is your best and worst memory from military service?"
Oh.
The worst is probably then when I went to and from the garage, over and over again.
But it is for a longer period.
The best thing was when I was at a shooting exercise in Älvdalen.
Then it was brilliant sunshine, completely crispy outside.
So we went up to a small height with pretty good views, and then we stood and shot there for several hours.
It was nice.
Drinking coffee and had gotten thread.
Luxurious anyway.
Being able to have it as an everyday life sometimes.
-And you?
I've been thinking about that question quite a few times.
The toughest thing is probably still the last exercise "never give up", is it called?
Type a form of basket test?
Or?
- Yes ... but you can say.
It was a type of end exercise you can say that would show whether you are a worthy soldier or not.
The cold ...
This motion all the time.
The uncertainty.
Exactly, the stress that came.
Yes, for everyone.
You learn to work well so early in the morning.
- Yes.
- Or the night.
I got a similar one.
Early up.
Tinges.
We slept type in water.
Everything was wet and then you would go with your shoes.
It was almost no idea to almost put on your boots.
Where did you have many of your exercises.
Pure geographically?
Älvdalen, then it was Skåne and Skövde.
Great question.
I'm from the army so I wear green.
It fits great in the forest.
I am blue like the sea, so the Navy I come from.
And that's where I did my military duty too.
Then the Navy is quite scattered.
And the Navy also has green uniform.
Especially in the field.
And I had that during the first few months.
Yes, everyone has, I think.
Now it rang.
"Is there any difference in the requirements or tasks for men and women under the military duty?"
Nah.
I wouldn't say that.
According to the duty and testing authority, this is the same requirement.
It doesn't matter if you are a guy or a girl.
Everyone is the same, it's just that everyone is different individuals.
That's really what you see.
Yes, but really.
One more, really.
"What happens when you have mucked? Am I free then or what do I have obligations afterwards?"
Muck is kind of like a student after high school.
Yes, an end.
And you get to meet commanders a little more civil, like ordinary people.
But what you do afterwards is a bit up to yourself.
But you are placed in war!
- Yes, everyone is placed in war.
And then you can choose to continue within the Armed Forces, or you go out civil.
Yes, you usually say ... For me it was kind of every other weekend.
Yes, so it was for me.
Some weekend you could choose to stay.
Then you had to stay with their polishes on the regiment.
It was pretty fun.
But otherwise it was every other weekend that I had to come home.
Then it can actually vary from band to bandage.
I had quite a lot of weekly leave.
We were out for a longer period and then we were vacant for a longer period.
It sounds pretty luxurious.
Or?
Yes, it was pretty good.
You work intensively for maybe a month -
- And then you were free for a longer period after that.
So, I think ... I had my friends a phone call away.
And you had some home time so you could talk to them.
But otherwise I think the pace of military service went in one.
So that's how you could hardly miss either.
You forgot it a little when you were in the business.
Because that's a pretty high tempo.
You think of something else in the meantime.
When it gets a little slower pace sometimes, some night when you don't have much to do.
Then it may be that you long for home.
But you have your friends there.
Then it becomes that you find something with them.
And it becomes a bit like a new family you get.
Yes, it's a bit like you go away as well, somewhere.
But the friends were really there and I still have quite a lot of contact with my polishes from the military duty.
I don't think so personally.
But was it too when you were going on the shooting range for the first time?
Ah, you were nervous.
It was a bit like this ... I'm not going to fail.
There are so many people watching.
There is a lot of commander.
The commanders were very very good.
They came up next to it.
Be with the first shots.
Continuously.
You felt safe.
And then it became a routine to learn to shoot.
It became like dramatized.
It feels like it in the beginning.
You probably play the bigger one at that time than it was.
Now that I think back on it, maybe there wasn't much screams.
Maybe it was just because you were nervous yourself.
But the sum of the cardamom is really that it is awesome how so many different people
can provide such a stable and secure community.
Thanks!
- Thanks!