What do you want today to say to your children -
- As has grown up within Jehovah's Witnesses, because you were a witness?
My love is neither less nor more than when I was a Jehovah's Witness.
My mother's love is the same.
I hope they have a good life, but I also apologize.
In which community did your children grow up?
In Pentecostal church.
I thought it felt good.
It was fun that she wanted to get involved.
It felt like...
... A good place, a safe environment with loving people.
When your daughter today talks about what it was like for her, what do you think?
I get really sad and very angry, how it can go like this.
This is the story of all the children who have taken harm-
- Of the religion their parents chose them.
And they are everywhere.
They grew up in different religious contexts, and they are many.
All children who grow up in religious home do not get bad.
But now it is about those who have done it.
Now let's listen to them.
Do you miss your family and your parents?
I don't miss them.
I don't miss my family.
I don't miss how I was with them.
I feel much better now than when I lived with them.
But I feel sympathy for my mother, even though she was my perpetrator.
Although she was the one who had the role of the one who controlled me the most.
Although she has caused me most pain in life -
- So I feel sympathy for her.
And sometimes I can fantasize about a day when we somehow -
- Get contact again, where she left my dad ...
... and where she can forgive me because I left her -
- And I can forgive her for what she did.
And where we can go ahead and have a nice mom-daughter relationship.
Many of the stories are about the fear of losing their parents -
- If you go against the religion they have chosen.
With those who were forced to break with their parents, there is grief.
Jonnah, who was excluded from Jehovah's Witnesses three years ago -
–Ach who was then forced to break with his family -
- Will never stop hoping that they will want to meet again.
She is thinking about how they should be affected by her telling us what happened.
That is why it became so hard to do this too.
I think if Dad would see, against presumption -
- So I don't know about ... For me, this is important to talk about -
- And that people should hear and understand what it means.
If Dad looks ... either then maybe it opens a door that is on the glare -
- Or it closes the door forever.
At the same time, I can't go and wait for my whole life that may happen.
- What is you dreaming about going to happen?
- That they want to talk to me.
Well, that's it.
I don't ask much, but just to ...
... you can be seen every now and then or talk about ...
... talk about the weather, type.
Whatever.
Talk about how things are going to school or at work or so.
Everyday things.
It is.
If one, as a young man, was forced to leave the religious contexts of his parents -
- For you want to live in a different way, or fall in love with someone ...
What do you want to say to someone who has been to cut with their parents?
To begin with, it is right to cut with the parents.
Otherwise, one will seriously limit your freedom ahead in time.
Then maybe you will have to do it later.
It is very important-
- To show to their parents that as an adult you have the right to make decisions -
- Run who you stay with, marry, etc.
The cutting of relationships is always very painful.
You live in a fog sometimes, in confusion -
- When an attachment relationship needs to be broken.
For a period, it may be important to set up.
One will long to return and experience confusion around it -
“But it is probably important to continue on a set -up course.
At the same time, it may be good not to diabolize their parents -
- For they are also caught in a context.
They may have grown up with it.
That you do not give up the possibility that it may someday -
- Can be found to find each other back.
Maybe not as close or so, but that you can still have some contact.
I think that is good -
- For the person's mental feeling and development anyway.
You make a decision and stick to it.
One should not diabolize the parents -
- Uteran see them as people who were also influenced by their environment.
How can you as a parent expose your child to that?
How can you choose the congregation and God before their own child?
I get in touch with a woman who wants to try to explain.
When she had children, it was a matter of course to raise them -
- In accordance with the doctrine of Jehovah's Witnesses.
Today, when she has left the movement, she thinks differently.
They grow up in a doctrine that is two -part.
There are some positive things -
- And things that can be scary for children, adult stuff.
The positive things are that you believe in a higher power -
- On a God who is loving.
And this god, Jehovah, will create a paradise on earth -
- Where everyone should live in peace and harmony.
The back is something that the children also learn:
In paradise, only those worship Jehovah are allowed to join.
And to be involved, one must behave in a certain way:
You should be a baptized Jehovah's Witness and Jehovah's Friend.
You learn about Harmageddon, the war that reveals all evil and evil people.
It is a two -part doctrine.
It is fine, but at a fairly high price, that you teach the children.
What do you think about it was the worldview your children grew up with?
After all, I'm a little ashamed of it.
It is an extremely simplified worldview to give children.
You teach the children -
- That we have friends in the congregation, and then they are worldly outside.
It is a worldview where you learn that the truth is in the congregation.
This means that the truth outside, what others believe in, is a lie.
What in the doctrine scared you as a child?
You grew up within Jehovah's Witnesses.
One thing I remember was my mother who was not a Jehovah's Witness.
I was terrified that she would not come to paradise.
I understood early on that Mom did not believe in this -
- So paradise would be without her.
And it would not be a paradise without my mother.
I said many times:
"You have to become a Jehovah's Witness! I don't want to live in paradise without you."
It is probably the biggest horror I had as a child -
- That mom would die and not be allowed to join.
When you had children yourself, did you think that they could feel the same fear?
No, it's strange.
After all, we were united in the congregation.
We had the whole family in the congregation.
It has not struck me.
However, I and the children's father have never been Armagedon parents.
We browsed past the tough stuff in the book with biblical stories.
Because I already thought it was not good for the kids.
But it doesn't matter, because they hear about it, they read and they see pictures.
And it has crept afterwards, from my youngest daughter special -
- What a scared she was and what she was ashamed when she did something wrong.
For Jehovah, everything sees.
What we who parents thought were nice -
- That you always have a God who supports you, be scary for her.
It means that God sees everything.
She told me yesterday about anything ... I had no idea.
When she went to the low school she had a best girlfriend -
- And that friend was kissed on her mouth.
At the same time, she knew how Jehovah's Witnesses view homosexuality.
She had a stomach ache and was so scared and sorry for doing wrong.
She would not come to paradise, because Jehovah was disappointed with her.
How does it feel today to think that it affected your children so much?
I am ashamed.
It's awful that I exposed them to it.
And so cheated you get.
I love my kids and would never do anything to scare them.
And yet I made my daughter constant stomach pain -
- For things she didn't dare tell me.
It's not just the children in Jehovah's Witnesses -
- Which tells about horror images that their parents' religion has given them.
What scared me as a child was hell.
That people are locked up in a psychotic darkness ...
... and screams with anxiety.
That was the picture I had of hell.
Not to get to heaven -
- Not to spend eternity with my parents and my family.
I was afraid that my friends who were not Christians would not be there.
The demons told me:
"You think you can hide from us, but we know you don't believe."
"We can get into you."
About everything that happens if you end up in hell.
About the warm fire.
About the devil who whips one.
About being forced to drink blood.
That I would not be allowed to get into heaven.
That I would die.
That I would stand outside the pearl gate and wait forever.
In the teens, the press escalated.
One would evangelize and testify -
-For non-Christian friends and for classmates and so on.
If I am a coward and do not talk about Jesus, then it can lead to ...
... someone's eternity is affected.
It was a huge pressure: "If you don't, who should?"
"Don't you think about the eternal souls of your friends?"
This is very difficult to describe -
- But I managed in some way to persuade myself that I wanted to.
It almost felt like committing abuse on oneself.
I didn't want to, but I told myself that I wanted to, and did it.
I was talking about Jesus for my high school class.
How does Amanda's mother think about what Amanda got to learn in church?
Most young people who participate here have explicitly asked us -
- Not contacting their families.
But with some parents I have still had contact.
It has been everything from sharp criticism for taking up the subject -
- That parents told them that they regret things from the child's upbringing.
For almost everyone, it is impossible to criticize their religious context.
Amanda's mother still decides to sit in front of the camera.
When your daughter today talks about what it was like for her, what do you think?
I get really sad and giant.
What has your daughter told you today, about how she has measured in the church?
She has felt a lot of stress and anxiety.
She is also forced how to dress, how to think.
She couldn't think of guys, it was a sin.
And when she sinned, she would fast and pray.
And then that she was forced -
- At school, tell about their faith for the whole class -
- It created a lot of anxiety, anxiety and stress.
- Did you know these things?
- Not when it happened.
I thought it was a safe place.
How do you think about your own responsibility?
You grew up within the Pentecostal movement -
- And chose your daughter to grow up there.
How do you think about it?
It was only natural to follow where you have been your whole life yourself.
It's like a homemade environment to be in.
How was it for yourself to be in church when you were young?
It was a bit both and, actually.
I have had my nightmares when I was a kid.
Then you had heard a lot about hell -
- And that those who are Christians come to heaven.
And we didn't know when we were going home to heaven.
So sometime when I woke up alone in the house at home, I panicked:
"Has he picked up them, and I'm still here alone?!"
I ran around looking.
Finally, I found them out on the site.
But what a horror.
Some things that you experienced as a child remain within the Pentecostal movement.
Why didn't you want to protect your child from it?
I thought we went on, that there wasn't, that we came further -
- And that it was a little nicer teaching.
When I left my faith and left the church so ...
... I felt it was talking about this.
I wanted to lift some things within the church and Christianity -
- As I think can be harmful.
My blog is very small.
It's not that ...
It is friends and family reading.
It started to come in ...
... very hard resistance from Christians.
It was personal attacks, threats.
It is difficult to describe disgust and the hatred directed at me.
These people had in the past -
—In the church context, when I thought they and was a Christian -
- Treated me with love and care.
It was a complete reversal, like I was almost no longer human.
And that I deserved it, had to blame myself.
- It was really awful.
- How did the reactions look like?
It was like almost hatred, threat ... it was emotional pressure.
In the end she called me and said, "Mom, I don't want to live anymore."
I have to sneak in here and hug you.
Oh, now the microphone and everything.
Amanda's mother wrestles with responsibility for having trusted a church-
- There it turned out that her daughter was bad.
For Karoline, the debt issue is heavier.
There was so much she as a parent and Jehovah's Witness was invited -
- To teach their children about.
My duty was to raise them in the Bible's doctrine, bring them to meetings -
- And teach them who to spend time with and how to behave.
My duty was also to teach the children to stand up for "what they believe in" -
- What we parents believe in -
- With birthday celebrations and everything else they do not take part in.
This is required for the children to stand up for.
My duty as a parent is to teach children -
- Defending their religion in school.
One has films that teach parents to handle it -
-And films that teach the children how to do it: Kevin and the Sofia films.
- Why don't we celebrate birthdays?
-Good question!
How would you answer?
Karoline: They go straight into the heart of the children.
- Because Jehovah doesn't like it.
-Good!
And why doesn't he?
Does it say that Jesus celebrated his birthday?
Eh ... no.
Just.
But he said we would celebrate the memory of his death.
He died for us so that we can live forever.
The films illustrate how the parents should speak the child to the right -
- With the Bible.
The child may promise not to do it, and make up it.
The important thing for us that parents are -
- To educate the children to stand up for Jehovah's Witnesses.
You like to get sweets and gifts?
But would you like them now?
When you celebrate birthdays you mix good things -
- With things that Jehovah doesn't like.
As a witness, why was it important to you that your children followed the doctrine?
Even if you say that all witnesses love and help each other -
- So you have very strong hierarchies in the parish community as well.
Those in the middle are role models:
Dads who have an appointment as elders and children who are exemplary.
And for you to keep yourself in the middle, the children should be exemplary.
There was always someone who was about to attend the meetings.
There was no good socializing, so they froze them quite strongly.
We did not spend time with them private-
- The way we wanted our children to have the influence of the fine young people.
What did you get for instructions as a parent about how you would behave -
- If any of your children were excluded?
A child who lives at home may do it until it moves away from home.
Then you have no responsibility for them anymore.
These are the clear instructions.
- It is total social foreclosure.
-What does that mean?
You must not meet, not talk on the phone, do not hang out.
You should treat your child as if it is dead.
There is no longer.
It is not in your reality, it is not part of your life.
And that approach did you accept when you were in Jehovah's Witnesses?
I was a witness, but I had a very hard time accepting it.
How can religion become so important to choose your child?
You choose God and the congregation before your own child.
If you actually believe that there is really a god -
—The one really is created by this god for an eternal life -
–And you see your child choose it -
- Then maybe you can compare it to a parent whose child becomes a heroinist.
And the parent, who loves his child -
- Inns that this is really a ...
Becoming a heroinist is so dangerous and destructive that one must do everything -
- To get the child on better thoughts.
It is believed that it is the order.
So a Jehovah's parent must get the child back to ...?
Yes, I think, if you really believe in the doctrine you proclaim.
What do you want today to say to your children -
- That has grown up within Jehovah's Witnesses, because you were a witness?
My love is neither less nor more than when I was a Jehovah's Witness.
My mother's love is the same.
I hope they have a good life, but I also apologize.
They could have had a much better childhood.
A childhood where they did not have to be afraid of Harmagedon.
A childhood that was carefree, where they were only allowed to be children -
- And didn't think about who was suitable to be with.
A childhood filled with sports activities instead of service on Saturdays.
Or birthday party instead of meetings Sunday afternoon.
A childhood where they got to choose who they wanted to be with -
- Rebound of religion, but only because of interests and personality.
I took it away from them.
Yes, for many parents it is only afterwards that it becomes clear -
- How faith affected their children.
But it is not only parents that a child meets during their upbringing.
Hello!
Welcome into the car.
-How's it going?
You're ready?
-Yes.
-Let's go.
Against Knutby!
–Yes.
A 26-year-old woman was arrested today-
-Missed for involvement in the murder of the 23-year-old shot in Knutby ...
The pastor in Knutby was arrested today ...
Helge Fossmo admits that he was involved in the murder and attempted murder.
In the middle of the storm that was the "sect Knutby" Linnea grew up.
Now she wants to know: Why could no one at school help her?
-In front.
Does it feel okay?
-Yes.
Let's go.
Texting: Ulrika Jansson Båving Swedish Media Text for SVT