Do you have an idea of which program or school is suitable for you?
But yeah, then you should keep track of your credit value and know what it is.
But it's not as difficult as it sounds, Melinda will help us.
Hi, what fun you are here again!
Thanks for coming here again, great fun!
How is it determined which students get a place on the national program?
All students are included based on their credit value, the highest credit value comes in first.
What credit value do you need to get in?
It may look very different.
The schools have no lowest requirements.
Without the higher search pressure it is on the programs, higher credit value may be required to enter.
It is therefore important that you have several options in their application.
How do you calculate your credit value?
All grades have a corresponding number value, the grades go from E to A and the digit value from 10 up to 20.
To calculate their credit value, you put together their 16 or 17 highest ratings.
You can have 340 points at most.
If you have read language in elementary school and have at least E on that subject, you can count on it as their 17th rating.
At high school.se there is a credit calculator, how smoothly?
I know that many can be worried about the credit value, can you see somewhere what it has looked like before?
Yes you can through your high school admission.
There you can see statistics from previous years and get a picture of what the search pressure looked like and what credit value may be required.
If you do not know if you will be qualified or not to a national high school program, what is important to consider then?
If you are unauthorized for the national high school programs, there are four different introductory programs that you can apply for.
If you are at risk of not being qualified, it is important that you have any of the options from the introductory programs in your application.
What is meant by introductory programs?
On the introductory programs, all students have an individual study plan.
With the aim of either being eligible for a national high school program or with the goal of being able to enter the labor market.
What suits you best and what you are qualified for can look very different depending on what subjects and how many subjects you lack grades from elementary school.
To know more about the alternatives you can talk to the study and the career counselor at your school.
But you can also read more about them in articles here at high school.se
Thank you so much Melina for wanting to be here again.
Thanks for coming here!
I've got a lot of good info!
I said it, not that difficult.
Another step closer to the gym!