Jacob, will it be too much to say that I am their best friend during the high school choice?
Yeah, because it's not you.
Right just that.
Because it is high school.
Yes.
Warm welcome to the first section of High School.
During three whole sections we will guide you through the high school elevator jungle.
We have invited a bunch of experts to help us with this.
We start this journey by talking to Linnéa who is a study and career counselor.
She will help us with where to really start.
We also have Adrian and My here.
Previous high school elements to share their experiences.
We're running!
A warm welcome here Linnéa.
What fun you want to join.
Yes, will be great fun.
You work as a study and career counselor.
What is the most fun thing about your job?
The most fun thing about my job is getting to work with people in change, in positive change.
I work on informing but also to challenge the students in their thoughts and perceptions about the high school choice.
And it's very fun to see that process from start to finish.
I understand that.
You really get to influence their decision.
Very important.
We have received some questions from ninth graders who need your help.
We will start by looking at the first.
Hi, Markus is my name.
How do you get started with the high school choice?
There is so much to choose from.
Exactly, where should you really start?
Yes, it really does.
Many people find it difficult to start and do not know at all what to start with.
Neither school nor programs.
I usually give them the advice to start with what they do not want.
Most people usually have a good idea of this.
Smart to reverse it instead.
Exactly, and start funnel down.
I don't want to go to that school.
I am not interested in that program.
And in this way, get down the search width a bit.
Is there any other tip, when you have come to the conclusion which you do not want?
When you start to tread, and remove schools and programs, then the supply will not be as great.
Then you can start there by reading.
And maybe find something that you feel feels fun.
Just.
What is important to find out about different schools before deciding?
What you have to start with is, do I want a big school?
Or do I want a small school?
Should it be municipal or private?
Itinerary, schedule.
Do you have a dining room or food card.
And so on.
A common concern in students can be: will the high school choice affect your entire future?
How decisive would you say that it is?
You have to have with you that high school is a basic education no matter what program you go and what school you attend.
It is a basic education and it is definitely not vital.
Most people change direction several times over.
Nice to bring it with you.
You can always change or do something else forward.
Exactly, great.
Are there any common questions that you usually get from students?
Yes, a common question is about finding a school where you fit.
And that is subjective.
What does it mean to fit in?
I think you should think more about interest.
If you choose something that you are interested in then you meet like -minded people and then you fit in.
You may not have to go so much on the template but more interest.
We have one more question from a ninth -grader.
We look at it.
For example, if you want to become a doctor, what choice do you have?
Yes, if then wants to become a doctor, is there any special program that you should choose then?
It depends a little.
Do you think you should go straight, directly from high school to the university,
Then it is scientific or technical where you can bring the eligibility to search directly.
Then you have to bring with you to the medical line, it is one of the most difficult education to get into.
It's almost maximum points.
If you go nature and technology, which can be quite difficult training, then you may not get the maximum ratings.
Then it is difficult to get in anyway.
Even if you have the authority.
So the most tactical thing is to go the program where you can get the absolute best rating
And bring with it a grade that is competitive.
And then read to a base year or similar to obtain the eligibility.
So to again choose what you think is fun and thus make easier to learn and actually get high grades.
So that the correct or straight road may not always be the best for you.
Right.
You have to think about it.
Most people do not go a straight path, even if you think it when you are 15.
And you might regret it.
Then it is good to be competitive for more education than just the medical line.
Exactly, to broaden their choices.
Thanks!
There are a lot of difficult words linked to the high school choice.
We will pick up the notice board.
To see if you can help us find out what they really mean.
(Whistling)
Wow!
Right!
We start with the first word.
It is a real tongue switch.
Much like six salmon in salmon box.
It is: "High Secondary subjects".
What does it mean?
The upper secondary school subjects are the theoretical subjects that you read on all high school programs.
It is common to all the programs.
Type like math?
Matte, Swedish, English, sports, religion.
It was easier to understand that way.
Then we run the next word.
"Program focus" is very often mentioned.
What does it really mean?
Program focus is the in -depth study within the framework of your program.
First you choose a program and then you also choose an orientation.
Just that, for example, there is the community program that is the program,
And then there are slightly different recesses that you can choose under it.
This one then?
Completely incomprehensible.
There are two words for that.
One is "student for a day" or "shading".
Have you heard of it?
It is the upper secondary schools that offer students at the elementary school to come and test on being a student for a day.
Just as it sounds.
You have to walk next to a student at lessons and lunch to see what it would be like to go to school.
And shading is the same.
This means shadowing a student and following it all day.
I understand, you get a shadow after you.
But it can be a great idea if you are not so sure of your choice.
To test in one day.
Yes, great, great.
Last then.
"High school work", what is it?
At all high school programs you do a high school work at the end of the third.
And it is an in -depth work within the framework of the program you read.
If you read the community program, you make a slightly larger social science in -depth work.
Well, but do you do it on both vocational preparation and college preparatory programs?
Yes, you do this on all the programs, but on the vocational preparation it can be a practical job.
And at the university preparatory, it is always a theoretical work.
Okay.
Thank you for being with today, great fun!
Thanks.
(Whistling)
We go ahead and welcome Adrian and My.
What fun to have you here.
Many thanks.
Thank you for being here.
You have both previously made a high school choice.
Now it was a bunch of years ago that you took the student.
Do you remember what it was like to make your high school choice?
Yes, I really do.
It was not an easy decision.
But I still landed in something that I am happy today.
How fun.
What did you think Adrian, was it difficult?
Well, that's it.
The most difficult thing was to first understand the difference between all the programs and schools,
Understand which one would choose and why.
There were many difficult decisions in a fairly short time.
It aroused many thoughts.
And confusion in many cases too.
Which program did you choose then?
I ultimately chose technology, but it was a long time between economics and technology.
Why did you just choose technology end?
It felt like a broad education where I would get a lot of knowledge that could help me whatever I wanted to read.
I always had a plan to walk the financial track but after I did some investigations
So I got the information that I could walk the financial track even if I read the technology program.
Which gave me pretty broad choices and it felt like a safe alternative to go.
Fun to get your interest as well.
Absolutely.
Which program did you choose my?
I chose to read the community program.
Was it an easy choice?
No it really wasn't.
I venered right into the last and I remember I changed the last hour before the deadline.
Oh!
It was tight.
Yes indeed.
It was precisely because I wanted something that was broad.
Which program did you stand and chose when you then changed your mind to community?
I chose between society and nature.
It was because nature has certain courses that you have to have in order to be allowed to read a doctor or so.
But then it was also a lot of peer pressure, what others chose.
I felt that if I choose nature then it is just because most others that I was with it.
Lucky you went after your own liking end.
What have you been doing since the student Adrian?
I actually started a company during my studies.
When I was nine but then it started during high school.
So already in one in high school I had companies, which I still run today.
Today I have about three companies I run.
On a daily basis.
Fun!
Is it the technology track or?
It actually is.
I thought, when I started the technology program,
That I would become a programmer and sit and tap code.
But realized that it wasn't my thing those pieces.
But gained enough understanding to understand how IT works.
And what it actually means.
Which makes me run IT companies at present, but I do not do any programming myself.
Without driving more sales track, which became my thing.
But has gained an incredible amount of knowledge from the studies.
Then you have really benefited from your education but maybe in a different way what was thinking from the beginning.
Absolutely.
It wasn't quite as I had imagined, but it resolved anyway.
What have you been doing since the student?
After the student, I was probably one of many who didn't really know what they wanted to do.
Then I worked as a substitute, in a substitute pool, around various schools in the municipality where I worked.
How fun.
Yes, it was really fun.
Then I want to continue with this track.
I wanted to do something broad because I didn't know what I wanted to work on.
Then I started reading the School of Economics at Lund University.
And today I work as a marketing coordinator.
You told me during the coffee break that today you are also a mentor to a guy who is studying at college today.
What are you doing then?
It is a mentoring network that Lund University has organized.
Students who are in the middle of their studies get a mentor.
I get to act his ball board during the studies.
How cool.
Are you happy with your choice of programs like this afterwards?
Yes, I would definitely say that.
Yes indeed.
Do you have any tips Adrian, to those who will start high school now?
I think it is very important that you do not put all the focus on just the studies, even though they are very important.
But I think it is very important also that you preserve a leisure activity, hobby or other interest.
And actually spend time with friends and do things you think is fun too.
It is easy to just snow in on the studies and get tired or get stuck and then suddenly it goes worse.
Dare to do what you think is fun and go a little your own way outside the plug too.
I think that is very important.
Great tips.
There are really three fun years to take advantage of, their high school time.
Really.
My, would you say in retrospect that your choice of program or school was vital?
Well, I really wouldn't.
There are many ways to go.
Wonderful to hear.
Thank you very much for being with you today and sharing your experiences.
Many thanks.
Thanks.
Big thanks for looking today.
In the end, we offer some high school students' best tips for you to make your choice.
See you in the next section.
Before I started high school, I had wished someone told me that it will be quite like elementary school.
But that more responsibility lies with yourself than with teachers and parents.
Because it is a little longer days and you have to have more responsibility and try to catch the plug.
I had wished someone told me that it is not at all dangerous to start high school.
You are obviously nervous before but it is something that disappears immediately when you get there.
For everyone is new and everyone is nervous and there is no danger.
I would have liked to be aware that it is important to put all the powder in the beginning and all the way through.
Since the grades you receive even in grade one are something that will remain all the way out.
So that you are not waiting to save everything in the last second.