Fill with new habits in Höststaden Gothenburg.
To fill up with the best inspiration for all the good pastries I do ...
... so I visit the best cafes in Gothenburg.
Gothenburg grows so it is cracking ...
... and it's great fun that people have experienced new food cultures.
That Gothenburg has grown like this with restaurants,
It has been absolutely magical.
To fill my autumn wardrobe, I like to go to a second hand shop.
I think it is very important to shop sustainable,
And in Gothenburg you can shop from sustainable stores.
Yes, now I am in the place that is the best to replenish energy.
I think the fig culture is highly up to date in Gothenburg.
You still want to sit and have a cup of coffee and eat a good pastry ...
... while you sit and gossip and chatter and have it wonderful.
Autumn city Gothenburg