The war is over and the Swedish army is retreat from Norway over the mountains.
Sweden has lost, and the road here has been long and difficult.
As the Great Power Time is heading to its end-
- Sweden goes through some of the most difficult times the country has been involved.
Witch burns, misgrowth and plague ...
All wars transform Sweden into a military state -
- And thousands of young men will die in the attempts to preserve the superpower.
This is the story of our country.
About the people and forces that have shaped it -
- Endure from the ice age until our days.
This is the story of Sweden.
Swedish Empire in 1658.
Years of successful wars have given Sweden areas both in the east and south.
Many pay tribute to the Swedish warriors.
Poets describe the Swedes as a people chosen by God -
- And scientist Olof Rudbeck writes that the country can be Atlantis.
But that the Swedish kingdom has become so great is a small comfort for ordinary people.
You have a hard time in Sweden.
Harvests fail and people starve.
It is a misery that must have an explanation - and a scapegoat.
The time of witch processes is here.
Stories about sorcery and witchcraft are starting to spread.
Swedish soldiers who return home have such stories with them.
On the continent, they become witnesses to bonfires and witchcraft processes.
/Church bells squeeze/
When the stories of witches are given, they spread like wildfire across the country.
Neighbors and family members begin to accuse each other for sorcery.
Here in Torsåker in Ångermanland, it is the priest who holds the clock.
In Sweden, priests had long accused people of doing magic -
- When they read rams about wounds and other things that the church thought was pagan.
But the allegations of witchcraft were something completely different.
It was children who accused, and they said they were abducted at night.
The children tell imaginative stories -
- In how the witches take them to Blåkulla at night.
That they had to write their names with blood in the devil's book during crazy parties.
The children said the women danced with the devil, had sex with him -
- And gave birth to children they boiled in tickles.
In the interrogation protocols, it is obvious that the children have been inspired by each other.
From the beginning, the governing bodies could accept a number of executions -
- To calm down the situation, but the result was exactly the opposite.
A mass hysteria with accusations and trunk burns spreads in the country.
One of the drivers behind the witch process in Torsåker-
- Is the priest Laurentius Hornaeus.
His mother had been executed for sorcery without trying to save her.
Hornaeus had the help of two spanks:
Two orphans who said they could show which were witches -
- By seeing a mark in the forehead of those who were in covenants with the devil.
Therefore, they got paid to stand on the church hill and point out witches.
Witch!
It was extremely difficult.
If the women went to the church, they could be designated.
And if they stayed at home, it could be a sign that they were witches.
On one occasion, one of the boys pointed out the priest's wife -
- But then he got a proper ear file.
Then he said he saw wrong because he had the sun in his eyes.
The accused are interrogated.
You want to know which others have been involved.
Soon more and more women are being identified.
On October 15, 1674, a trial begins.
The women here are believed to have been locked up all winter while waiting for execution.
It must have been very scary.
Accusations, interrogations, death sentences and certainly nightmares as well.
In the end, maybe they began to doubt themselves.
About seventy people are charged, and almost all are women.
Every fifth woman living here is identified as a witch.
And it's not just where people are accused.
The death sentences become so many -
–The authorities try to stop them with special sorcery commissions -
- which must try the judges before anyone can be executed.
In Torsåker, many people probably believed that the Commission would mitigate the judges.
And some government officials thought the witch processes went too far.
You do not know why, but the Commission did not mitigate the judges in Torsåker.
After months of interrogation and waiting, it is decided to execute the sentence.
The convicted people should be killed.
On the execution day, they are given communion - and then understand what will happen.
In total, some seventy people are executed this night.
And the bodies are then burned on a bonfire.
These terrible witch processes that occur in many parts of the country -
-In the end of the 17th century, was called "the great noise".
In Stockholm, several people are convicted of sorcery -
- Here at Stigberget on Södermalm.
But now ever higher protests are starting to be heard.
How many are to die?
The authorities may have enough and more are starting to suspect that the children are inventing.
Suddenly one of the children who testifies together during a hearing breaks.
And this girl can tell you that the children's stories are pure lies.
They have driven each other with their fantasies.
And so the hot hunt is over.
The authorities call the witch charges for mass hysteria.
In the country's churches, the priests must now stand in the pulpit and tell -
- The witch processes have been a mistake, that the devil has deceived us all.
In the Torsåker district it is said that people afterwards went detours -
- To avoid walking past the parsonage.
The two speeches in Torsåker are found to be killed.
No one cares to investigate who is guilty of their death.
At this time, a new king sits on the Swedish throne - Karl XI.
He has become of legal age and will control the superpower that he inherited from his father.
Many people underestimate the young Karl XI.
He is probably dyslexics and his studies are slow.
Many people believe that the king is uneducated and doubts that he has what is required -
- To solve the problems Sweden is facing.
Sweden has been ruled by a guardian government.
There is a crisis in the Treasury.
And in Denmark Kristian V is waiting for an opportunity to attack Sweden -
- And take back Skåne, Blekinge and Halland.
And when he notices that Sweden's situation is bad, he sees his chance.
Now the war comes to Swedish soil.
Denmark attacks Sweden from several directions.
The uncertainty that Karl XI has shown in the lesson room is as blown away -
- When he is going up in the saddle on his horse.
He will show his ability in the war that now breaks out -
- When Denmark is trying to take back Skåne.
At first, things are not going well.
Once the war has been going on for a year-
- If the Danes have taken up almost all of Skåne.
The Swedish army is weakened.
One -third of the soldiers have died -
- Or they have become ill in the cold and infected tent camps.
When winter comes, the Swedish army is close to Lund -
- Where the Danish army has camped.
The Swedes stand on one side of Kävlingeån, the Danes on the other.
The Swedes decide to surprise the Danes -
–Com by moving very early in the morning -
- The day after the Danes have had a wet party in the camp.
With a surprise attack, Karl XI intends to invest everything on a card -
- In one last desperate maneuver to break a long series of Danish victories.
The Swedes are at a sub-
“But the soldiers are trained to fight in a way that turns out effectively.
The Swedish combat technology is based on, one could almost say -
- You surprise the opponent and go to brutal attack.
The Swedish soldiers take turns to fire their muskets against the enemy -
- At the same time as they advance.
And the cavalry attacks in groups, they ride closely together -
- With the enemy lines, without stopping to shoot.
The Swedes do not have much choice.
If you want to win this kind, an aggressive behavior is required.
As quickly as possible, you get into close range.
The moment is in for Karl XI's chance.
With their 8,000 men-
- He try to surprise the Danish army that is 5,000 people stronger.
Before the attack, he writes to his mother, the widow queen Hedvig Eleonora:
"We shall fight or die."
At half past three in the morning of December 4, 1676-
- Is the ice on Kävlingeån thick enough to carry an entire army.
It is the introduction to the Battle of Lund.
The two forces collapse at half past nine.
There was a basic plan for how to arrange the troops:
The infantry in the middle and cavalry on the wings.
But once the battle starts, an organized chaos arises.
It is black gun smoke, projectiles and horses that swirl up dust -
- So an individual soldier perceives very little of what is happening.
He looks a few meters.
It is tunnel vision at best.
A large part of the soldiers will not be able to work on the battlefield at all.
They will be paralyzed by horror.
Soldiers and people are injured around.
It must be an extreme fear.
You have to feel huge adrenaline rush.
They come from the same parishes, it can be childhood mates and relatives.
One does not fight primarily for the national feeling, the king or the commanders-
- You are fighting for the closest comrades.
The fighting waves back and forth.
But when the Swedish Army attacks the Danes from two directions -
- With Karl XI at the head of the cavalry, the Danes flee.
At five o'clock in the afternoon, Karl XI gives orders for ceasefire.
The Swedes win in the bloodiest battle on Swedish soil ever.
About 9,000 men die, of which 6,000 are Danes -
- Double as many as the Swedish losses.
The battle becomes a turning point in the war, and three years later the war is over.
Karl XI has proven himself on the battlefield.
Sweden may keep Skåne, but it is in ash and ruins.
After the Scanian war, the Swedish Treasury is in lousy condition.
The war has cost both in crew and in money resources -
–And you need new income.
Instead of tax increases, which was the usual road -
- Getting funds for the Treasury, so you made another choice.
You reduced the nobility's goods, you pulled in goods to the crown.
Some nobles got rid of a lot.
After all, they were not poor -
- But they had lost several of their significant goods.
This action goes to history as "the great reduction".
In the same vein, Karl XI makes a singleness.
Like the Danish and French king, he would have unrestricted power.
The peasants want to limit the power of the nobility and support the decision on a single king.
Both statutory and executive power are now placed in the king's hands.
The king plays skillfully here, as young he is.
Karl XI manages to maneuver the groups towards each other -
- and make themselves a single.
When now the king was liable only before God-
- It was almost impossible for the nobility to oppose.
Karl XI can now control the kingdom entirely himself.
The young king can initiate war, enact laws and introduce taxes -
- Created as he wants.
Karl XI has a plan.
He will build a defense that can protect the Swedish superpower.
So he builds the armed forces deep in Swedish society.
In the countryside, women who get married can become soldier wives.
In the Swedish villages there must be professional soldiers who are ready for war.
A standing army.
The peasants should themselves obtain suitable soldiers -
- As they give a torpedo with land to grow on, in peacetime.
And the soldiers get names like lance, shooter and fast.
Over time, Karl XI's soldiers will be called Carolines.
It is now that the Carolines get their uniform uniform:
The blue famous uniform with the half -length jacket.
55,000 are manufactured across the country.
The whole of Sweden is started and becomes an effective military state.
Except that all soldiers get a soil -clogging after their rank-
- So you also get a house.
Soldiers get torp, and then in rising order-
- From sub -officers to officers and colonel, you get a residence -
- As a military position corresponds to.
The church is the state's propaganda machine.
At the worship services, the people are informed of the success of the country and the king.
The pulpits are also used to read laws and regulations.
But everyone does not fit into Karl XI's new order for Sweden.
Some who happen to be bad are the Sami.
In the 17th century came the loose driver law, as protection against loose driver and begging.
People were not allowed to run loose.
Sami became one of the groups that went under the loose driver.
At this time, Sami lives not only in the north, but down to Mälardalen.
Some lived in cities, some were farmers or fishermen-
- While others lived like nomads.
Since the nomads had no fixed address, they were difficult to tax.
You do not want population outside the patchwork lands, which cannot be taxed.
Thus, you force, or try to force, Sami to move to the north.
The state, Kronan, wanted the Sami out in the mountain world -
-For they were at home with their reindeer, so it gave the work return -
- In the form of tax that the crown took in.
So the Sami began to tame the wilds instead, and have them closer.
The view of the Sami is partly changed in the 17th century.
They begin to be considered an exciting, exotic element -
- And you are interested in the Sami high -quality crafts and products.
A "we and judgment" perspective is created.
The view of the patchwork is different.
The area is seen as a large colony-
-for example.
as India or Africa, with resources to exploit.
You go there to see the exclusive, exotic, unexpected -
- And to buy and may sometimes steal Sami objects, Sami craft.
You could say that it is the basis for politics that comes.
"Patch should be a patch" is very clear during the 20th century.
The end of the 17th century are difficult times.
At the same time as “the flower time” begins to be sung in the country-
- Sweden's Sweden is affected and starvation.
These years of the 1690s are terrible disaster years.
It is among the worst times to live in Sweden ever.
Harvests fail several years in a row because the weather is very strange.
This is during the Little Ice Age, with a generally cooler climate than today.
In addition, the seasons seem to be out of play.
It is hot in winter, the grass grows in February.
And in the summer it rains and is frost.
The crops do not grow and it causes people to starve to death, simply.
The famine and weather phenomena were seen by some as evil ome-
- Conditions about a future disaster.
And at the castle, Karl XI is severely ill and weak.
His body is eaten by a cancerous tumor that grows in his stomach.
That the king is struck in this situation, while the famine advises -
- It is interpreted as now wanting God to punish Sweden for real.
The king dies in April 1697, but the accidents do not end there.
Just a month later, a fire spreads at the castle Three Kronor.
And the castle burns down.
When Karl XI dies, his son inherits the crown.
Karl XII now becomes the king of Sweden.
He is crowned 15 years old and calls himself Carolus.
For him, it is a matter of course to be a single.
It is a difficult challenge for Karl XII to control its large areas.
He is untested and very young -
- And Sweden's enemies see their chance to regain territories they lost.
After a series of attacks in 1700, Sweden ends up in war with three enemies.
The king has no choice.
He must defend the Swedish territories.
And this is the beginning of the Great Nordic War.
Karl XII is only 17 years old when the war breaks out.
The sources tell about a man who is both eager and nervous.
He sees it as his sacred duty to defend the kingdom he inherited.
Karl XII is now in motion all the military defense machine -
- As his father built up.
Soldiers are called in.
At the estate Salshult in Småland, rider champion Jon Stålhammar - has
- The wife Sofia Drake and the couple's four children.
Sofia writes in her calendar: "Anno 1700 on June 7" -
- "My dear husband traveled away from me to Skåne, as well as the whole army."
"God give them all his blessing" -
- "And soon let them with health, peace and joy come home to us again."
The farewell is many and the uncertainty is great.
Do they ever come back?
During the 17th century war, eight of ten called died in war service.
Everyone was aware of.
It was very alive in the popular memory how dangerous it was to be a soldier.
Karl XII directs his power south.
The Carolines march to Skåne and Denmark.
With the help of allies, Sweden presses the Danish King -
- To withdraw their troops and cancel the war.
Then Karl XII looks at Russia which besieged the Swedish city of Narva.
He ships his army to the Baltic.
But in Narva it looks very dark.
The Swedish army stands against almost four times as many Russian soldiers.
In Sweden, many want to know how things are going for friends and relatives in the army.
So you gather in the churches, where news about the war is spread.
When the war is successful, you celebrate thanksgiving days in all churches.
Everyone learns how good the soldiers and the king have been.
But when things go bad, then it is quiet.
While the women are waiting for a message about their spouses, they have a great responsibility -
- Take care of the yard, the animals and the children.
A very tiring job.
But they are also awaiting concern for the message for another reason:
If the husband dies in battle, the woman must leave her torp-
- If within a year she will not find herself a new man who can become a soldier.
If that does not happen, she must leave from home and farm with her children.
After a long silence of the king ...
/Church bells and cannon salute/
... reaches the news Stockholm.
10,000 Carolines have defeated a four times as much Russian strength -
- At Narva in the Baltic States.
The Swedish people are encouraged to celebrate the victory - and they are happy to do so.
The stories of Narva emphasize that Karl XII bravely rode in the first line -
- Something that was unusual at this time.
Now the image of Karl XII - is created
- As the great warrior king, and then he is depicted several hundred years later.
After the Battle of Narva, the Russian Army is temporarily eliminated -
- But other enemies remain.
So Karl XII directs his army towards present -day Poland and northern Germany.
When the king is out in the field, the Swedish kingdom is governed by the Royal Council.
Since the castle Three Kronor burned down, the council sits in the Wrangelska palace.
But it is still Karl XII who decides.
He controls the kingdom with letter-
- As he sends from the campaign, and the council does as the king says.
The letters may take months to arrive.
It says that the king wants -
- The advice will withdraw more money and send more soldiers.
Karl XII does not come home to Sweden for many years.
He remains down on the continent in an extended war.
The motive behind almost all of the Karl XII did -
- Where to preserve the kingdom that his father had built up.
I think, because no one knows for sure.
The result, which no one could know from the beginning-
- Boyed a big failure.
A war company that depleted the country on resources -
- Especially money and mankraft.
Stålhammar hopes during the first years of the war on a near peace.
In 1703 he writes to Sofia from Riga that if he only saw her again -
- he never would go away again.
He gives her advice on how to manage the farm.
It should be cleared and walled in the Great Hall.
Unlike others, Sofia gets a better economy when her husband has become a major.
She invests when the krona sells farms to finance the war.
And Stålhammar sends home war changes such as furs, fabrics and valuables.
For several years, Karl XII is fighting in present -day Poland and northern Germany.
The army is dependent on the local community and lives on what the area has to provide.
This is one of the reasons why you prefer to fight abroad.
Mostly they were in march and in camps and tried to survive.
It was the soldier's everyday life.
Battle were only explosive small elements that lasted a day at most.
The greatest risk of dying was not in the battle field, but it was of illness.
Most often it is dysentery that has to do with food, or it is typhoid.
And this is spread in the camps, where you live close to each other.
The soldiers, military leadership and officers -
- They were not alone in an army.
Here was the belief, which was an obvious part.
It consisted of various craftsmen needed for the maintenance of the army:
Wagons with food and horses that drew all this.
And in addition a civilian companion-
- Women and children and share the locals -
- From the resorts that the army passed.
Several women are active in the Market Center -
- Where you sell tobacco, spirits, some food and stuff to the soldiers.
Karl XII considered it problematic with women in the field, especially if they were -
- Of lower rank.
They were unsatisfied, he thought, and the slow -down pace.
Karl XII wants as little as possible to do with civilists -
- And others who can interfere with military and military purposes.
In different ways the king tried to reduce the need -
- Of civilian assistants, especially women.
Women for the care of the sick were needed, and marketing shoes were needed.
But others were not welcome.
Karl XII introduced restrictions on marriage in the field -
- Prompt all marriage in enemy country.
But these rules were still not carved in stone.
It appeared that soldiers met someone in the locals -
- As the soldier wanted to marry.
After all, women were important for some functions in the army.
So it happened that the military leadership approved marriage -
- The restrictive attitude of the king.
In August 1708, the Nordic War has been going on for eight years -
-And Karl XII leaves Poland-Liteuan.
But he doesn't return home.
Peter the Great has taken Narva and mastered a large part of the Baltic -
- So Karl XII heads east with his soldiers, towards the Russian army.
It will lead to the end of a long series of successes for Karl XII.
On the way to the Russian army, Stålhammar writes to his wife Sofia Drake.
He has been in the field for many years.
She is worried that he is falling for temptation.
But he assures her: "I'm faithful to you."
Despite the fact that Stålhammar tried to discourage the children from becoming soldiers -
- So seventeen -year -old son Johan Adolf joins the father in the field.
And now Stålhammar has to send bad news to his wife.
The son Johan Adolf has been shot in his leg.
But steel hammers comfort:
"Don't worry. The boy will survive, the wound is not deep."
But a week later Sofia gets a new letter -
- Where Stålhammar tells us that the son is dead:
"Wound fever put in, no medicine helped."
"I'm of the heart sad" -
- "But what can you do other than to submit to God's gracious will?"
"Now at least the boy doesn't have to suffer more, avoiding this world" -
- "which is so full of sin and pain."
Even Major Stålhammar dies later that year -
- On November 3, 1708 on the border with Ukraine.
The pain of war affects both poor and rich.
At the end of August 1709, the news reaches Sweden for a terrible defeat.
A disaster has hit Karl XII's army.
The Swedish main force has been wiped out by the Russians at Poltava.
After the loss at Poltava–
- A large number of prisoners of war will be added to Russia, maybe 20,000.
Soldiers such as civilians, men as women, become prisoners of war -
- In various locations in Russia, where they will perform criminal work.
Many of them never revisit their homeland again.
After the defeat, Karl XII goes to Bender in Moldova -
- Where he is protected by the Ottoman Sultan.
With him he has only 1,300 soldiers - those left by his large army.
According to him, Poltava was just a temporary defeat.
He writes:
"The war must continue. The Council must raise money for a new army."
To recruit, equip and train a brand new field army -
- As is to be shipped across the continent to the king, is not easy.
The Swedish people have already been hard tested by famine and the burden of war.
And new difficulties are soon on the way.
In June 1710, a hungry sea captain manages to throw past the guards -
- As will keep all ships in quarantine to protect Stockholm.
At a tavern just outside the capital, the captain suddenly dies ...
... infected by the plague.
The dreaded disease is back in Stockholm.
People get sick in high fever, with large bumps in groin and armpits.
Most die within a couple of days.
The worst spreads here among the poor and crowded at Södermalm.
But the disease does not spare social strata.
The plague -hit homes are marked with a white cross on the door.
Funerals, weddings, baptisms and parties are canceled and the schools are kept closed.
No loose animals may be found on the streets.
Thousands of dogs and cats are killed.
In Stockholm, almost 22,000 died, of a population of 55,000.
Almost half the population died in just six months.
Karl XII remains in the Ottoman Empire for several years.
He tries to get the Turkish Sultan to help Sweden against the Russians -
- But fails.
And despite the fact that the Swedish people are hard pressed -
- So Karl XII now wants even more resources for his army.
He decides that everyone in Sweden should pay 2 percent of everything they own -
- In a new treasure.
And it hits hard against the already poor Swedes.
The tax becomes another burden that the people will carry.
Because of the wars, new amounts of men are constantly written into the armies.
In the end, it becomes difficult to get men to the armies -
- And it will be a big surplus of women.
In Stockholm, as much as 60 percent of the population consists of women -
- What is likely to be world -unique.
It leads to some other world -unique:
The female thieves become more than the male in Stockholm.
In normal cases, thieves are a male occupation.
Not only thieves are looking for exchanges at the Stockholm pubs.
The enrollers are looking for new soldiers.
The system created by Karl XII's father was intended for defense -
- And the soldiers are not enough for Karl XII's major war company.
So to obtain new soldiers, the authorities take to questionable methods.
The enrollers had tricks to make the young men become soldiers.
Officially, it was voluntary and an honor to become the king's soldier.
But many needed to be persuaded.
In 1714, Karl XII has fought for 14 years.
It is now bad for soldiers and money.
Karl XII returns to Sweden from his long campaign abroad.
Many people hope that it can finally be peace.
But it won't be.
The king tries to negotiate peace, but fails.
New mobilization is needed.
New soldiers and new treasures.
The king takes all possible means.
He takes international loans-
- And many emergency coins are characterized, which will stimulate the economy.
It may seem strange that the protests -
–Mot Karl XII's regime, the war companies and the war policy -
- Not more extensive than they were.
There were protests, but on a very small scale.
Going against a single king, selected by God, is unthinkable for most.
A new generation of soldiers are now being printed.
As Sweden is again at war with Denmark -
–Chink Karl XII attack the Danes by entering Norway -
- As at this time, part of the Danish empire is.
The kingdom's baking rooms are now given a role in the king's new strategy.
For the army has very little to live in the barren Norwegian landscape.
The king lets bake a nutritious and durable bread.
The result is a compact and dry crust -
- As has to be soaked to eat.
This device engaged a large part of the country's bakers-
–And all sorts of groups that were allowed to porch food -
- To special magazines along the Norwegian border.
The idea is that the Carolines themselves should carry parts of their food -
- To be able to fight without being dependent on the enemy resources.
An effect of this huge organization where -
- The civilian sequence was reduced precisely because it was not needed.
His crusts are precursors to the soldiers' field food even in our time.
It was an innovation in military strategy, one could say -
- Organizing the food attitude in this way.
Although Sweden's people are depleted and war -tired -
- Is Karl XII's soldiers still loyal.
They see the king closest as a mythical figure, someone who is invulnerable -
- And maybe even immortal.
Karl XII has fortified the image of himself -
- As a fearless leader who fights with his men.
And so it was also this evening, November 30, 1718 in Norway.
The king inspects the siege work in the dark.
Cannons at this time sometimes fired so -called mapsch shoots -
–Dvs.
A shotgun of old scrap and balls of different sizes.
Suddenly, Karl XII is met by a projectile in the temple.
Probably it is such a shot from the Norwegian side -
- Which goes straight through the king's skull and kills him immediately.
And the Swedish military state stops.
Carolines, the proud army -
- As so often surprised and struck out of the disadvantage, collapses.
The famous fashion and cohesion are gone.
The great warrior king is dead.
The news strikes like a bomb.
The great power is over, and for generations, man - will
- To look back at and romanticize this era.
166 years after the king's death, Gustaf Cederström paints this board.
It will long be the mindset for how Karl XII's equality went.
It expresses not only a beaten army, but also a people in mourning.
But the artist took liberties.
This was not how it went.
It was a much simpler story.
He is placed in a pine with a lid.
In this way you transport the king, not over the mountain.
The Swedish border is crossed at Svinesund, on a barge or via a raft bridge.
Eventually this corpse comes to Uddevalla -
- Where you also make a more lavish coffin of oak.
The death sentence reaches the force that has entered Norway for a long time north-
- With soldiers from mainly Finland, but also from Norrland.
Lieutenant General Carl Gustaf Armfeldt leads a strength of about 6,000 men.
On New Year's Eve, they start their return over the mountains.
It is terribly cold and they have far too poor equipment.
They are bad with clothes and bad with food.
A storm strikes when the strength reached the mountain side.
At least 3,000 soldiers remained in the mountains, dead.
And of those who survived, around 600 people suffered injuries for life.
The wars are not over just because the king dies.
When Karl XII's sister Ulrika Eleonora is crowned to Queen -
- She and the Royal Council negotiate peace with Russia.
But the negotiations drag on over time.
For several years, Russian forces occupy Finland-
–And Fire Rarms settlements and cities along the coast -
- From Luleå and Piteå in the north to Norrköping in the south.
But there will be peace with Denmark, for payment of damages and customs.
And then with Russia.
And some of the Swedish soldiers -
- Which has been prisoners of war in Russia, now manages to get home.
But the Sweden they left is not the same.
After so many years, many soldiers have been declared dead -
–And their wives then have married a new soldier -
- To cope with everyday life and keep their home.
Sweden is forced to leave the territories in the Baltics and around the Baltic Sea.
The attempts to defend the superpower had a high price.
For 100 years, up to 1721, so you count on -
- The third adult Swedish man dies in the service of the army or the fleet.
But now the great power is over.
New winds are starting to blow.
New goods and new thoughts from the world outside should push away the old -
- And change society and the life of the Swedes.
Texting: Ulrika Jansson Båving Swedish Media Text for SVT