She will be one of the most powerful Middle Ages.
After this day, people will think that she is in contact with God.
She will be one of the Catholic Church's most important saints.
Known in the world as the Holy Birgitta.
We are in the early Middle Ages.
It starts well, these are good times.
The Swedes have become Christians.
The economy is booming, the harvests are good and the population is growing.
The Swedish Empire is being built, step by step.
But everything is challenged when times get worse, the climate becomes colder -
- And the plague pulls out and wipes out a third of the population.
Christianity promises eternal life-
- But many people get to meet hell here on earth.
This is the story of our country.
About the people and forces that have shaped it -
- Endure from the ice age until our days.
This is the story of Sweden.
Today, many people do not care that Christmas is about Jesus' birth.
So it was not in the Middle Ages.
Then faith was strong.
Christmas night was known to be filled with ghosts.
It was said that it was when the boundary between living and dead was blurred.
It is the mid-1100s, and King Sverker is on his way to Santa.
Sverker has been king for over 20 years.
It is a long time for a king in the Nordic countries at this time.
Rarely do you survive as long as king.
/BLEATING/
/LAUGH/
Sverker is murdered by one of his own men.
No unusual fate for a king during the early Middle Ages.
Different great men are constantly fighting for power.
The kings are weak and not very rich.
Sweden is a fairly small kingdom at this time.
The king's power is limited.
Instead, there are great men and bishops who are strong.
In different alliances, they decide who is to become king.
It takes 100 years before the royal power is strong enough and rich -
- To be able to control the whole country and become a real national power.
But we're not there yet.
It is not so important who is king over Sweden.
Instead, God and faith play the greatest role in the lives of people.
Sweden has become Christian.
Churches are being built around the country-
- And monastery, like this in Alvastra.
With Christianity, the belief will that everyone can have a life after death.
People have been given a new worldview and their lives a new meaning.
In the churches, the priests preach how man should have eternal life.
Christianity gave man new opportunities.
During the Viking Age, only the warriors came to Valhall, a heavenly nest.
Now everyone can have a life after death, if you just follow God's commandments.
Everyone is given the opportunity to get to heaven.
And that becomes your own responsibility.
You get greater responsibility and greater opportunities in this way.
The ideals in society change with the values of the Christian Church.
The poor and vulnerable also have a soul.
You should be humble and include them in society.
The rites in Christianity also mean some news.
There is a lot of magic in them.
Hoc est enim ...
Hoc est Enim Corpus MEM - Hocus Pocus comes from those words.
They were heard in the fair and could not place them.
The priest turns wine and bread into the blood and body of Christ.
The Catholic Church and Christianity affect the Swedes in many ways.
The worldview is changing.
Christianity explains both heaven and earth.
Society is changing.
This applies to healing arts, it applies to agriculture ...
... mining.
Everything, really.
Many people think of the Middle Ages as dark, but that is not true.
During the early Middle Ages, in the 12th century, life is quite good.
The climate is warm and comfortable, the harvesters good, the country is booming.
Maybe you connect this with the new faith and the Christian God.
It seemed that God appreciated hard work and faith -
- And that he heard their prayers.
The people had earned themselves the good times.
God was behind everything.
The good harvests also cause Sweden's population to grow.
They become about twice as many -
- During the first two centuries in medieval Sweden.
Agricultural technology is changing, and we have access to iron.
Then we can improve the tools we work with.
The shovel comes as a tool, you work more with dika ur-
–And use chips that one did not use before-
- But now needed to grow food for the entire population.
Increased productivity means that tax revenue for royal power increases.
Over time, it will strengthen it.
The church also serves on the good times.
The church benefits from agriculture expanding and providing surplus.
Here you drum in our first permanent tax - tiondet -
- A tenth of everything is given to the church.
The basis for our municipal tax.
It took a long time to drum through, but people saw where the riches went.
They were channeled to the church, which could then repair bridges and roads -
- Pay for someone to plug.
When you saw where it went, it was accepted.
Something new the Catholic Church brings with it is the belief in saints.
Saints are people who are considered sacred after their death.
In the Middle Ages, they are hugely popular.
One of Sweden's first saints will be this woman.
With her life, and dramatic death, she writes in Swedish history -
- And becomes known as Holy Elin, or Saint Helena.
She is still honored today.
She is a rich widow with large properties in the Skövdetrakt.
She gives many gifts to the church, and lives a godly life.
She marries one of her daughters, but the marriage is not successful.
Instead, it causes Elin's life to take a violent turn.
The son -in -law abuses Elin's daughter.
In the area you start talking behind Elin's back.
The situation must of course have plagued Elin personally a lot.
But in addition, it is serious for her social position.
She must be able to protect her child.
How else can she protect the countryside?
/Tormented screams and angry cries/
When the son -in -law is murdered, Elin is suspected of being behind his death.
Whether she is guilty or not, we do not know.
Shortly after the murder, Elin leaves on a pilgrimage, and is away for a long time.
Pilgrimage trips, as well as crusades -
- to search for sacred places, wander in the footsteps of Jesus -
- Is a spiritual investment in life after this and one's own bliss.
Elin is one of the first Swedes to visit Holy Jerusalem.
Elin is gone for almost two years before she returns home.
The son -in -law's family is still said to suspect Elin for the murder.
Shortly after Elin's return, a church will be opened nearby.
Elin has donated money to the building, and moves to the inauguration.
But she never arrives.
According to the story, it is the son -in -law's family that ensures that Elin is killed.
A water source is said to break forward at the site where she is murdered -
- And it is followed by more miracles.
Soon Elin will be declared.
With his pious life, the gifts to the church, the pilgrimage to Jerusalem -
- And since the awful death, Elin was a perfect saint.
Then she becomes a great spiritual resource for her survivors -
- As a saint in the family.
And Skövdebygden gets a saint.
Saint, miracles, sacred relics, spiritual wonders -
- Are big during this era.
Not everyone can afford Jerusalem, but you can go to Skövde.
It was to this church in Götene that Elin was on her way when she was murdered.
In here, something unusual is hidden.
In the altar, a shrine has been walled since the Middle Ages.
In it, Elin's finger is said to lie, wrapped in linen fabric.
In the stories of Elin a blind man stroked his finger over his eyes -
- And got the sight back.
This little skeleton part is thus a relic.
In the Middle Ages, relics were worth gold.
They were said to cure diseases and protect against evil.
The person or institution that had a chip from the Holy Cross-
-A tag from Jesus' thorn crown or a finger joint from a saint -
- Kundde is happy.
Then they stood under the protection of a saint.
Where the relics were there, it was also believed that the saints were.
The relationship with a saint could be more personal than the one to God.
As a saint, women can also be revered in the same way as men.
But this ends with the Reformation in the 16th century.
Then the saint worship is banned, and relics are destroyed throughout the country.
But Elin's finger was rescued and walled into the altar.
As one of Sweden's earliest saints, she is present today.
Skövde has her on her city weapon.
Here you still honor her in the Catholic congregation.
Christianity affects both faith, everyday life and the whole of Sweden's development.
With the Catholic Church comes the monasteries, and with them new knowledge.
In the monasteries you sit and write, you study.
You develop what we call science today.
The monasteries offer the only training of the time, the center of knowledge.
You start using Latin, and then you can communicate across national borders.
The monasteries and the church in Sweden exchange letters with the Pope Church in Rome.
Now we can follow Sweden's history in text.
The letters say that Sweden gets its first archbishop -
- Out of the Pope in 1164.
With the appointment, Sweden is recognized by the Catholic Church -
- As a private Christian kingdom with its own Swedish kings.
Many historians believe that it is now Sweden becomes a kingdom to be expected.
The church is involved in the national formation of Sweden.
In the Swedish forests, in the bedrock, something - hides - hides -
- As over time, Sweden contributes to a national power:
The iron ore.
The trade in the iron over time makes the royal power richer -
- So the king, step by step, can increase his control over the kingdom.
The blast furnaces extract the iron from the ore.
We are probably the first in Europe to develop the blast furnaces.
They make iron to such an extent that there will be a large -scale industrial -
- Which is important in Sweden today.
When we start using the blast furnace, we can melt rock ore.
We can have a continuous production, without having to stop the oven.
We go from zero production to maybe upwards of 300 tonnes per year -
- On only maybe 150 years.
The development is going very fast.
You have a production where people move up to Bergslagen.
They get work there, they receive pay.
We get a type of monetary system.
Bergslagen is almost the first to develop just wage work.
When working in agriculture you were often paid in food and shelter.
But here you got paid in money.
Here we meet both women and children as labor -
- When it comes to crushing the ore down to thumb size.
One builds an entire network -
- With coaling, blast furnace operation, mining, exports and trade.
The blast furnaces cause the forests in Bergslagen to be populated.
Many move here to get rich in the iron production.
The demand for iron in Europe is high and trade is very profitable.
Over time, the blast furnace owners form a new class of society - the mountain men.
When it comes to the blast furnace mill and working on getting iron -
- So there is no older dated blast furnace in Europe -
- It is outside Norberg, in Lapphyttan.
Based on what we know today we are first in Europe.
In the winter, the watercourses freeze.
The blast furnaces go out when the drive wheels stop.
But in the smiths, the mountain men continue their work.
When it is dark and cold, there is less to be done on the farms.
Then you take the opportunity to celebrate holidays.
The church is a gathering place at baptism, funeral and wedding -
- And both the church and the cemetery also serve as a party room.
It is the duty of the great men to stand for party and spectacle.
They should bid on food and drink, and be generous.
It is also the duty of the church.
Church and great men stand for the public.
They should be generous, especially at major holidays.
Weddings, funerals and holidays were celebrated in the church with ceremonies -
- But also with dance and music and a lot of beer.
It took time for the Swedes to be sedated in the church.
Historical sources say that they drank Christmas.
In medieval calendars, the holidays had been engraved with symbols.
For Christmas, there was a beer stop.
/Joint song/
What the word Christmas has does not know.
It goes a long way back.
But the Urethian word Juhla probably meant that they were partying.
/Music and Song/
Holidays were of great importance, they had a supernatural touch.
Crime was also punished harder.
There were higher fines for murder and other crimes during holidays, like Christmas.
You could be sentenced to peacelessness and forced to leave everything behind.
/Suffocated sound/
/CRY/
If you are guilty of murder or murder during Christmas, and want to survive -
- Make it to get as far away as possible.
Maybe even abroad.
People in the early Middle Ages were more moving than we usually think.
It was easy to follow the old trade routes -
- And you could move to cities, which increased in number during the period.
People moved into the cities a little everywhere.
Lund is already an established city in the late 12th century-
- But it belongs to Denmark, not Sweden.
There were more in the cities as interregional trade increased.
The raw material volumes are increasing, and consumption is increasing.
It becomes a much greater volume to both intensity and quantity.
It pulls people into the cities, a lot from other countries.
People who speak German, Englishmen, Slavic guests as well.
All trade in the cities is also profitable for the Kings of Middle Ages.
The king promises to protect the cities against attackers.
For that, the royal power receives taxes and customs fees from the inhabitants.
Residents are allowed to solve waste management and sewer.
They certainly did their best, because purity was important.
But a saying said that you felt the stench of a city before you saw it.
Injuries and illnesses could be treated by doctors and heroes.
One could treat wounds, cut up and sew the ulcers -
–And you could cure fractures.
In fact, most fractures have healed as well as a fracture today.
Excavations in Lund have found veins, scalpels -
- Surgery pliers and other surgical instruments.
The best care was given at a monastery.
Monks and nuns brought with them medical knowledge from the continent.
There was also an experience -based medical knowledge -
- As often inherited, and was a little anywhere in society.
The medieval knowledge of how the body works has its limitations.
There are some standard methods used for all possible diseases.
One of the most popular is vein.
The logic behind it was that the body must be at healthy fluids.
It was believed that diseases were generated by imbalance between the fluids:
Yellow bile, black bile, mucus and blood.
By reducing it that it was too much of, the disease symptoms decreased.
So vein was a universal remedy to make the sick healthy.
Cities change over time.
New houses are being built where old ones stood.
This church ruin is located under a contemporary pub in central Lund.
That is what is left of a church built in the early Middle Ages.
Next to the church was the cemetery.
The legs buried here-
-Can be told a lot about what it was like to live in Lund in the 12th century.
In the Lund material I have examined just over 4,500 skeletons.
After all, people have lived in the city.
For example, we have some bone fractures -
- This can be linked to the construction when the city expanded.
People have fallen, squeezed.
We see fractures and other types of damage.
One of the skeletons testifies that the art had its shortcomings.
This person, a man, has broken the femur just above the knee.
They have tried to help him.
He could not support on the femur -
- So you have tied up the lower leg behind him, and then he had crutches.
But this binding of the leg has lasted so long -
–So when it was time to remove it -
- Had the kneecap simply stuck in that position.
So he could never support the leg again, but had crutches life.
Lund is a Christian city.
Christianity has strong perceptions of what is sinful and not.
The rules can hit women hard.
Especially if you become pregnant without being married.
Young women are exposed.
Christianity prohibits sex outside of marriage.
Unmarried women who become pregnant are not just a moral problem.
An extra -marital child draws disgrace throughout the family.
During an excavation of a house in Lund, an unexpected finding is made.
Inside the house, something has buried an infant in secret.
We had been digging for a while.
When small, small legs showed up, I recognized it - a small child.
It was right next to the hearth in the house.
The child must have been born in secret, inside the house.
It deviates from norms and ethics during this time.
Respect for the children was great.
It is seen among stillborn children that they were taken care of according to the laws.
In all likelihood, the child is both born and buried in secret.
We do not know the background, but probably the family wanted to avoid disgrace.
It is a sign of how hard one looked at extra -marital children -
- And how vulnerable unmarried women were when they became pregnant.
When we enter the 13th century, Finland has become part of Sweden.
Sweden does not conquer Finland.
It is Finland who chooses to become part of the Swedish Empire.
The Finns are not many, maybe 50,000 people.
They feel threatened by the Russians who are growing strong in the east.
By paying taxes to Sweden, they buy security and protection.
You can see it as a win-win situation.
Sweden gets new taxpayers, you get a buffer zone in the east.
Finns get the security they realize they need.
Finland is a good deal for Sweden.
During the good times of the 13th century-
- The Swedish royal power is growing increasingly richer and stronger.
The good harvests of the farmers, the trade in iron, and the new cities -
- For increased revenue for the royal power through customs and taxes.
The king lives well on what the Swedish people perform.
But now the king is starting to be able to give back something.
The time when the Swedish kings do not play any role is soon over.
The one who will change it is called Birger Jarl.
Birger Jarl is a cunning and skilled power player.
He can be cruel and violent, but is good at building alliances.
Birger never becomes king himself, but he is the king's closest man -
- And he decides through the king.
What Birger wants, is to make the Swedish kingdom strong and stable.
Birger Jarl, an important name in Swedish history.
By the middle of the 13th century, he lets build a fortress here at Helgeandsholmen.
The purpose is to prevent the pirates on the Baltic Sea from entering Lake Mälaren.
Here Stockholm is now formed, which far later becomes the capital in Sweden.
But Birger Jarl has just begun.
He has grand plans for Sweden.
Birger Jarl has great power, and he works to strengthen the royal power.
He executes opponents who can claim the Swedish throne.
If you avoid constant power struggle for the throne, then it will be stability.
He understands that he has to bring the people with him to get through this.
And what the people need is security.
Security can be created with law and order.
The previous laws were different depending on where they lived in the kingdom.
Birger Jarl creates uniform laws called peace laws.
They aimed to create just peace.
Birger Jarl's laws were followed by district negotiations around the kingdom.
The laws were read by local lawmen who represented the king.
There is a lot of evidence that people knew laws and regulations.
As the cities are emerging, the penalty becomes harsher.
It is easier to judge someone you do not know of harsh punishment.
The punishment could be a shame - it would appear that you were a criminal.
A thief could have the ear cut off.
An unfaithful woman could have her hair cut off, or her nose cut off.
One of the most nasty punishment must be to be stepped.
First counseled - man mashes man, cracking the bones in the body -
- And then you take the body and braid it into a wheel on the gallows.
The one who becomes counseled and intimidated in the Stegling Wheel -
- Can often survive for a few days with terrible pain.
It is probably one of the worst punishments.
The punishment can be very cruel.
But the medieval judicial order has gained unnecessarily bad reputation.
Most crimes were punished with fines.
The most severe penalties were mainly deterrent and were rarely used.
You were pretty pragmatic.
It was about resolving conflicts -
- And to make society work.
Birger Jarl's Peace Laws are liked by the people.
They create order in the country.
Birger Jarl's influence and power are growing in line with his success.
When the old king dies, he places his son on the Swedish throne.
But it is still Birger who governs, without being king.
In this way he gets stability in the state and royal power.
It is during Birger Jarl's time that Sweden becomes a national power with a king -
- rich and powerful enough to control the entire kingdom through laws and bailiffs.
The only thing missing is an organized military defense.
Birger Jarl's son, Magnus Ladulås, will realize that.
King Magnus Ladulås makes a deal with Swedish great men and big farmers.
He gives them tax exemption, against the fact that they put up with men and weapons at war.
In this way, the royal power gets weapons and knights to defend the kingdom.
The agreement is called Alsnö Stat.
With that, the foundation is laid for the Swedish nobility.
Darkness and cold pull over the country.
It is the beginning of the 1300s, and the good times end.
The climate is getting colder.
The period called the Little Ice Age begins.
The domestic animals are lacking in bait, and the harvests become bad.
People starve and have a hard time - and it is believed that God is dissatisfied.
Someone who claims to know the cause of the bad times is Holy Birgitta.
She will be one of the Catholic Church's most important saints.
But so far she is just a mourning widow.
Birgitta was the daughter of a rich man.
Her mother was related to the king.
As a kid, she was special.
She saw things that others did not see.
Some meant that she was crazy, others that she was in contact with God.
When her husband dies, she begins to get revelations.
She first thinks that it is the devil who haunts her.
In the end, she understands that it is Jesus.
He convinces her.
They should work together, and she will be his bride.
Then she has the task of saving humanity -
- And work against pride and evil, throughout the world.
Birgitta had direct contact with God, Christ and the Virgin Mary -
- As their language tubes, to bring their words to humanity.
And she would found a monastery in their name.
Birgitta's revelations were taken very seriously.
Guidance was needed.
And she was consulting on leadership in these difficult times.
Birgitta's revelations are convincing.
They describe a reality that people recognize themselves in.
In the revelations, God explains that the famine and the suffering of the people depend on -
- That the powerful are boastful and just care about their wealth.
If the suffering is to end, they must think more about God and less about themselves.
In the revelations, it is often an aggressive and vulgar language.
She criticizes both Pope, church and royalty.
A bishop was like a snail bathing in poop.
A pope is compared to Judas.
Queen Johanna of Naples an Aphhona that smells on her stinking buttocks.
Birgitta has a credibility that makes her get away with her criticism.
Her background made her high reputation.
This was true both in Sweden and internationally.
During the 1340s, Birgitta is close to the royal power.
She is related to the king, and moves freely in the corridors of power.
The one now sits on the Swedish throne is Magnus Eriksson.
A strong and powerful king of both Sweden and Norway.
He reverses the greatest empire in Europe at this time.
It extends from Finland in the east to Greenland in the west.
But it is a great power that is based on a loose foundation.
Magnus has borrowed a lot of money to buy Skåne from the Danes.
A deal he will regret.
For now, King Magnus is starting to have problems.
King Magnus has loaned considerably.
Now he has trouble paying the debts to the church and the Pope.
But there is someone who thinks they have the solution to the problems - Birgitta.
She has a plan.
Birgitta persuades the king to go out on a crusade east, towards Novgorod.
As the crusades occur in the name of God, for the Catholic Church -
- Can King Magnus wait to pay the debts to the Pope.
If the crusades succeed, both Magnus and the Pope can benefit from it.
The crusades are religious companies.
Catholicism should be spread.
It is important for the papacy.
It is also a political company.
Different kingdoms want to expand, and then the crusades are used for it.
Magnus Eriksson is driven by the fact that he wants crusades against Novgorod -
–And expand the Swedish national power in that direction.
Initially, at least military, you are successful.
But it will not end well.
If times have already become bad, they will be even worse.
No crusades or prayers can save Sweden from the darkness that is on their way.
In 1349, a boat from England adds to the harbor of Berg.
On board the crews are sick or already dead.
The plague has come.
One year later, it comes across the border to Sweden.
It is the race bites that infect.
The fleas are spread with the help of the rats.
Often a plague epidemic began with flea bite -
- As resulted in bulbs in armpits or groin.
It leads to death in about half of the cases.
But worse was whether the bloodstream brought the bacteria to the lungs.
In pneumonia, the bacteria were coughed to all around -
- So that it became the spread of infection through the air.
Then there is a hundred percent mortality, and many more who fall ill.
The plague, the deaths, spreads across Europe during the mid-1300s.
The people were, of course, completely terrified.
For them, it must have been God's punishment and the downfall of the world.
One third of all in Sweden die when the plague epidemics pull over the country.
In 1350, the death of death emerges like a Lieman and harvests victims in Sweden.
Thus, the Swedish tax base becomes more than halved -
- And Magnus Eriksson has no opportunity to continue war.
This will be the beginning of Magnus Eriksson's many accidents.
The crusade against Novgorod and Nöteborg becomes a failure.
He has lost Nöteborg.
He owes the Pope and the Church so much money that he is banned.
While it is bad for King Magnus, Birgitta is far away.
She is in Rome to seek the Pope's support for her monastery.
The rumor of Birgitta and her revelations is spread in Europe.
It is difficult today to understand what influence her revelations had -
- In the Christian world during this time.
Birgitta never revisites Sweden.
She dies in Rome 1373.
But her revelations are spread, they are gathered and published in book form.
Birgitta's ideas about reforming the relaxed Christianity -
- And giving women influence, affects the entire Christian world.
Birgitta Klosterorden opens in Vadstena 1384.
Birgitta herself is declared saint in 1391, just 18 years after his death.
I don't think any Swedish -
- Have had the same meaning in the world as Birgitta.
But how is it for Sweden and King Magnus Eriksson?
Not so good.
Magnus has a hard time repaying his huge debts.
He tries to solve it in other ways - by making new money.
The new coins are cheaper and are faster to manufacture.
But at the same time they contain less silver than the previous coins.
Then King Magnus forces people to switch old valuable to the new ones.
But the new coins have such low quality that the church refuses to receive them.
King Magnus money is useless.
The kingdom is now in deep economic and political crisis.
In addition, the plague continues to ravage in the country.
The stability they managed to create in Sweden is now far away.
It will take several hundred years before that change will be changed.
Many will try to take control of the country.
But only one will succeed.
Texting: Karina Berg Johansson Swedish Media text for SVT