My name is \ halaa elshebeny-
-And I read the preschool teacher education \ H \ HERE at Halmstad University.
Right now I am in the Q-house, where we spend most of the time.
I chose this program because I enjoy working with younger children.
I worked before as a system tester.
But felt that I will-
-Bab with people and especially with children of preschool age.
The best thing about the program is that it is very broad and interesting-
-and that we have very experienced and dedicated teachers-
-As is happy to share their experiences.
We read, among other things, about children's care, learning-
-And development that together form a whole.
We get several occasions to be out on internship-
-And practice at preschools.
And it's called VFU.
This is a great way to anchor the theory in practice-
-Then we get to plan and implement several teaching opportunities with the children.
In the future so-
-I want to work at a preschool where I together with my future colleagues-
-To the basis for children's lifelong learning.
I also want to invest in creating a good environment-
-And meet the needs of the children.