My name is Anna Isaksson and I am an associate professor of sociology at the Academy of Health and Welfare.
- A main track in my research is about something called norm -critical design.
And how to use norm -critical design -
–Can make visible invisible norms, habitual performances -
- And things that we take for granted in our everyday lives.
Norms that consciously or unconsciously can result in discrimination -
- And exclusion of different groups.
Together with a research group, we have together developed a method and approach.
-And it is first that we do a survey you can say -
- Above what it looks like within an organization.
For example, what norms prevent the development of equality and diversity in a workplace.
–And when we then compile and analyze what we have obtained through the mapping -
- So we not only present these research results -
- In the form of a scientific publication or report.
- The extent we translate these results into so -called norm -critical design concepts.
It is simply physical things that illustrate and visualize -
- The norms that we have seen as obstructs in the first step.
And this can be a bit provocative and that is the idea.
Because we want to visualize problems and obstacles -
- And so that the organization can jointly discuss "okay, this is what it looks like".
So the next step is about being norm creative and being more solution -oriented.
This also creates room for change and innovation.
- For example within the fire defense that we have worked a lot with -
- There we have focused on norms in, for example, physical environment -
- which contributes to exclusion and discrimination.
Then we produced a norm -critical design concept that we called the "recovery room".
How would the physical environment, for example, dressing rooms -
- Known is arranged in a different way to promote inclusion and participation.
Based on this norm -critical design concept, we worked together -
–With the current fire defense and also an architectural firm ahead -
- This norm -creative solution that we call "social building norm" -
–A which focuses on the social aspects and why it and why it is important to elucidate -
- In connection with rebuilding and new construction.
- There are a lot of studies that have pointed out that organizations like to - want -
“But it is difficult to work with their gender equality and diversity work.
And you have long -liked -
- Scientifically proven and concrete methods for this work.
And there has been something that I together with the research group I worked a lot with -
- Has sought to contribute.
To really develop methods that are perceived as meaningful -
- And which is actually a tool in the concrete change work.
- Many have lifted that you see a great value in working with -
- To visualize research results also in physical things.
And that is because theories -
–S, for example, concerns gender, equality, equality and diversity -
- In many ways, it is perceived as abstract and difficult to put into practical action.
Why I think it's important to conduct research -
- It is to actually contribute to change in the surrounding community
- In addition to the research I conduct, I also work part of my service -
- At Leap for Life, which is an innovation center.
Leap for Life has a great focus on information -driven care.
–And I have had the opportunity for several years to participate in Project -
–In elderly care, for example -
- Where I have been able to study and follow up on the introduction of digital technical solutions.
Another important part of my work day is teaching.
–When I find very exciting and developing -
–And where you as a researcher are also given the opportunity to take part in -
- Students' wise recording
There I also think that questions related to -
- Genus, equality and diversity are incredibly important for students to take part in.
Many of our students step into a working life -
- As in several ways, unequal.
And then I think it is important that we as a higher education institution prepare them -
- To be able to meet this.