In tonight's section of Ifs - immigrants for Swedes:
Police who do not want to teach their children Arabic: Nadim Ghazale.
Skåne's moral conscience: Petrina Solange.
The Roma Jewish horse dealer: Chang Frick.
Pandemin's hardest working influencer: Antonija Mandir.
Sweden's second best celebrity dancer: Filip Dikmen.
Don't forget Sweden's most fun Chinese: Evelyn Mok.
Rinkeby's own Harry Potter: Daniel Sanchez.
The world's Swedish Arab: Elaf Ali.
Greek from Alby: Thanos Fotas.
The Kurd who speaks better German than Swedish: Incredible Big O.
Last but not least: Our unanimous program manager Ahmed Berhan!
Welcome to IFS.
The program with more diversity than the Migration Board's repository.
My name is Ahmed Berhan.
You see the quiz about all culture in Sweden.
Keep up that applause for our competitors: Niklas, Sofia and Fredrik!
The contestant chooses one in the panel that I ask another question.
The contestants decide whether the panelists are lying or not.
In the end, it is the two with the most points that advance to the final!
Backstage we drew about who can start.
That's a small advantage.
The one who won was no less than Sofia!
- Sofia, you are a researcher.
-Yes.
Can it help you decide if the panelists' hypotheses are correct?
No, not the least.
- Are you good at reading people?
-Quite.
Then we'll see.
Which panelist do you start with?
–Evelyn.
-Ah!
The relationship between me and my dildo.
- It's fun, because it's true.
-It's true.
No, but a pleasure marriage ...
Japan has strange sexual inclinations.
But it is illegal to have sex with animal -
- Unless you marry the animal first.
It's called Genki Kekkon.
It is a pleasure marriage.
- It was your answer?
- She sounded skeptical.
- What do you feel, Sofia?
- Lite sick.
- Have you been to Japan?
-No not yet.
I say it's false.
You are doing absolutely right.
Congratulations!
You've received your first point!
Thanks.
It is a disputed rule within shia-islam-
- There is an imam wig and woman to make temporary sex halal.
It would have been fun if you got to marry an animal.
Imagine poison at first sight.
"I don't know, maybe a woman or a turtle. Exciting."
- Is it going on TV4 or Animal Planet?
-Both.
Congratulations to the first point, Sofia.
- Fredrik, entered the match.
- I want to ... - Filip, help me.
-Yo, sir!
- Filip.
The sequel to Jumanji.
Sorani and Kurmanji are Kurdish version of Adam and Eva.
First man and woman on earth.
Sorani is the woman, Kurmanji the man.
- Developed version of it.
-Absolutely.
You believe in Filip?
- Fredrik thinks what Filip says is true.
You are wrong.
The two largest Kurdish dialects are Sorani and Kurmanji.
Good.
Thanks!
- Niklas, how does it feel?
-Good!
I decided a long time ago.
- What have you decided on?
- Big o, put your hands up.
My brother.
I'll help.
Big o ...
When a Muslim Bakk on a deed, he greets from the heart.
"You're mine. I'll yan you tonight."
No, brother!
No, Muslims greet from the heart to avoid physical contact.
–The'rå.
- Well!
- Do you understand or should I repeat?
- I say it's false.
You think it's false.
Why don't you trust Big O?
- He is unreliable.
- Then he chose you first.
But it feels ... that's not true.
Big o is unreliable.
O Too unreliable.
- Niklas, you are wrong.
Muslims greet their hearts to avoid physical contact.
I thought they put my hand on the heart because they are always offended.
"Oh, oh!"
They walk around so every day.
Oh!
Unfortunately no points.
Sofia, you have the lead.
Can you get one more point?
Yeah.
Here we go.
Eh ... Petrina.
Suheib Saleh played drug addicts most of all.
He played the gangster type -
- And advertised a digital healthcare service.
A journalist thought:
"You can't be an actor and advertise care services."
He was not allowed to be a gangster and advertise care.
So they got sour.
Do you say that Muslims are offended?
It sounds like a reasonable thing that may have happened.
The question is whether it is too easy to be true.
- His research brain started now.
- I say it's true.
Just right.
You've got one more point.
The easily offended journalist from Summary could not have two balls -
- When he saw the actor who played drug addicts in advertising for drugs.
He wrote an article about it.
Fredrik, do you want to get into the match?
-Obvious.
- Who in the panel are you choosing?
-Thanos.
-Yes.
The words cannot be translated directly.
Then you explain with a sentence.
Inshallah means "most likely no".
You meet an old friend.
"We'll have a coffee one day?"
- "Inshallah."
Or type season 2 of immigrants for Swedes.
"Will it get rid of?"
Eh ... "Inshallah."
You can apply it in a lot of different contexts.
Yes...
The examples you radi up can definitely fit into it.
But the explanation for the expression itself is wrong.
You will believe that if you want.
Inshallah that you get a point.
Obviously it's false!
What good, what good!
Inshallah means "if God wants".
God wanted you to get a point.
- Niklas?
- I have to move up.
- What are you taking?
–Alaf.
They panicked to be there.
No, but the truth is that they were there because they did PR ...
... to calm the immigrants.
The laser man ravaged Sweden and shot a lot of foreigners.
That's right.
Totally convinced.
- Are you there?
-No.
Congratulations, Niklas.
You've received your first point.
No matter how sick it sounds, in 1992 it became noisy in Rinkeby's People's House.
Then Birgit thought you would sing a little.
- Congratulations to the point.
- They got angry when people didn't sing.
- They couldn't know the text.
- They could not Swedish.
- The song is in English.
- They couldn't either.
All competitors have points, but Sofia has two.
- Should we skip to three?
-Yes.
It has been so good with The Ladies, so I continue there.
- Sorry, Boys.
So Antonija.
He assumed that he was going to play in a new, Turkish club.
It made his dear Syrian home fans flipped out.
- No, that's not true.
-Okay.
-Not?
Because you know that ...?
-It was well during the World Cup.
I don't really remember what happened, but it wasn't.
- Are you absolutely sure?
-Quite.
- Trot that Antonija did that mine?
- You were convincing in every way.
But it was false.
Just right, Sofia.
You've received your third point.
That's what you were in: The World Cup.
He did so Germany got a free kick in the final minutes and scored goals.
We lost by 2-1.
Some blamed his Syrian background.
With all rights!
Congratulations to the point, Sofia.
- Fredrik, it's your turn now.
I think ... Sanchez.
-Are you ready?
-Absolutely.
Obvious.
Time for a picture question.
The first girl who does not believe in zodiac signs.
She is a Swedish artist and dancer -
- And first woman over 30 who dated Leonardo DiCaprio.
Yes...
It can sue everything.
But I was hesitant that Leonardo has dated someone over 30.
No.
I say it's false.
-Are you sure?
- No, but it's false.
Of course, you do that right in.
False.
Elli Avram is the first Swede to play in a Bollywood movie.
- Niklas, do you know what is happening now?
- I must be right.
Unfortunately, if you do not collect points now, you will not move on to the final.
So try not to do away with you.
- Chang avoids eye contact.
- Very good choice.
They accused him of being Kurd but he is Turk.
They had written that he had spent three years for drug offenses.
But another Babbe was called the same.
They took the wrong black skull, you know.
Then they got to poodle.
Happens easily.
Been there, done that.
I didn't know it at all.
I have to go on your credibility.
- Are you lit on a one like me?
-Yes.
Who the hell trust Chang?!
We live in a ding ding world.
You did absolutely right to trust Chang.
Sofia, it's your turn now.
You have the chance to get a full pot.
-Cruelly.
Do you think you nail it?
-Yes, I think so.
- Night, now we drive.
-Just right.
I deliver.
Green is the favorite color, blonde women are my favorite breed.
He's not even lying.
In fact, I know this.
Half came to Borås, Hässleholmen, and the other half I have arrested.
I know they come from 160, 150 countries.
–160, 150 countries?
–150, 160 approx.
It is tricky, but absolutely reasonable.
- Senipers come here, from there ... - than half were my cousins.
No, but I believe in Nadim.
Sofia, congratulations.
You've got a full pot.
The competition was no play for you.
The best thing that happened now, except Sofia went to the final -
- Is we find out who comes with you there.
It's time for the rash issue.
I ask the question, you write down your answer to your little trays -
- And then you hold up the answer.
Closest to wins.
/LAUGH/
- Do you feel ready?
-Yes.
The question was: How many IKEA department stores are there in Africa?
Closest to wins.
Niklas and Fredrik, show your answers.
-Oh oh oh!
- What a big difference!
–1.
- Why in hell you take 1?
- It may be 1. - did you know why?
He wanted to win.
Congratulations, Niklas!
You are closest.
The correct answer is five department stores.
They are located in Morocco and in Egypt.
A sixth is underway in Morocco.
- Niklas, you made it to the final.
Sofia, you have made it to the final.
- Thanks, Fredrik, for joining you.
Now we drive the first to five.
Gather them as quickly as possible.
But there is a small twist.
If you answer wrong, the opponent will receive a point.
Sofia, you had a full pot and won.
Then you start the final round.
Ah!
Again!
I'll take Evelyn again.
It went so well last time.
A good basketball player in Afghanistan.
I know his name.
Usama bin Lay-up.
No, it's actually something that Ahmed knows very well.
- It's a type of hash.
-Tell me more.
Oh my God.
Popo!
It's a type of hash.
It is very soft, a little dark.
Afghan in the name comes from being grown in the Afghan mountains.
It has a dominant indica-stain-
- which gives a very nice, relaxing and uplifting high.
- Therefore, people like it.
- Is that why I get munchies?
-I think so.
- It was difficult.
Some things are grown in the mountains in Afghanistan.
-How do you know that?
-Researcher.
-"Researcher".
- It is difficult, that is.
But ... we say so.
I trust you.
True!
You trust Evelyn?
Black Afghan is a hash that is grown in the mountains?
We are in Afghanistan.
Kush Mountains.
Third mountain from the right.
Sofia ...
Congratulations!
You got your first point in the final round.
Black Afghan is a specific hash variety from Afghanistan.
Allegedly.
- Taking Notes.
- Niklas, your turn.
- Review.
Big o, come on now.
- Otherwise you have to do this.
You trust me, otherwise you will not get a kebab roll.
It's Kim Kardashian's body measure.
What happened halfway to the body when you ...?
I was with you here, but this one?
Are you sure you don't think about Caitlyn Jenner?
What the fuck oh are you ate?
It was a good, fucking joke!
Okay, no, that 6-24 something ...
It is one of the Old Testament -
–Mest controversy ... controversial verses.
Good, sfi!
Big O, have you smoked black Afghan before?
It is the Old Testament's most controversial verse with the phrase:
"Thank you, God, for not creating me as a woman for the guys."
Huh!
It would have been worse.
- What do you say, Niklas?
- It's either ...
Or it is when Big o is born.
–Wa?
–24 June 1990.
- No, that's not true.
- brother, in the homeland I am forty.
I trust you, Big O.
You should definitely not have done that.
It's false.
6-24-90 describes the requirements for the Home Guard's crisis preparedness.
It should be running in 6 hours, fully active within 24–
- And last for 90 days.
There were no points.
You know what that means.
- Sofia, you got a free score.
- TACKS.
Sofia is fatal.
Ice cold.
Check her eyes.
She looks like a shark.
No but...
Karen view.
You are about to call the boss anytime.
It's no Karen.
She has lived with blats.
She has lived.
–And noted.
She has put us in ... --... experimental cages.
-Just.
- "They eat like ordinary people."
"They experience love. They experience grief and pain in injury."
/APPLAUSE/
–Alaf.
–Yes.
At Indian restaurant you can order lamb, chicken, but not beef.
Skåne: Jeo, but Keon ...
- Keeeeoon!
- Serve it again, Elaf.
Nothing wrong to talk Seu after all.
Is it ugly with Kristianstad dialect?
We are a chamber team.
The cow is sacred-
- For you mean that the gods and goddesses live in it.
So everything with the cow is sacred.
Even its kiss and poop are used in religious ceremonies.
-Yes it's true.
- Pan.
-I believe in you.
- Have you eaten a Kiss and poop?
No.
But consultation is sacred, one must not touch it, in Hinduism.
- I think it's true.
- It felt like you taught us.
-Yes, teaacher!
- It was not included in the fact.
But congratulations, you got one more point.
- Niklas ... —Mm.
Now it's starting to be ... Antonija, I think.
- Niklas!
-Absolutely.
I am Croat and have grown up with my parents told me:
Unless you listen to us and do as we say -
- Will Babaroga, a great aunt, and kidnap you.
I'm scared even today.
- When did they last say that?
-Yesterday.
When Antonija told me she would be here.
Never heard of, but that's not true.
Antonija spoke truth.
- Niklas!
- It's as sick as possible.
- Still anyway, it feels very Balkans.
-Yes.
They talk so much crap.
- What do Swedes threaten the children with?
- They have to wait for the room without food.
Niklas, you answered wrong.
You know what that means.
Sofia got one more point.
Because Niklas answered wrong, you got a free score.
If you answer correctly now you have not only swept first round -
- Without the entire program and won the entire competition.
Then it becomes Petrina.
One takes a hood over the main - main
- And film that execution.
Then you write it on VHSs that you sell.
Then comes the American intervention force and kills the butcher -
- And dumps his body in the sea.
A large cost to taxpayers.
But then you wanted it, so you got it.
No.
A Muslim person reads a prayer, turns the animal towards Mecca.
Bam!
Then you slaughter it just like all other animals.
- Sofia?
- It can definitely be true.
I might mix up how to slaughter animals.
In some religions one must not have anesthetic.
Such things.
But in Sweden you have other ways of ... hm.
That's the question.
This was a Swedish way?
I have no idea.
I guess it's right.
You speak the truth.
-You know what?
-Wrong?
You were right.
Sofia is our winner!
A big applause!
Come on here, Sofia.
Come come!
Sofia is our winner who swept the first round.
A diploma to hang up and a flower.
Thank you so much to our competitors, to the audience -
- To you at home and not least our panel.
See you when we see you.
Texting: Cristel Nyqvist Swedish Media Text for SVT