In the season premiere of IFS, the question of all culture in Sweden ...
Syrian on the run from Özz Nûjen: Filip Dikmen!
The pastry Moroccan Guardians: Camilla Hamid!
IFS brother from Jordbro: Big O. Humor philosopher Thanos photographed.
The Swedish's Swedish Arab: Elaf Ali.
The man who gave the Goth a face: Caline!
Comedy Ping Pong between Gbg and London: Evelyn Mok!
The Somali pirate from Götlaborg: Assia Dahir.
Only a puzzle piece is missing: the man, myth - host Ahmed Berhan!
Welcome to the premiere of Season 3 of Ifs!
The only program that makes the whole SVT shake its castle.
I'm Ahmed Berhan -
- And you look at the quiz about all culture in Sweden.
Our fantastic competitors: closest to me, at Rosa Pult: Inge!
Next to him: Emelie!
Last but not least, from Södertälje but not Syrian - Robin!
Welcome to this fantastic program.
Inge, choose a panelist.
- Who do you put your cards on?
- Big O.
Is there any face in Sweden you get happier to see?
The audience just: "Walla."
Someone who checked too much at Emil in Lönneberga.
No, "boy" is a derogatory word for anyone who has a suedi job-
- Type in stores or in stock.
You should preferably plug or invest in the music or become a broker.
It's true.
A derogatory word for someone with a helf job.
Knever.
You thought that black skulls couldn't know the word "knee".
You think it's true.
Sorry, no point for you.
You took a chance as a real boy.
Dräng is derogatory, but more for someone who is idiot or useless.
A Polar said: A boy is someone who is a fucking joint picker.
But thank you for starting us.
- Emelie.
Who do you choose?
Filip.
Suryoyozone is for Syrians - I'm Syrian ...
It is a social media platform for dating-
- So it's haram, but it's halal.
-Oops.
- It's dating.
But they share cooking recipes.
So it's Tinder, but also Mom's Facebook.
- Have you been hanging with Syrians something?
-No...
-What was called ... - it's called Suryoyozone.
--Suryoyo-son ...-She made it Finnish!
- Not "Son", without "Zone"!
- Zone.
We have it on everything.
Andersson, Bengtsson ...
Just give her points!
She thought you have a whole platform for a family!
It was very much in one.
Either you are extremely creative ...
But it felt cake on the cake.
I think it's false.
You think there are no social media for Syrians solely.
Called Syriansson.
No.
The whole of Södertälje right now:
Naknemo!
You think it's false.
Unfortunately - that's true.
Suryoyozone is a platform for Syrians to network -
- Communicating, and as Filip said, try to date, find singles ...
And by singles he means cousins.
Thanks so much Emelie.
- Robin?
-Thanos.
-Thanos, time for a video question.
Seni Gidi Findikkiran Yilani Partiginden çikaran
This song from Tarkan was for a while the city's national anthem.
Thanos, what does Tarkan sing about?
He sings about his girlfriend who has been unfaithful to another guy.
And that he should look up the guy and give him a ... /pussy sound /
Robin?
Do you think Tarkan would floor people?
- I could that ever before ... - Turkish?
No, the song.
But I don't remember.
I think that's true.
You choose to believe in Thanos response -
- That Tarkan's song is about lowering the guy who has taken his girl.
/ Piss sound/ no point to you!
This song has nothing to do with force - just a broken heart.
Tarkan is unfortunate in love with a girl who consciously makes him jealous.
As soon as he sees her he wants to kiss her.
Unfortunately, there was no point for anyone.
This season is the extra special -
- For those who win tonight move on to our semi -finals.
Then you go to the final, where you can win the fantastic IFS buck.
–Inge, your turn to choose.
- Camilla.
Camilla.
We have the laser cushion, the forest cushion, even
Zucchiniturken.
Absolutely!
The dog turkey is the laser cure dog, which was sitting in the car in the clip.
Most people only know the laser turf, but he has a dog -
- which has been named "Dog Turken".
- Stacks Inge!
- You run animal ambulance.
Yes.
But I didn't have to run any dog turquoise there, not.
There is actually!
–Inge, what do you think?
- Now it's false.
- What was the laser cushion?
- He was on and running.
You are right in a way!
Many Turks lasers.
But you think Camilla is lying -
- And with that I say congratulations to your first point!
The dog Turken was an idea in the 18th century about a human-eating monster.
Even in the 18th century, Swedes called all black shells "Turks".
The dog turkey had dog heads and cooked people.
When I first heard it, I thought of Filip Dikmen with a bad hair day.
Thanks for that, Inge.
Congratulations on the score!
- Emelie?
Elaf.
In the autumn of 2023, the imam aroused from Malmö, Salahuddin Barakat -
- Benefit attention on Facebook.
What did he write?
That Muslims hate gays.
It's true!
He wrote type to think that the practice of homosexuality is wrong -
- Or sinful ... so in that case all Muslims are homophobes.
Do you have many imams on your Facebook?
Not many.
But I want to trust you!
Do you trust me, or do you think Muslims hate gays?
-I trust you.
- You believe that it is true.
It gives her a point!
It's true!
Imam Salahuddin Barakat wrote that all Muslims are probably homophobes -
-As all Muslims apparently think that LGBTQ documents are a shame.
But this is public service.
Not all Muslims are homophobes at all.
Only Salahuddin and Elaf.
But you know, I actually checked the Qur'an.
Or, I googled.
In fact, it is not verbatim that homosexuality is wrong.
But it says that men must not enter a woman's anus.
So...
-!
How did we end up there?
- So anal sex ...
So anal sex is actually prohibited.
Imam should start "Muslims against anal sex", type.
Over to someone who likes anal sex - Robin.
- That's where you cut away.
-It's done.
Who do you choose?
–Eh ... Evelyn.
- It's done, after that comment.
Do I look like those who usually give you massage?
They don't cut it away, Robin!
Evelyn.
There is a tradition in China, Vietnam and Southeast Asia.
Then you have the type of pot when you train your children.
The family gathers when it is time to train and so you have a party.
When the baby walks on the pot, the family stands around and cheers -
–And you give presents.
Type like a baptism, though for poop.
- Oh, how nice.
- Supported.
So that's certainly true.
- But ... - "I have read this on Flashback."
I think that's true.
- That you have a party for pot training.
- Secure.
Robin, that's not true.
Unfortunately, there will be no points.
They have a different way of potting, but not through a bridal shower.
Without as soon as the kid should pee or poop they whistle.
- They condition them.
- As Pavlov's dogs!
- One in the room has read a book once!
- If I whistle, she shits down.
Stop!
If you treat your children as dogs, do you eat them too?
- Filip!
- i'm sorry.
Robin, thank you for guessing.
- Inge.
You are tagged in choosing -
- But you don't get it, because you have received a letter from Botkyrka.
Yes, here I stand and enjoy a sweet baklava -
- A popular dessert in the Middle East and in the Balkans.
But when the Greeks make Baklava, they use 33 layers of filo dough.
You didn't know that!
One warehouse for each year in Jesus' life.
Thank you, Dogge Doggelito.
--E,, do you think that's true?
- It was tricky.
Baklava is just sugar and crap.
-Excuse?!
- In Agree.
Bla bla.
It's not a mariex.
- Care I know an old crust.
- Then you can't whistle either.
–What do you think, true or false?
- Dogge is a filur.
What do you mean?
-What's your name?
-Thanos.
Come on, Inge!
- I think he is lying.
- Good that the angle was down.
By then there had been no season 4.
I think 30 layers ... No, it's false.
You don't think the Greeks made 33 layers for 33 years of Jesus' life.
Unfortunately, Jesus is not with you today.
You don't get any points.
It's true.
The origin is probably from the Ottoman Empire.
It may have been a Greek protest to do if the dessert-
- With a Christian dispute.
- Emelie.
- Califf, are you ready for me?
- Hey, baby.
Hey!
Caline!
- Nino Brown.
-What is this?
Ahmed before he got a beard.
It is used as a substitute when trying to quit smoking.
Instead of sucking on a cigar, you suck on that twig.
- Is it the one you hold?
-Yes.
- I look at him deep in the eyes.
- It is common during fasting.
- For you must not smoke then.
-It's true.
But...
- No, I think it's false.
–You think about califf ...
Now you give me that look again.
I'm getting stressed!
- It's false!
- You think Kaliffa is lying.
Congratulations!
One more point.
Twigs from the Salvadora Persica tree are used to clean the teeth.
It is common in the Middle East and Africa and is linked to Islam-
- Then the Prophet used "Miswak" regularly.
A natural toothbrush.
- Can you show how to do it?
-Like this.
Emelie wishes she was that stick.
As soon as he did this, her leg ...
I saw when Evelyn stuffed it in the butt before.
Congratulations Emelie.
One more point.
- Robin!
You are from Södertälje.
You can swear in Arabic?
"Nakno emo".
Time out!
Syrians are not Arabs!
It was Syrian!
You have taken everything from us.
Don't take our language too!
Robin learned something new.
"Are Syrians not Arabs?"
He comes back to Södertälje: "Ey guys, Syrians are Turks."
- They have deceived me the whole upbringing.
-Cruelly.
But now you have to take a point.
To get a chance to move on.
You put your card on Assia.
–Yes.
Save me.
--Assia.
This is the first time Filip is told that Somalia has a government.
I thought you were just hanging out on banana fields.
Camilla, directly: "I have sponsors and stuff."
- Should you come "at my peeps"?
- Get a country.
Yi-ha!
Sorry.
The question?
What has the Somali government sanctioned in Sweden?
- Consolidation.
-Oh my God!
Sorry!
I'll take it back.
No!
What the Somali government has approved is the first national team ...
... in bandy.
Laugh?
/LAUGH/
They are based in Borlänge and are the world's first African national team -
- In bandy.
- Are there Somalis in Borlänge?
- They are in Lithuania.
They are everywhere!
Except in the labor market.
Boom!
Oh, shit.
Just because it came from Elaf ...
Three seasons, sixteen episodes ... - Robin, what do you think?
I think that's true.
Congratulations to your first point!
The first African bandy team was formed in Borlänge -
- and was sanctioned by the Olympic Committee.
- Emelie, you have already moved on.
-Is it true?!
But we have to decide which of the guys comes along.
Time for a rash question: closest wins.
In the classic song "The Vocal's Favorites" with Labyrinth -
- They show love for suburbs and streets.
How many resorts and streets are mentioned?
Robin turns to someone in the audience: "Brother, I ask you, solve this."
- Have you written down your answer?
-Yes.
Show them at the same time.
Three, two, one!
5 and 14. OH!
The question was therefore how many places and streets are mentioned in the song.
Response:
22!
So congratulations, Inge!
- Robin, thank you for joining.
Unfortunately, you do not move on but Inge and Emelie run the duel.
It's time for the round we call the duel.
Freedom of choice is over.
From now on, I choose the panelists to answer.
Two panelists should answer at the same time.
One tells the truth-
- And the other a lie.
Inge, we start with you.
Your panelists will be Assia and Caline.
In 2013, Labyrinth got headlines over an event at the Grammis Gala.
They mow, they mow two, they mow three fire!
That's what happened.
I thought it was the Lion King.
Some Disney song.
/Mimics/
For real...
Labyrinth was a little Kanye West: iga-
- And stormed the stage when Danny Sudoku won.
Saucedo!
Because he won the best album and not them.
"Yo Danny, I'm a Let You Finish But We had the best album."
"We had a real one asked there."
"They mow one, they mow two!"
The guys were a little stressed, so they smoked a joint -
- At the after party at Café Opera.
I think they smoked, actually.
- What a racist!
- I believe in Kaliffa.
You choose to believe in Kaliffa.
You do this right in. Congratulations, Inge.
That's right.
At the after party at Café Opera, they chose to ...
... and not fit it to anyone else.
Emelie, you should talk to Evelyn and Camilla.
The ring in the Muslim story about the ring.
Okay, no.
The Allah Ring is ... at Muslim funerals-
– Using the nearest family stands in a ring around the coffin -
- And so you pray a prayer for the dead.
It's called the Allah ring.
Okay, but now the Muslim will speak.
It is a ring from the Viking Age where you engraved the word Allah -
- Written in Arabic.
The ring has been exhibited at the Historical Museum.
- I am the Muslim!
I am right.
–Emelie, what do you say?
I'm afraid I'm losing.
But ... Evelyn, I think you're right.
- Now Camilla goes home!
- You believe in Evelyn.
-Yes.
Camilla sounds so convinced.
- Because I'm a Muslim!
Evelyn said that the Allah ring is a ceremony at the funerals-
- Where you stand in ring and pray.
It was wrong.
The true answer was Camillas.
The Allah ring has been found in a Viking grave.
It says Allah on it.
!
Time for your next question.
It goes to Elaf and Thanos.
By 2022, people from India and Poland were the largest immigrant groups.
You may not think it is Poland and India, because they are not.
It's not that strange - many came from Ukraine and had to stay.
Ukraine, simply.
Mm.
But that is not true.
You may not think about it, because they are light -haired and blend in.
It may be mostly noticeable on the brothels.
Elaf, you have stepped the fuck up.
It was rough-
- But you have graduated in Blatt.
Each time someone has a good punchline, Filip will come and high-fuck!
Sit down and shut up.
It is enough.
You are like bird buzz, you are everywhere!
Stop it!
-Inge?
-Poland.
India.
The question was probably which - not plural.
Oh ...
Pluralis means two.
More than one.
And the program became SFI!
- Then I believe in Elaf.
-Ukraine.
- You shouldn't have done that.
-Yes.
That's not how the program works.
The true answer was given by Thanos.
The groups that were granted the most residence permits in 2022 were -
- Indies, Poles and after the Germans.
- Emelie?
–Yes?
- You have to answer correctly.
Filip and Big O. Please!
–Emelie.
- Yes, Big O.
- Älvsjö, Klockaretorpet, Smedby ... - I don't know what they are.
Älvsjö was a vulnerable area, but now they are Gitted.
Do you understand?
Yani, they are not included in the police list of vulnerable areas.
- So they have been removed.
-Okay.
- Filip?
- Union what the person in question said.
He has not passed Swedish 2 yet.
These areas competed in a fight in the SM for sandwich cake -
- Where different neighborhoods competed for which cake is the longest and best.
The longest, best and best is also Kaliffa's Tinder cinema.
Seriously!
- Big o, can I trust you?
- Probably.
-Okay.
I drive at Big O. - If you are wrong, it's over.
I know!
You believe that these five places have been removed from the list.
Congratulations Älvsjö, Klockartorp, Raneberget -
- Medjebyn and Falkagården.
They are not left on the list.
You get points!
Inge and Emelie, you got a point each.
We can't have two winners.
It will be another issue.
Oh, no!
Oh my God.
I have no idea.
This doesn't feel good.
That's the point of this game.
Three, two, one - show your answers.
Zero?
You don't think any Iranians have been adopted?
You choose zero, you chose 300. The correct answer is ...
582 children were adopted from Iran, which means ...
Emelie, you are our winner!
Come on here.
Congratulations, Emelie!
Tonight's winner.
- The single single is your price.
-Thanks.
A big thank you to our panel, our competitors and our audience.
See you in the semi -finals and see you next week.
Feel the best!
Congratulations!
Texting: Annika Wiehager (C) Swedish Television AB 2024