In tonight's semi -final of IFS - the quiz about all culture in Sweden:
Landskrona's most fun Syrian - Filip Dikmen!
Abracadabra!
He's back - Megic Mike!
If you cross Angola and Degeberga you get Petrina Solange!
The beach rag from Botkyrka - Thanos Fotas!
Sweden's most fun Chinese - Evelyn Mok!
The sweet version of Saddam Hussein - Elaf Ali!
Rågsved's musical July child, who has a heart of IS - Naod!
And IF's brother from Jordbro - Big O!
And now, the man with big A and even bigger B - Ahmed Berhan!
IFS - The program that helps Swedes charm immigrants at Tinder.
My name is Ahmed Berhan, and it's semi -finals -
- In the quiz about all culture in Sweden!
Our semi -finalists:
He was looking forward to the truth and he is here again - Jonas!
She loves to pop a frill, but today she will try to win - Zoofie!
And last but not least, the only Gunilla Persson IFS admits:
Countess from Hässelby - Gunilla!
The contestants choose one in the panel that I ask another question.
The panelist answers, the contestant decides whether the panelist is lying or not.
- Jonas, is it just as easy today?
-I hope so.
- What are you starting with?
- It I meet in everyday life - Big O.
Jalla, big o!
What kind of clock?
No idea, but I think the clock maker has really good Äzi.
This is what the bells look like in Ethiopia.
Wallah, it's COK Smart.
You start the day when the sun rises, at six in the morning -
- And when the sun goes down, six hours later, you start from one again.
- This sounds totally sick.
-Yes.
I go on the gut feeling: False.
You pulled a rivet, because the big o said is true.
That is why Eritreans and Ethiopians never arrive on time.
The clock counts from when the sun rises, and at twelve it has gone down.
- Zoofie, who do you want to start with?
-Thanos.
Liberal Carl B Hamilton left Parliament after a statement.
- What had he said?
- "Allahu Akbar."
No, he had said that prostitution is okay, as long as she is foreign-
- For then it is not counted as Swedish labor.
- It's the Liberals.
- Free labor market, "and what not".
It's sounds too sick to be true, and that's why I think ...
I think you speak the truth.
It sounds too sick to not be true.
You think it's true, and that means ...
... no point to you either!
- We start strongly.
- It was false.
Liberal Carl B Hamilton was allowed to leave Parliament after he had said -
– That the limit for L's cooperation with SD goes -
- When they start talking about Jews as they talk about Muslims.
Can you repeat?
I did not understand.
Racism against Jews - no.
Racism against Muslims - yes.
Okay, now I understand.
We move on to Gunilla.
- Who do you want to start the evening with?
–Evelyn.
Hi, Gunilla!
–Evelyn Mok.
- Hed Berhan.
Some Koreans, Japanese, perhaps Asians -
—The need not use deodorant, because we have a gene -
- This means that our apocrine glands produce less of that sweat ...
- What?
--... that smells bad.
- Apocrine glands.
-What does it mean?
- I didn't know either.
- Basically: I don't smell sweat.
Yes, I notice.
Koreans, especially, have this gene and their sweat does not smell.
- So we don't use deodorant.
- No, I don't think you smell sweaty.
- You don't need deodorant.
- So that's true, what she says?
You have received the first point of the evening.
Congratulations, Gunilla!
It's as Evelyn said.
Some Asians have a variant of this gene -
- Which makes them not smell bad.
- Jonas, who do you choose?
- I take the beautiful - elaf.
King Carl Gustaf once managed to make Pakistan very varnish.
How?
Well, our Swedish king had a dog and he named it Ali.
But Ali is the name of one of Islam's holy men.
Then Pakistan became shit, because they are Muslims and hate dogs.
Then he had to change his name on his dog, and poodle.
This should have heard of this - it is totally sick.
- That he named his dog for Ali?
- Yes, that too.
I say it's false.
- He did.
- Fucking hell.
That's right.
The king baptized his dog after Ali after boxer Muhammad Ali.
Because people became lacquer, the dog is now called Charlie.
- Zoofie, who do you want to talk to?
- Petrina.
John Bouvin was a politician for New Democracy.
He said that the children died in Africa of disasters -
- And that they were eaten by lions.
Then they provided Africa assistance and then the people survived -
“But it was not good, because then it was overcrowded, he thought.
"It was bad with assistance," he said.
- I think what Petrina says is true.
You do that right in. Congratulations, you get a point!
In the past, two to three kids died of different disasters-
-for example.
they were recognized by some wild animal.
Now we help them, so there will be no deaths, and then there will be a disaster.
–Wooo ... - is he racist or not?
No, that's good.
Megic, do you know many who have been eaten by lions?
Yes, there are many who have been eaten by lions.
My uncle.
-For real?
-Yes.
-What happened?
- He was on his way to school.
- Zoofie, congratulations!
- Why are you laughing?
- Gunilla, who do you choose?
- Filip.
Wedding.
When someone goes away at a young age -
- It is a bit celebrated, especially if it is an unmarried teenager.
You can kind of shake the coffin a little, and do ...
-I can not.
Anyone in the audience maybe?
-I can!
/Ululates/
Allah Sawa, dose dose!
You celebrate on his behalf, because he couldn't do it himself.
-Which age?
- When someone is generally young.
- Get like if someone gets murdered?
- If anyone is attacked by a lion.
Aha ... my uncle was eaten when he was 32.
Why did your uncle went to school if he was 32?
It's never too late to learn.
- Gunilla, true or false?
- I think it sounded a bit beautiful.
- I think it's true.
-You are absolutely right.
Congratulations!
That's right.
It can happen if someone is unmarried and young-
- That you throw in small Wedding at the funeral ceremony.
Why not?
- Jonas.
- I take "The Rapper" - Naod.
Which Swedish rapper had plans to rob the Swedish hip hopelitis?
Big O.
No I'm joking.
It was money 'per.
He was the cartel before the cartel-a hip-hop pioneer.
But he was tired of Para-Knas, some money, and such stuff-
- So he realized that he would start taking money from other rappers -
- As had already started making money.
He was going to start with Mange Schmidt.
-Do you know what Para-Knas means?
-He is a police officer-he has been para-one.
I have listened to hip hop all my upbringing - I should have heard about it.
This is false.
I'm ashamed if I'm wrong with this one.
- What are you listening to for hip hop?
- snoop.
Snoop Dogg.
How can you listen to Snoop Dogg?
You are aina!
He goes against his profession.
Jonas, you say it's false ...
... and it's false.
You got a point.
However, the story is true, with modification.
The story does not come from money 'per but from Ken Ring's autobiography -
-There he told me he had plans to trick the hip-hop elite-
- And then force them to overwrite their royalties.
Najs.
Congratulations on the point, Jonas!
Zoofie, it's time for letters from Botkyrka.
YES!
We are in Alby center on fruit and vegetables in Northern Botkyrka.
- What fruit do you sell most of it?
- Watermelon from Morocco.
And the potato, what way does it have?
Germany or Peru?
You should not answer that - the contestants will answer that.
Wasn't it mango?
Was it potatoes?
- Wallah, I thought it was mango.
- No, but ... Germany?
Ein potatoes?
Zoofie thinks the potato is from Germany, which means ...
There will be no point to you.
The potato comes from Peru.
The Spaniards found it when they were there and toured.
- Gunilla ...
- Frequently SKINA!
Who do you choose?
- Megic Mike.
Which Swedish comedian was fighting in MMA - and became known on humor sketches?
It was Anis Don Demina.
He started with Youtube sketches-
- And he hung out with Samir and Viktor.
They made a "hang around" and then he drove some fight, right left.
But he thought he was too thick, so he put the MMA gloves on the shelf.
- What was the person called?
- Ananis Don Demina.
- Did you, Gunilla?
-Yes.
- I don't think he has been a boxer.
- not boxers - MMA!
He said it was an MMA fighter that was too overweight, so he left.
Brother, that's enough!
That's my question.
Absolutely right, Mike!
- I can take the question if you want.
- No, thank you, I'm trying to think.
It's hard in this company - to think.
No, I think it's false.
You don't think Anis Don Demina has had a career in MMA?
-No.
- Gunilla, why?!
- I am sad, Megic.
- No, you just got one more point.
Gunilla is finished in the first round.
The Swedish comedian who has a fighting background within MMA ...
... before he became a humor end ice cream, is no less than our own Megic Mike!
Well!
- How did you get into these fights?
- Card History Facts:
I came to Sweden 2018.
My friends cheated me on an underground fight.
They said the winner gets 10,000, the loser gets 7,000.
I said, "Okay, I need money."
I went in, I won the match -
- And I became known.
"Let's go!"
"Pound for pound."
Thanks for that!
Zoofie and Jonas, you have a point each.
We need a rash question, so it's time for us to drive closest to win.
The question is: Uppsala is Sweden's most expensive kebab city ...
- Are you kebabi enthusiasts?
- I love kebab.
May we see your answers?
Three, two, one ...
-Oh!
The kebab in Uppsala costs SEK 132.
Zoofie is a point away.
- Congratulations!
You have made it to the next round.
- Jonas, thank you for joining!
Gunilla and Zoofie, see you in the duel.
Zoofie, you know how it goes, so we drive!
You get Big O and Filip.
This drink recognizes most Turks again.
When do you drink it?
Thus, brother, this drink is called Lohusa Serbeti.
Do you understand, brother?
It is made of cinnamon, manel cloves and the guys Yani.
When a woman gives birth to a child, when she gets inhabited yani ...
... when she drinking it, she producerish breast milk.
Do you understand?
When it becomes Jetski, brother.
-Do you understand?
- I understood you.
Incorrect.
The correct answer is that it is a Turkish version of Viagra -
- As a drink during the wedding evening for the groom to perform better.
- So it's a "magical drink".
-Thanks so much!
Or ... break.
When I think about it, I agree with Big O. What I said is not true.
Pause.
Frankly, all love, but Filip speaks the truth.
-Reverse psychology!
- I'm confused now.
Who is right?
Do you think it is drinking as a potency -enhancing means -
- Or to make the breasts go "squirt, squirt"?
I believe in the first option.
- So you believe in Filip?
-Yes.
I don't usually trust him.
–The Same Applies To You, Shaitan.
- Chalas.
You should have gone on your gut feeling, because Filip lied to you.
It is not a potency -enhancing drink.
The truth came from Big O. It is a drink you give to new mothers -
- To help with milk production.
It wasn't Viagra?
Damn, the man, I would buy it.
Gunilla, you should get your duel.
You get Petrina and Megic Mike.
Petrina and Megic ... the proverb "fits like the hand in the glove" ...
What does "verbatim" mean?
Should we rename the show to SFI?
But come on, I can't Swedish.
Should you put Finnish too?
But yes ... Finnish makes snuff of everything -
-And the "hand in the glove" means "the hand on the rod".
Or if you are African: "Hand on Medingo".
You understand what I mean.
No, this means "fits like the knife in a childhood friend".
No...
What the f ...?
No, but that means "fits like the fist in the eye".
Finns are a little more straightforward, so it means fits like the fist in the eye.
I don't think Petrina speaks the truth.
I believe in Megic Mike.
- Why Megic Mike?
- You believe in the "hand around the rod"?
Yes, I believe more about the Finns than that, than they get a fist in the eye.
They have knives instead.
- It sounded too good for the Finns?
- Yes, it sounded a little kind.
- So you go straight on ... - Yes?
- Yes, sorry ...
- Can you pronounce the Finnish word again?
- As you will understand it.
"Sopia Kuin Nyrkki Silmään."
"Supri Koin Numros Selema."
This is the first time someone applauds when someone gets a stroke on TV.
You chose to believe in Megic Mike, that it is hand around the rod -
- For Finns are filthy.
But, Gunilla, you are wrong.
Megic Mike lied to you.
Petrina gave you the truth.
The Finnish may have had a good deal, but that means "like a fist in the eye".
Okay.
None of you got points, but you have a chance for points.
Zoofie, your duel goes over to Evelyn and Naod.
Then my question is to you: Last year Sweden beat an unusual record -
- There only Mexico was ahead of us.
What was that?
Who has the world's most fairly big cock.
What happens, the man?
This is not IFS, it is porn.
It is blasting it is about, which is crazy.
But last year was Mexico, of all countries that are not at war -
- What is only type three countries ...
They had the most blasts per capita-
- And Sweden is second on that list.
So ... in a survey, Sweden had gone about the United States, and countries in South America -
- In eating tortillas, per capita.
- Otherwise, it sounds a bit prejudiced.
- Who doesn't like tacos?
Yes, but that it would be the investigation - most tortillas.
- Swedes love their tacos!
- Yes, Taco Friday.
Do you know how much Sweden loves its blasts?
What is Taco for something?
- Zoofie, who do you choose to believe in?
- I put my vote on Naod.
But I don't listen to you.
I choose Evelyn.
I choose Evelyn, because Filip said I would choose Naod.
- So if I go out it's Filip's wrong.
- Come at me, bitch!
Imagine when Filip will present her red -haired girl with satan tattoos -
- For her mother!
So you believe in Evelyn, that Sweden stands out with -
- Is the number of blasts we have in Sweden.
You blasted up to your first score in the second round.
Congratulations!
The man, before we move on ... what is tacos?
Nobody believes that you haven't cooked tacos - there is nothing you haven't chewed!
Gunilla, you are in the last round, the last question.
If you take this, we will play, but if you answer the wrong ...
Then I can say "Bye, Bye".
Last duel: Remains are no less than Thanos and Elaf.
Here we have a good question: When Usama bin Ladins ... /Laughter /
... computer was confiscated after his death, so did you find what in his computer?
Do we have any anime fans here?
That was what was found in his computer.
He liked anime, and he gave a lot of time.
You are a big Animefan, so you and Usama had a lot in common.
They found, among other things.
Dragon Ball, One Piece and Naruto on his computer.
So he was a nerd.
When you didn't think you could like Usama bin Laden more ...
Elaf Ali.
Gunilla, you hear ... he talks shit as always.
I know this best, I'm from Iraq.
The truth is that they found a folder on his computer -
- which was called 9/11.
It did not contain secret material with maps and so, as one hoped -
-It contained a lot of 9/11 and Usama memes.
Gunilla, Gunilla ...
Should you believe in someone who spends so much time in front of the mirror?
She probably doesn't need much time in front of the mirror - she's beautiful anyway.
I have never seen any disarmed people so much with love.
We're here to talk truth.
Please may we be late.
- Yes, I'll take Thanos.
- you?!
Why?
If it is Zoofie who wins, then congratulations to her.
- Gunilla!
She gives up, the man.
- Gunilla, you're too cute.
You chose to believe in Thanos - that Usama bin Laden is an animen nerd.
You've received a point.
That's right.
When the CIA revealed the material from Bin Ladin's computer -
-They invented everything from wedding videos to Disney movies and video games.
- I think my answer was better.
-It was really 50-50.
- You are so credible ... - it's called manipulative.
Gunilla, if anyone calls you and asks about your bank ID-Spend!
Add at once!
I love you.
That's my tip for you.
Awesome work!
Both got a point, but only one can move on to the final.
It's time for the closest win.
The question is:
How about you show what you have written on your paintings?
You have written 200,000. - And you have written 500,000.
The correct answer is: 1.2 million Swedes left.
Congratulations, Gunilla, you have made it to the final!
Come, Gunilla, and you'll get your price!
You have won nothing less than Megic Mike's signed glove.
- We love you, Gunilla!
- We are seen in the final.
Next week we will pick up the three worst participants from the season.
Then it will be time for summer school.
An applause to Gunilla!
Texting: SVT Language & amp;
Accessibility (C) Swedish Television AB 2024