In tonight's section of Ifs, the question of all culture in Sweden ...
Gothenburg's best Somalier, Assia Dahir.
With the pockets full of fresh zucchini, Thanos Fatas.
The world's Swedishest Arab, Elaf Ali.
The almost lawyer and carpentry snack artist Filip Dikmen.
The humor slaughter from Serbia, Branne Pavlovic.
And Sweden's most fun Chinese, Evelyn Mok.
Our fucking brother, Yousif Jawad.
The legend that rips northern B since -93, Douglas "Doggelito" León.
And now, the man you are all waiting for: host Ahmed Berhan!
Welcome to the IFS, the program where no one pays the radio and TV fee.
I am Ahmed Berhan, your program leader, and this is our competitors.
Player Malmö: Matilda.
The man in green: Martin.
And at the far end, but not last, but not least: Caroline.
It is possible that a competitor chooses one in the panel -
- which answers a question, and will then decide whether it is true or false.
Caroline, you are a middle school teacher.
Which are messiest:
–You class or panel?
- Hundred percent the panel.
So which of the messy do you choose?
There is one who has something in common with me, so I choose Dogge.
I'm as old as Dogge's career.
It's a good thing.
A compliment.
If you are as old as his career you should have died 20 years ago!
- Oh, wow ... –Oh no, what a nasty!
Now I took.
- We start sharply.
Dogge, how are you?
- Giantbra.
Thanks so much.
A blatte ran around in the 80s and sprayed down ... No, I'm kidding.
- This is a family program, brother.
- Do you talk about yourself?
It is a syringe with vaccine that gives a scar that you see on immigrants -
- And immigrants' children.
That scar is called the Blatte Stamp.
What do you say, Caroline?
It sounds as unreasonable as my food habits.
I say it's false.
We're going to amuse you, you should not amuse yourself!
- You're pretty good at that otherwise.
- She's sharp, this one.
- She's sharp.
- You thought Dogge lied.
Unfortunately.
No point.
It's true.
It is a scar after tuberculosis vaccine.
It does not mean that you are born abroad, but at least one parent-
- Has its origin in a country where tuberculosis is more common than in Sweden.
Can everyone in the audience pull up their right arm?
- I have one here.
-I have.
You said turbo colos.
It is a very fast disease.
- We move on to you, Matilda.
You said you are from a village of Skåne, and had not seen an immigrant -
- Trees you moved to London.
A little exaggerated, but kind of yes.
You needed to become an immigrant to see an immigrant.
Matilda, who do you choose?
I've been in love with this person for a long time.
Dogge again.
It's not possible.
You can only choose the panelist once.
- Night, it's Branne.
-Oh!
-I blush.
Now it gets hard.
- You are white.
How can you be red?
- It's makeup.
- Branne ...
In the Balkans kitchen you will find vegetable.
What is it?
"Vegeeta."
It's a shotgun.
Or as we in Serbia say:
Problem solver.
Argumentation winner.
It is a wedding present that you get from your father -in -law when you get married.
Then you get a shotgun as a gift.
-Oh!
- It is a ballet tradition.
The shots in Sarajevo.
It was a wedding that went wrong.
Matilda calls her dad: "We have to buy a shotgun!"
- What are you saying?
One thing I learned in London was that you can't trust jugger guys.
But...
- But it sounds very Balkans.
- It sounds the Balkans?
You believe in Branne?
- Fan, I don't want to be naive again.
- Matilda has been hurt before.
Matilda, if this is to work, you have to believe in me.
-What are you saying?
True or false?
- False.
You say falsely.
Congratulations, Matilda, you have received a point.
Vegeta is a spice mixture that
Used in soups and sauces.
Martin, time for you to shine.
Who do you choose?
--Assia I start with.
- A classic clip from Idol.
You think we're racists?
I am half -palestinians.
Here is no racist!
- That was not said.
-You can go.
Because she fucking is a racist.
You can't be Rasse if you are blatte.
It doesn't work.
We blast love each other, right?
Joking aside.
It was an applicant who was rejected and became a shit.
Was crossed at Laila and called her racist.
The sick thing was that this person himself was Palestinians.
And who was the person?
Well, namely a young Gina Dirawi.
I think it's partly true, but not that it was Gina, but a man.
I don't really remember the clip.
So I say it's ...
- So you say ...?
- I say it's false.
Awesome, Martin.
We are checking.
Hello!
What's your name?
Filip Dikmen.
My mom says I sing nicely as a bird.
"Sings nicely as a bird."
“ÄFRY” NIGHT IN MY DREAM
I See You, I See You
-It does not sound good.
- All others say it, just not you!
Martin, you said it was false.
Congratulations, you've got a point.
An applicant was rejected and called Laila racist.
- But it was our own Filip Dikmen.
--Walla, it was Suleyman, not me!
- Caroline, who do you choose?
- Then I take Filip.
The roaster.
-Hello Hello!
- Filip ...
That's what Elaf means to me.
You got embarrassed for real.
The man, chill, I'm sarcastic!
Habibti is the girl variant of Habibi which means darling.
To guys you say Habibi, to girls Habibti.
Arabic has not developed sufficiently so they or non binary-
- Neither he nor she, you call Hmar.
Otherwise it means darling.
Did you have to bring the last one?
There it burst.
I've seen fast cash, so I know all the resorts.
So I would say ...
Oh my God!
Let him lie down.
Leave him left!
If he dies, he dies.
You just need to keep track of Habibti and Habibi.
Then I say true.
You think Habibti is the feminine version of Habibi, "my darling"?
Just right, Habibti.
Congratulations, you've got one more point.
- Congratulations to your first point.
- Thanks, fast cash.
We're with you, Matilda.
Who do you choose?
Thanos.
- Tjena, Ahmed.
- Tjena, Thanos.
The situation?
I feel like a dry svenne today.
- But the hair is moistened.
It is good.
- It's always.
From the Kalabalikistan, of course.
Well, you understand ...
No, but Kalabalik comes from Turkish.
It means crowd.
Is it a crowd of Turks -
- Then they know it will be a calabic.
Is it good?
Yes...
- It's my final answer.
-What are you saying?
Can you say that you know that is true?
It's true.
Did you hang out with Turks in London too?
- How do you know it's true?
- A friend is Turk.
Please...
Every time he is with Matilda, it becomes calabal.
Martin.
I heard that you at work ... you work a lot with immigrants.
- It's right.
-What do you work as?
Defense Attorney.
- Who do you choose to talk to?
-Oh...
–Yousif.
- My fucking brother.
–What are you taking an hour?
- Like to hear you say so!
Yousif.
The suburban hose Brösta took a difficult task -
–And entered the new word list in 2022. Where did the term origin?
Breastfeeding.
Breastfeeding, brother.
They said to my mom, "Do you really want to brush this child?"
No, I drive.
Seriously now.
It comes from football.
When someone adds a post and you receive it, you chest it.
It actually sounds reasonable, so I say it's true.
-It's true.
You trust Yousif?
- No, but ... I think it's true.
Unfortunately, it's false, so there will be no points this time.
Originally “to crowd” or boast, but are also suburban hose -
- To accept something, for example: "Who picks up the food? - I chest it."
Martin's clients have been browned for many years.
- Caroline, we move on to you.
- I take Evelyn.
Evelyn, 2017, the radio channel Mix Megapol suffered a coup.
What so?
Under "Gry Forsell with friends", the frequency was cut by jihadists.
So is basicly hijacked Mix Megapol's radio frequency -
–And played a jihadist song in type half an hour -
- Till's mix got the frequency back.
Salil al-Salam ...
- Caroline ... - I am a jihadist in my spare time ...
... so I happen to know it's true.
She has seen fast cash.
Caroline, great work.
You got one more point.
It's true.
Mix Megapol's Malmö frequency was cut by pirate transmitters.
Surprise, Surprise.
- Matilda, do you feel ready?
- Yeah.
- What do you choose?
–Alaf.
Elaf, time for a picture question.
It is Evelyn's mother who burns Evelyn's inheritance -
- For it will not be grandchildren.
She kill your entire tribe, the man!
No, that was another Chinese aunt.
She burns pretend money.
Chinese believe that if you burn paper copies of something -
- So they reach their dead relatives.
They also burn brand bags and branded shoes, iPads and iPhones -
—To the dead relatives not to miss the technological development -
- and have fomo in heaven.
I have no idea.
It sounds...
So, you can't burn iPads.
- But there are paper copies.
- Yes, but then it's true.
Then it's true?
Okay.
Then it became true.
Matilda, do you know what?
You just got full pot: 3 out of 3.
It is done at the holiday Qingming, the Day of Death.
You burn paper versions of things you want to send to your ancestors.
Martin, as you can see, is all panelists selected.
Therefore, your panelist becomes ...
... randomly selected.
- Filip.
- Hit me!
The cock.
- Ey, BRE, help me.
Shall I help you?
That's a lot ... heres.
It's very much heres.
The area is ... maybe not the cock, but wrote.
- This area?
–Yes.
Yes, but I think you have seen that, that kind of dance.
Martin pretends that he himself does not usually whina.
I have tried, but no one wants to see, so it is better that you do.
You seem to know it, so it should be reasonable.
- Or what do you say?
But do you think it's true?
He tried to drive a lawyer.
"It's reasonable."
He wanted to get away.
I don't want to go out.
I say it's ... true.
You say it is true that the focus in the Eskista dance is written and cock.
It's false.
Unfortunately.
There will be no point for you.
It is the focus on the shoulders in the Ethiopian dance Esskista.
No, it felt like a hate crime.
Dogge drives a car, brother.
Ahmed, show!
Unfortunately, I don't get paid for it.
Martin, you do not follow the final.
But Matilda and Caroline are on to the final.
It's about coming first to five.
But if you answer wrong, the score goes to your opponent.
Are you in?
-I am with.
- What do you start the final round with?
Yes...
–Eh ... —You get Branne.
Yes, I thought so.
Branne, you are a nice Andrew Tate.
I'm going now.
- He is lying, but you take him anyway.
- I didn't lie!
- You did.
- Okay, I lied to her.
Not only patchwork distributes fines in the resort.
Who else can you be fined?
SL.
That's it.
No, joking aside ...
It is religious uncles acting as a police officer.
They go around in Ford Escort.
Look how you behave at the mosque.
- Do you sprinkle outside ... - She don't know what Pipas is!
Sorry.
Sunflower seeds.
See if the name is correctly spelled on your designer clothes.
If you show ankles.
You are fined and have to leave gifts in the mosque.
Dates.
A lamb if you fucked up properly.
-What are you saying?
- The end, then ...
No, that can't be true.
- You think Branne is lying to you?
-Yes.
Nice that you learn from experiences.
Obviously it's false.
Your first point in the final round.
It is not religious as a fine.
However, it is not unusual -
- That a criminal with violence capital puts a debt on you.
Congratulations to your score.
- Caroline, we move on to you.
-Thanos.
Hairdresser, dry cleaner and wedding fixer.
No, but Hovsjö is called Lilla Lagos.
It is because that lives many Nigerians, Somalis and Finns.
–Dogge: Finns.
- Do you own Finns?
Sorry.
-Eh ... -nigerians, Somalis and Finns.
- They are the three dominant groups.
- You don't have to translate.
- Clearly I needed it.
- Or that's what he needed.
What can it be?
Haven't you seen fast cash?
They are in completely different places.
I say it's false.
False.
You don't believe in Thanos.
If you are wrong, the point goes to the opponent.
It doesn't.
False.
Congratulations, Caroline.
You get your first point in the final round.
It's false.
The ethnicities are Assyrians/Syrians, Armenians and Sweden Finlanders.
Syrians.
Do you understand?
You said there were Somalis in Södertälje.
We don't do that.
Matilda, who do you choose to talk to?
- Then I was going to take Filip.
-Hello Hello!
Filip, it's time for a picture question.
For the hospital's V-undone t-shirts-
- So he had to flase his fucking chest hair.
What the fuck is that?!
He wrote that he was very grateful to all white people -
- Which has been involved in creating the Swedish democratic welfare society.
If I don't remember, he's a Swedish Democrat, so it may be true.
- Sant.
-You say true?
Damn, what your memory doesn't fail you.
Just right.
Congratulations.
Good!
- We will check out the real tweet.
- I've probably seen it.
He was extremely grateful for all the whites who built the Swedish welfare.
He looked at Hanif Bali: "Hold My Beer, Buddy."
Caroline, we're going back to you.
--Assia.
-Hello!
Assia, 2016, a department store chain got to taste the annual Lucia Break.
-What was that about?
- They sold Lucia crowns that were hijabs.
No, sorry.
I'm kidding.
They went full multi-culti-
- And had a little black boy like Lucia in his Christmas catalog.
-What are you saying?
-I recognise that.
It's true.
Congratulations, you got one more point.
Åhléns had a black boy in an advertising campaign and it became a drive.
Hundreds of racist comments on social media.
- Matilda.
- I choose Elaf.
-Elaf ...
These are the four members of a boy band called Waheed.
They have become a symbol of a united Middle East.
They live in Berlin, but come from different countries in the Arab world.
They consist of two Muslims, a Jew and a Christian.
Eh ... Was it the name of the members you said, then?
-Yes.
What were the names?
- As you have listened ...
–Ojava, baking watch, basur, rojhel.
- Yeah.
It's on her Spotify.
I try that is true.
You believe in Elaf, that it is a project to combine MENA.
- It's false.
- Fuck!
Congratulations, Caroline.
You have received points.
It's false.
It is the four parts of Kurdistan that coincide with -
- The Kurdish minorities in Turkey, Syria, Iraq and Iran.
- Can you tell them again?
-Absolutely not.
It sounds like a hogwart role formula.
Rashigorarshira ...!
–Ojava, baking watch, basur, rojhel.
--Oooh!
Caroline ... we look at the score.
It stands 3–2 to you.
- What do you choose?
–Evelyn.
Evelyn ...
Shoo.
VGD?
What are you doing?
No.
The thing is...
Big, rapper, is actually pronounced right -
- So he contacted the Moderates and wanted to write a campaign song for them.
But the Moderates refused, because they do not want to be associated with the resort.
- Caroline, what do you say?
- Yes, that is the question.
Hearing greatly to Kristersson to offer a campaign song?
I think I recognize it.
I say it's true.
You choose to believe in Evelyn.
Which then means that ...
Matilda, you've got one more point.
It's false.
Large urged their followers-
- Writing "Hédi Fried" on Ulf Kristersson's Instagram -
- As he promised her to never have anything contact with SD.
- They would be a good duo, big and Ulf.
-Big and small.
Who, Matilda?
Now I choose Dogge.
- DOGGE.
–Yes.
It was Bert Karlsson, but it was the elephant who rode on Bert.
No I'm joking.
It was Sean Banan 2014.
And the song was called ...
... "bananas in the concrete" if I remember just right.
Yes, I have absolutely no idea.
Can you even ride an elephant in Sweden?
- In the resort you can get everything.
- It wasn't Sean Banan, so false.
- You say it's false?
- No, I say it's true.
Unfortunately, it is false, Matilda.
No point to you, but to Caroline.
To answer if you can rent an elephant to ride: Yes, you can.
The year was 1999. The artist was Ayo and the song obviously "The Concrete Jungle Book".
Never feel the prisoner in the suburban concrete
- You know who it is.
- In the suburb you ride on camel.
Caroline.
We should not think about animals anymore.
But do you know what to think about?
You have 4 points.
This means that if you answer correctly, you take home the whole thing.
–Yousif.
What are you saying?
Stand.
Abow, that's true too.
No.
The real answer is bargain.
If you bargain loudly and it smells, you have to "reset" and redo everything -
- Hold yourself and ask for.
But some, who are not really trained, say -
- That if you are fishery and there will be no sound or smell, you will get away.
So ... it's unreasonable to have a prayer ritual that stimulates the intestines -
–And you lie down in a typically bargain -friendly position -
- To say "if you bargain when we exposed you to this" ...
The position, not the prayer.
"Then you have to start over."
It feels unreasonable.
It feels more reasonable for it to be a nice and enjoyable moment.
You say it's false.
You choose not to believe in Yousif.
Unfortunately, it cost you a point.
Then the score goes to Matilda.
It's true.
You must not hustle during the prayer.
You know what?
We are in an extremely exciting and fun location.
As you can see, it is 4–4.
We have no panelists left.
- We run the rash issue closest to wins.
-Ooh!
Are you ready to show your answers?
- This is exciting!
- Matilda, you guess at 1608.
Caroline guesses at 1523.
The correct answer is ...
... 1983.
This means that Matilda was closest.
You don't just win the round -
- You win the whole competition!
Congratulations, Matilda!
Here you have your fine IFS diploma.
Here you have a lot of Chinese fake copies to burn to the ancestors.
A large applause to the winner Matilda and to Caroline and Martin.
Our fantastic panel!
Our wonderful audience and all of you at home: Thank you!
See you again soon!
Texting: Barbro Garneij Swedish Media Text for SVT