Hey all.
Fun to talk to you all from my home office in Helsinki.
The subject of my lecture today is address and tone in government communication.
I have promised to move in the past and show examples of how to do before
before we get back to the present again.
The background to this is -
That I wrote a dissertation that is about addressing in commercials from the 20th century.
Advertising films are something other than government communication
But the collection I work with consists of over 400 films.
Among them are some that were not common commercials
Without rather information films directed from authorities to the public.
The purpose of this dissertation was to illuminate the Dure form -
So I particularly looked at what kind of speech used -
When you turn directly to the viewer, and how the tone generally became more informal -
with the 1960s as a kind of breaking point in development.
There are crucial differences between government films and ordinary commercials.
The most important thing is that commercial players sell
while authorities rather inform.
But on the other hand you can say that informative is also about selling
If not products, at least ideas, attitudes and concepts.
So you want to influence recipients, get the viewer to watch out in traffic, vote in the election
Eat healthy, stop sipping and start exercising.
Both advertising and the information films use classic rhetorical grip -
Like ethos, logos and pathos.
Ethos means that you convince through your person, e.g.
by showing experts.
Logos means that you appeal to reason.
It is perhaps a more common grip for authorities
While pathos - that you appeal to emotion - is more typical of commercial actors.
The history of the film began in the late 1800s.
They soon realized the film's potential for the advertising industry.
The oldest Swedish commercials are silent films that were made around 1915.
The oldest government films I have found are also from that time.
There is admittedly even older movie reports
which depicts royalty and other dignitaries who visit different places.
They are perhaps also a kind of government films
But around 1915 you found out that you could appeal to the viewer more direct -
And influence the viewer, instead of just showing something impressive that happened.
Here you can see some examples of films that represent social information
directly from an authority or some other public and public benefit.
In a while you will see examples from a couple of these movies.
But there are lots of films similar to government films
Although they are not really.
The so-called housewives films made from the 50s to the 70s-
Consists of cavalcades of longer and shorter elements.
There, advertising is interspersed.
information and entertainment.
The Savings Banks Movement has extensive campaigns
which up to the 70s is about saving, not wasting.
Insurance companies can also make films that seem slightly more enlightened.
For example, they want
prevent accidents.
When it comes to elections, political parties make films where they analyze society
and urges the viewer to vote.
But today I will concentrate on authorities
And on how new media has provided new opportunities.
A very early evidence of discussion about this can be found in the magazine Idun in 1918.
Then food and fuel shortages were severe throughout Europe, including in Sweden.
There was a great need to inform about the situation.
You made journal films where you got to see ringing queues with people waiting for
to get a ration bread or something similar.
But it was also found that the film could be used to teach people in
How to deal with this deficiency.
This article from March 1918 is actually about rational housekeeping and film.
The newest Christian education.
Here we see pictures of how to fry herring without fat.
How to use a very ordinary sleeve case and a hat box for savings.
And how to fry plates of potato flakes, obviously in a tiled stove.
I want to highlight a quote from this article.
(Reading the text)
When I found the quote was the first thing I did to find Fairbanks and Love
Because I wanted something to compare with -
When I then looked at the Food Board's teaching film -
Which is about how to cook and bake bread in the stove.
I would very much like to show it to you, but it is five minutes long
So you have to find it yourself if you are curious.
But what happens in the movie is quite typically
Something that occurs in commercials and housewife films throughout the 20th century.
First we have the Etoskomponent, the male expert who demonstrates for us -
How a special cooking box is designed.
Then we get to see a female housekeeper who uses the box.
In the film, there are no middle texts and thus no direct address to the viewer.
A few times she looks into the camera and meets our gaze, this young woman
Who has been commissioned to show us how to do when cooking in the stove.
The Food Board's tiled stove film from 1917 thus only shows how to do it.
It does not appeal to our emotions, and it completely lacks middle texts
So that turmoil is not the viewer.
When you appeal to the viewer's feelings, amuse and worry
Can be used to be informal and tell you to the viewer also in the very oldest films.
In fun movies you can build up a fictional intimacy.
You pretend to be friends with the viewer.
But you can also say you in the most serious context.
It may sound a little surprising, but it seems that really seriously leads to
To peel away all courtesy forms.
We find it in many war -time newspaper ads where you want to encourage Swedes -
To donate money to Finland or stand up as volunteers in the war.
These ads appeal to the reader with you.
It also makes a road safety campaign.
This movie, which is also a little too long for this context
begins with neutral factual reason arguments -
While we get to see a scene that ends with us seeing a child being hit by a car -
in the lively Stockholm traffic.
At the end, the film turns to a purely pathos-grip-
Where you convince the viewer of the seriousness of this issue with direct you-speech to the viewer.
We see a police officer standing with the lifeless child in their arms
and hear the narrator voice saying:
(Reading the text)
The very direct speech and the dumby -
Certainly could have been perceived as excessive in the 40s.
But because of the deeply serious message, it still works.
Dure form is not the only change in the 1960s.
One can see at the same time partially overlapping, but completely revolving changes
which is usually called informalization, democracy, intimisation and conversation.
Dure form is the clearest linguistic cursor, but it happens much more.
This is seen in the films of time that began to use a completely different tone
towards the recipient.
This is an example from the year 1967
When you switched from left -hand traffic to right -hand traffic.
A little info film that reminds the viewer of
That you have to sharpen so that you do not end up on the wrong side when driving in traffic.
I'll play it for you.
Here we can note many new features compared to old films.
That i have colored with green in the text
Are especially clear markers for a new informal and free style.
"Oh you" Here you are used for the viewer, but not as a common address -
but as soon as a discourse marker.
"Mary mode" time -typical youth language, I think.
"So you don't have to do away with it."
Here the movie has the stomach to suggest that the viewer could do away with traffic.
A statement that would hardly have been possible ten years earlier.
We can also note the cameraman's vacant upholstery and hairstyle.
The new spirit permeates everything.
Both the previous example of right -hand traffic and this one about voting
are examples of a new grip that you can call "behind the scenes".
Instead of showing off a grounded end product
If you show something that will represent an insight into the process.
He who is in the middle of the picture is Gottfried Grafström.
He has written a script that is evaluated by actor Birgitta Andersson to the right.
She thinks the script lacks humor and now you should see it.
But there is also a type of government film that is much more straightforward
Teaching and educating.
A splendid example of this was served by the National Board of Health and Welfare in 1975.
This one in itself well - the film today looks so absurd out -
that it has rolled around in social media where it has been commented and discussed.
Often by today's youth who think it is absolutely sick to tell this way
How to do it, into the smallest detail.
Some of you have certainly seen it, but hopefully not too many.
This grip that serves detailed good advice for the viewer
Of course have their good and bad sides.
The purpose was good.
They wanted equality, equality, democratization.
A healthy and happy population that could work hard for Sweden's best.
But this type of government information can easily and with good reasons
accused of standardization, requirements for uniformity, detailed control of privacy -
touch sticks and a kind of unauthorized declaration of the citizen.
This is certainly why this film has later been divided and discussed in social media
Where today's young people think it is absolutely incredible.
This is exactly what I do not think our authorities are guilty of today.
But that does not mean that we should be completely uncritical to all new opportunities
that opens up for us ... (sound loss)
The social media today, has become a bit like the movie was a hundred years ago.
It is new, you can experiment with new forms of appeal and tone to citizens.
You can fail with it, and then you can easily be perceived as manipulative.
When borrowing languages and other forms from the private sphere
It becomes more difficult for the recipient to identify power.
The link between democratization and informalization is not at all obvious.
But when the new form experiments succeed
Could it be an astonishingly effective way to reach out with information -
by packing it in an attractive cover.
Thanks.