One two Three!
Good morning!
I just want to say before we start:
I've been in a little bad mood today so ... damn lucky we are here now
I'll probably gasp up!
[Laugh]
[Laughs] Fy fuck!
[High-five sound] It's quiet.
Shall we say 'Gomorron'?
-Yes, Gomorron!
It is still sick, that it does not rain today.
-17 degrees!
These are dark clouds, but today we are at Skara Summerland for ourselves ... type.
In a little while.
-Yes.
Yes, as you can see, we have it completely for ourselves.
Yes ... - Ahh.
Here we go!
-A time, now we drive.
One two Three!
Shall we go in?
-Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah!
"See You Later, Girls".
Here's a train?
Should we go it?
-No, dammit!
Why should we go it?
But isn't that a little fun then?
Why do they do that?
- If we go it, we miss everything later, we don't have that long.
No, okay.
Where does the train go then?
To Skövde?
-It's just around there ... to Skövde.
[Silent laughter]
There is a damn lot of roller coaster and then there is the water country.
We think we should start grazing all the rides that exist,
If you can't bring such things with you, we have to take a goopron.
We start with this then, "the duck".
“Swinging Duck”
So it is a duck that goes ... -you sit in the wings.
Ahh.
[Happy music]
[Lucas] I sit down at the front then.
This was pretty high!
[Lucas] Oh damn!
[Lucas, with a loud voice] Näähäädu, Nähäädu, you are kidding!
What the hell!
[They scream]
Hell!
I thought we would spin around there?
Well, we can't hang up and down in a fucking strap.
Imagine if you had brought Sam and Love on this, they didn't have ...
They hadn't gone this!
- No!
He had been terrified!
Fun that everyone just looks at us ...
We just [talk nonsense]
But do you know what?
Go -kart now.
I promise you, I win.
I'm sorry Jonas, but you should jump into it first.
"Ooooh!"
It is turned off, otherwise I would have gone seven times.
[Tension -filled music]
[Car motor sounds are heard]
It's so fun to drive outside.
-Yes it is!
But do you feel your thumbs?
It was the same when we ... - I got hot on my back.
Do you know the muscles here?
That it ... -here?
You!
Check this then.
[Battle-Lieuting Operation]
Should we go to the water land now?
-Yes, but do you know what we do on the road?
Bacon snacks.
Now we have the whole water land for ourselves.
Thus, the whole water land, everything.
Do we have it?
Baconchips then?
Before you jump in and take off your clothes.
-Yes but you know what, then you can get cramps.
Do you know it's just a myth?
The parents said it so that the kids would not go down and play ... -Yes now you have told everyone.
... the parents could chill.
My mom always said so instead: "Please Jonas, don't swim after dinner because we want to chill a little"
[Uppetempo music]
So now we are at the water park and just as we left the hospital ...
... because you had problems.
Hanging purse.
Could not fix so can go with it anyway.
We get to present our experts too, you may say hello to the camera and what you are called.
Hello!
Adam.
-Tjena, Rickard.
They will take care of us today so we don't ... shit down.
They are experts.
-There is no one who dares to trust us.
The idea is today that we will test all these fun as well.
[In chorus] -aah.
"COBRAN!"
-Yes "cobra", it looks good.
We start with "Kobra"!
We must not go three, we have to go four.
Rickard, you go on it!
[They sing loudly in chorus]
[Lucas] Oh!
Oh!
-Oh damn!
[Lucas] Oh damn what it goes!
[Jonas, cut] you kidding me!
Ahh!
[Everyone screams]
[Cry]
[Lucas, loud] what the hell happened?!
[Scream] - damn !!
Oh!
Satan what it went!
-Is what it went!
It was fun you!
[Lucas] it was giant .... [laughter]
Now it's time for "racer", hang out!
Check Niclas, so you can see here: Bana one, two, three, four and then you see who is the fastest
We drive at the same time?
-Yes!
Aha, it's time for?
What a thing!
Not at the same time?
[Out of picture] - No, not time.
No, not time.
You!
We won't have any damn time if you thought so.
No, we really won't have that.
"See You Later Bro"
We have been talking about Badland for several years,
And they haven't wanted to go.
Look at them!
They are like children.
[Behind the camera] ready, ready go!
[They roar]
[Screams] yeah!
[Behind the camera] damn!
It was even.
-Where?
I couldn't see who!
Check in reprise then.
I couldn't see who.
-Is what fun!
There was a lot of pressure on the stomach.
You have to comment on who won, we didn't see it.
- I won!
YES!
And I vote for what to do next.
When you got up there on the back it was something we had not seen.
Waka Waka?
[They sing] "Tsamina Mina, eh, eh waka waka, eh, eh"
We drive it then.
Do you know what we had in Nittorp?
Similar, it was called "Fucking Fuck".
Just that, were you and the mother
"Fuck Fuck With Yo Motha Motha" was called it.
It was a ring too, like ...
??
Waka Waka!
-Oh...
[Jonas] Oh, oh.
You go fast!
[They tease and scream] woaaaaaaah!
Damn!
This one was asnajs!
Hell what fun!
We have bent three stuff in here now.
What was the best of "cobran", "racer" and this one?
So I thought the cobra was eh ... -I also thought so.
Really good.
-But it was a little scary.
It was long.
Exactly.
-Here you got to enjoy a little.
"That's what she said" -haha.
There you got to enjoy yes!
[Laugh]
[Inaudible]
And I go on ...
[Rhythmic music]
I got a cold soup.
-Ah sorry, I had to pee.
Now we're going to go this one.
"The White Metal Death" is called it.
This one can really only go two.
But we in JLC are always three.
Oh damn!
Are you kidding!
No, it will fall out!
Damn it is fatal!
Hello!
[Inaudible]
Turn around!
[Nervous laughter]
[Inaudible] ... go backwards!
We will go out!
You can only be two!
You can only be two Niclas!
[Inaudible]
Hell!
[Bubble-sound]
[Nervous laughter]
So it was 20 cm ... I keep Lucas like this!
Up there we wouldn't be ... -No!
We were out in the discounts!
We were too heavy.
[Niclas] aha, oh ...
It started to rain as hell!
-En once or?
Next!
Yes, next.
-This was fun.
It was really fun!
Damn!
[Laugh out of picture]
[Screams]
Everything feels ... like you should hit everything.
I hit my feet!
I also said it, you are so damn close to hitting everything.
Bieber!
-What fucking bieber!
[Sings made] "and I don't want the world to see me ..."
How is it going?
[Niclas] -What emo ...
How's the song going?
[Niclas] He who has the strawberry?
[Niclas] HA!
Which one is now again?
"And I don't want ..." [laughter]
How the hell does it go?
[Niclas] No!
No!
It's not "Cut My Life"
Comment if you know who it is!
See you!
[Giggle]
[Singing voice is heard on the screen]
[Sings made] "'Cause tonight will be the night that I will fall for you!"
"'Cause tonight ..." [laughter]
[Laughter] It's it!
The strawberry!
After all, someone has made an emo-earth guy!
[Someone sings on the song in the background]
[Men's voice sings] "'Cause Tonight Will Be The Night That I Will Fall For You!"
From free fall, Skara Summerland and Rutch canoes to the motorhome and advertising for Air Up.
We've worked with these before,
And it's so amazing, for:
You buy one like this and you put a capsule on,
And then you drink, and then you are tricked via the scent capsule that the water tastes just that taste it stands.
And what is also great that this is the new bottle, such a metal bottle.
So it keeps cold very good.
So you pour cold water here it is cold for a long time.
Such a taste pod is five liters of water,
So you don't have to go to the store, you don't have to buy lots of plastic bottles that you then throw away.
So this is a more environmentally friendly alternative as well.
And so it is also that summer is nearing its end.
People start working, you may start training again, and then you need to drink plenty of water.
And why drink out of glass when you can do it in a slightly more fun way?
And taste.
-Check this out.
Look how fun this is.
[Laughing to be done]
There are over 25 flavors, we have lots that are here in front.
I want to test this "sweet coconut".
[Jonas] But you!
I changed the taste now ... Winter apple, what is the difference between winter apple and regular apple?
So then it is with cinnamon and stuff in!
Apple and cinnamon ... like a little ... -Fan what a cozy!
Oh!
Apple pie!
-I get smelling?
Mmm!
Smell Coconut.
You are!
It smells creamy.
I'll test it so we'll see ...
Mmm, "Sweet Coconut", I recommend it.
And this is how it is: we have a code for you now,
It's JLC10, so you get ten (10%) percent discount.
So click on the link in the description,
Go in and treat yourself to a bottle.
Drink water!
You forget it.
You have to drink more water.
And the code is valid for fifth (5) September.
It cannot be combined with other offers ... so.
Go to the link in the description and see if something is right for you.
Listen to this then.
Back to the Rutch Canoes.
Who wants to go with Strawberry?
[Lucas] But you go together.
Yes.
[Lucas] -Co it.
It does not matter.
-Why?
No, but do you.
You should not sit two so big in these.
Because you go into the wall.
Three, two one ... drive!
[They sing] "'Cause Tonight Will Be The Night That I Will Fall For You"
We take .... Oh damn!
[Cry]
No no no!
[Laughter behind the camera]
AJ my wrists!
[Niclas] It was exactly as you said Lucas!
[Laughter] aj ... aj ... aj ...
[Laughter] Aj my wrists!
[Laugh]
We are at the final!
No I won't go there.
Oh damn!
-Here, take this one and film out there.
Should I go first then?
-Yes, do you want it?
Yes.
-You, if you want it.
Ah but ... -do you keep it?
Yes I thought so.
-Oh my God.
This was much scary than ... -drive hard Lucas!
Yeah!
[From the picture] -You probably survive.
Yes drive, probably anyway.
It feels like I'm falling backwards ... [behind the camera] Oh my God ...
[Behind the camera] I love you!
Lucas!
[Voice in the background] "Three, Two, one ..."
[Carl, cut] Oh damn!
... ...
[Loudly] Oh!
What a shock!
Hell!
I just disappeared!
So in myself!
Hell what it was going on!
Ah but in the beginning you know, the hand stopped and the body went down,
So I probably didn't get it on the camera ...
Oh I get shaky ... Satan!
Should I drive now?
[Carl] -come again now Jonas, should I run last?
Yes.
[Laughs] "Yes" you say?
How does it feel?
Oh fuck what scary.
-It's just back with your head and breathing.
Lucas solved it gallantly, he's down there waiting for you.
Here we go!
-Come again Jonas!
I love you!
Oh fuck.
[Voice in the background] "Three, Two, one ..."
[Lucas laughs] -Oh gentlemen!
Aaaah!
It's just small!
And my legs!
[Lucas] Surely it is shaky now?
-If i'm shaking yes?
This one was ball but not so fun.
The first two seconds so you think you are almost dying
It just gets completely white and black and ...
It feels like you are falling right down!
-Yes!
Yes Yes.
That you are going down in some fucking concrete lump type.
Oh fuck.
This doesn't feel good.
Oh damn, I'll be vomiting.
[Voice outside] ready?
-Yes!
[Inaudible]
... ...
Oh damn!
Woah!
Lets go home!
Lets go home.
AAAAAH!
Surely it was sick?
-Yes I hate this damn shit!
Shaky in the legs?
They were on and say they would push and not push me away,
And fucking and opening the door and then I said that "do you do it then, then I faint and spit"!
But do you feel shaking in your legs now or?
"Kobra" was the more fun, this one was not fun.
But do you know what is good anyway?
-That you have done it?
Aaa, and that it goes so fast that you don't get what happens.
-Yes!
No I know!
The first thing you think when you go down BA:
"Damn how fast it goes" and then it is very soft ...
[Screams] Yes!
YES!
-Yes and it just gets black and white and ...
Ah Fy Fan ... -I'm shaking.
I got such a kick when I came down, you were not there then.
I told Jonas "Yes!"
-No you didn't, you pray "Now we go home!"
"Now we go home, now we go home!"
-As he?
[Mimic Carl] "Nah! Now we go home! Jonas, I don't want to be involved in this, now we go home!"
After that came the kick and then I said "Yes!"
A day at Skara, it was as you said Calle.
It was much more fun than I thought it would be.
[In chorus] Yes.
You think so "Rutchkana" but damn it ... and it's zero sponsored collaboration.
I think it was fucking fun.
Do you know what I think ... -Stort thanks to Skara Summerland for being here.
They have let us be here and have some fun.
-Really.
Do you know what I think?
-No?
Don't forget to give a thumbs up and comment, but ...
I think it was so damn fun to go to the US, the biggest amusement park and the biggest water park.
[In chorus] Yes.
-And big thanks to our lifeguards,
Adam and Rickard.
-No problem!
Thanks for the help!
You know what?
Now you have to shower huh?
-Yes!
[Laugh]
Subtitles: Alice Skårbratt