Good morning!
Goood morning!
-God morning, good morning, good morning
[Singing] "Good morning world, here I come!"
Oh what an echo it is!
[Vocalizes]
"B-B-B-B-Borka B-B-Borka" [vocalizes]
Welcome to you should be to today's section where we run blind dating.
Here will be girls who are going to blind dating a guy sitting behind that protection
And the guy who will sit on the other side today, it's Andreas-
-A tictoker from Malmö.
Well it is not.
Niklas, it's you.
-Yes!
You're going to blind dating today.
You are the one who is going to sit there.
-Japp.
[Silent laughter]
This is so good pranks.
-Boom!
We prank.
-Prank channel.
First we took you there with the camper ... -Yes yes.
Then Niklas went on it.
Soon he will come in again with an ax and threatens Niklas.
[In chorus] just that.
Because it's his brides.
We will react to this.
-Ah.
We have no idea how the blind dating has gone for Niklas.
-No.
Anton who helped film this has cut this together as a draft and we will see how the hell is.
You and I, Lucas, we ... -went in and masturbated yes.
In another room, so we didn't see this.
-No what it was wrong.
On each other.
This, we may say is a little fiveish thing and what are the others called ...?
-Sidemen
But we hook it up, we test.
-Yes Yes.
They are so damn awesome at it so we, we test.
[Casted Voice] Fucking Copycat, that is.
Check out Nikla's reaction now.
No No Niklas.
Yes, drive!
So Niklas is a new single.
It's fun that Anton cut that music, because it's like Niklas never met a girl in his life
[Laughter] It sounded like Jönsson League.
[Hums]
Isn't it also like he is very happy and tear -eyed?
[Made up] "Should I?"
Have bought a car for Niklas.
You need to date.
Should I go on blind dating?
Do you know what the fun is?
Niklas has been involved in writing the questions.
[Himmar Niklas] "We must have really sick fucking questions!"
So Niklas, you can settle down there.
Anton will soon come and film all this.
What should ....?
Yes!
There will be lots of girls and you will date them.
One of these could be your future wife, Niklas.
I'm in shock ...
Sit there.
-Do I do this?
I was sweating now.
[Out of picture] Yes.
This is how it will work now: you ask these questions ...
Now check, the legs just bounce.
... and then based on their response, which is the worst, so you say "No, number Tres answers I don't like ..."
Disappear.
How to send her out.
So there is one left, and you have to marry it.
Oh, he jerks.
[Laughter, nonsense sound]
He couldn't keep up.
[LAUGH]
Looked like he was standing and toxin.
-No, but he probably did.
Now comes the brides.
-I just have to check.
What happened there?
[Laughter] does he piss?
Here comes the brides yes.
Here they come.
[Expectant music] -I can't cope.
He couldn't stay for three minutes.
Down there is Annie, she may recognize from Tiktok.
Also from Kungsbacka.
So is Niklas.
What the hell?
My name is Pamela, I am 20 years old and live in Stenungsund at the moment.
Hello!
Vanessa, 22, from Alingsås.
Caroline, 24 from Helsingborg.
Denise, 22 years old from Helsingborg.
Ellen, 24, lives here in Gothenburg.
Vilma, 23, comes from Gävle but lives in Gothenburg.
Angelica, but my friends say Angie, 22 years old and is from Alingsås.
Hanna, 20 ...
Angie?
Doesn't anyone say?
Are they saying Angie?
Isn't it more difficult to say?
I usually call Jolie it ...
Who is Jolie?
Angelina Jolie?
Angelina Jolie.
From Tranemo huh?
No!
Ambjörnarp.
Ljungsarp.
-Ljungsarp.
Before moving to Hollywood.
From Stenungsund.
And Annie, 23 from Gothenburg.
Okay, should I ask the first question?
What does our first date look like?
It was a very good question.
Activity.
Feel free to find something ...
Then maybe go ... -Why looks Niklas so damn angry?
So: [laughter]
No, but check, this is not a tagged date.
[Added] “Vafan do you say”
[Added] "Activity, are you stupid in ..."
Do you know what the fun is?
I think Niklas decided to be hard from the beginning.
I do not know what it is.
[Niklas says something outside the room] -Ye?
What did you say Niklas?
He is outside and panic now.
[Niklas] She fucking bitten my pants ...
A little funfact: He has brought one of the brides to the office now because they are together.
She is completely crazy and has broken his pants.
Has she broken her pants?
-Angie?
Try to leave her.
-She just jumps around.
Oh damn.
-It's always so at the beginning of a relationship Niklas.
Was it Angie he talked about?
-Yes.
Damn.
Now Stella has bitten..Ah ...
She can't calm down ...
Eat and eat, that's what I had to give.
-I would say we sit down at a bar.
Then we run a blue and white match at Ullevi.
Then maybe if it gets a little, ah ... feeling then maybe you go to a hotel room.
Have a little good or so maybe.
What did you say?
-A bar, blue and white and then hotel room?
Damn ... what a fucking date.
What does she mean by that?
Hotel room ... isn't it prayed there?
-They have bedded?
Do you care if it is bedded or not?
What are you saying?
It is well bedded for ... sex?
[Made] but hotel rooms, is there a flat-screen TV?
[Talking in the mouth] -It is bedded for it ...
[Himmar Lucas] hotel room, then it is bedded ...
It is very straightforward if you say so.
-Do you never stay in a hotel?
Have they bedded there or?
-It's sheet and everything then or?
Blue -white and ... damn what she was driving there.
-Do you know what I think too?
You must have a pretty good budget on that date.
After all, several thousand go there.
I would say that ...
He is skeptical!
[Laughs] Blue White ... hotel room ...
Everyone gets giggled and Niklas will be so:
[LAUGH]
Well, when we drive.
That we play paddle or bowels,
And then out and eat but there will be no hotel room first ...
Okay number four.
We would sit down on some shy hook, take a bee,
And maybe play billiards afterwards.
Casual as well.
Number five.
No, but I think we go to some cool bar,
And order ... are they alcoholics?
Hole bunch?
-Why does it look like Niklas wants to shoot himself in the head every time they answer?
He is backwards.
He doesn't want to talk about alcohol.
Why doesn't he smile?
He looks very happy.
-He is nervous.
Look at him.
-He is nervous yes.
He sweats.
-Or is this Niklas when he's happy?
... orders drinks for each other.
A little fun to see what you have for a drink the first date I think.
Number six.
I'm probably thinking ... -
Drink flavor?
So, I order a Bloody Mary for you.
Well, it's not that it's an ice .. -Then it must be really sick drinks.
It is if anyone pulls ten Long Island, then maybe you are like this "you and I" but about anyone ...
But if anyone chooses gin and tonic or rum and cola ...
No, but then I drink drinks ... -Va?
[Giggle]
No, but I just drink if there is bedded.
No, but I don't date girls who don't drink Jägermeister.
No, but I'm the opposite.
They don't drink joluca ...
Oh!
How lucky you had the lid on Calle.
Damn ...
Oh ... then Lucas had to clean here.
Should we let it go a bit now?
Damn what we pause.
Group dating with some of my friends and some of yours.
Either go out and take some drinks and maybe go out to the club,
If not, I probably would have liked to drive some tennis or paddle.
I had driven something sick so with a little pulse, a little Liseberg, Escape Room, such a fucking fun.
Ah, eight.
It is assumed then it is summer, but I enjoy bathing.
Everyone speaks Gothenburg.
[Gothenburg] "Likes and Bath"
... home and watch a horror movie.
Number nine.
I had probably said a classic bar round.
Just walk around and test different bars and drink drinks.
It must be alcohol involved.
-Yes absolutely.
Of these then, which one suits you best?
Me?
Yes, as the first date as well?
Number 22. -Yeah, I thought you meant what a girl.
[Laughter] No, no ...
[Made] You have a sandwich table in front of you, who do you take?
Which date do you think ... no, they have said what first date they want to go,
Which first date do you think sounds nice?
So eh ...
Blue -white and hotels sounded najs.
You know what.
Annie's date, that you bring poles.
Think it is great ... because then it will not be so "it is just you and me here" but you are a good bunch.
I can tan with my polar bear and they can tan, so.
So it is a top idea.
[In chorus] mmm.
I like it with the hotel room.
[Inaudible] -No you just want to sleep in a newly bedded bed.
Yes.
Is it bedded?
So a classic pub round.
-I have a question then.
I think it was number three who said bowla.
Is it true?
-I'm shit on it.
I have no other questions I think.
Number four said billiards.
-Tiljar, okay.
It's fine, that's fine.
-What did you do on the first date?
It depends on the person you meet, but preferably you do an activity.
Not bowling though, I hate.
Then I start by sending home number three.
Unfortunately.
-Bowling.
She from Helsingborg.
-Hon has thus taken the car from Helsingborg.
Niklas sends her out with her head before.
-I think it was I who sent her here.
She was so damn tagged.
I think she was the most tagged in the conversation.
"It's going to be so damn fun," she said.
-Seven hours in the car she sat.
She was in for three seconds.
-Mm.
Just because she happened to say bowling.
Thanks anyway!
Lucas, you like to bowl.
-Ah.
I am engaged.
-It doesn't matter, it's just bowling.
Yes we can do that.
[In chorus] mmm.
I don't mean to bowl ... are you going to bowl with her?
Yes?
-Yeah?
[LAUGH]
Hello!
-Hello.
Do you regret your choice?
Eh ... no I don't.
But we drive next.
What the hell Niklas?
Damn what sad.
-He looked at her ...
He checks from the top down.
I don't think that was the point, he thought ... -No it wasn't.
This is what I mean, I think Niklas wants to be a little hard here.
It is good.
-That's really good.
Oh!
That's damn good.
But it's a little ... a bit stiff huh?
No, fuck.
-Next.
Drag your best ragging replica.
Oh fuck.
I just say a basic here but give me one more chance then on the next.
Are you google?
Because you are exactly everything I am looking for.
Okay...
When I pick up the most eye contact and so "hey how nice you are".
"Maybe you want a shot?"
[Laughter] -What did she say?
Was it ragging?
They are too cute.
It was still a bit of fun so:
"Ah I think you're fine, do you want a shot?"
[Laughter] You can't do that everywhere.
Say you are single, someone comes up to you, a cute girl:
[CONTAINED VOOK] "Hello you're fine, you want a shot".
You just had: Yes! "
It had easily worked.
-Yes Yes!
It's shit charming.
-Yes.
"You're fine, you want a shot".
When she ordered two, peel her, take her shot too, I got two.
When in world history a girl has gone to a guy and said "you're fine, do you want a shot?"?
Does it really happen?
-Number two has done it a lot of times.
Do you think so?
-Yes that can probably happen often.
It feels like you do it if you are properly packed.
Had I been single, I would have been the worst at picking up.
Incredibly bad.
-Rag me once.
It's a penny now.
Sit there.
I am a bartender.
Should you have raw juice?
[Light voice] I'm so damn horny!
[Laughter] -What did he say?
Horny?
Huh?
-You stand with the bartender?
I do not know why...
I thought she was there, it is three o'clock at night ...
We start over.
-Okay.
Then it was a raw juice for you here.
-Yes thank you.
Well can yes beat me down here?
[CONSIDERED VOOK] Okay.
What did you say?
-Okay.
I think you are incredibly nice.
Your beard, how thick it is.
Eh ... may I offer something to drink?
Yes, I want a tequila sunrise.
Do you want a tequila Sunrise?
Does she say so?
Is that the first thing ...?
"Do you want something to drink? Yes a Tequila Sunrise" [laughs to]
I thought she likes it.
Is it Conchita Wurst?
- Mmm.
Imagine your fucking beard.
Had I met a girl with that beard ...
Imagine what a beard, but also think which cock.
Okay....
We are on the second question.
-Number four.
Tjena biscuit, do you stand there and crumble? [Giggle]
I can't pick up unfortunately, that's why I'm here.
That was a good answer.
-Number five, eh ...
I also run without words I think, I like eye contact,
Preferably long eye contact.
Napa -07 thus.
... chemistry I think, then we take the talk from there.
Number six, there is absolutely no ragging replica really.
It's just too "corny" I think.
So it's a small rhyme: roses are red, violets are blue.
If I want a Birkin- do you buy it then?
Oooh.
-Najs, then you got a bag on the purchase.
Number seven then, I can run a ragging replica.
Birkin is a piss -expensive, which Loy got.
Bag for 400 thousand.
-Yeah it's still charming.
I would say that too.
First date.
Birkin.
-Ah.
Did we go to the same school?
Because I can swear that we have chemistry.
It was a bit good huh?
-It was good!
So kind of so: "I've lost my number, can I have yours?"
So so.
I also have no ragging replica, I run a lot of eye contact.
Maybe a little boring, but it seems to work anyway.
...or not.
-Wh that goes?
We know Niklas.
Who is going?
Do you know what? "I've lost my number, can I have yours?"
But at least it is a ragging replica.
But is it a little smart anyway?
Yes it is great, it is a classic ragging replica.
I think five people go.
I think five or one.
I think five is for ... the others were very laughing but she was like that:
She felt a little adult.
-Very adult.
I think Niklas is looking for something more ... -He likes children.
[LAUGH]
I thought they were good, most.
Then I send ... I can't remember what number.
Four or five.
The biscuit line.
Well, Denise, nice.
-It was the second Helsingborg citizen?
Yes I do.
Typical.
-Nelest time maybe biscuits work.
What "I do"?
-He regretted.
He said yes.
Damn how fast he was there!
It felt like a Niklas bride.
-Ioke hair color.
Why is everything going so fast here?
They ask no question except "Do you regret your choice?"
"yes!"
I think it's nervousness.
-Yes, nervousness.
They just want to go from there.
Appearance?
Blonde, 25 years, like to sport ...
Gym cod preferably, I like to work out.
-She looked stiff.
I like blonde guys, so I'm not so ... the look doesn't matter that much, but a little long-
Blonde guys.
Does she know that it is Niklas on the other side?
We had printed that the guy is blonde.
Advantage for her.
Smart girl anyway!
Longer than me, nice lips and nice eyes.
It is important.
Number five.
Scandinavian look, preferably longer than me.
I'm 1.71.
Blue eyes I think is nice.
-Scandinavian appearance?
Femman has very clear requirements.
-Yes, preferences.
Could that be why she is single?
You have to think what you want, but it limits ... -very specifically.
You limit most of the world.
It feels like she has very high demands.
You recognize that in people who are singles with too high demands, they never meet anyone.
You have to lower the garden a little.
Uppercut.
-Red in the kidney.
I like long guys, preferably over 1.90.
-There it happened.
It's a plus, but no dealbreaker.
They may like to have brown hair,
I have blond hair myself so don't think it's as-sexy with someone who looks like me.
He will send her now.
-Thered broad -axled.
It is also a plus at the edge.
I'm not so picky, so I would say nice eyes ...
Get a good burn for the summer ... tattoos are najs.
It is this classic.
"I'm not so picky ... but preferably nice eyes ..." -"Good pigment, tattoos"
Yes exactly.
[LAUGH]
Money, housing ... -Abs.
[Added] "can imagine skipping cohabitation agreements"
"23 Slak"
"Contacts ..." Yes, just that.
I think he will send Annie now, number 6. -I
It described the opposite of Niklas.
I think he likes number seven.
I usually meet short guys, actually, but ...
It is nice if they are long too but,
Blonde or brunette does not matter, but preferably bright eyes.
And preferably tattoos.
Yes, preferably some tall guys.
Preferably not below 1.80.
Nice eyes, preferably tattoos, and preferably good clothing style too.
I think it is important that he can dress.
Hair color has probably become brunette but it is not very important.
Which number was the last?
Oh!
-Do I just say a thing?
If you want to talk about this with length, then there is no guy ...
If guys would say they liked tall girls,
Then it becomes more discriminatory to the girl than it is if girls say so about guys.
Yes.
-Are you involved in what I mean?
You do not set length requirements on a girl.
But it is done fanimej on guys all the time.
Is it that the guy should not be shorter than the girl huh?
It looks fun.
[Laugh to] Yes it does ... maybe.
[Giggly] isn't that ...?
-If a girl is 1.90, should she only meet two -meter guys then?
Ah exactly.
-Yes unfortunately.
No, I'm kidding, it doesn't matter.
-Yes then it will be.
But I think it is very common for the girl not to want the guy to be shorter.
I would have had to take notes if I were to sit in there.
You liked long guys, and I don't know if I'm going to expos myself but I'm not over 1.80.
So there will be a damn problem here.
-You aren't that tall or?
No I'm not that long, no.
But it's okay, you don't have to be so long.
Only you are longer than me, okay?
How tall were you?
-Number one, I'm 1.70.
You may have dug your own grave there.
Or I'm just kidding, it goes well whatever you are.
What is your type?
-What my type is?
I don't have any kind if they are blondes, brunettes, red -haired or whatever, it doesn't matter.
Preferably shorter than me.
However, I have met people who are as long as me so it is not very dangerous.
But then just ... -He sounds a little nervous.
[Mimics Niklas] The guy!
But she seems too nice, number one.
She seems absolutely incredible.
She was a little late too.
[Mimic girl 1] "Yes I drove around ... Dududu"
I saw her that she ran around there everywhere ...
... and look like this:
"There you are!"
"You may be longer than me, doesn't matter"
If you do not have humor, then I do not know if we will click.
I will send number nine.
Hello!
Wilma.
-Hello.
Nice.
Do you regret your choice?
-Yes I do.
Is it something you really don't want to do in bed?
Gosh!
-Number one.
Yes there are actually quite a lot of things but one thing I absolutely won't do is ...
There are the second hole.
Absolutely not.
What is going on?
-This is a little hard to look at.
What the hell is happening?
-No I need a coffee I think.
[Laughter] Now when she said the second hole ... "Well I get to take a cup"
Damn what sick .. I think it was Niklas ... -Yes it was Niklas who came up with that question.
The funny thing was that the day before ...
It was the same day before the recording we were in the office and went through questions,
Then Niklas said: "It must be raw!"
[CONTINUED VOOK] It must be the sickest fucking questions then!
-Bdsm.
He dug his own grave a little there.
-Do you have a cup?
Are we going to?
-Yes.
Then we were back with a cup in our hand.
Absolutely not, think it is really-sonajs.
Yes it depends on a little who it is with,
If it is with someone you are comfortable with,
There is some stuff you may not want to do with someone you are not comfortable with.
It depends on a little but yes, it is kind of that you said.
Number five.
Yes, no fight, no kind, I don't like to take that.
And don't give.
-Do Riml-feel anyway?
I like to jump that.
Okay number six.
What does she mean?
Speech on ... or?
-Yes but some ... some ... eh ...
Some people drive damn hard.
But no fight?
-It had been totally sick after all.
[Laughs] You lie with a girl ... -Fear take a neck swing on her.
No, but it was reasonable.
-Yes.
So tail sex and fights on the first three.
Spontaneously, I think it feels uncomfortable to answer this question as I haven't seen you yet.
A little early stage.
There are things I don't like, but ...
You will know that if you are so fortunate, I think.
Number seven then ... you have to explore it a little yourself.
-Good answer.
But I would never drive anal.
[Girl] anal?
Nah.
Feet go away.
No foot fetish here.
It was exciting answers.
I send number six home.
Ouch.
Hello!
Annie.
Do you regret?
-Yes I do.
But I think like this: Aj .... Oww.
I thought Niklas would be tough and say that he does not regret his choice all the time.
He regrets everyone except the first.
-Yes no it was a little ...
But Annie's answer was good after all.
Annie's response ... but,
It was so: "If you are lucky so".
But maybe it was not a straight answer either.
For the others were really like that: "This I don't like"
Is it perhaps that Niklas does not appreciate star sex then?
We slept together in Berlin after all ...
Right.
Then he took ... -then it was he who was on you.
No, we were sleeping together.
-Oskar.
[Mumbles] YES ...
Who is your Swedish free pass?
A celebrity in Sweden as well.
How many will say Joel Kinnaman ... Zlatan?
-Zlatan I don't think anyone will say.
Don `t you think so?
-No.
Isn't he good looking?
- In other words...
I don't think you think of Zlatan as a free pass.
Or do you do it?
- Yes, I think so.
It probably does many.
Joel Kinnaman, Zlatan or Persbrandt.
Some of them will come up.
-I think it's some of the Skarsgårds.
Bill Skarsgård can probably come up.
I think that too says.
-He is not ugly.
I think so too.
I am loyal, so there are no free passes for me if I am to be completely honest.
But since I am single, I would say Viktor Leksell.
He is nice.
She is beautiful.
Number two yes, I have one and his name is Oliver Strige.
No, but huh?
Strige!
-Weah!
Are you kidding me!
-Stige!
What the hell ... -But wait now here, isn't that a little too reasonable?
Isn't that a little too close ...?
Yes he is from Gothenburg ... but we talk about Zlatan and Skarsgård and ...
Strige?
[In chorus] yes?!
The funny thing is that both Viktor and Strige are from Gothenburg.
They have their free passes in the same city!
-In the same city yes.
It is icy after all.
Oliver Strige we can say that we feel very good.
It was a little fun that he came to talk.
-Yes it was a little ...
But he is not ugly.
He is shitty.
Really, but also very busy.
So there it happened.
Number five.
Yes but ... Danny Saucedo, he is nice to watch.
Yes would not drive a free pass but Joel Kinnaman ...
Now he does not live in Sweden, but he is Swedish.
Eight.
Benjamin Ingrosso.
Oh!
Yes of course.
Yes, catty.
Who is your free pass?
-Are you kidding?
Bianca Ingrosso then.
[Giggle] I knew it!
Then we match a little.
-Okay,
I choose to send home ... I think it was number five.
Danny Saucedo?
-No!
Then I send home the one that was before.
No!
He changed.
-Do you regret?
Eh, no I don't.
[Upset] No but I can't cope!
-"Ah okay..."
Everyone is very nice and cute after all.
[Done] in its own way!
I think everyone is really nice!
-Yes, but ...
He must be honest.
-He can't say he regrets all.
You get a little pain in the heart.
-Yes.
Such a sad guy ... -No!
Was she sad there?
Yes...
What is your favorite body part of a partner?
Obviously, the heart is most important to me.
But otherwise to look at except face then ... [giggle] the cock.
So I would say the stomach.
Or back.
Number five.
-Beer stomach.
If you do not choose the face, it may be ... happens.
Arms and hands.
Same here if you can't say face then it is happening or back.
Number eight.
So we did not say that you could not say face so I will say eyes and hands I think.
Quite straight answers.
-What is your favorite on the girl then?
My favorite body part ... I'm weak for nice legs.
May I say ... mm.
Did he say Lena Ben?
-No, fine.
Unfortunately, I will send home number five.
"I'm weak for Lena Ben ..." -HE, Ella.
Hello.
—Do you sing your choice?
No, I do not.
-Okay [giggle]
Niklas!
-What is your fetish?
Three left now.
-If you now have someone.
Number one here.
Frankly, I actually have no fetish.
I think it's najs when lying in bed and someone is behind and breathing one in the neck.
But it's not a fetish, I have none.
Like this.
Check it out.
[Groaning silently]
Did you get goose?
- Yes it was ...
Also have no fetish.
Number seven, by the way.
But if I have to say something then when the guy is good at taking command, have some good confidence.
[Barsian] Now you take the disk I tell you!
[Laughter] and then so ...
[Laughter] And after that you cook or!
And then we jump in the chamber!
A little hybris maybe.
Number eight.
My students will see this ... when you are a little hard -handed maybe.
-Teacher?
But damn ... why are you looking into the camera like that?
When you said that.
-Is she teacher?
[Mimics] "My students will see this ... a little hard -handed maybe?"
Surely she is not a preschool educator?
[Laughter] No I don't know ... -But she's a teacher you know.
Okay are you going on this then?
Ah ... -a little hard.
Not so hard.
-Are you?
Niklas got giggled!
-Dududu ... so!
Nice!
-Shiiiit.
This is difficult, but I send home ... the panting in the neck there.
One.
"Panting in the neck" ...
Hello!
Pamela.
Do you regret?
-Yes I do.
See you certainly some other day.
-Yes we do that safely.
What is required for your parents ... -come again now!
He is a little golden boy.
I flush back a bit.
-Winga Niklas!
What is required for your parents to like me?
Big cock.
-Okay number seven then.
I think it's kind of treating me well and having a good job type.
Dad is so: "Good job".
For me, it is most important that my nephews like you.
And if you are good with children, you go home as well.
-FIN response.
But my mom, she is very easy.
So humor, type.
But the most important thing is that my siblings like you.
I heard something with nephew, want children, I think?
Well!
No I said ...
I don't know how you look ... [laughter]
Well, he interpreted wrong!
-He haven't heard her.
"Want children? I don't know how you look?"
Like that's the problem.
They don't know each other.
She just talked about that ... what a wrong it was.
-Nephew.
It is therefore most important about my brother's children, ie my brother's arelands like you.
I spend a lot of time with them.
They are a very big part of my family as well.
So you are a family -like person?
-Yes.
It's important, it's good.
First, what did you say again?
-I said my dad likes a guy with good humor.
My mom is pretty easy to be taken with,
She changed now!
-As she?
She said Dad said good job?
-Yes exactly!
"Good job and treat me with respect," she said.
And just because she changed and family "yes humor, family, mom ..."
[Made] Yes and that everyone is the same and safe in the family!
And that you like brother's kids.
She has no nephews.
-I am a little family girl so.
Changes altogether.
[Made] and I love short blonde guys ... so.
I have dogs so it's important that they like you.
But they are kind, so ... -How many then?
My dog just bit his pants.
I've made my choice.
I send the dogs home there, number seven.
He doesn't want dogs.
-I like cats.
Hello!
Hanna.
Do you regret?
-Eh, no.
[Screaming to] -she was a little shocked?
She couldn't take it.
"Do you regret? No. [Dramatic Inhalation]"
What happened there?
He said he didn't regret it.
-She was shocked.
Didn't you see her mine?
-Take about it again, what the hell happened there?
Hello!
Hanna.
Do you regret?
Eh no.
[Shocked sound]
[Dramatic sound] Aaah!
Starting to run around ... [laughter]
"Do you regret? No. [Dramatic sound]"
[High sound] -she couldn't take it.
Damn, she expected him to say yes, maybe.
There is only one left.
No ... It wasn't good.
It will be such a Big Reveal now.
There is only one left now, so we can see who it is.
Hi, Angelica.
-Niklas, do you get a hug?
Yes, the very good.
-Hello.
“Yes giant Äre”
I was so nervous, I thought I would work today!
I'm totally shaky.
Niklas thought it would be another guy there.
I called a Andreas ...
You really went like this and I thought "Damn what unpleasant"
It was because Lucas said I would not look at the girls.
I just: "Why not look at the girls?"
Our employees must not look at the brides.
What was you called again?
-Angelica.
Angelica.
And where are you from?
-Alingsås.
And how old are you?
-I'm 22.
And you?
-24, turns 25.
They said slightly different ages.
I know, they just tried to fool me.
-26.25, 24 ...
So I was fooled.
-They were cheated.
Are we doing outro today or?
-Yes!
You can make an outro.
-Thank you for looking!
Farewell!
Now it will be a date, type.
One left, and you have to marry her.
Swedish subtitle: Alice Skårbratt alice@skarbratt.se