--Ulf, do you have to eat in bed?
-I'm hungry.
But crab ...?
Tord fills evenly on Friday.
I have started a collection for a gift.
We put three bucks per person.
It is much nicer with string panties, and you do not have the edge of faith.
It is very sexy with string, but Kristina does not like it.
"It's not nice, it's uncomfortable."
I think you feel fresh.
Well you, it's a party in my cap.
Party.
-Do you work here?
-No.
- I will not buy anything.
-It's not that easy.
I have bought some meat and vegetables.
- I take your basket ... - no!
What is your boss called?!
-Whats happening here?
That is my basket.
- No, you have your own.
It is full of onions.
I don't want onions.
- Then you have to put it back yourself.
-Yes exactly.
These are my goods.
Have you paid for them?
It is the one who pays the goods that gets them.
This is ...
Okay.
You get them.
Congratulations!
Damn...
- The worst what he got angry.
–445 kr.
SEK 445
Excuse me!
This was going crazy.
This is your goods.
Yes exactly.
You are welcome.
- Damn...
-I'm sorry.
Can you forgive me?
- I thought it was hidden camera.
–20 kr.
- There was a difference.
- Can't I have a hug?
-No.
So.
- Did it go good to shop?
- I've been shopping since I was ten years old!
- You bought a lot of onions.
- It was well on the list.
It's just onions.
YES!
Onions are good!
What a fucking coffee!
Why did you become a police officer?
You are not directly built as a police officer.
You are a girl, so it can't be easy to throw through the system.
-I was a course at the Polish Academy.
- Yes, but why did you become a police officer?
I wanted to make an effort.
I have a high moral perception -
- And stable psyche.
Mom and Dad were police officers and grandfather were police chief.
-And you?
- I didn't get into the hairdressing line.
No, now I break the ice!
We have been riding this bus together for several years ...
I have been riding this bus for six years and I just want to say that ...
... My name is Marit.
Hello!
-Hello!
What's your name?
- Bengt.
I recognize you.
We have gone here every morning.
Hello!
Hey what's your name?
Yes, my name is Marit anyway.
Hello!
I think you should talk to each other.
- Or how, Bengt?
We are quite close to each other because we go the bus every day.
Maybe we should play a game?
It usually lightens up.
What should we play ...?
The whisper, maybe?
Surely everyone can?
Then I whispers something to you, Bengt.
What should I whisper ... yes!
-I can not hear what you're saying.
- Morning time has gold in Mund ... no!
No, what a crazy!
Now I said out loud what to whisper.
Maybe we should sing something instead?
What do you say about it?
The English fleet has been sifted at Vinga
Oh Boy, Oh Boy, Oh Boy!
A thousand little sailors that we are going to expose
Then we will be delighted at Liseberg with Charlie, Pete and Tom ...
Hello Hello!
What it was empty on the bus today.
Tut!
-What are you doing?
- I honed.
- What are you on your head?
- A strut.
- Why do you have a strut on your head?
- I thought of having fun.
- It wasn't fun.
-No...
- Then I'll take it off.
-Yes do it.
- It got a little wrong, Carita.
- Yes, it was.
- Then I don't bring this up either?
-No.
Then I don't.
-Hello.
- Do you want to talk about the meaning of life?
- It only takes a minute.
- We are envoy from a higher power.
- We have a message to you.
No thanks.
I'm not interested.
We want to testify to a savior who can do wonders.
His name is Satan.
We are from the Swedish Satanist Church and you will soon switch to us.
No thanks.
We respect it, but give you this brochure in four -color pressure.
He knows where you live.
Satan, Satan, Satan
I want to elevate your name
You are the king of the dark you are the prince of my life
It started with ... shortness of breath, although I have learned to handle it.
The worst is the migraine.
It can last two days in a row.
I believe that confrontation therapy -
- Is the best way for you to avoid the symptoms.
Yes ... it's silly, but I have itching too.
Nothing is silly here.
We all have our phobias.
You can't have it like this.
Do you feel prepared?
Can we bring in the FOBI subject?
Yes.
You can look at him.
- A beer would be good!
- Now it goes too fast!
Where is the hockey?
Calm down, calm!
He is still in the cage.
I came to think of a funny story.
It was a Norwegian ...
You should travel away for a couple of weeks?
Sin!
I am looking for a substitute.
It is difficult to find one with your skills.
-I have a suggestion.
Here is Koko.
- A monkey, I see.
A chimpanzee.
He can take over your job without any notice.
- I make my job better than a monkey.
- It may stand for you.
Here is Coconut CV.
Nice testimonials from both Skansen and Kolmården ...
- It's an unusually intelligent monkey?
- No, it's a regular monkey ...
... but he is younger than you, so he learns to run about you.
- You have no other options?
- Yes - this plant.
- He can achieve the same results.
- You think that?
You are more mobile, but when it comes to intelligence he gives you a match.
We would do a market analysis.
You have apparently been replaced.
I have got a better employee.
I'm going to work with this cup.
Okay.
Then we will leave you in peace.
I'll give you a log-in.
Shall we continue?
Should we try to release him?
-No.
- We try.
Ugh, I don't know ... if I'm ready.
- We make a small attempt, just.
-Okay.
Hm Hm Hm ...
You didn't say he would hum!
Do you think you can say something to him?
Stop humming!
I remember when my dad picked up the boat ...
It was a holiday for us young.
We had a green boat.
Military service - or lump as one often says -
- Has all we will be able to do together.
This is where we guys become men.
It is a hard and demanding time -
- But also a period filled with happy laughter and male community.
The humor on the door is known for its must and burlesque tone ...
... I understand.
But the purpose of the lump is to prepare us men for war.
War is a hell -
- So we were going to illustrate what you can be exposed to on the battlefield.
Rifle shot
- Set, soldier!
The enemy is sifted.
- The Russians come from all directions.
You have to fight for the motherland!
War for the crown!
POP MUSIC
It's an old band ... but this is how it can be.
- River, we pray for the food first.
-Sorry.
So!
Now it will be good with sausages.
You should feel what it is like to be exposed to a grenade attack.
- Inserting grenade!
- It's the most dangerous bombs!
- Duck, soldier!
- It's fire and powder!
They write a lot about people who make class trips, but never where they travel.
I've made a shit cool class trip.
At nine I was in Sala silver mine.
It is quiet in the field today.
We have to sneak so the Germans don't see us.
Soldier!
Now I see the goal for our mission - "Örnnästet".
- There is the secret Nazi gold hidden.
-Fast!
Jump into the jeep.
-Wait for me!
I sit down.
-Okay, now we drive.
There has been a lot of violence today-
- But in peacetime, life on the door can be cozy.
We are going to cut with a game that is very popular in the lump.
- Torbjörn, you bought a cinnamon bun?
-Yes.
If everyone comes here we will be in a ring around the bun.
Welcome!
I heard that you should call the man's genitals the "flute" in front of children.
Should you then say that you play a cumbling in the Municipal Music School?
Hello!
Hello.
Hey.
Everything about food recommended this - Italian.
-Exciting.
-Hello!
- Don't Jenny come with you?
-No...
- His new guy is with, huh?
-Yes.
My mobile rings!
- What is so special about that guy?
- They met in Paris.
- What romantic!
- We met in Vänersborg.
- He is a foreigner.
- I hate foreigners.
It is so hard if he cannot Swedish.
Then everyone can speak English.
You come?
Good!
Hello.
- They are on their way by taxi.
- What romantic, and Danish!
- Danish?
- Yes, he's Danish.
Is he from Denmark?
It's a difference!
Jeg Snakker Danish.
I'm basically Danish.
Tuborg!
It is Bandidos, Kristina, and Mul- and Klövsyge ...
–OEDE POENS ... --... with Floede.
- We should probably contact the headquarters.
- Yeah.
- The hike to the bakery.
- Bagarn here.
- We remain on the corner.
Come.
- The prevailing situation?
- Inbaked Vesuvio.
Come.
- You mean Calzone?
-That is correct.
-Roger.
-Over and out.
Why don't you use the usual codes?
Is traffic intercepted?
Yes, it's kind of ... eavesdropped.
- A calzone.
You are welcome.
-Thanks!
It went away.
Can you look yourself for a while?
- This was delicious!
-Yes indeed.
- Prosciutto we spoke in Italy.
- Yes, in Rome we ate it.
Mads!
The Danish television program Murder Commission ...
–... og taxi ... –Yes, og hotel.
We have all these programs here in Sweden.
We see them.
That is why we are looking so good Danish!
- Lite more wine?
-No no!
Now wine is over!
Mads and I are going to drink old Danish!
And Tuborg.
- Don't we have old Danish?
- No, but stuff like that green ...
- Green Tuborg, Mads!
Hvergang!
- No, Midori is called.
It's a melon liqueur.
- You bought it.
I haven't bought any melon liqueur.
It was you - not yes!
No, for the pile!
Melon liqueur, hell ...
- Mads speaks seven languages.
--Ikke completely refugee.
- Seven language!
What a guy!
- Swedes speak many languages.
I myself speak English, Swedish, German and Danish.
There are four languages.
Jeg Snakker Five Languages: Swedish, English, German, Danish and Åland.
- Active is not a language.
-Yes.
- Magnus and Ulf, do you speak Danish?
- We have a good time Danish all evening.
-No...
–For Hillvete!
We're talking Danish now.
- No, it's not Danish.
- Hold so jaw, Mads!
- Ulf!
- Ulf, put down!
- Hold Shy!
-Stop!
- I joke with a Danish!
Oh, what a hard time!
We speak German instead.
You said that you could.
Das ist eine gute idee.
Nicht War?
--Ulf, is there more coffee?
- Kristina?
A little more coffee.
- Yes, of course ... do you want coffee?
-Yes thank you.
AULF?
-Yes.
Perfect.
Program text: Britta L Bergman (C) Swedish Television AB 2004
We are Roye
Come on now!
We your hvide
We stand the same, Side on Side
We stand the same!