Willy lives in this box.
It's my best friend.
It is a rice cake.
Oh, fuck!
Date: 2002–11–15.
Male, about 30 years, white, Caucasian origin.
Medium length, slightly overweight, lost muscles ...
... incipient flint, heavily soiled nails.
He has apparently lost control of gastrointestinal function.
Personal listing: You lose faith in humanity when you look like that.
The decay process has apparently been going on for a long time.
For God's sake - I'm trying to work.
There is some bastard who has bitten Willy.
Now they will close the post here as well.
Is there anything worse than the post office?
Chernobyl.
-Sorry.
Was it warm?
- Scolding.
- We have to lower the heat.
- Now it gets even warmer.
It is dear.
You seem to be quite clean in your hair.
We don't have to wash it.
Be so good and in the chair over there.
So you were relegated from Yvon Holm Hair Academy ...?
- It was so ridiculous.
- It was one of my test customers.
She claimed that she had a reduced sight since I had cut her.
Bullshit!
- She was blind to the eye before.
-Certainly.
You saw that.
And you?
Old man ...!
- What did it take to her?
- She had such an Ossis.
One of her test customers died.
Excuse me...
Hello?
May I help you?
With male voice: Hello.
Sir, I'm a woman.
Do you want to know the Meaning of Life?
-You have to navigate in a countryscape.
- Can I Ask You ...
--Is your TV set going?
–Yes, it's going very well.
Tie it!
-Hello?
-Ouch!
- Have you hurt yourself?
Hello.
I lay here in the bath and relaxed ...
Suddenly I got pissed off and relieved the pressure.
-In the bathtub?
God, be 'disgusting!
-Yes is not it?
It hurt a lot.
Suddenly I kissed my kidney stones.
Oh God...!
It must have hurt terribly!
Yes.
And I don't know ...
What do you do with such a thing?
Can you have it as an ornamental thing?
Yes.
I want the hair that Kajsa Bergqvist has it.
Do you know, then?
Absolutely!
She is very nice in her hair.
-Ouch!
-Sorry!
I was a little spent.
There is nothing visible.
- It bleeds.
-No problem.
Sit still.
-Take it away!
- I should burn the wound.
-It works.
- I know, but pick up a patch.
Well, damn ...!
-Serve something that is worse than P-fines.
- Relief cancer.
Thanks, please Ingvar.
You were the best plot we've had.
It was fun.
You can jokingly say: being the plot is like anal sex.
You penetrate a smoke -filled opening and empty your bag.
Okay.
Bye.
Thanks.
I need to drink hot.
I have a sore throat.
I have a cold.
It's hard when it runs.
I've got ... Witch milk.
Men can get it.
Milk -like liquid that comes out of the breasts.
- Milk out of the nipples?
- A milk -like liquid.
When I stimulate the nipple ...
Oh!
Yes, it's hard.
It fixes no brides.
No, but I'm trying to see it positively.
You can have it as a party trick.
It breaks the ice.
- Is it good with tea at sore throat?
-Yes.
And I stood for the milk.
I wanted to look like Kajsa Bergqvist!
She doesn't look like this!
- Lite she looks.
-No!
If she had cut herself here, so ... it will be SEK 350.
- I can sue you.
Damn pussy!
- We say 300 evenly, then.
This takes hours.
My wife who has dinner ...
Is there anything worse than an angry girl in the house?
Termites.
Half the plate should always consist of vegetables.
You can choose exactly what you want.
This should be for people with weight problems.
Only me is fat!
- Now we talk about our vegetables.
- Then I have a question.
- Is a biscuit chocolate a vegetable?
-No.
A composite meal should consist of carbohydrates, proteins and vegetables.
- carbohydrates are pasta, rice, potatoes.
- Then I have a question.
If you do not lose weight you get the money back?
I have gained weight since I started.
I have to get compensation!
- Have you gone down?
-A little.
- You have never been fat.
- Now we return to our plate.
- Two cooked potatoes ... - Do you get mazarin for the coffee then?
If you would like a mazarin for the coffee, you can always save points.
- Three glass of wine corresponds to a mazarin.
- Three tubs wine for a nasty mazarin!
- Needs have no law ... - you can exercise - it helps.
I'll have a mazarin!
What are you looking at, fucking anorectic?!
Hello, Elsa-Britta.
Now I am here.
NEMS LOOK!
Isn't it the home service with his pile and rosy cheeks?
- Yes, here I am.
- Now, little friend, you should help me.
There is a package of Topz.
And there hangs a crystal chandelier.
Take a topz and polish the crystal chandelier really well.
- I did this last week.
- Dustrious, yes.
Now you get another chance.
Now I have to say.
I do not have time.
I will visit many today.
Many people can't even get out of bed.
Lord Jesus, say as it is - that you wish I was dead!
Don't say so, Elsa-Britta.
Obviously I don't want you to die
Go, you.
Just go!
I'll probably do this, you will see.
No, Elsa-Britta ...
- I just go up here ... - no, it is not possible ...
I have to do it.
You fall and hit you.
There you go!
Clean it properly.
If it breaks, you will do with me!
-Have you understood?
-Yes I understand.
I love this person.
Look!
I love him.
-We made the Asia trip as planned.
- Walked in the Himalayas?
We flew to Sri Lanka and went on an elephant safari - in unexplored jungle.
Imagine your early morning, the animals come to life ... the sounds, the scents ...
- We were at High Chaparral this summer.
- It's not much to talk about.
No, but it was a great experience.
Big Bengt has built up an authentic western city.
Bank, Saloon, Sheriff's office - all!
Magnus, can you just go and rent an elephant and ride out in the jungle?
We did not ride ourselves - we had an elephant driver.
Incredibly skilled.
He ruled the elephant with small movements.
Rodeon at High Chaparral is fascinating.
The riders must have a hand in the air all the time.
It's full roll!
And the horse does everything to throw the rider.
- Tell the Himalayas.
- The flight in Nepal is not so good?
CRY
So it is if you want to come to the unique places.
When we went to High Chaparral, we have to change trains in Alvesta.
- A time wait.
- You can show the prayer wool?
We were in a Buddhist temple 4,000 m above sea level.
There Magnus bought this prayer wool from an old monk.
We also bought some stuff on the "chapp".
Unnecessary, Kristina thought, but I thought it was fun to have.
- Hands up, man!
- Check those signs.
Yiiiha!
I'm Big Bengt.
- This writing is not used today.
- hand up.
I'll blow your hate off.
I'm gonna kill you.
It's just for fun, Kristina.
Huh?
What are you saying?
Ulf is lying.
We haven't been to High Chaparral.
We haven't been there.
That's true, what Kristina says.
I've been lying here tonight.
We have never been to High Chaparral.
We have lived on a lie.
We haven't even been to Småland.
But one day, honey ... we're going there.
I promise you.
Ouch ouch ouch!
The Indians have shot me.
Indian devils.
Call 90,000.
I'm bleeding.
Ouch ouch ouch.
Surely the discount attracts many from the university?
Yes.
Researchers are better as customers in terms of creative freedom.
That's how it is.
You trust our expertise.
If we say you are good looking, you trust it.
- You have to trust people.
-Yes is not it?
-OUCH!
- Wanting, was it too hot?
- It was probably a little hot.
- Then we take it a little colder ...
- You were together with a scientist?
- The bear.
He was an economist.
He never cared about what he looked like in his hair.
He didn't want me to cut him.
What I was joking!
In the end he gave with him.
Old man ...!
- Doesn't she get well?
- It's a bit sensitive ... Jörgen died.
Very boring.
So!
Then you can sit in the chair.
Brokers and rock stars are allowed to go ahead in the queue.
But never sweeter!
Some teach their children to be afraid of sweeteners.
- Have any profession worse "cred" than sweethearts?
-Executioner.
I'm glad you came, Kristina.
I can not live without you.
I have missed you so much.
I do not get it...
I do anything for you to come back.
Say what you want me to do, I do.
Then I want you to cancel the cable TV subscription.
Then we get the evenings together without football.
If you want it, I can terminate cable TV.
Yes.
-Okay.
-Good.
It can be difficult - it is a year's notice period.
Telling it out now, we will be rid of it in a year.
I terminate Viasat Sport, and then we keep Canal Plus.
It's much more than just football.
But huh, damn, Kristina!
Why did you just choose cable TV?
I had to choose anything.
Because I love you.
I didn't think you would turn it to me.
It depends on ... Kristina ...
What do you work with?
I prepare an experiment that we will do in a particle accelerator.
- Do you feel for quantum physics?
- I forgot everything from high school.
We have many medicines here.
- We take 175 for them.
- Well, do they have an extra discount?
Yes, they can put on themselves.
Now it's finished.
So there it was.
It got good in the neck too.
Then I thank you for that.
–200.
- So it was said ... be so good.
Now you are soon on the run again.
Is there anything that spikes up more than coffee?
BEEP
THE DOORBELL RINGS
Hello.
I'm so sorry to wake you up.
In just Felt so lost and in needed some support.
I'm Lost in the Material World.
What do I do to become a good human being?
You have to learn how to navigate in a countryscape.
I'm so sorry, she is so ... material.
Are you sleeping?
-Did you sleep?
-Yes.
It was nothing special.
We'll take it tomorrow.
SVT program text: Ulla Zedigh Brenner
- I am going on a weekend now.
Have a good one.
- Can I borrow your rubber chicken?
Take it.
See you on Monday.