Shouldn't I cut myself soon?
You can wait a bit.
You fit in slightly longer hair.
Do you think?
Yes maybe.
I have a tip for you.
If you have a small slack wine left -
- So you can take an ice tray and freeze the wine.
Then you can use it for a wine sauce.
Yes, may she live, yes, may she live!
Congratulations!
A coffee maker?
We already have a coffee maker.
We needed a bigger one at work so I changed.
But this one works well.
- The funnel is broken.
- Yes, but you can fix that.
Such a weather rabbits ... Check out here!
Walk around with hanging ears, when it's so easy to lift in Estonia!
And cheap is.
- Is there any coffee?
-Yes soon.
One two three four!
Orange plupp chance.
What do the Scania call juice made on elderflower?
- Shelf juice, is that saying your mom?
- I have it on the tongue ...
- It's shelf juice!
- Are you from Skåne?!
No, you are from Flen!
- What do you answer?
-Say again.
What do the Scania call juice made on elderflower?
I have it ... what did mom say?
"Now you'll get a glass ..."
Mixed juice!
The correct answer is shelf juice.
Now we lost a plump!
Well done!
Well done.
What is the name...
Our question will go about!
I knew the answer!
You distracted me!
- Release that!
- What should I let go?
The cup?
Look now...
Well ... now we have spilled too, and lost the plump.
Are you happy now?
Are you happy?
First we lose, and then we spill.
Great!
Always when we play, we should spill and lose questions.
This was successful!
Your damn!
- Why are you drying up?
-It does not matter.
Wipe up after you, Ulf!
We start over, and change couples.
- Then I want to be with you.
- And me with Andreas.
Then I can still be with Kristina.
Thanks for that!
Ulf, I can't sleep.
Herb tea usually helps.
I have been drinking two cups.
If you do this ... you take a plastic bag.
Then you pour in contact glue.
You spray some glue in the bag.
And then you pull in the vapors.
Then you become very drowsy.
I do not know...
Drink a glass of warm milk, then.
Yes ... maybe I'll try it.
Do you see the old man?
He probably has problems.
- Is he drowning?
-I do not know.
What do you think?
I don't look at this distance.
I'm nearsighted.
I can read, but at a distance I look blurred.
It has come in recent years.
I have not been to the optician.
- You have glasses?
- No, lentils.
Get to see ... Yes, look!
- You hardly see them.
- No, that's the wrong strength.
It's actually a pretty bad optician.
It's sad ...
It's wrong you in the wrong place!
What are feminists against these magazines?
It's almost just girls in the pictures!
-What's that?
-A hate paw.
My happiness amulet.
It is important to have one.
I go nowhere without this one.
- It gives you lucky?
- Yes, maybe not in terms of brides ...
- It's pretty big to carry with you.
- It is worth it if it protects!
This is too sad!
Now Lundberg and Super sit again.
It's only a month since he lost the job!
Look!
Now he falls asleep over his bag with strong beer.
It hurts me.
You should do something!
Yes, go and get the strong beer, you.
Surely we have peanuts at home?
-How is it going?
- I feel like a treasure!
No, it's really nice.
Fresh.
I'm glad I smoke!
Imagine if I had sniffed.
Girls who sniff are as disgusting as guys baking!
I'll take these.
You there!
In the green bathing pants, yes.
Run and pick up my cig on the desk!
Otherwise, you may leave the bath.
- Now they are on the little kid again.
- The little thick?
Now they chase him!
- They are on him every day!
- He doesn't have it easy.
Now they hold him underwater.
- Children can be stupid.
- And no adult intervenes!
-Thanks.
- Do you offer?
-Hello!
I want to go by bus.
- Tjugo crowns, thank you.
- Can I get a ticket of you?
-Where!
Thanks.
Yeah ... Now we're probably running soon.
Anytime...
-How is it going?
- It almost feels like a uniform.
But if you unbutton a button?
Look, how nice it was!
All animals are equal, but some animals are more equal than others.
A quote from the animal farm by George Orwell, which we will talk about today.
Hi, my name is Gunnar.
Welcome to the book circle.
-What's your name?
- Jim.
Can you describe the book?
It is white.
Can you say anything about the content?
Eh ... there are no pictures in it.
The animals on a farmhouse feel oppressed by the farmer.
They take over power-
- But the new system will soon become as corrupt as the old one.
Comments?
- I thought it was unreal.
-What do you mean?
It was unrealistic that the animals could talk.
Yes, but it was probably a conscious choice.
How many people perceived the book as an allegory?
It's an allegory.
The character Napoleon, is he a metaphor?
No, a pig.
Yes, but also a metaphor for Stalin.
The entire animal farm is a metaphor for totalitarian Soviet communism.
Anyone have a question?
Is it ok if I go to the bathroom?
Sure.
Two simple espresso.
I take a blueberry muffin.
- It's been a long time since I traveled.
- You get away too rarely.
How much does it cost to go to London a weekend?
Not many kronor.
No, sometimes it is cheaper than traveling within Sweden.
Thanks.
You should really treat that.
Okay.
You have all had to choose each favorite piece from the animal farm.
Jim, can you read what you chose?
-Rather not.
-Okay.
There is no coercion.
Gunilla ... Which paragraph have you chosen?
Nothing.
I was going to sing the song World Wide Web by Nick Borgen.
World Wide Web, World Wide Web
I feel happy, here is no stress
Here's my new home address
Thanks.
That is enough for today.
Excuse me, I would just take that apple.
Can you give me that?
Okay.
Let's go!
You are big in the trout, dear, but now it is the turn of the fists!
Here is Mr. Aj and Mrs. Pain.
They have been meeting with you!
Let's Get Ready to Rumble!
Ouch!
Are you crazy?
What kind of man are you?
You, what is the name of the swim?
Do you see him with a white bath cap?
-Do you mean like this...?
- No, more so ...
-No clue.
-Neither do I.
-I am going in.
- We have just drank up!
How long should we wait?
20 minutes?
The Rejv Parts will realize that we are cops!
No, it's "under cover"!
Hi, it's Lukas.
-Hello.
Per.
- We have long -distance guests ...
-Nice to meet you.
- Conny here is Taliban.
Hello.
Per.
There is a good atmosphere in here!
It's been a nice day.
The rain never came.
You have to take the forecasts with a pinch of salt.
But otherwise, so ... It's a nice time now.
They said on the radio that it would be sunny tomorrow, upwards of 18 degrees.
The radio usually predicts better than TV.
TV is not the same since Pohlman quit.
- He would love to have a funny grunt ... - Yes, he was fun!
- Do you live nearby?
-Yes, in a southern terrain villa.
You should meet the wife.
- British!
-Hello.
Britt.
-Per.
Excuse.
You sit in my place.
-Do I?
- Yes, I was just at Dass.
I apologize.
- Think after a little next time.
- I didn't know you were sitting there.
-Excuse?
Okay!
Let's go.
You and I.
Here and now.
Come on!
-What do you mean?
- It's not so strange.
You muck with me.
I give you a strike.
- I don't intend to fight.
- You would have thought about that before!
Now the smack train rolls!
I offer a knuckle sandwich.
Two slices stroke with a little bang in between.
Come on!
Stop it...
The train to Strymberga!
We stay in blue, leg crackers and nasal bleeding.
Come on!
You are big, but slow!
I float like a butterfly, I stick like a bee ...
Aoo!
How hurt it does!
Are you crazy?
- Have you lived there for a long time?
-Awhile.
-Where are you from?
- Lomma.
We are really from Afghanistan, but have lived here for 1 1/2 years.
- It's not that long.
- No, but you get into it quickly.
But don't you miss the home areas?
No, we never fit into Lomma.
There were strange types there.
- I mean Afghanistan.
- No, it was much like Lomma ...
... firmly warmer.
We don't play TP tonight!
You may start talking about something else.
Tp!
- I am treasurer in the hockey club.
- You can also become association -active!
- It's not much to talk about.
- Lite secret ...
We are a bunch of guys who want to take over the world.
Rotary is called.
What 'fuck are you doing?
After all, you stand and push me!
Sorry.
Sorry?
Okay!
Here we go!
Come on!
In normal cases I do not beat women but I can make an exception.
I don't want to give you a hit.
I didn't want to dance, but you offered!
Relax a little.
Congratulations!
You have won at Stryktipset.
Award ceremony!
What time is it?
The big pointer stands on the bang, the little one on the rod.
Come on!
You get first free.
You get a free stroke!
Put this one!
That was very nice!
I did such a foil loops -
- And it was a nice shade!
If you ask me about future dreams ...
I would like to go to Dalhalla -
–And look at Robert Wells with "Rhapsody in Rock".
And so I want all Americans to burn in hell.
That's what I want.
You ... Do you think I'm boring?
I'm not very funny, but I try to be happy anyway.
I feel that I am stuck in a role - Magnus, the boring.
It's not me.
Yes, I am, but ...
If you take Peter at my job ...
When he tells things, people listen, because he is so funny.
But why do you have to be so damn funny?
That's not the most important thing.
It is important to be interesting.
I try to be ...
... when I tell things.
Don't you think I can be interesting?
Frida ...
Program text: Birgitta Sunnerdal (C) Swedish Television AB 2004