I do not know how many houses there are in Norrland, which many do not know that it haunts.
The house in Yrttivaara was definitely such a house we did not know, but which we soon became aware that paranormal things happen in.
The house was built during the Second World War and part of the house was then a store, where they sold nails.
At that time, you had to buy a whole railway carriage with nails, which you also did.
The deal was closed down and demolished, but remaining the old wooden stairs and the concrete slab, where the store once stood.
The house changed owners and renovations began.
That's when everything started.
Inside one of the bedrooms you began to hear banks from the wall where the store once stood.
You also heard how someone goes with clogs up for the old wooden stairs.
Although no one is there.
The basement door which is immediately when you come in to the left, opens and closes inexplicably.
And on the second floor, today's owners feel that a woman with curly hair stands and stare at them.
Who that woman is you do not know, but a huge discomfort radiates into the room when she is present.
We did not know what we were about to meet during this investigation.
And maybe it was good, because the house in Yrttivaara will do something with us at LAXTON that we have never experienced before.
Then we will just go here in Yrttivaara, in an old business.
But the deal is no longer left.
We have been with the bags.
I was putting on the vest, yes we are a little taken here.
Yes.
I think we've caught it on surveillance.
There are two things.
I go to the toilet which is just inside the left.
And you Niclas should go around and start the audio recording on all surveillance cameras.
Yes, so we get sound for surveillance.
And when I'm in there I hear how you go Niclas and I think it is he who hits the handle on the toilet door.
I just said "yes" or something like that.
And then I go out and asked if you turned on the handle.
And you say "No, I haven't touched the handle"
So hopefully the monitoring has taken that angle.
And not only that, me and Johan go out here, we are right where we are right now.
We go in and we go to the kitchen, then I hear how the basement door just "Bang!"
Damn!
The door closed!
Open that door completely.
Monitoring takes it.
What I think is interesting is what she tells.
Just with this door, but I don't think she said anything about the toilet door.
We also have knocks in the wall, we also have things that are visible, ie shadow figures.
A woman is visible in here, we have lots of things.
And we just have time to step in, we will prepare to start this investigation.
And then it starts.
It is really cool, we will see where this is going.
A nice house, but it may be slightly darker in here, I have no idea.
And they are renovating and this tends to tear up energies, I think it can be even stronger.
And the owner said earlier today that she feels this pier in the scalp and body and so it usually is when it happens amazing things.
Shall we go in?
It's a little chilly out now.
Then we are inside the hall here.
There we are the door, it is completely still now.
This one was closed and when you asked if it could open more it did.
And it has happened to her.
This is how it sounded about if I should reconstruct what happened.
Like it went again.
And that it then ...
went up.
Type like that.
When we prayed it open.
Just.
And what also happened, for her, because I have her as a reference, because this will be a hot spot.
She is upstairs and she hears a bang from here.
She said she always locks this door, we have chosen to have it open of course.
And behind here is the toilet.
Here I was, I close the door and then I hear this ..
Like someone turns pretty hard on the handle.
I also walk by here and I hear it, but I think Tony is watching so the door is locked.
But it's not me.
No, I thought 100% that it was you who wanted to say that now you have to come out.
Very strange.
Hopefully we have a good angle on this since then.
In the kitchen we have all the technology.
Should we go in and start walking around a little neighbor?
Detect.
I think we should start there.
I even shudder there, it's interesting.
I pull a PSR there directly, with static and strap.
I put it so it even touches the door.
Do you have Polterscript on you?
Yes.
Should we have it running and see if we can get any direct communication?
We have Lennie sitting on the bus, he has the time codes, he has saved everything.
So we'll go back and watch this later.
Then you will see it, if we got it.
We have now put a PRS down there.
It is our paranormal rem static.
We have the strap function, just like a remepod, even static.
I start Polterscript, see if we can get anything about what happened here exactly.
As if we have someone with us here who just did them things, jerked the handle or closed the door.
Can you do any of them things again?
Close this door or hit the toilet handle.
I shudder when I stand here.
Strange.
I think this is current to the machine.
So there we have nothing.
I got the feeling when I came in here, that I was not welcome to be there.
Like "out of here!"
Yes, it's a bit like that.
*Footsteps*
Was that a step up from?
You, I forgot to say one thing.
When I was standing here before and just going out, I thought I heard like a growl.
It is also interesting, they have plans for this house.
They are renovating and that is when it has started.
Do you know what they have for plan with this house?
I haven't been rugged here before.
I have been in here and fixed stuff.
The forest.
I also asked if this ditch they have dug out.
I wondered when they did that.
There is memory out there.
So what they have dug is next to a cat that they have buried.
One of the people who have lived here said we have to move on the cat and someone said "No, we shit in the cat"
And I also think, you pull a deep sheep out in the woods, when you have to dig down a cable.
It is open now.
You think so.
There was a lot that came here right away.
I'll check if you have electromagnetic fields at you.
As you can see, it's zero.
At Tony here.
Try walking towards the doors.
Did you hear?
Someone hit this one.
Where did it come from?
When I got two on Polterscript, I saw two on it.
This is how it sounded.
We have 0.2.
0.1.
That sound must have come along, it was like someone was snapping on the meter.
If you have touched this door, do it again, you are kind.
Here is 01, 02. 03. This is the base we had throughout the day when we went here and looked.
I also thought when you said if it is electricity and you feel something ..
I shudder and it comes from something.
I've never been to that.
No, it was like something struck.
Can you try to go up?
Do we have EMF further up?
02. But it has not been during the day when I have been watching.
They have electricity here that we can use, but there is nothing that is leaking, what I have found.
It may remain there.
Should we take a lap and feel a little neighbor?
I have a new instrument here.
A pyramid, you don't really have the name for it yet, it's a prototype still.
I want to say it's paranormal pyramid of truth.
It's like yes and no on it.
We put this one, something on one side so it shines green, something comes on the other so it shines red.
Then we can also ask questions and communicate.
Should we put it on the table so do we stand a bit away?
Now it takes red for my hand.
I put it a bit away from us.
Now it will start pulse with a blue light.
That's how.
Now the shivers comes in here.
Good!
You who are here now ..
You who are here, Nancy came up.
Can you touch this pyramid?
Make it shine green.
It is a damn discomfort to stand here against this.
I almost look at the basement here.
Come to this now that blinks blue.
I think about this cat.
If there are several men here now ..
In this house ...
You who move here, is it the woman who has been seen here?
After all, it is a woman on the above floor that the owners have seen.
With a little shorter curly hair, she only stands at a doorway there.
We don't know the name of her.
And we will go through the entire building, but hot spots are the strongest places.
Should we bring it and go through the rooms down here?
This is a room that every bedroom before.
The previous owners have told them that they have heard knocks.
And the old deal, Everts old business as it is called
It is behind the wall here.
Here they have heard knocks from the wall.
It is also an old staircase that goes here, where they have heard someone walking up with clogs.
Exactly, it has been heard at night.
Can you knock back on this wall?
Evert, are you left here?
Tap here.
Or if someone else is left here so knock in the walls.
Can you make a loud sound so we know where to go?
Can you run upstairs if you are there?
I think it is interesting, because it is a fairly small house, but then the chances of something could happen.
We compress without quite well, it is not a castle.
So is someone running here or knocks in the wall, we hear it immediately.
Yes definitely.
So that's good.
It would be damn interesting to get back the knocks.
But as I said...
There is no discomfort here but there is more discomfort in the hall.
Do not you think so?
Yes, definitely.
I'm drawn up a bit, should we try to go there?
Should we try close the door?
If I close the door completely we will see if we get a move here.
We put this against it.
Boys.
Yes?
Very strange white fog down in the basement by the stairs.
White fog in the basement?
We go down there now, now there is a white fog in the basement.
We were going to go up, but we go there instead.
Now we go into that surface, the deal is not left above, but the concrete foundation remains.
And the old stairs are left.
Now the question is where the fog is.
The camera is further in.
Lennie does Lennie hear us now?
Yes.
Where is the fog?
The fog came where you stand now, then it passed the stairs two, three steps down, thick.
Okay, I get 37 years here too.
Ugh what shivers it was here.
Are you down here all?
You see that it is moisture damage, it drops in.
But as I said, it is this staircase that belongs to the old store here.
And this is where they have heard someone run up in clogs.
*Bang in the room*
It was a bang in the corner here.
Who do we have here?
I try the mood.
Okay, this fog that is here ...
Where!
Exactly where Lennie said it was before.
Who are you?
Is it you Evert?
Where.
Should I interpret it as a yes?
I look here in the corner.
*Bang in the room next to*
What was that?
Was this behind?
In here we have no surveillance camera.
No.
Is it on red?
Or orange?
Orange.
Okay, can you back are you kind?
Who are you?
Is it you Evert?
You talked about an army with people here.
Are you many who are here?
I'm starting ... I'll test a thing just ..
I turn off strap.
Now we see MG, this plug cabinet does not work.
Nothing at all?
Zero.
03 here now.
08.
1.1.
There was nothing at all here.
Huh?
And now it comes.
But it's pretty low.
Check this out.
1.1.
2.8.
3.0.
Here it goes down.
So I need to be damn close.
You see, now I'm 30 cm from the cabinet.
Then it's 0.
And here was what we got.
I'll start it again.
Can you touch that antenna now?
Right in front of Niclas.
If we have with this army with men you describe who are here.
Wondering what it was?
It was like something was pushed away.
After all, we got a rash immediately when we came in here.
We go back here to the fog then.
3.9 degrees.
And zero ...
Here is something ... zero in EMF ..
Away.
Come back to me here.
And grab it properly in this iron stick.
Do you want us out of here?
Do you want us to stay here?
It's up here.
But it is still zero in EMF.
It's pretty cool, it's in the doorway.
And the degrees go up.
To 7.2, we had 4 recently.
It gets warmer there.
Now I go out.
It's strong here.
Huh?
What was that?
Was it you who did that?
What did you do?
I got a shock in my finger.
A shock?!
So disgusting.
Like I took in ..
In metal type?
Cables that were loose.
*First words from Polterscript when we enter the basement*
How disgusting that was.
At first I thought I was bitten by something, but there is nothing here.
That was like a shock in your finger.
Like I take in two cables that have low power, I felt it was tingling.
Irritated?
You, the owner said it started to tingle in the body.
It was interesting that you feel it.
And now 4 degrees again.
4.5.
It went up to 7 degrees and this one went.
Warmer.
Nothing.
Lennie.
do you hear us?
Yes.
Is the fog gone or is it left?
The fog is gone.
We do this, we document this Lennie, we continue to document it.
If there is something else that is starting to manifest, then we go back here.
If the fog all the time, we know if it is an army of energies moving here.
We drive on it.
We go back to the house again.
*High bang in the room next to us*
What the hell was that?
It's like it slams in here.
That sounded like something was moved.
Is anyone down here and playing with us?
I'll start this again.
It was like you turned on something.
It seems you like to turn on things.
You turn on the meters, you turn on handles.
If you want us to stay here with you, then touch this iron stick.
Yes, take in this black box I have here.
I'm starting to think about some other things now, it talked about forest before Niclas.
Now a box, it may be something else it wants to convey.
Now it is snow outside so we can't go out and dig, but it's something they want to be able to convey.
I turned off this, that was what sounded.
But I also think like this, if they have stirred up the ground, they have renovated here, they might pull in something else.
I am starting to feel the outside.
I will test stand here in the door where we had high value.
I have so we can measure even more.
When it said Orb it went up to 276!
MAN.
Was it this box they talked about maybe?
Shit what it started talking.
Do you think it's fun with that one?
01, 02. It went up to 276 ... when the first word came.
Orb.
Throughout the house it has been 01, 02 all the time.
05 as max.
But this was .. What did you say?
null
And just with the word orb.
We'll see if we catch something on the camera, or in the surveillance camera when we entered here.
Should we go back to the house?
We do it.
So we let these shadows are manifested because we catch it on film.
This is also absolutely incredible, it is five inches of fresh snow suddenly from nowhere.
We had sun and nice weather before.
I think we close the door, we put a PRS in front, so we see if we get a move on it, because this is said to be opened by itself.
And we got some of it on the surveillance earlier, you hope.
So put PRS in front.
I pick up Ovilus and test it too.
I want to place some instruments.
If there are any younger energies moving on this floor, for things that are not where they should be.
I put this on the table.
And this is a Remdeddy.
So if something comes close to it ...
So if you do not think it should sit there, then you may want to push it down.
We saw you in the basement, or we saw you in the basement.
How many are you up here?
When the shivers comes, they disappear, then they come and disappear.
Do you know what I do with this one?
No?
This is our movement sensor that we have now, also a demo that we are testing.
I can set this alarm.
Should I put it inside the office over there?
Where they have heard the knocks?
Just.
If we come down and this one flashes then ...
I put it like this, so it's exactly against the wall.
And then I start it.
So if we have someone behind the wall, who wants to knock or knock in the wall then do it now then we will see it then when we come down.
We leave it there.
Or get up from the basement if you like.
Push that away.
Open the toilet door too.
Touch the teddy bear unless it is there.
And everything we are putting out now is in front of surveillance cameras, so hopefully we catch it if something happens.
We go up to the second floor.
This is where you have seen this woman stand.
*When we go upstairs this happens with the door to the basement downstairs*
We can also say that there is a room that they are carpentry in, here they have had no experiences.
*Bang in the room*
What was that?
I heard it immediately when we came in here, like something was thrown.
Interesting, because here they said they had nothing.
I don't know if it was thrown on the window or whatever it was.
Can you make that sound again?
*Bang in the room*
It's here.
We test like this ..
Is it wooden floors or plastic floors that we stand on here?
It slams at our feet, but it slams here.
I put one thing here on the floor to you.
So it must be here.
Now stir at that iron stick.
If you walk around here, can you kick it off?
We put it at the doorway, then we should get it on the camera if something comes there.
Now the camera is right here.
Put it at the entrance right where you get up.
This is the doorway at the kitchen, this is where you have seen this lady stand.
Right here.
Should we try a PMB?
Align it straight up.
Lisa, I got a name here again.
The woman who has been seen here ...
Can you come in to us here?
There are more people who have experienced phenomena here.
That you hear knocks, you have seen you.
There are things you could have pulled out or open here in the kitchen, these boxes.
If you are up here with us.
Then can stand here and fix in the kitchen.
They talk about men down in the basement here.
Can any of you come up here?
We are testing a Ghost box and we will see, if it comes through something up here.
Do you hear this noise?
Get near me here.
If that woman is in this room right now, can you come out to us?
Who gave me a shock in my finger?
Down in the basement.
Who was the one who hit the handle down by the toilet?
Who opened the cellar door?
I move a little here too.
*Tony hears steps behind him*
It sounded like someone was going here, did you hear it?
I remove PMB here.
It was just like someone went here.
I felt it in the floor, because I stood a little obliquely behind.
It was like someone was walking, because it swayed in the floor behind here.
And it was like a bang, I have a hard time saying where it came from.
That woman, or whoever went here, can you come in and talk to us here?
Shit, it spun when I went in here.
Like it's leaning.
The woman who has been seen here ..
Who are you?
I try the other corner too.
"You are disgusting"
Did it say what disgusting you are?
It sounded like it.
It is the first thing I get through and it is a man who says it.
Who are you?
He didn't sound nice.
The one who came through was really ... "How disgusting you are"
I shudder all over my body.
That's the only word we had.
It was a whole meaning and I think it was very clear.
Right?
I'll check.
What did you say?
I'll check, it stings there.
On hand.
I put in the Owlus and see if I get something more.
"Beware"
Beware!
It was a woman, in Finnish, who said beware.
I shudder when I go into the corner here, what sick.
Can you tap or slap into the walls if you are Robert?
I'm standing here in the corner.
If so, you may have to push me off.
*Something moved in the building*
It was something that fell or thrown out there.
I'm standing here.
Can you push me away, or pass in front of me, like a shadow.
Can you do something that makes me want to go away from here?
*Steps heard in the building*
It's steps!
It was steps.
But it came .. There is nothing up there.
I just shudder.
Tap the wall again if it was you.
The knocks were great.
Do it again.
If the lady is here, come in here to us.
What a stinging feeling in my head I got.
I can stand out there, I'm in front of a camera if I'm out there.
Do you stand Johan?
If you stand there.
Now we are divided, Niclas is behind here.
Make that sound again.
Join us on some tearmark now that Niclas.
Do something that makes sure we go out of here, that we think it is so uncomfortable.
Bat in the walls here.
Not the lamp Johan, stay there.
Tony, come.
We have a surveillance camera on this, come, come, come.
Check the floor.
Isn't the black there something else?
Does it look like something is on the floor?
At the stairs?
At the stairs, right in front.
Very black.
If we pull a lamp there, it will disappear.
Should we just go there?
It's like something is there.
It is darker than the darkness.
It's so damn dark.
Just like something that has come up.
Slowly came Johan.
Damn what dark it is.
Now it starts to disappear ...
That was damn crazy.
The carpet is here, but what was located was here.
Imagine someone lying down on the floor.
And I saw the contours .. I just shudder when I stand here.
Was it you we saw here?
Has it happened to you something here?
It burns on my knees.
It's really strange.
As tear marks or burns?
It burns, we must see if there are tear marks.
It usually starts with it getting hot, but what was it I saw there?
Imagine a man lying here.
It is just manifested from nowhere, suddenly it was just there.
Like this, do you see this brand here?
Imagine something like that though you see ... Yes, it was really strange ..
Something manifested that lay there.
Shall we go in there?
Should I put a PMB targeted here?
So we see.
Johan if you go in there.
It calibrates.
Anyone who may be in the hall at the stairs, came in, pass the kitchen and came here to Niclas in the corner.
This one works like a spirit box.
Although it is digital only.
And the sound is on this page, that's why I have it up and down.
Did it say that?
I thought it said Niclas.
I thought it said your name.
Did you say my name recently?
Is the former owner here?
He who had the deal.
Are you still in this building?
What do you think about these renovations that happen here?
Will it be your way, the way you want it?
It was me who put my hand ....
"Worse"
I shudder in here.
If you don't like it, can you make a loud bang here?
Try turning it off again.
Sick, I thought it said Niclas ...
I thought it flashed, but we'll see, the surveillance is there.
*Surveillance did not catch a blink in the room*
But as I said the one you got through did not feel very nice.
He who said how disgusting you are.
But I think, did he talk to me?
I do not know.
Or did he talk to the woman?
Was it that woman we saw?
Has something happened to her?
Was that where she collapsed?
But them the steps ...
They were so clear, where they came from.
What the hell was that?
It was as if someone was looking .. on the floor, like something looked here.
Here.
Or what was it I saw?
Type that something made me see something like ...
*Nothing was caught on the surveillance*
Or if there was any child or something that looked forward.
I go and sit down here.
I bring Johan.
And if you try to go down and sit down, you can choose.
I sit down in the bedroom where they have heard these banks.
So I listen and see if I hear the banks.
Then you up here.
So we see if we hear something between us.
I go down myself then.
Now I sit here myself.
It is me and Johan, but Tony is himself.
"We go"
We go.
Now I'm down here, Niclas is just above.
I sit in bed.
Go down to Tony.
All.
Touch the wall, hit there.
Sound from there.
Sound from here.
Don't you want me in this room?
Is that why you go from here?
"Beware"
Beware ..
It's like I see someone standing there, in the contours.
Go toward me ...
It looks like someone less, like a woman ..
Shorter.
It stands in the hall, but it is not visible in that camera, it is exactly at the door edge.
And tell me, who was it I saw as lying on the floor?
"Me"
I see you there.
Come here.
It's cold around here.
Shit, around the face ...
I sit down again then, so you have to make that sound.
Come walking in the corridor here.
Again.
I hear someone walking here.
Has something happened up here?
That made a person die ...
"Woman"
I ask the question again, that woman ...
Who has been seen here, have you died in this building?
"Silent"
Silent.
MAN.
Yes.
We do this Johan, I shut it down.
We leave and go down to Tony.
I put a motion detector right here.
You know how it sounds, it's a Hello Welcome.
And we hear this downstairs ...
Then we know we had movement here.
I hear so much steps, it's like someone goes down here.
And here, exactly here, when I stand in the room at the bottom with them there the knocks, like there is a girl here, just standing there.
I see the silhouette of her, because I see the window behind.
She just stands and looks.
And then I hear steps, like someone's going.
At the ground floor.
We put a motion detector up there now, where she has been seen.
So it sounds like it is in that passage.
I think we remove that, we put a PMB against this door.
So if you're there ...
in the basement....
that army of ...
energies, so get up here.
Now this one is calibrating.
So if something then goes by here ...
So we will know it when it starts playing.
We make us go up there.
And we bring a car that goes static.
We place it a bit away.
After all, we had static up there that woman lay.
I think we place it there.
So we'll see if it starts to go.
If it reacts to static.
I leave that chair, stuck to it a bit, we still have PMB and the other instruments.
Plus I will take the pyramid and put it .. The Pyramid of Truth, that it will be green or red in bed as well.
Because it is completely different up there and we hear the steps too.
We test.
So if a static field shows up, this car will go away.
I put this fast here then we go out and see if the car comes.
We go out here again then.
I put it farthest, at the far end here.
The figure we saw low on the floor, can you walk near this car?
Can you put your hand on it so maybe it goes here to us?
And you who have been seen ... directly!
It stuck right away.
Can you put your hand on it and then ... That was right!
Try again, this is absolutely incredible.
And as I said this goes on static fields that have appeared earlier.
And immediately when I say put your hand on this one.
Because we saw something lying on the floor, it looked like a woman lying on the floor.
And it sounded like she said suicide.
Green!
Suicide....
Thanks!
Was it you who put your hand on the car now?
It was interesting that it answered right over there, .. green again!
Is it?
That I find it interesting that it answers ...
So now Tony has put back the static car.
Are you here?
If you are still with us here ...
So put your hand on the car again.
So you can get it to go here.
Did you go out there in the hall?
Is it you we've seen?
So do the same thing again.
There, now!
Now it's static here.
Good, go out to the car there.
And do the same thing again, put your hand on it.
I pull up the volume.
Good.
Just come here.
"Yepp"
A man.
The man who is here, do you see the car out in the hall?
Can you go and kick it?
Do you see this pyramid in bed that lies there?
Can you put your hand at it?
Run past us here and out to this black bus.
"Away"
Just when you talked, it was a man who said away.
The car!
"Running"
*Tony is starting to feel weird*
I feel damn bad up here.
Are you feeling bad?
I feel throughout my body.
I almost feel spiteful.
I don't know if I feel something here.
It just came and I feel dizzy too.
Is it any of the energies in the house that affects Tony now?
Beat the wall in case it is.
Green!
I think I have to go out ... It feels like I'm about to vomit ..
Men's voice saying "hmm"
It doesn't shine at all!
Did them turn it off?
I'll probably go out a turn, damn what I'm feeling bad.
Being so influenced by a house that you finally cannot be able to remain, has never happened to us before.
This completely unknown house for us made us do something we have never done before on our investigations.
Namely to cancel.
Tony was so strongly influenced by something inside the house that he goes out and sprouts immediately after the investigation.
Johan feels after Tony has left the house, that he too is starting to feel strange.
Then the decision was made to cancel.
In retrospect, we have thought about what really happened.
Why was Tony so strongly affected?
Could it be because he asked the house to do something, on several occasions during the investigation.
When you look back at the investigation from Yrttivaara, we see that the further into the investigation we come, Tony gets worse and worse and must eventually hold on to the table in order to continue.
What stands out during this investigation is several things, except that Tony was affected.
The door to the basement opens.
The handle to the toilet is knocked down.
Steps heard in the house.
The fog in the basement that also affected the melmeter when we got there.
What is also interesting is when we saw the dark shade lying on the floor.
Which also affected the static bus, which leaves when Niclas asks it to put his hand on it.
But the strongest memory will be that we had to leave the house.
The house in Yrttivaara won over us this time, but it will be a next time, so we will make sure to be more prepared for the dark forces of the house.
And at that time we will not cancel.