Then we finally arrived at The Conjuring House.
And it is warm, my glasses Immar again I notice.
So exciting to be here really, this is a dream to investigate.
Oh my God.
One of the world's most haunted houses.
If you have seen the movie The Conjuring, everything in the movie is about what happened here, though a little converted, it is a movie.
And it is said that what was included in the film is only a fraction of it, but have toned it down a lot, what happened here in reality, with the Perron family.
They lived here for almost ten years.
But there are things that have happened here.
We have the big Sean room, now there is no table and so left there.
They say that the mother sits there and is thrown all the way away and hits the fireplace.
They get very angry and then they throw out oath and Lorraine from here after this session.
We have the form of a little boy upstairs.
We have something that goes down in the basement.
You also talk about The Crooked Lady.
There is a child who has drawn a woman with crooked neck, much like being hung.
"There is no documented suicide in the house that someone has been hung"
It's really cool.
This will really be a great evening, the team has already started to carry in all the bags.
We are fixing all the cameras, so I think we start the investigation.
We go in.
Yes, then we are inside the house.
How does it feel?
I feel bad.
Yes you see ... we have talked a little off camera too ...
Already when we got here I started to get some headaches.
Then we have walked around the house, filmed a little behind the scenes and I just feel worse and worse, now I feel completely finished.
Yes, it is a powerful house, we talked about it initially, it has happened so much here.
Now we are going to form our own view, there are many who were here and investigated
And there are many stories.
Now we are here to see if it is true that people tell.
And I think we should have the background the story of the Perron family with us.
Because we know that happened, there is documented.
So we start from that.
Obvious.
How does it feel Johanna now when you entered the house here?
Dizzy and nausea.
I would be surprised if I was not vomited today.
Is it so bad?
Yes, it's the same feeling.
I do not feel good...
Wilma then?
I have never felt so affected.
I already feel that I am very affected.
I feel pressure over my head, I feel a little groggy.
Like I'm a little full.
Even nausea and like the eyes just hang.
So this ...
Exciting introduction.
And we should start now.
What was that?
Was there something that bit me there or?
Bet you?
Damn what it stuck.
Huh?
Like a damn needle.
I thought it was a wasp that bit me.
Was it so powerful?
Wait I have to hold on to me.
I was completely crazy.
Huh?
Is there anything?
Does it feel like a wasp stack you?
It was like someone is taking a needle and ...
There is nothing visible.
Okay, but we have control over it in case it shows up.
It's like this, we've gone around, we've set up all the cameras here and you feel very affected.
I feel that I'm pretty much at the top, yet.
I may not have really got that paranormal feeling of the house, but I have done this so many times so I know it will come.
And you?
I have been walking around here and in some places these shivers.
And it's hot here, but it feels like someone is behind one and it gets ice cold, the hair just rises.
Goose bumps really.
We can say that it is not cold in here.
It is probably 27.28 degrees in the house here.
And you see how we are dressed.
It's not that we freeze.
But it is good that we go with only arms because then maybe we know these caresses, because they can touch one or caress one on their backs.
So we'll see what pops up.
And it happens in some places here in the building.
But what do you say, should we start?
And I think that first you go Niclas, me and Wilma, we walk around almost the whole house.
We just know and bring few tools.
And then you get ... did you see something?
Lennie came here ....
No, it's not you either.
No, Viktor, you have to remain there.
I have to see what it is.
It looks like....
Johan, touching you.
It is Johan who is visible in the mirror, it looked like someone was standing and looking in through a window.
But it was a mirror, okay.
You see, this house will give us things, we are on the alert.
Every little thing we will definitely chop here.
Then we have a surveillance with six cameras outside.
We will also place a few different things and test here.
But we drive like that, we start walking around.
You Johanna and Lennie need to rest, drink some water and sit at the surveillance with Johan.
So we run.
Here again.
I go into something all the time.
Check this out.
I don't know if you see this.
It's like going into something, this came after the boat, I don't know, so much I haven't known before.
Sick, you go into it.
The instruments I have brought are melmeter, polterscript and so I have a spirit box in my pocket.
You have an oily.
Now it is ... you haven't been inside the house before, you came in right now, but this is where the big Sean table was.
Where the Perron family had their seans.
So you know that story so it was here that she, the mother of the family flew into this fireplace.
I see as an energy line, right here around the sofa of the same size, as a circle.
And this has happened far back, then you were doing black magic here, in this room.
So you have thrown spells and called up and down lots of evil forces.
I see a bunch of women who have been doing this and you have not really known what you have been doing.
So that here it is like an open portal, anyone can get in here, from the spirit world.
Or even the being can get in here.
And I feel that there is a lot of activity here, but precisely the spirits that belong to the house do not like to be here.
Without this, this is out.
Spirits that come from and into this portal then.
For the energies in the house are in different rooms here instead, because they do not like this with taking in anything or that it comes and goes energy.
I start an OVILUS so we have it.
Here I am very affected, it is rushing in my ears and it becomes like a lid.
And in here there is a lot of activity
I'll take a step in ..
It's like the energy in here .. I get to me that there are two energies here.
It wants to pull us in, but when we come in it disappears, it wants to run a game.
And I see that these two energies collaborate and will build up during the evening.
The more times you pass here, the stronger it will be.
A man and a woman, they belong together in some way.
They have made this their room and there is something about the books here, it is a special book.
After all, I've got to myself before, a few weeks ago, a blue book that will fall.
I can't pin point out who it is now.
But it is a book that is very special, like those who were here before and put Spells, they have also put a game on that book.
There are some blue books here, because this was a very active area.
Here we have some blue books that stand out.
It could be something.
I try scanning a little.
Yes, it can be interesting.
Because this has been a completely different room, you know about it.
And, what had to do with this room ..
Is a little special.
They had ...
A shape that appeared here.
And it wasn't very nice.
No.
It looked pretty threatening.
And it stood here.
For this was previously a bedroom.
So the bookshelf and it has come in a little later, but we know that books are flying here.
Should we go around with Melmeter just and look around the library here?
Here we have a lot with doors too ..
I was going to say to doors Niclas, they are said to open and close.
There are lots of blue books you are doing there.
That is why I was drawn to this.
It was..
If we have something in here that could throw out any of these books ..
that has that power.
Do you have that power and strength to be able to pull out one of the books?
Oh, powerful right away!
It is blue...
What is it called?
Leave.
It feels like they don't like, this energy Johnny or who it might be ..
Every time you say Johnny.
He is angry with me because I am digging something now, what I mention with the book, it is something ..
Now it sticks in my back when I talk about it too.
It's something he doesn't want me to dig up and speculate on.
It becomes very aggressive.
Now the shivers comes again, they come and go all the time.
Like someone is behind one.
I was just going to say that, he's behind us.
He's on my back all the time.
I just come in between you.
I don't know who Johnny is, it's not a name that we recognize.
Can you throw down any of the books for us?
Can you make this light up against which book you will throw?
I go to this shelf.
You have done this here before.
I get communication with him now.
Then I make me say that you do not know what you are playing with now.
Like he wants to warn, now now does not know what you are about to do.
Should we check out in the living room too?
The first thing I get to me here is that there is someone in the armchair behind it.
And that energy was already sitting here when I came in, it has been sitting here all the time.
And it's like that energy sticks to this surface and keeps a little track of who passes in and out.
And this energy communicates with the other spirits here and tells us that now they come in here and they will do this.
It is a male energy and it is like he blocks, that he finds out everything about us and sends it to them others.
It's the only one I get on this surface.
Is it a basement or something here?
It's a basement there.
Okay, because I've heard that it is shouted from there.
A woman with a knot in her hair sits waiting down there.
What threw the mother in the perron family ..
across the room ..
Could you please do something so we know you're here?
Tap the wall or move something.
What this mother was in contact with, do you get who it might have where?
Because it is a case that you have talked about.
It was a form of portal, that it was not the spirits that were around, but it was something else.
What is it that has such power, I think.
Because it is almost five meters and being drawn or throwing requires a huge power.
Yes, I get like it is .. within the ritual world or how to call it, when you take from the good you take up from and when you take from the evil that digs down.
And I see pictures that you have been sitting in a circle, a bunch of women and that they have dug up.
I also see that you have been doing woodoo dolls.
Needles have been put in dolls to harm others.
And this that they have raised, it is an energy form I have never seen before.
It feels like it could be something demonic or something very, very dark.
I think it was interesting when you said it about needles and woodoo dolls, I thought about the introduction with your leg Niclas.
Needles, Stungen.
We are standing near this too.
Yes and when you mentioned it I get the number 7. I think we should remember the number 7 because it feels important, I can't link why now.
There is something about 7, when you started talking about it.
Now that we have been standing here, this was a long time that I knew, I have had them here the shivers, but right now it is like someone compressing the shoulder blades.
Like someone sitting or hanging on one.
That is why I get these shivers I think that something is behind.
I feel it as a weight in the shoulders.
You know that what usually bends then it will go down.
Then it will settle in the lumbar spine.
We'll see if it releases.
But should we go down?
Wilma was pulled there.
When you opened the door I got the name Deborah.
Check that name.
I got interesting now.
Here it has really happened, a lot has happened here and it is a very, very powerful place.
There is a woman here, who moves like this, runs here.
She has dark hair with a ball, she also has something white on her.
She runs here and this is her place as well.
And I see much like a schizophrenia, like that on the day she is an ordinary woman, but at night she completely changes.
Then she gets long nails, she gets dark hair in front of her face and gets really unpleasant.
And she has pulled us down now, she is waiting for us.
She shows me at three o'clock, as a sign that at night something happens here.
Yes we'll see.
Again it with Niclas, that needle thing.
Or the sticker that you felt.
Down here you talk about The Crooked Lady.
She with her neck of Sne.
What happened there?
Spiritbox started in my pocket.
It may mean that we have to communicate.
Exactly, I thought so too.
Should we get there?
No, stand.
Who are you?
Is your debroah called?
There is also a woman in here who says she wants to talk.
A woman.
Could you say your name to me?
Here it is good, here I shudder.
Should we get away there then?
Wait, just let me be here a bit, I want this feeling.
It was like she just wanted to say go out, leave.
And the last thing was like I'm tired of it now, leave.
I feel that this woman has no problems with me.
She likes me a lot and she likes women.
And I hear oh, a witch like me!
That she recognizes herself in me.
But that men make her provoked, that they come down here and just provoke.
She wants to talk about that.
I get a warmth here, I could lie down on the floor here.
I feel no threat that way.
So it is also a little interesting, against what she sends out.
This is where the father in the Perron family got caresses on his back, when he went down here.
What was that?
*The sound of something being moved in the building*
In the middle of your speech.
Can you do it again?
I think, Wilma knows some in that room.
We leave this one, we go a little there then.
Wait..
Something was dropped on the floor above.
*The sound that Niclas hears*
It will be ... above the floor, inside ...
At the fireplace will it be huh?
That is it?
Now we are in a very special place, we have a well behind it.
You must not take any more steps behind because I do not want you to fall into it.
But if you get something with this well, it is also very special they said.
The first thing I get to me is the name Nea, or Linnea.
It feels like I'm standing at a funeral, or not a funeral either but that someone has been thrown down here, someone who died here.
I see a little girl, like throwing a child down or having brought something down here.
And I know them the energies and that energy is stuck here and calls for me.
Or shouting for some kind of contact.
And it feels like this room is very active.
That you have sat here and really get in touch here.
For what is below me is so desperate, it really wants to communicate.
And here in the chair it is like there is an older woman and she is not so despairing that there is something down here.
It's more like she's guarding, she's wished we would come in here.
But it feels very powerful, that it is linked to throwing someone down here.
We can say that child screams have been heard from there.
That it is like there is a child there.
There are voices in here and everything possible, so here you could sit down and be completely silent just.
Here I think they have done some challenge and tested here.
After all, I read in the book about hangers, moving, thrown when the Perron family was here.
They even got beaten with hangers in some wardrobes.
A voice is heard in the room.
What the hell was that?
Did you hear?
Wait I check.
Someone was talking.
A voice is heard in the room.
Woman.
Damn, I heard something through the handsets.
Did you?
There was a woman who answered.
Could you hear what she said?
No, it was not possible.
Damn what I shudder.
Did anyone whisper?
Yes.
It was something like that.
Good.
This is what can happen and now it is happening.
This is what we want because voices have been heard here and now you heard it Viktor.
Too bad you couldn't interpret what she said.
Because I just said Hello, so maybe it was a Hello back.
What's your name?
This is the coolest I have ever experienced now.
Right now it is pillaged in the hair in different ways.
Are you touching me now?
Grab my arm properly.
Imagine when you get a touch here, one there, one here, it jumps between.
I thought I would see if the hair could move.
But awesome with an EVP.
Wonder what it said.
But we will be able to listen to that during the analysis.
And it's fun that you heard it in real time.
I am super happy about that.
There is something about the mirror I think.
I try to sit in front of it.
I do, because it's like they step out all the time.
I stand here next to it.
Can you show up in the mirror for Niclas?
It was kind of what I knew.
Wait!
Is anyone going?
There is someone who goes.
There were clear steps here.
That must have been heard!
We go against it, I just have to pick this up.
Did you hear the steps in the headphones?
Damn!
This is here Niclas.
Go against it then.
Again!
But we go up the stairs now, and we will come back to the living room.
Then we take the upstairs as well.
Did it start again?
Now its time.
I'll take this up then.
It is sick that it starts twice.
We start something more, I put on this.
It's a damn run here, it's everywhere.
What are you feeling?
What is up here?
I feel stressed and get stress up here.
I see children again, but I also see adult energies.
I see that there has been a family here, or a mom and a dad.
And that something dark has stood here and roared and frightened.
And that you have stepped forward and so you have come from the side and taken a strangle of people who have slept in this bed.
Then it is a huge portal from here and here, this is where everything runs comes.
Very much in that.
It's like the energies just pull me in there.
That we should go further.
Should we go further then?
Should we bring it too?
Bring PRS.
Here was the children's bedroom.
Those who slept in these beds went into that room, that's where the big sister always was, Andrea platform.
But this is also here, around the wall, this is where they woke up and heard this frame.
And you have found them bodies, outside the house.
Just.
The previous owners took the theory of these soldiers.
That it may not be this wall but the wall that goes around.
And then they found five.
But they have not excavated them.
They don't really know, but they think it's there.
Should we try to go into the last room here too?
See if anything more happens.
And this should be Andrea Perron's bedroom.
The oldest in the siblings.
I get to see two peers in any case, two girls.
Now it is one of these girls who shows how she pulled out of this bed.
That she was lying in bed and then been pulled in her leg and pulled out.
She wants to show me that there is something here.
I also see a smaller girl, who gets out of bed and walks around the room, in circles.
Like she wakes up and then walking around and around like this.
Like something that has affected her and tried to take over her body.
Someone controls her?
Exactly.
The children have come in here because it thought it was a safe place.
But they have also seen a little boy coming.
They have even played with the boy and had discussions with him what I understand.
But they have also been around thrown in that scrub there.
The door to that scrub has also been opened so I think you can check it out too before we go down.
I get very dizzy in here.
I see as an energy that sits down, narrow and dark.
It is not a man I see but this is also some kind of being.
Who just grumbled for me.
Sitting in the corner now and growls, with red eyes.
Very unpleasant.
Sitting there in ....
It sits and the corner and bites the nails like this.
So yes, very uncomfortable.
We go down and we make a new constellation.
Now we have changed a bit in the groups here.
I think we are going down into the basement, you see that I have been lurking on me so it will be an Este's method.
Or if Johanna gets to test.
We will go down to this table which is down in the basement, we here too this well there.
We will place some instruments in the corridor at the same time.
Now I start to shudder, now it will ..
Good.
I've had it twice, you've had it a little more.
It comes from nowhere, that's nice.
Or?
But we will go down, place stuff and get started and communicate a little.
We have no other communication tool, but now we are and listen for voices.
And maybe we manage to catch something more EVP, we caught one when we stood down there.
We go down.
What is it?
It was a red lamp that flashed over there.
Wait stay here.
Did you say a red lamp?
Yes.
I'll check if it flashes again.
No.
Here.
Here it was a red lamp that flashed.
So hopefully the camera caught, no damn I was probably in the way of it.
I thought if it might be an aggregate that was shining, but it is not.
I will post paranormal Movement Alert.
We may hear it if something is moving out here.
I also have some motion sensors, who say Hello Welcome, so I post them here.
And we know that the woman has been seen walking here.
Now I have put it quite sensitive, in case something goes by there.
I'll try stamp next to it.
Here I put a Hello Welcome.
And so we have these cats toys.
We place everything in a line here.
We then have a surveillance camera over there and we go into the room there.
Here Johanna is one that you talked about, The Crooked Lady.
It is this that the children have drawn.
Yes, they have drawn her yes.
Yes.
I will post this one.
Red and green.
Wilma said there is a woman in this chair.
So we can see if it gives answers at the same time, because I will sit here, you can sit there and one there maybe.
So I start with Este's method.
I put one more flux behind us here.
For those of you who do not know what Este's method is, Niclas will start a spirit box with headphones.
He also has a blindfold so he doesn't see.
So all the energies that are down here in the basement.
May come in here.
Go to these blue pulsating ...
By the way, I have Noise Canceling, so I will not hear what you say.
Yes.
Good!
I get started.
Now I got shudder.
There has been nothing started before huh?
No, now this is starting.
What's your name?
Why do you want us to go?
Will you show up for us tonight?
Then show you to us.
Behind who?
Can you make a loud sound?
Yes, there!
It starts to shudder on my arms.
Same here.
Both!
There and there.
Someone touched me at the neck.
Okay.
Check!
He also doesn't know that these have just started.
No, he doesn't know.
What is it?
It sounded like someone was standing there.
Who are you who came and supported?
Do you see that he is watching this?
Where you tell me you saw someone.
No, I heard ..
It crushed as well as in the floor.
We want to know who you are.
Who are you?
Do you want us to leave this room?
There is someone who moves me at the neck all the time, I get mad.
Are you behind Niclas now?
Continue touching the neck.
You can touch him.
I got a lot of headaches now.
Did you get a headache?
Here.
In the temple?
I don't really see.
Yes, the temples.
Okay.
Who is it that affects Viktor too?
I have to break.
What is it?
Someone pulls their fingers in the neck all the time, it's so damn uncomfortable.
Like this?
No, very loose.
Like this.
From one side to the other.
First, I think it might be a moth or something that landed on my neck.
But then you had seen it and said it.
Viktor got a damn headache.
Is it going well?
But now I've tested.
Now I want you to test this.
Do you want to hold it?
Directly we get green.
Good.
We get directly green.
And so shivers.
What's your name?
Can you say who you are?
Were you behind me before?
*No steps recorded*
I heard someone walking there.
Is a woman here with us?
Can you do something against Johanna?
*High bang in the building*
Did you hear that?
It came from the iron cabinet ...
What was that?
Did you hear that?
Yes.
It's out.
It was it ..
Though a daughter bang.
*High bang in the building*
Now everything is starting to spin for me.
At the same time, it sounds like a cricket, but we haven't had that in here.
No.
It starts to spin for Johanna.
She may know something in the neck there.
What is that sound?
I don't know if there is any cricket or ...
Does it come out from or?
Now something happens.
It feels like someone is pressing, I want to pull my head like this ...
It's like someone presses like this.
What is it?
The battery on this one.
On which?
It went down to 20% now.
On the display?
Yes.
And so this strange sound.
Now it takes on battery.
Should I break?
You can do that.
Be strange.
It was really like, I didn't feel anyone pressed, but it felt like the head wanted that way.
And then when I was going to pick it up, it was sluggish.
We said your name once, then you say your name.
Yes, green.
I really heard Johanna.
I have a headache.
Shall we cancel and get up?
Or should you run up and get a Sony camera and do we drive a little neighbor?
We just drive in Nighvision here.
Okay.
We have switched to Nighvision because we do not have the usual camera we usually have.
For Viktor who has the camera has extreme headaches, we also have Lennie who has crashed totally, he is completely exhausted.
Wilma who also knows things, we have not been up for a while so we do not know how the others feel.
But we had to send away Viktor so he has to recover a little neighbor.
We drive down here.
I feel it still works for me.
Does it work for you?
Yes.
For you?
Same here.
We have tested Este's method and we got decent stuff on different instruments.
Wait...
Now it's music.
Huh?
Is it music?
Didn't you hear music?
No.
With piano.
I hear it!
I shiver!
Why do I hear this music?
I hope the camera catches this.
*Music Niclas Hear not caught by the camera*
Is it this lady with crooked neck who goes down here?
Green on it.
Directly there.
Thanks!
What shivers I have again, they come and go.
Do you want to go and stand there and look here?
Okay, if anyone behind Johanna can you come here?
So Johanna will feel you, if you are there.
I don't like this.
Does it feel like it could ...?
I hear steps!
There is something behind it.
It's like someone stands like this.
Will you show up for us tonight here?
*Knock*
Do you know what we do Johanna?
We go up and check if Viktor is okay, then I think you and Wilma go away.
I want you to test sit on the sofa where the Seans room was.
And after that, I want you to take you upstairs and test.
So we'll see if something happens.
We go and look at how it is with the others.
Where do you want?
I am drawn to the room with the books.
So if we go in there and see what I get through.
I have a PMB with me that I intend to place against this bookshelf.
What I will do now is I open up and then I pray the energies ...
come here.
It is still this blue book that is talked about.
That's what I see linked to this man.
I'll see if I can get any name.
You who stand there could you touch any of the books?
Would you be able to push something down from the bookshelf?
I would like to ask you to push something down from the bookshelf.
Thank you so much that you show us so clearly.
*Steps in the second room*
*Whispers heard from other room*
Surely someone whispers outside?
Oh God!
That's exactly what I heard.
As soon as I started with my hands.
What was that?
It was a giant movement.
But God I saw some shape here on the sofa!
Step in here with us and influence the equipment again.
He sneaks out there.
He sneaks around out there and it's like he wants to pull us out.
Do you want to move out there?
Does he want us to go out there?
Yes or so he ....
I would like him to come in here first.
If he comes in here, we are happy to go out to him later.
Oh my God!
This is totally sick.
Very strong.
Thanks!
We are very happy to come out now.
Yes, now we have actually said it.
We thank you so much and we will come out to you.
Now he's here!
He is playing here now.
He probably wanted to be in there himself then.
He wants us.
Certainly what he wanted.
I have such shivers now.
Would you like to sit on the couch, will I sit on the floor?
Can i put this one?
Place it between us here.
And the energy I had contact with in there is in the doorway and looks at us.
It's like they are uploading for something to happen here.
If we have someone with us now ..
Thanks.
Is your name George?
Thanks!
Is it your book George that you show me all the time?
Does that book belong to you?
Thanks.
I see as he uploads a lot, with energy before he can answer.
He has quite weak energy in himself, not so powerful so it takes a lot for him.
Thanks!
Would you be able to pick up the book and show us?
If it falls a book now I die ...
I know you have affected and torn down that book, can you do it again?
*High bang in the building*
What was that?!
What was that?
Was it a book?
It may have been a book.
It was from there!
Yes.
Yes, it was from there.
100%.
Up from.
It sounded like a chair or something was overturned.
It was just after we asked him too.
It was like someone was throwing something.
Should we check the library down there?
No book that lies.
The stones are still there.
I heard it like it came from the hall.
Yes I heard it in your direction as well.
There's no one here.
Now all crickets we hear.
Tony and I are sitting with lurks and we hear this bang, we know it in the floor.
And everyone says it came from where we sit.
Johan who sits without headphones says it comes from the outside.
Very difficult this.
*High bang in the building*
This house has been on our bucket list as long as we have had the paranormal interest.
The dream of once being allowed to get to the United States and being able to investigate this house has been a dream and it now feels almost unreal to stand in this mentioned house.
We went into the house with the knowledge of what happened to previous owners and the hopes of experiencing something that this is large.
We got to know early on the feeling of being observed and the whole group was affected in different ways.
What stands out during this investigation is the sound of steps in the basement.
And an EVP that the cameraman perceived.
But what affected us most is the clear bang that everyone heard, but which we did not find the reason for.
We thoroughly went through the whole house and outside, but without finding the cause of the sound.
If we get the chance, we will once go back and hopefully get to see and experience what got the Perron family to leave for good.