(The sound in the background comes from the castle bailiff's baby on the floor below)
This is how we did, or I
You hear.
I feel here and have to turn the key
And then release it, then it is haspad
And that's when the door comes
Stays here
Should you say where we are somewhere?
We are at Ekenäs Castle.
That's where it happened
You see, you have to twist.
If you get closer here ..
This one must around the corner.
You see, now I can't close it.
(dog/child in the background)
So it is the one who locks the door
And you closed it?
That's how
It's not possible...
Closed
And it really makes it all even better
Yeah.
And it stays there.
It might as well have been able to do so ..
If it is winds.
You see ...
So the door stops here, then it pulls again
at full speed
You have to turn this lock on this to get it.
And it turns on the outside so
And it hooks stuck here, behind the iron case
So if you walk in the inside once and see what it looks like when I close
Do you see now?
Yes
So
Nice!