The Matfors factory may be one of Leader Mittland Plus completed projects
But continues to burst with creativity and ingenuity.
The history of the mill, ingenuity and creativity permeates the old factory premises,
which has become an important meeting place in the countryside.
The idea of creating the meeting place that Matforsfabriken is today took Form 2017.
The project group made a trip down to Skåne, where they looked at an interactive castle
And got fun ideas and spreads for the factory premises' design.
Recycling was the key word when the Matfors factory was developed.
Lena Schmidt, project participants tell us more about the wealth of invention.
The idea of this mobile café part Here you should get a feeling that you are sitting inside a house
and here the feeling should be on the outside of a house
Here you walk like a street, with fences and numbers on the houses.
That's what the idea is.
Creativity is bursting inside the room.
It is possible to have a snack at Götas Café but also look into
Röhman's old business that used to be in Matfors.
One should also take the opportunity to open the door to the artistically decorated toilet.
It is not possible to miss the fact that the Matfors factory attracts visits.
Sigrid Lehman and Marianne Näsvik appreciate creativity and think it is a nice tourist destination.
It was interesting what was indoors, flea ice cream and there was play corner and playing corner,
And I think about this if you have children and grandchildren with them so they can do things inside
Or they can do things outside.
And so you should visit the toilet, because it is very worth seeing,
Even if you do not need, you can wash your hands just you can go in there and so and look a little around.
Yes, fully agree.
That it was Röhman's old business.
I remember.
You have been there and traded.
Very nice initiative this.
Lena Schmidt tells us more about what Leader meant for the project.
If we had not received this support from Leader, the Matfors factory would not have been lost.
Because we didn't have the financial muscles to do this ourselves, simply.
The project is completed, but the Matfors factory continues to be innovative and there are many plans for the future.
We at Leader Mittland Plus can't help but agree
That creativity is bursting at the factory and understands that it attracts many visits.