Billy!
- Fan, I'm hungry.
-Me too.
We fill this one once and for all.
There is only one thing to do.
- The municipality has withdrawn the hunting right.
- I shit in!
Our family has been hunting here for generations.
You should not look like a hungry goat.
The freezer should be full.
Yes but, Leif ... it's a big freezer.
I must be a little effective.
- clear, Billy.
–Okej, Mr. Leif.
Blue Eagle Is Ready.
Starting Engines in Two, Three ...
-Sorry, I Mean Three, Two ... - just drive, Billy!
... one!
One in my sight!
- Pass on, large wild boar 200 meters to the right.
-Hit!
- Nice!
Enemy Down.
Satan ... - Pass on, big fucking moose 300 meters ahead.
Ready to Engage.
-Hit!
- Fuck you, good sniper!
Come on now, Leffe!
Hit!
Okay, Mr. Leif, Lock and Load.
Huge Pig Incoming!
Oh fuck.
False Alarm, Leif.
It was just an old bitch walking.
Billy, put off with that fucking English.
Sharpening now!
Be prepared.
Billy, now we fill the freezer!
That was a new dimension of hunting.
Yes, now we just gather the animals.
Fy fuck.
Good Job, Mr. Sniper Boss!
- What I said about English!
-Yes Yes.
Good Leif!
Thanks.
- We will be allowed to go out tomorrow again.
–Wa?
Didn't it be drunk?
Not even half full.
Once again should be enough.
A measured man is a happy man.
Tappations
Hello!
Go you, Billy.
Leif!
-What is it?
-Come here.
He is coming soon.
Yes ... this is my brother Leif and this is our new neighbor.
Hey.
Tony.
There has been poachers in progress here all day.
Oh, damn.
We have found at least eight slaughter piles on the southern gravel road.
A fucking life.
- It was like hell.
- Have you heard or seen anything?
Well ... we haven't seen or heard anything.
- We are not so much out.
- Can you keep your eyes and ears open?
If you hear something, you can hear from you.
Obvious!
We keep all channels open.
- We do not want to have.
- No, it's a hell.
-Thank you then.
Nice house.
-Nice to meet you.
It does not feel good!
Imagine if he is on the tracks.
Pigo hunting gives prison.
Take it easy.
What should the fourth do?
I shit in if it's his land.
It will be a long day tomorrow.
Check out, Tönten and his fucking hunting team.
"Tony, Rikard and Jonas are sure they will find the poachers."
"The police are seriously looking at this."
- Fuck, this doesn't feel good.
-Take it easy.
- But the police, Leif!
- We have to change tactics.
They will look here so we have to leave the car at home and hunt on foot.
- We can end up in jail.
- Billy!
The freezer should be full.
Check!
The moose roars
- Nice, Leffe!
-Silent.
- Fy, Satan, which best.
Great!
- Yes, but now I want to shoot more.
Go down in the weak you, and I go over the crest.
Shoot on everything!
Squirrels, wild boar, crows, woodpeckers ...
- We make mixed mince.
--Leif, what the hell is that?
ELTEL camera.
The damn homophobic gay for neighbor has set it up.
- A eel camera?
- Yes, it's hunting fraud.
In motion, it begins to film.
This one, you.
- Damn!
- Fan, Leif, take it a little quiet!
-Get it together.
Now we drive, Billy!
If you see more fucking cameras, just shrug them.
What the hell?
Well ...
Here's another one!
Here too.
Two moose and a damn lot of small game.
Six broken cameras ...
What is the fucking psychopaths?
- The last time, then we are done.
--Leif, this is enough.
The freezer should be full, not half full.
We'll get up early tomorrow.
Another moose should be enough.
- We go down and see if we find anyone.
-Yes.
- Close the door, Billy!
-Sorry.
Have they set up one more fucking camera?
Hörni, Stockholm Fjolornas Hunting Team!
You can change tactics if you are to get hold of us.
- Take off ... - it's calm.
--Wanna fuck with the brothers of ... - take it a little quiet, Leif.
Keep on with cameras here and there ... hunt as hunters, fucking bumps.
I heard a bang up here.
Satan!
I go up and check!
-Damn!
-Silent.
–O, my God.
-I did say...
Let me think.
Cursed.
We'll see who gets the last word.
Well, now we'll see.
One more fucking camera?
Change tactics if you are going to get hold of us!
I knew it!
Now I have you, your little damn ...
Ouch!
What the hell are you doing?
The memory card!
YES!
I have to call the police.
Hi, it's Tony from Sörbäcken, regarding the poaching.
It's the fucking brothers Öhman.
They have completely checked out!
Yes, we already have a patrol there in another case.
Good!
Because I have a thing here that you have to see.
Bye!
Hello!
Hello.
Your fucking madmen.
Now you go there!
We will look at this.
Film.
Throw it into the jar.
Come on!
They want to see.
- We want to look at this.
- Then we will see what you have on the card.
Soon it will start.
Bridges
What the hell is this?
There should be no moose in this clip.
This must be wrong.
Are you doing this?
Oh, now it sounds like someone is a bit desperate.
They must have replaced this in some way.
When we still look at memory cards, the constable may want to see this.
A very interesting clip.
It's just a selection of what's going on here.
We were going to go down to the party.
We go, because we may have a beer.
We leave the car at home, otherwise the police will come.
-Ouch!
What was that!
- But check out.
Tony!
What are you doing?
- You must not hunt from the kitchen?
-What the hell?!
- No, but I shit in!
- a little happy ...
- This is the sickest thing I've seen.
- We want to look at you, Tony.
Here is the kitchen, here is nothing.
- Here is, like ... what is this?
- We don't know.
- Have you put this one?
- Oh.
Interesting to see what is in such a freezer.
- Red me in the ass.
Fuck!
- Animal killing.
- Come again now, guys.
- It smells like damn.
- It was you!
- No, these are these guys.
- Fuck, Tony.
- It's enough now, Tony.
- It's not my freezer!
Remove the killer finger!
Calm down!
Remove the dirty murderer fingers.
- He is drug -affected by marijuana!
- Remove my fingers from me.
He tore me on his neck.
Blood white!
This is how he has kept all the time, shooting and threatening people -
–And throws at one.
Lucky we got stuck.
We can help you fire up the shit.
No, this is seized.
Can you help me carry it out to the car?
Cursed!
- It was the last.
-Thanks boys.
Bye!
That did not go as planned.
We may try on Andersson's lands.
- But hell!
- The freezer should be full.
-Leif!
-Come now.
Texting: SVT Language & amp;
Accessibility (C) Swedish Television AB 2018