It's not any fucking girl who comes here, Billy.
You are so handsome, so beautiful!
And so sexy ...
-Satan ... - you owe me 100,000.
You have to pay, otherwise you will never see her again.
Irja ... No!
IRJA !!
Mobile signal
That's him.
I might as well kill myself.
-Respond.
Stop it.
Just take it.
-Oh my God...
-Leif ... listen carefully now, thick.
You have 24 hours to fix the money, then I kill the dear.
- Snug Leif, they are so nasty to me.
--Irja?
Ija!
Take it easy, I'll free you.
Irja?
Hello?
Cursed!
I have met the woman in my life.
We would just start making children, and then they come and kidnap her.
Welcome to Leif's universe, where everything just fucks out!
100,000 in 24 hours.
How the hell should we manage to get it together?
We may try to sell something.
Selling something?
God, what a good idea, Billy!
Did you hear what smart boy?
We sell something and it will resolve.
What should we sell for 100,000?
We just have scrap.
Volvon?
Should we post it on the block?
Full of bird piss and slaughter residues.
100,000 - bargain and clear.
- It was a proposal, Leif.
-Oh my God.
I have to go down on my bare knees.
Down in the dirt and make shit.
There is nothing else now.
We get to beg money with the neighbors.
Hello!
- Tjena, Tony.
-Hello.
What do you want, then?
We were going to check if you would like to buy a service from us.
No.
- I can mow the grass for a year.
-No I do not want to.
Billy can wash for you for a year for 10,000.
It's a good offer, really.
- No, there will be nothing with that.
- I will put the cards on the table.
I sit in an economic trouble and would have to borrow money.
Could I be able to borrow 10,000?
-Obvious.
-For real?
If you sit tight, it is clear that I help.
Here you have one ... I had one more ... there!
- There you have another one.
-Good.
Thanks.
I have more in here.
Here is a ... on the shelf.
Where are you going?
- Tjena, Bullen.
- Hi, boys.
Me and my brother go around to the neighbors and offer services.
- We need extra money.
-Are you interested?
Well, you think so?
I don't know if that's something I would need to do.
I do not think so.
We do anything.
We can rake or wash.
Soot the chimney or clean the gutters.
Do you hear ... boys ...
It is bad about women here and it was a long time since I had to empty myself.
We do not conduct any pimp operations.
We can't fix women's timber.
You probably have a mouth, you too ...
Stop!
No.
It is a misunderstanding.
- You get 10,000. It's going fast.
-No in my entire life.
Fy fuck, the bun.
I didn't believe that about you.
You know where the door is if you change.
10,000 ...
Not a bastard wants to help.
- I get to go and rob the bank.
- You should not rob any bank.
Then I might as well kill myself, if Irja is to die.
We go to the mother and say hello.
It is her birthday today.
I promise we will be on something.
It's just a lot now, Billy.
Happy birthday mom.
We wish you were here.
It would have been brilliant if you got to see which achievements we succeed in.
We manage to get fatter even though we live on the minimum of existence.
Thank you for putting me to life!
Nothing works.
Everything just sucks!
We can't even take care of a woman.
- Curse fucking piss life!
- Not at the mother's grave.
We are not completely useless.
I have kept the same weight for three months.
Leif is grumpy because his girl has been kidnapped.
That's why we need money.
Do you remember the jewelry mom wore when she was buried?
- Put off, Leif.
- Did you know what it is worth?
- We can buy sweets for ten years.
- She should bring it to the angels.
-Good night mom.
- But God cursed, Billy.
She is dead.
She doesn't understand.
It's a like you talk to.
Come, we have jobs to do.
Two meters down we have the answers to all our problems.
No...
No no no!
Never in my life!
We can sell it and save Irja.
I don't let you shield the mother's grave!
Never!
Okay ... - you hear, mom.
It's a nice, little guy we have.
He became moral in older days.
Now he can finally dry his ass.
Happy Birthday.
Congratulations to Billy which is so good.
See you, the mother.
Tjena ... are you already awake?
Where have you been?
- I have fixed 90,000. - How then?
I went another beggar round and Anderssons had won on the trot.
That's good.
- You did, huh?
Admitted!
- Take it easy, Billy.
You were violating the mother's grave.
You plundered our own mother's grave.
That's what you did ...
Sorry, Billy.
Now damn damn!
Your damn!
-I hate you!
-Stop...
- I kill you!
- Don't you see the whole?
Two women - mom and Irja.
Yin and yang.
My sperm for further our genes.
Everything is connected.
The circle closes, and the jewelry was the key.
I pledged the necklace.
We can fix it back later.
- The mother had wanted to.
- Look that we buy it back!
I promise, Billy!
Away...
After all, 10,000 are still missing.
Wait here, Billy.
TV sound
The door opens
Vomit sound
What did you do at Bullen?
I saw that you went in to him.
How did you get the money?
Have you become a fucking spy?
You are constantly checking what I do.
Okay, I went to the bun!
Sorry.
I threatened him.
"If I can't borrow money, I murder you."
So he lent them.
- I thought if you might have ... - cursed!
I save the life of Irja and you ask like a eroded birdhouse.
We have to go.
We will meet the can in 40 minutes.
He should get his fucking money.
Come!
Have you seen!
Isn't it the fat brothers who have arrived?
In time too.
- We have the money with us too.
- Good, Leif.
You can trust you.
I get the money.
You should get your money, but first I want to see Irja.
Hey Baby.
Everything will be fine.
Just be calm.
Here she is.
The money first.
No danger, irja.
You can be calm.
Look at fuck!
You have fixed all the money.
How good you are!
Release irja now.
It's quiet, Irja.
I'll save you.
Come ... Irja, come.
Irja?
Irja, what are you doing?
-What is going on?
- Consult me, Leif.
I needed the money.
But I loved you, and ...
Your peas!
It was we who planted Irja from the beginning.
Please Irja, say it's not true.
-Forgive me.
-I love you.
Yes, fat!
Then you were free from your debts.
Irja ... please don't do this.
I love...
You did it anyway!
Why didn't you say you had sex with Irja?
- I haven't had sex with Irja.
- What is this, then?
The Northern sexture!
Good job, the brother.
Vomit sound
Texting: Tove Gustafsson (C) Swedish Television AB 2019