ALARM CLOCK
ONE DROP
CLATTER
Leif: Cursed!
-cursed.
-Did you see that aunt has died?
No.
Have you seen the boiler died?
Yes, it was damn cold tonight.
And then it drops from the ceiling.
Yes, the whole damn house collapses.
I just want to break the pan.
What the hell are we going to do?
We can buy a new pan.
But what a good idea!
After all, I have hidden 15,000 in one of the sofa cushions.
Can't you go and pick them up, so we go and buy one?
Get them, so maybe we buy ice cream on the road too.
Well.
God damnit...
-Do you find them?
-They probably went in.
But God cursed!
What happened to you?
Sometimes one wonders if the mother strolled with a gull.
-Stop it!
-You have a bird brain in the skull.
We have been eating potatoes and water for a month.
Would I hide 15,000?
-Yes, I don't know.
Take it a little quiet.
-Lugnt?
What a position to take it easy.
-It drops and are minus degrees!
-I take, Leif.
-You don't have to get so damn ... -What then?
"Leif Öhman is ..." Good!
I can be like Billy Öhman and take it easy.
Then I can only lie here.
How nice!
You can move in with some seal family on Svalbard and may have been on some ice floe.
-I get it.
My God ... -cursed.
Surely you can't sit and glow while the house collapses?
It is the tar paper that is bad.
Which idiot has built this house?
What the hell are we going to do with the heat?
I will get the bird flu.
Billy, we have a barn full of firewood.
It's just to fire.
And pull in that damn stomach.
You take up four square meters.
Cursed ...
Cursed, fucking piss.
Everything starts to fuck at the same time.
What should we do?
The heat, the water ...
I know!
Stop, I'm getting stressed.
We must fix it.
We get to fire in the stove until we can buy a new boiler.
And then we cook under the roof tiles.
Leif?
Why doesn't it smoke out of the chimney?
Pull the ass over the eye!
Cursed!
Get the fire extinguisher!
-Billy!
-Satan!
Hello.
You, those boilers you have behind ...
-To do they go to buy in a construction account?
-Yes.
-Then you pay on an invoice?
-Correct.
Perfect.
Then we want to open an account.
-Leif, you know it can't.
-Why wouldn't that go, then?
-No was here one night and stole boards.
-Stal and stole ...
My God, we borrowed some planks.
You have closed on Sundays.
I'm sorry, but you can never open an account here.
Okay, is that how you want it?
Then I will not shop here.
As far as I know you have never traded here.
It makes no difference to us.
Should you have something of that?
There are others who want to shop.
-Leif, we only have SEK 239.
-I know.
-Able the garbage bags?
-Yes.
This is the last time I shop here.
This is a bad shop.
-Can you help here?
-Yes Yes...
-During the roof plate!
-Okay!
Oh my God.
-Do we cook the roof with garbage bags?
-Ar brain.
We have no choice right now.
This is provisional.
You have to make the best of the situation, Billy.
Hello guys!
Dad?
-Lill-Billyponk!
-Nice to see you!
That makes me happy!
Satan, what a fucking surprise!
What are you doing at home?
Yes...
Tjena, Dad.
The little boy min.
-Nice to see you.
-Yes...
-What did you say?
-It's funeral for aunt.
We read that she rolled off the stick.
I wanted to cremate her, but the others wanted a funeral.
-Remember to have two buckets extra.
-Yes, Dad Lars.
I have done that.
I know how a coffee maker works.
-Yeah.
A little Finnish sticks and coffee.
-Lovely.
Well.
What about my guys?
You had a little cold in the house.
Yes, it is the boiler that is broken.
But otherwise everything is as usual.
-IN CASE WEASS FLY IN ... -BILLY ...
What then?
Do you have bad steals at the checkout?
It's not gracious right now.
We only eat potatoes and tap water.
-But God cursed!
-What?
Well, you exaggerate.
Stop swinging.
- It's not that serious.
-I should take a look at your forehead.
-Thanks, it is not necessary.
I am in control.
Yes, it was blurry then!
Are you wrong with the coffee maker too?
-No have to buy a new heating boiler, boys.
-I told Leif.
Although it is possible to fix it.
You have to order some spare parts.
-It's a hose piece that has dried.
-Yeah.
What good, Leif.
Then you can order it from China, so it can fly around half the globe!
-Take it calmly, dad.
-I can take care, Leif.
That you have a house you can't take care of I don't have to care!
No, I can sit here and wait-
-So maybe the heat boiler gets legs and takes a walk down to the workshop.
-That it does not work, we ignore!
-OK, I understand.
God cursed ...
Leif says the tar paper has rotted.
Yes ... tar paper.
And how would it have happened?
Just like that?
Huh?
That you would be born with frigolite brain is a mystery to me.
It is obvious that the roof tiles are bad.
Have you even looked?
-He has not, actually.
-Fy fuck ...
The tar board?
-Pull in your stomach.
-Yes.
- What are you laughing at?
Yuk.
How wonderful that the dad is at home.
Very wonderful with someone who walks around whining and thinks he knows everything.
Snoring
How cozy to lie down now.
When a damn riding mower roars like some jet engine in the living room.
-You snoring exactly the same.
-Stop it.
I do not.
-Then I had known about it myself.
-Yes ... good night then, Leif.
Morning Has ...
Banking
The bankings continue
Oh my God...
-What the hell is he doing?
-I do not know.
It's just like I said!
There are some roof tiles that are bad here.
Well.
Damn what good, dad.
-If have you cooked the roof with garbage bags?
-It was Leif's idea.
It was provisional, but you get where they go when it blows.
Exactly.
So.
Is it strong enough?
So, good.
-Cok what the dad found in the chimney.
-It was lucky that you did not burn.
Then the whole house had become smoke -filled.
Lucky then you found it so that the kitchen was not smoke -filled.
I have already put in extra buckets.
Well ... I was going to go down to Danne and greet a turn.
Do you come along?
-I like to come along.
-No, I have lots to fix with.
I have already ordered a new one there.
But hey?
Stop, I'll fix that!
But take it easy, for damn.
I just wanted to check out.
You do not have to.
I have fixed it.
-Sure there were ten plates you said?
-Yes, it should work.
Thanks, Danne.
-You're welcome.
Where is Leif?
-He is home and fixes with the house.
Yes, I don't know that ... He mostly walks around and pretend jobs.
I don't know what he has done with the house.
It is raging.
-What do you have for the boiler on the back?
-You mean the boiler?
-Does it work?
-Of course.
It does.
"But what good! I'll just check out, Leif. It's the roof tiles, Leif."
"I'm so damn good and know everything about everything!"
Cursed Break -up Jävlar.
-Help for here, Billy.
-Yes.
Leif!
Come you see!
Where the hell is he?
Hello?
Hello!
Help!
Ouch!
-What the hell are you doing?
-I am stuck.
Help me.
Drag!
Ouch!
Cursed fucking badgers.
What are they going to do during our house and do?
Last year, Leif stopped a New Year's rocket to blast them.
-So it wasn't really.
-You took the rocket and turned on.
-Grevings?
-Yes...
But God cursed, Leif!
Have you become an ornithologist since last time?
-What then "ornithologist"?
-Dard skull!
These are not badgers.
After all, it is badly drained!
The water has nowhere to go!
Surely there is not a badger who wants to build a nest under your shit house?
-Leif has always said that ... -silent.
Well.
What will be the next thing, then?
Big, fucking anacondas crawling around under the house-
-or a kangaroo in the forest?
Fuck!
-Hop here, Billy.
-Yes.
-What does one cost one there, then?
-Nothing.
-Danne owed me a favor.
-Ssny, dad.
What did you do?
Sucked by him?
It's not free with a heating boiler.
But God damned, Leif Öhman ... what if you could show some gratitude.
Stop pulling your feet after you.
Problems are not resolved because you look at them and whine.
Okay sorry.
You may ask or wonder?
It was a fun.
Do you have any suit for the funeral, or should I need to fix it too?
Hello There, Mr. Sex Object!
What did you say?
You think I'm threat?
Look down here.
It's Pretty Hot.
Six?
No, in Cannot have sex today.
My auntie is dead, so I'm sad.
Maybe Next Time.
-Screw me!
Really handsome!
-Do you think?
Good, is not it?
But Leif!
My God, what a damn bridal magnet!
-Really.
Shit, Leif.
-Thanks.
But ... Surely damn is that my old student costume?
-Wo?
Is it your old student costume?
-Do on the pulley.
Sure damn it is!
-I should not have it anyway.
-So clear you should.
You are shitty!
Yes, though it scratches and smells strange, so I don't want it.
Really handsome, Billy.
Now the mom would see you.
Snoring
Duns and saw sounds
What the hell is this?
-It is called an excavator, Leif.
-I know, but where does it come from?
Dad picked it up.
He borrowed it from Danne so we can drain the kitchen.
But it didn't notice you because you slept all morning.
Oh my God...
-And what the hell are you doing on the roof?
-The roof tiles do not cook themselves.
-Yes, but ... I fix that myself.
-It won't take long.
Cursed!
Come down from the roof, for hell!
It's my house, my plates and my roof, so I do it myself!
Yes, what the hell ... I may need a small coffee break.
-Remember to secure!
-Yes, yes, yes!
-He wanted to cook the plates himself.
-Yeah.
Fy damn, have you read this?
Idiots.
When they started ...
What the hell?!
How did it go?
Have you broken anything?
-Release me ... -Come up here.
-I'll be fine.
-What did I say about the fuse?
Leif, concussion is not to play with.
Now it is important to rest.
Because the neck is properly broken ...
Where the hell is he?
Yes you, Billy ... we'll be at a funeral in 30 minutes.
Now he is coming.
How did it go?
Hurry up and change.
We must not arrive too late for the funeral.
What the hell, we have a quarter over?
We have a house that is collapsing.
We have a quarter of us!
Maybe we can watch out?
Roof tiles.
There we have one to be replaced.
There is one more.
Maybe we should take it before the crows get there.
So, now the roof was fixed!
What fun, dad!
But look, a little disgusting excavator!
We can take the opportunity to drain-
-So that there will be no flooding!
I love to drain!
It's so damn nice!
Oh how nice!
Do you see what good?
Your son can, he!
When we are still on the move, maybe we should fix a little more?
So damn fun with a handy son!
What the hell are we going to do?
Fy fuck ... so damn fun that you are home.
Let's go!
What do you say, Dad?
Damn, how wonderful!
Get to hell, what I love this!
Damn, how nice it is to fix!
Fuck off!
Fuck!
What a fucking gun it is in the machine fuck you borrowed, the dad!
-Now I feel much better.
-Leif, for hell!
For the hell, Lars Öhman!
This is my house.
We have paid for it.
I am of age!
I do what I want.
We can cook a little in the stove, maybe?
We fire, so we get the heat.
Then you do not have to walk around in long underwear.
How nice it will be!
Huh?
This is my fucking house.
And now we are going to fire in the stove, so we don't need the piss boiler you have fixed.
It works just as well with pisswood!
Then we can invite the whole family!
We can undress naked and aunt's tits can go around the entire kitchen!
You became a refuge for the weak, and for the poor in his distress.
Protection against the rain.
Protection in heat.
The rage of the violence is like an ice -cold rain and heat in the desert.
You end up the strangers alarm ...
Leif?
Leif!
Isn't that where our house stands?
Huh?
You got the hatch again for the stove?
Cursed!
Damn!
Excuse me.
Sorry...
Had the stove hatch been dense, the incandescent would not have jumped out there.
-There is needed a real remediation.
-Yes, fuck.
-It could have ended really badly.
-Yes.
Hello then, my pone.
Hello then, Dad.
Well?
Yes ... Hello then, Dad.
Yes, but this is you fixing, Leif?
Hello then, the boys mine.
Ayatollah's in Iran Russians in Afghanistan
Wheel of Fortune, Sally Ride, Heavy Metal, Suicide
Foreign Debts, Homeless Vets, AIDS, Crack, Bernie Goetz
Hypodermics on the Shores China's under Martial Law
Rock and Roller Cola Wars in Can't Take It Anymore
We Didn't Start The Fire
It was always Burning SINCE THE WORLD'S BEEN TURNING
But when we are gone will it still burn on, and on ...
Swedish texture: Gabriella Eseland BTI Studios for SVT