What will happen to me later, then?
When you're gone, I mean.
How the hell should I manage?
Can, for the hell I can just die too ...
Maybe I should go to the doctor again and ask for a second statement.
Imagine if they were wrong for the first time.
It does not hurt to ask for a second statement.
Leif, you haven't lied again?
This is not the first time you are lying that you are going to die.
Lied and lied ... maybe I drew a white lie.
So you are not going to die?
For hell, Leif!
Take it easy.
Yeah, I overreacted maybe-
-But the doctor said "change your liver".
It can be interpreted freely.
My God, you are too fucking nymphomaniac!
-Hypocondrics, it's called.
-You have lied about you to die.
I have stolen money from a fucking robbery and thought you are going to die!
But I'll die.
Once, once I'll die.
All people die, so it might be good that you had to prepare yourself.
Yes, but ...
Yes, but sorry, then.
Sorry for ...
I'm just human, me too.
Good morning, thick-Leffe.
Did you sleep well?
Yes you, thick-leffe ...
I have been questioned by this new cop in Sörbäcken.
She has imagined that I am behind some fucking bank robbery.
The train station!
Run, then!
I've robbed a bank!
I've never seen so much money.
I have goose bumps in every corner.
Is it Biggest Loser final in town?
Nämen ... thank you, Leif.
The banknote has a serial number.
The banknote comes from the robbery in Sörbyn.
I got it in gear on the station.
Have you robbed a bank?
Are you absolutely sure it was him?
-What quick you were.
-Police, open the door!
First you will give me the money.
Then you can go to the police.
Although it is not possible.
The money is gone.
The police took the caravan, and the money was there.
-Have I gone here unnecessarily?
-No but...
What if I dump you in the lake?
Okay, the can, the money is.
We have dug them down.
Have you seen!
2-0 to albinon.
Pack your stuff, so we get.
-What the hell did you tell you so?
-I tried to buy us more time.
And pull out on the suffering?
It's great.
Come on now, for the hell!
Touch the fat pork.
Yes ... it was there.
Do you think I'm totally fucking stupid?
I know you are trying to fool me.
Do you know what I do with such?
Do it then!
You who should be so tough.
What the hell is it with you?
Move!
-What the hell is he talking about?
-It's his liver.
-What is it for the liver on the liver?
-It's totally fucking rotten.
The doctors do not want to give me a new one, so I have three months left.
Dad also died.
Yes, I regret.
But it is just to like the situation and go home.
You can hope that you will be able to die before the Kronofogden takes the kitchen.
Do you have Kronofogden on you too?
Yes.
If we do not fix 600,000 in a week, they will take the house from us.
Welcome to Leif Öhman's fucking pissuniversum.
I just want to go home.
For hell, uhman ... Are you going to give up so damn easy?
The whole fucking life I have tried to fix food in mouth on us two-
-But now it's run.
We are absolutely fucking pan.
For hell, where do you have the fighting glow?
You should die, and you intend to let the state take your house anyway.
I have a contact in Luleå who can fix some job for us.
It's not necessary.
It will surely work out.
What do you think the father would have done if he had been given the same chance?
Would he give up and let the brother continue without a roof over his head?
-Do you want to die like a mes?
-No, I don't want to die like a mes ...
What did you say?
Do you want to die like a mes?
No, I don't want to die like a MES!
How nice.
Then we go and talk to my contact.
I don't want to travel with the madman.
How would I know that his dad died of cirrhosis?
We must escape.
-Yes, we really have to.
-Then so, boys.
Now we go to Luleå.
-Hello.
-Jokkmokk police called earlier.
-They have seen Volvon drive towards Luleå.
-Have you put someone on it?
No...
Hell!
Is it just me working here?
Now you understand why I'm here.
You owe me a lot of money.
You will never forget anything.
You are like you.
I know I said it was not a rush, but ...
I get your thing.
There is a guy.
His name is the herring.
He owes me 600,000.
I owe you 500. Get them, and then you have to keep the rest.
Okay.
We'll fix it.
It's good that you are three.
He can be a little difficult, the herring.
He lives up on ...
What are you doing?
Nothing...
You just laid under the chair.
No, I did not.
Stand up.
Come here.
Come.
-What's that?
What's that?
-It's cords.
Okay.
Damn ...
-Take it up.
Pick it up, I said.
-Okay.
Keep it up.
-Do you know how much bacteria it has?
-No.
Stand up.
-Sit down.
-Okay.
Creep...
-Where were we somewhere?
-Sill owed you 600,000.
The herring owes me 600,000. You pick them up and keep everything.
I know he has the money at home.
-Sisten that you do not struggle with Anders.
-You know me.
Stick.
Dirt.
And touch nothing on the way out.
Billy, you follow me, and Leif stops and guard.
Billy, you can hang with the can.
-And why should I do it?
-You put us in this situation.
Look -cooked eggs ... The brother is dead.
Shouldn't he suffer that?
-Yes, though he's not even ... -But, please the egg ... I'm dying.
-Yes yes, okay!
-Good.
Tjena, the herring.
Calm and nice now.
Into the apartment.
You owe Anders's money.
Your fucking idiot, don't trust Anders.
I have no fucking money.
Billy, search the apartment.
No problem.
I'm just going to the herring and talk a little.
It is quiet.
Cursed ...
For fuck, Billy.
Where the hell is the money?
You're lying!
Damn Luffare!
-Are you an idiot?
Remove the money.
-I don't have them, I say!
So you come home to my fucking home and lace my money?
Damn stupid.
Anders has deceived you.
Go home to Norrland instead.
Do you think you own the whole world?
Do you know who I am?
Fucking herring!
Cursed ...
-What are you saying now, your little scarf?
-Leif, behind!
Put down the weapon before I shoot the pick off you.
Stand still, fucking drug.
-I saw, the can?
-Yes.
Remove us.
-Fan, what a satan bang!
Did you see?
-What fucking dream team we are!
-Staff at the station.
-Not now, Billy.
I'm about to shit.
Should I shit in the glove compartment?
-Let him shit.
It's the nerves.
-Okay then.
Leif, you saved my life in there.
Well ... that's what happens.
Not anyone has such stakes.
I will never forget it.
Thanks.
Hell ... It's that new thing from Sörbyn.
-What the hell ... -What hell is she doing here?
-Ring Billy.
We have to knit.
-Damn...
-Hurry up.
-Yes.
He has forgotten the phone in the car, the pea iron.
Damn!
Hey.
Two grilled with mustard and ketchup.
I am at the station at the 76th north of Luleå.
I have been aiming for the suspected Volvon and the robbers.
Request reinforcement.
Come.
-I send all cars directly.
-See them to rap.
What the hell are you doing, Billy?
-Where fuck is he?
-It takes time to squeeze the sausages.
Turn on some extra mustard so it runs.
-Yeah, is it sausage day?
-Yes.
There are few things that hit a grilled with bread, actually.
Yes, that's why I take two.
Just.
-Is it your 740 out there?
-Is there something fucking "Joppardy" game?
-Yes, it's mine and the brother's 740. -o, good car.
-Here are the sausages.
-Thousand thanks.
You can keep the gear.
Oh, thank you so much!
-WAVA, you forgot this.
-You can actually keep it.
I am a police officer.
I know that you are called Billy Öhman and that you stole the change at the robbery.
I also know that you were involved in a money -dread in Luleå.
They pull north.
I follow.
-There are two cops after us.
-Stay.
It's just as good to admit.
-No, dammit!
Drive now, Leif.
-I drive!
Take it easy.
-Come again, uhman!
Gas, for hell!
-We drive away!
Gas!
Shake off the snug devils!
-Leif, brake.
-Drive, drive, drive!
The cock!
-Brake, Leif!
-Drive, then!
I dropped them.
Ouch...
-Take it calmly, Leif.
-I am I alive?
-You live, but you've been sedated.
-No...
Billy, he's dead.
Billy is dead!
Billy is doing well, but we have had to interrogate him for a few days.
-Can I talk?
-Obvious.
- The doctor is coming soon.
How's it, Leif?
-I do not really know.
-It was a fucking story, huh?
I don't remember much.
I had something wrong with the brain.
Memorial loss.
You don't have to lie anymore.
He has already admitted everything.
-What then "recognized"?
-The bank robbery and the money back.
-Iven pea -brain.
-In fact.
The can was very cooperative.
-Wo?
Dunk, right?
-Yes, he acknowledged everything.
He had threatened you with a gun.
He had forced you to perform all these criminal acts.
Yes, just that ... now I'm starting to remember a little there.
Right...
Now you have to focus on resting yourself, and you will get through this.
-You are strong, Leif.
-Yes.
Then we say so.
The guys gravel ...
Yes ... yeah, so you should stay here now for a while, then?
Yes, six years I will shake grates.
The can, why did you put everything on?
Leif, you saved for my life.
That's the least I can do.
You two had not passed a day here-
-But for me it's like a second home.
Yes, you may be right.
The money, then?
Come here.
These are coordinates.
They will solve your problems with Kronofogden.
Okay.
Now you have to live in peace and quiet your last time in life.
Billy does not need a lot of debts.
Damn ... thank you, the can.
Thanks, the can.
Damn, Leif ... I'm sorry if I have been so piggy to you all year-
-But it's nothing personal.
It resolved pretty well in the end.
The debt is paid, and the house is ours.
Yes, damn what a nice.
I never want to leave Sörbäcken again.
Ever.
It's damn the best place on the whole globe.
Yes, that's fine.
It's damn nice, Billy.
-What the hell do you want?
-I wanted to hear your voice in there.
-I said I would put you there.
-You know that I handed in myself.
What about Billy?
It must be tough when Leif is gone.
-What do you mean?
-His liver must have been put off now.
His liver?
No, he's not sick.
I saw him at the pizzeria.
He stood and pushed for mash.
-So he's not sick?
-No.
Who told you that?
Hello?
The can?
Swedish text: Staffan Åhman Bti Studios for SVT