Billy!
Billy, step up now!
- Claim up!
- Take it quiet, Leif.
- Why don't you step up?
- I wanted to pull me for a while.
Lying and pulling, it's great ... what do you have under the blanket?
- Is it a beer?
-No.
- You don't lie and drink beer?
- Yeah, Satan!
There is no beer!
Stop it.
Ouch.
Fy fuck.
Snuffpelle.
Go and wash.
You should be at work in a quarter.
Yuk.
Well ... do you have a cup of coffee?
Not as you have been lying and filming you.
It was a regular morning stand.
I shit in if it was a sunbathing.
You should work, but lie and pill on yourself.
Where is the work ethic?
Why do I have to take the piss job?
If I didn't fix the house, it wouldn't be another day.
Roof tiles should be replaced, the elements knock, and the A-box is soon over.
Come now.
So, drive now.
Cursed ... Sew.
-Out.
-Okay.
I'll pick you up later.
Salad, tomato, onion, feferoni.
When the customer says "everything on", you take everything.
Hi, Billy.
This is Jerker.
He is responsible for the pizza salad.
And you should fold these.
Fold 500 pieces.
There are more in the warehouse.
Jerker, I'll show you how to make sauce.
Alone time ... what to find?
Maybe the old man wants to find something.
Well, welcome.
Maybe a little backrest ...
So...
It smells good.
Do you have a new perfume?
Louis Vuitton, I like it.
Well ...
Calm down, old man!
Maybe we should start by looking at something.
What does the company want to look at?
What did you say?
Oh, you have good taste.
I like that.
This one is good.
Watch the movie, you shouldn't sit and watch me.
This devil is good.
Horses and stuff.
It's tear.
I like you.
You are a good girl, straightforward.
Damn...
Oh!
Now it gets hot in the old man.
It might be time to move towards the bed room.
Mobile signal
Cursed ...
-Hello.
- Well, I'm.
It's so damn boring here.
I will soon kill myself.
What are you doing?
- I seal the roof.
What do you want?
- I just want to talk a little.
Gnawing
-What was that?
A horse?
-No.
Now a carpenter came in.
I have to hang up.
See you later.
Hello?
He does not understand that you need to have some lonely time, and be allowed to be yourself.
What do you crave?
Wine?
Beer?
Then I fix some beer.
Sit on, old man.
I'll be coming soon.
The beer is over.
What the hell...
No, I'm working.
It's not possible.
Calm down, I'll come.
Leif, what are you doing?
I need money for materials.
Can you get advance on the salary?
Advance?
It's my first day, I can't ask for advance.
- Do you want the house to collapse?
-No.
- Then maybe you should help.
- Yes, calm.
I may well ask.
Calm down.
- God, what embarrassing.
Here.
-Thanks.
Good work.
See you later.
- Tjena, Jerker.
-How is it going?
It's totally fucking useless.
So damn boring.
I'd rather have been home.
But what the hell?
Did he buy beer for the money, the damn latrine?
Do you want to help me with one thing, Jerker?
Well ... I really need the salary.
- How much do you earn in one day?
–200.
I can give you 300. Are you on?
Okay.
But the boss will never allow it.
See and learn, Jerker.
- Fuck ... hormos, come here!
–What disgusting.
Fy fuck.
I've got stomach ailment.
Jerker has infected me.
Out here, both.
Out!
Away.
Is that your brother?
Is it him we are going to fuck with?
Yeah.
I'm not going to let him lie down and laze himself the whole Dan-
- As I work my ass.
Now he should look at fuck.
Mobile signal
Hell...
–Leif.
- It's Billy.
What are you doing?
I sit a little inconvenient.
I'm up on the roof.
What do you want?
I was just going to check what you are doing.
You can't call all the time.
I have a lot to do.
I apologize.
I was just going to say that I'm working over today.
We have a lot to do.
How good you are.
Wow.
See ya.
Oh my God...
Then we get a little more time for each other.
Fy fuck.
- Jerker, run away.
Mobile signal
Leif Öhman.
It is from department ten on the psyche.
Then you called wrong.
We call people to tell you that a psychic man has escaped.
He was just seen in your neighborhoods.
So it's good if you lock doors and windows and keep you indoors.
Then we know.
Fuck!
Satan's Hell!
Has!
Get away from me.
I kill you.
Get off my yard.
Tvi.
Take it easy, the old man.
No problem.
Mobile signal
Cursed, what it rings all the time.
–Leif Öhman.
- It's from the psyche again.
I forgot to tell you that one should avoid eye contact with the man.
Why?
He is fatal.
He can't handle eye contact.
He wants to murder if he makes eye contact.
I think he was here exactly.
Hello!
Can you hear me?
Cursed.
- Yours, Leif.
- Where the hell are the shots for the rifle?
They ended last week.
Come here.
There is some psychopath here.
Say you got salmonella.
I can not hear what you're saying.
There seems to be bad reception.
- I have to continue working.
- Billy.
Hello!
Hell!
Sorry.
Okay, take it easy.
Think!
Calm, old man.
I'll fix this.
Fuck off!
Leave from here.
I have weapon.
I'm weaponized.
I'm Armed with ... Stick!
Calm down, baby.
Solbäck police.
An ax killer psychopath wants to kill me.
Stop it.
We don't have time with this.
He is getting into the house.
Send someone here!
It is best that it is for real.
Take it easy, baby.
It is perhaps now we may say goodbye.
No, stop!
Turn off.
Hey.
Is it Leif who has called?
Yes, he had some psychopathic madness after him.
It's just a prank.
- A prank?
-Yes.
Don't know what it is?
Yes, but we have more important things for us than to run after you.
Yes, it was stupid.
Sorry, the constable.
- Don't fuck this again.
-No I promise.
Never again.
Clear end, the constable.
Have a nice day.
Mobile signal
–Leif.
-Hello.
It is from the police station.
We have been prevented.
A tree has fallen down, so we can't come.
What the hell am I going to do?
Help me.
Say what to do.
Unfortunately, we can't do anything.
Bye.
Damn.
DAMN!
Satan!
Satan.
Okay, Jerker.
Now we run the last step.
Isn't it going a little too far?
- Do you want to have your money?
-Yes.
Come on here now.
Glass is crushed
Satan!
NO!
Satan.
Fuck!
We have to jump, honey.
I have no choice.
What the hell?
Follow and scare the shit out of him.
God cursed, Billy Öhman.
Billy, come fast!
Billy!
What the hell have you been doing?
- Leif!
- What the hell have you done?
- I said it went too far.
Take it easy, Leif, breathe.
Wake up, Leif.
The ambulance is coming soon.
He seems to suffer from post -traumatic stress.
It is important that he is not exposed to any strenuous activity.
Okay.
Thanks so much.
Now I'll take care of you, the brother.
You should not have to do anything.
I will help you with everything.
You'll be good again soon.
So.
Let's see...
So, then we go.
Can you stand?
Everything will be okay.
I'll never do it again, I promise.
Texting: Charlotte Engström (C) Swedish Television AB 2018