-How are you?
-What do you think?
I feel dizzy and feverish.
Now they will operate at two.
Operate?
You just got a scratch off that rifle ball in the ham?
The body is well in shock, or it is blood poisoning.
Yes ... Elin told you not to shoot at the can in front of the stone.
- It can be rich schett.
- Burk devil!
It was your fault.
You set the can obliquely.
Now I stay here for a long time.
They said I could pick you up at three.
You know how it is.
Once they cut into the body, they find other diseases.
In such an old body it can be anything.
I feel a lump.
-Can I see?
- Don't pill!
There will be a lot to fix in the yard for you when I'm gone.
- Remember to check the boiler.
- I keep track of that.
Turn off the stove when you leave home.
Now we have no home insurance, Billy.
Check twice when boiling coffee.
Maybe I should write this down.
Lets see.
- The boiler ... look if the post has come.
The mail.
Take a praise down to the swamp and witness the traps.
Check out the traps in the swamp ...
And dress warm, Billy.
If you also end up here, no one can take care of the yard.
- Dress me warmly ... - you don't have to write that!
Cough attack
-How is it?
Should I shout on someone?
-No.
They say that I will not stress myself too much.
Go and fix the yard.
Okay.
You should not have to worry about the farm, Leif.
I arrange everything.
Get on you, the brother.
Talk to you soon.
Hello then, Billy.
Should the little brother take care of the yard just by itself?
- Hi, Billy!
-Hi Elin.
What the hell?
He is doing all right.
I'll pick him up.
I'm fine for fucking int 'good!
- But should we go and have a drink for so long?
-It would be nice.
- I am so damn coffee.
- Something calls ... It's Leif.
Hi, Leif.
- Hallå, Billy.
Now it's bad.
-What has happened?
I was with the specialist.
It's not good at all.
They say I'm really sick.
We'll see if I survive the night.
- What are you too sick?
- Blood poisoning and bird flu.
But shit in it, Billy.
I can handle myself...
But my God, Leif!
Leif!
- The doctors say that Leif will not do well.
What?
After all, he had only got a little scratch.
This is really strange.
We talk to the doctors.
Come!
- Here he lies.
—Leif?
Hello?
Leif?
The brother?
- Are we getting too late?
Give me a sign, at least!
Damn, damn, Billy Ödman, you came back.
- The brother!
You are alive!
- I just saw the light.
- What is she doing there?
- We bumped into each other outside.
What have the doctors said?
It's really bad.
There are blood viruses, parasites and bird flu.
The body is declining.
Bird flu?
How did you get it?
It was well through that damn spirit you stopped.
Strange.
Are there no doctors here?
Elin, go int '!
I don't want more bad messages.
I just want to fall asleep.
-Do not say so.
- Now the light comes in the tunnel.
Focus!
Be with me!
Good, Leif.
Breathe with the abdomen.
I will help you.
Leif says he has received the bird flu and that he is dying.
He has only a little metal splits in the ham.
But ... so he doesn't have bird flu?
- Who told you?
- A doctor who took samples on me.
But it's just me here today.
How can I see the difference?
It was probably some specialist physician.
Or I hallucinated.
Here it just says that you have splits in the ham.
Just sounded very serious.
And now...
Leif, how are you, really?
Yes, what should I say?
It swayes in the skull and the inside measurement is weak.
I am eaten from the inside.
That light comes all the time against me.
I get to take more samples.
He remains overnight.
But now ... it still feels pretty good.
How nice.
Now everything released.
Billy, you can pick me up at three anyway.
No, you stay here.
Billy, then we pull.
- You can do your job.
We hear when you know more.
-Absolutely.
I'll let you know.
- Yes, but we ...
Remember to arrange everything in the yard, Billy.
When you touch my arm I get tenderness
When I see how you smile with your beauty
When you say that everything
will be arranged in the end
When I see that you love
I get love
When you lie with me I get close
Satan!
You whisper to me words about faithfulness
What the hell!
When you see all the beautiful in the world as you do
The little brother and I ...
When you give everything you own
I get love
BUSY TONE
Well, you find a new company when the brother is for death.
Cursed, Billy.
Now it's enough!
Tonight, tonight came and give, come and take
Come and dance with me you are all i want
Nothing we do is tabu nothing stops us now
Damn.
Leif!
What are you doing?
God, damn ...
Leif!
Tjena, thick-Leffe.
A naked man is a naked man
I dress i dress up naked
Here I am
SWEDISH SUPPORT: SVT Subtitle (C) Swedish Television AB 2017