Sven-Eric's "every little dream"
-What a nice time that the a-box is back.
- It was three damn tough months.
You have hardly been able to eat.
Check, Leif.
What a idiocy!
Imagine people go on such hocus pocus.
- No, Leif.
-Quiet!
I'll just look what she can do.
Don't get rid of the entire A-box right away!
- Oh my God...
Hello?
Hello!
What can I help you with?
Can you look into the future?
I can look into the future.
Sit down!
Okay.
I would like to see twenty years into the future.
How I look, how much money I have, if I have children and wife.
It's just running!
-It costs money.
- Yeah, how much?
- Two thousand SEK.
- It's pure robbery.
I can do a tarot reading for 400 bucks.
No, nothing like that.
Wait, then I'll see ...
Don't get rid of the entire A-box.
Run, then!
Okay.
- Then I want you to close your eyes.
-Okay.
And then you have them closed throughout the session.
Nasty laugh
What the hell?!
After all, a shit has not happened here.
Same old fucking shit stuff.
RATTLING
I may have a small family anyway.
- Tjena, Leif!
- What is the food ate?
- To you and me.
- It's a lot of food to be ...
-What?
- You look like a ...
A pregnant hippopotamus?
A crowbar with obesity, a waterlike-
- Something with sex lines in the stomach?
What will it be this time?
Come on something new!
Move!
No!
Oh my God.
Oh no, Billy ... - Can you change the future?
Obvious.
But we have to steer our lives in the right direction.
All the choices we make affect our future - more than we think.
Thanks.
How did it go?
-What the hell are you doing?!
- Release the sausages!
Oh my God...
- You can't throw out the sausages.
- There are things you don't understand.
We have to change some things in our lives.
Just be quiet!
Now there is mustard on the gear lever.
-Hello?
What are you looking for?
- Father's old training trunk.
-Hello!
Leif.
- Fuck!
- Come, Billy!
-Oh my God...
- See!
- I don't intend to eat that.
- See, Billy!
-Okay.
One?
But what...?
Ouch!
Leif.
Swallow!
Then you take this and then you train.
Continuously.
You will thank me, the brother.
Ouch!
-You are back.
- I have made changes.
Watch me!
-Money.
- Can I get a discount?
Well.
Yes Yes...
Look, get started!
What the hell...?
What the hell am I somewhere?
Billy.
- Little brother ... - don't touch me, fucking pig!
What the hell do you want me, Leif?
What the hell are you doing on Kumla?
-Are you kidding me?
What do you want from me?!
- Why are you in prison?
Don't play games with me, your rat!
You made me become anabolic cod.
Then you forced me to sell, and now I'm sitting here.
It's your fault!
- Conduct, I didn't know.
- Are you here to have fun with me?
You are dead to me.
I never want to see your fucking Nylle here again.
Do you understand?
Sorry, Billy.
I'm finished!
Open!
Leif, what the hell do you want me?!
Respond!
Oh no!
This is fun.
I have passed 30 in line.
- No, get it here!
- Slip!
What are you doing?
-What are you doing?
- You will never understand.
–Leif ... —Sist!
What are you doing?
-What the hell are you doing?!
- We should not do things like that.
There are many bids now.
What the hell am I going to do?!
Lend a hand!
Use the brain for something good, but we should not exercise.
You are good on your computer.
Can't you do anything good on the computer?
- Play, or?
- No, no fucking game.
I don't want you to end up in some fucking gaming abuse.
Shares!
- Shares, Billy!
There we have it.
-Shares?
I have 300 on the card.
Insert it on the web and try to make money.
Post them on some fucking site.
This is going to go, the brother.
Watch me!
- It costs two thousand, you know.
-Oh my God!
Don't be so fucking greedy.
Give me some quantity discount.
I can give you a tarot reading or crystal healing.
- I want to look into the future.
- Then two thousand apply.
You are welcome.
Look so, come on!
Set up the damn ritual now.
I managed.
YES!
Billy.
Well, what about everything, with work and health and so on?
How does it feel to run a stock empire?
Yes, it feels damn good, if you say so.
Wow, run stock empire ... Leif, your devil, you did.
-What did you say?
- No, I didn't say anything.
- Fun to see you, the brother.
-The same.
Do you remember when we had such a scrap truck?
We traveled around like two takers in town.
–What do you mushrooms?
It's your car.
–What my car?
You have been driving around that fucking scraper for 40 years.
But is that our house?
Leif, it's my house.
You have your house left in Sörbäcken.
- Have you stopped the medicine again?
- We share brotherly on everything?
Yes, we did it - until you threw me out.
I probably would not have been able to pay for all the food you are pouring into you.
What do you swam about?
Yes.
I look like a pregnant hippopotamus.
Quiet.
You have looked like that for 15 years.
Oh my God!
No...
-Sit down.
You can't stand up.
--Neej ...
What happened?
What did you see?
I will be back soon.
Hell, hell ...
-What the hell...?
- She went 20 minutes ago.
- She has been able to throw again.
-Who?
Spåtanten?
-Yes.
She has gone around and cheated people.
–What, how do you mean?
She uses a drug, so people think they can look into the future.
A scam.
Have you had contact with her?
No, I haven't ... Such a fucking mumbojumbo I don't do.
-Good.
- Jaw?
- Yes, easy!
- What are you going to do with them?
-Nothing.
-Good!
I deduct it from your debt.
- Snip, I need the money.
You have been criticizing me for three years.
Time to start paying back.
-Come on.
-I do not want to hear!
Oh!
Now the bills have come.
We have expenses at 14,300. Not gracious.
Lucky you got the A-box.
Texting: Elin Törnqvist (C) Swedish Television AB 2019