My name is Yadgar.
I am 23 years old
And goes on the third year of civil engineering in computer technology.
Should you make a computer game and want to simulate reality,
Is it very important that you understand the physics behind reality, so you can reflect it in the computer.
When I started, I had not coded a single line of code.
Never programmed in my entire life.
Without just after a year, I would say that most are as competent as those who coded before.
It was a course.
We would make a sea rescue weavers.
The hovercraft could get out on water, to a point.
Save someone or something and then get back to land again.
And it would be managed autonomously.
We just tell it which punk it is going to, so the hovercraft solves the rest himself.
It was incredibly rewarding.
I learned a lot of new practical knowledge.
There are, after all, Liu alums in every corner of the world,
Who works for companies like SpaceX, Google, Tesla, Apple, Microsoft.
I think this shows the confidence the business community has on the engineers who are trained here.
14 different master orientations!
I simply went on feeling and took what I thought was most interesting.
IT security.
It's like an opponent you have.
You should protect a network or company.
I find a big drive in it.
Only you have the interest, the rest takes care of the education!