Many who start at universities come directly from high school.
What is the biggest difference between high school and university?
There is very much own responsibility at the university.
Nobody will chatter on one when things are to be submitted, but you have to keep track of yourself.
But I think you get a lot of support in the beginning, on the civil engineering program.
You get a lot of help with the mat and you get good instructions on how the exam should go to and what tools you can have.
So you get a lot of help.
But then when you get into it you can not count on the same support.
So much own responsibility.
What do you think Maja?
On the teacher program we read one course at a time.
So what is different is that you can focus on one thing at a time.
This means that you can immerse yourself in the subject and really focus on what you should learn.
I think it's good.
Focus on one thing at a time and not 16 different subjects.
I will try to understand then when I come out as a high school teacher.
But can't it be boring to just read one thing?
Isn't it getting tired?
Each substance is still quite wide, e.g.
religion.
The thing you read religious history to five different world religions, however, the pace becomes high.
Then you move on to eg.
Bible science becomes the large areas of that subject.
High tempo but fun.
The subjects are then perhaps wider than you think of high school, so it will not be boring.
What did you experience as the biggest difference Alexander?
About the same thing.
It is a lot of self -responsibility.
There are compulsory parts, but you do not have to attend all lectures.
You have to spend a lot of your own time studying.
The biggest difference now is that you read things that you are actually interested in.
In high school there were things that were a little less interesting, but you still had to read it.
But here you choose the subject because you are interested in it.
Everything becomes relevant.
You read more fun things.
But is everything fun then?
There are things that are less fun of course, but that are still important.
When you read 5.5 years you can specialize in as many different things as possible.
Everything will not be fun, but on the whole it is fun.
In high school you often know the teachers well and the classes are small.
Is it so on lectures?
It may look very different.
Some courses we only read the subject teachers together.
We read some courses with other programs as well.
So sometimes we are 100 people and sometimes we are 30.
How's it for you ina?
I would say that we get close contact with our lecturers.
We are also different numbers, but often we have lessons in smaller groups, so you get close and get to know each other.
Is it so on the medical program too?
It varies some.
In my class there are about 150 people.
It will be a little difficult to have the same contact with the teachers you had in high school.
But we also have basic group opportunities, where we have supervisors who are lecturers.
So then you get closer to them.
Many teachers are part of so-called theme groups that design lectures and elements in the education.
If you are involved you can meet them, so there are many different ways to get similar contact as in high school.
Many teachers are very committed.
There is always a conversation between teachers and students, which is important.
It sounds like it can vary between larger and smaller classes.