Hello there!
Welcome to debate in Lund!
Some think it's chill
to write as one speaks,
Others are a little more Old School and freaks out
When new generations say something that is Cringe.
So should one let the language go with the flow or should swedish teacher continue
And fight to teach them and them instead of them to today's young people?
What is the signal value really with a correct language costume?
To really master
Swedish in the traditional way?
If more people write wrong, will it eventually be correct?
And who decides that?
About fine language and ugly language is this day's debate in Lund.
The language as a class marker is something that we should take a closer look at as well.
What debate in Lund is for something, I expect many of you who follow in television know
and certainly all of you who are
Here at the Grand Hotel as well.
This increasingly rich forum we see as a place for Lund University
sharpest brains and carefully selected guests to discuss what might be right or wrong,
or true or false.
And I think many of you who are here today are well acquainted with debate in Lund
after more than a decade.
It's no stranger than that.
Four experts are discussing a topic
Without the slightest fear of making it more complicated than it already was.
This, my friends, is the equivalent of Tiktok but the opposite.
My name is Andreas Ekström and I am often found at Sydsvenskan but it is Lund University
And especially the Faculty of Social Sciences, which hosts debate in Lund.
Today's discussion is about language.
Cane horses you could say and you should not imagine anything
All of you who are here in this crowded hall, which cane horses did you ride here?
Anyone want to shout just?
What is your linguistic cane horse?
Judgment.
What did we have in the back?
Don't be shy now!
Specials yes!
You don't have to make it tonight anyway
Because this is oral so they do not hear, it is a great advantage for you.
I am convinced that we all have our different ones.
Right now, where we are in time, I am struggling with "Mello".
Melodifestivalen spelled with an L, "Mello" with two L and it's so incredibly infantile
That you can't use the whole word so I sit and stay in the table.
Even the newspapers' telegram agency has switched to writing "Mello" in its reports.
I will lose that battle too.
I guess you feel the same way.
We also have some people with us on stage here
Who knows differently about such things.
Cane horses have them, I can promise, but also quite different views on what
can be nice and ugly language and the value of both the conservative
And the progressive attitude.
First and foremost, closest to me we meet Anna Gustafsson who is an associate professor and associate professor
In the Swedish language with a background in the editorial staff for SAOB, the Swedish Academy Dictionary.
Welcome Anna!
Many of you certainly recognize Ola Wikander, who is an associate professor of Bible science
And expert in extinct language.
Welcome!
We are also very happy to have the linguist and the writer
For the book "Handbook for Language Police" here, Sara Lövestam!
Last but not least, experienced Swedish teacher from the Cathedral School, high school here in Lund,
Here we have Daniel Sandin, welcome!
You know what?
I actually assume that you love language.
You do that huh?
Why?
Something is it that has brought you
To the place where you devote your life to this.
Do you want to start Daniel?
Where does love come from?
Where would I be without language?
Without language I would not be me, I think.
Without language, no one would be in here who we are.
No one would have been people without language.
It is simply the origin of life for you?
Yes...
It is almost existential now that I hear myself speak.
But the fact is yes,
It feels like it's so important.
Everything that happens in here can not be something but the language I dress it in words with.
And without the language I probably would not have thought either.
What does Sara say then?
Where does your love come from?
It is difficult to even
say for this special interest,
I have had that whole life.
I cared so incredibly much about
Language from I was two
and therefore it is difficult to say where it comes from
As I see in language,
So it is that it is ...
It is a nothing but an agreement
between all the people who speak a particular language.
Had we not agreed
Then we could not use it and then it had not existed.
So it's like
the most intricate, complicated and universal agreement that exists
And I don't understand how someone can't be interested in it.
Welcome to Lund University!
Here are thousands of employees who feel exactly so for their subject.
Ola Wikander, you are one of them, associate professor just in Bible science.
But you
is known in popular culture for your love for many
Language and extinct language, not least.
Where does this come from?
Yes, just to pick up what you said, this with humanity.
One of my private favorite thinkers, who was not a language philosopher, is Louis-Claude de Saint-Martin.
He used to say something style with that
"We must explain the world from man and not man from the world",
Which is a rather radical humanistic position.
If you say so, what is most typically
For man really as we see?
Yes, the language.
We cannot express anything without the linguistic
and that makes it if we want to be in any sense of the word humanists
and explain the world and man in any sense
so we have to take the language by the horns, to use a strange catakres,
but but,
Yes, because it is the most human we have so I agree with it and
Not only
I as a human being without man with great m
is the speaking ...
Yes, that's enough.
Really.
But then I am very fond of taking the language by the horns, then I immediately become very happy,
better than...
It was both good and bad at the same time in some way.
Rather a bird in hand before jumping over the hedge.
Yes yes, you mix them up there, I love this, very nice.
Anna, you've gone all the way.
Swedish Academy Dictionary and Research,
why?
Why?
So I have to tie a little to the gang here but I think it is ...
We have all been there to
We try to find words to
describe what we know or what we think and
had difficulty for it,
I think.
Everyone also has the experience of this.
It has probably been a driving force,
Interest in the language.
But then it probably has come to be
How the language becomes the link to other people, how we understand each other.
From the dictionary and the different meanings of words, how you can perceive words
in different ways depending on which contexts,
which persons that pronounces them, in which meetings they occur to
How we interpret impendings in political communication.
So it has always been this link to others and how we understand each other.
Just that, what you say with political communication,
It has become a whole science
just as a citizen that one must be observant
On "We BRAKE WITH US", "We review our routines", "Yes, I hear what you say", all these empty ...
"I hear what you say" just means I see you talk.
I love all these expressions and what I want to ask you is of course
If you have that observance?
Can you really participate in regular conversations without the research brain ticking?
No, that does not work.
Absolutely not.
It's easy to start as well,
You are looking for implications everywhere.
I have devoted myself to this pretty much lately to
to think about what is implied in political communication,
Especially in connection with the election this fall.
Because the debate we have received now
that is so fast,
compressed, we have like
Twitter posts with vocabulary or instagram posts or
TV debate times that are time-limited, you get to talk for 30 seconds.
People react to single
Words that become signal on such [explosion sound].
Yes, that too, but it is also the case that as a politician you have to penetrate something
Instead of saying, and now I'm going to give a very short example:
In Sweden there are parallel communities.
Parallel societies have their own legal system.
This legal system is a threat to our society.
There are three statements, one can go against each of them
If you listen.
You could say: "Stop, is there really a legal system there?"
Instead, you compress this to a single sentence that is perhaps:
Parallel communities in Sweden
With their own legal systems is a threat.
So the one who will then respond to it must respond to the claim in a threat.
It requires much more of the one who listens to pick up these underpriced things
In text that says parallel communities in a specific form,
What do you mean by that?
You don't
and then the heavenly mass of subordinates becomes that
Sprinkled on.
What you say is that a good linguistic science is immediately
Politically important?
I mean absolutely
And I really meant that this one
the competence to see it as being understood
is some kind
Civil armor
which everyone should be trained in.
Yes, it is interesting because this is something that we have talked a lot about in other types of debates,
Thus, political polarization and media logic that we have also debated here in debate in Lund.
What the language does with one's understanding is something that we should go into deeper but also
where you place yourself as a human being, who do you then become as voter and
as a citizen.
We had another debate here that was about meritocracy,
Very much our students here at the university.
How do you qualify best if you think about one career in one or the other?
And what should be measured and what should be important?
It was probably a year ago or so, you can check it through the web if you want.
But then I ask this then:
To what extent is
A good language merit?
Very loud, the highest.
Because that's what we have.
I think everyone could have responded to this with humanity.
That's what we have.
We have nothing else to convey our expertise
And our knowledge in something than the language.
So we can't convey it then ...
Yes, but I now think of my old ones, I have a background as a SFI teacher
and precisely the experience of all sitting there, adult students in an SFI classroom
that have so many adult abilities, knowledge
and so the only thing they can say
"When does the bus leave?,
"What time is it?"
And so you have all this.
So yes, it is quite telling how much the language controls how you are perceived.
If you ever fight Daniel by motivating your students by plugging into the next sample,
Do you use the future argument a lot?
So because
See that this you need this, you will not be able to write good job applications,
You will not be able to write good home tentor.
I do that of course but I don't think they take it
because it lies like in the age of age and
The nature of youth not to really see those arguments.
But I am convinced, that is that
Builds my vision of what is incredibly important.
I want to give them, as we certainly come in at later, not to
back too much but really stand up to that it is so
Incredibly important
Being able to express oneself,
Incredibly important to master language
as they perceive is old -fashioned or passé.
For it provides access to arenas that
They may not even know that they will need it but they will need it.
But explaining to them that it is important is very difficult
Because they don't have the tools to understand it always.
Sometimes, sometimes not.
But sometimes I think that we don't understand either.
Just as you say, that's what we have.
Language is the most important work tool for a lot of professions that do not think about it.
So doctors, how do they know how the patient is doing?
Yes, the language.
A rather different language than they themselves are used to formulating these things in so it becomes
Some kind of double -speaking between that situation.
Just!
Then you have to have your own and be able to understand ...
One must be able to have the analytical scientific language running in the brain
While hearing the patient tell with other terminology.
It is a fairly sophisticated situation there.
This really applies to a lot of working groups.
You simply have to be an educator.
Ola, you said a word there, double -lust.
What was the nice word for that?
Diglossi.
Diglossi, then I have learned the first new words of the evening.
I note this, nice.
Cucumber you had before.
Cucumber, that's before we started with the TV broadcast,
I'll just say it to the poor TV audience.
Now everyone sits here wondering what it is.
We do not intend to talk about this but now we continue with ours.
Anna, you have identified differences
in word knowledge
between generations not least.
I know you did a study on this.
Can't you tell us a little bit about what it was you learned?
Yes.
That was me and David Håkansson in
Uppsala who did a study of the college exam.
We looked at how the comprehension of word on the college exam had over time between
in 2000 and 2011.
Then we could see ...
This is like a somewhat difficult method because there are new words that are tested every year but
All the words that are being tested have also been performed and then we could compare the pre -tests
With regular tests, so to speak.
Then we could see that the comprehension of word
in the younger generation and in the older generation,
And we say that the younger one is below 25 and the older one is 40 plus, went apart.
It is the college exam we are talking about here, so you have to think from that perspective.
They went apart, the distance between the generations increased during this period.
And what happened as we went closer and looked at these results was to
the younger generation
lost understanding of Germanic and Nordic words.
It was mainly there that it went down.
That's the English influence then?
Yes, or it is that they do not read that type of text where those words are.
Say news texts or newspaper texts simply.
However, it was pretty even
In the understanding of English words,
There, their understanding stood.
So that what happened was really the understanding of old Swedish words,
I have actually marked here
Which words went down the most.
Post, culvert strange enough,
withdrawal,
tedious,
warn,
exist.
So words like man ...
Bureaucratic embossed Germanic words.
In addition, but also as you can find in some news texts.
We had chosen words, we have not examined all the words but words that appear in newspapers,
So it was our selection criteria.
Serious words simply.
Serious words.
It made an effort.
But something I have noticed
When I have been out, I am not just about language but I write novels, after all,
so i'm out and hold
Printer workshop for children and young people
and then I have
A rule that it can only be volunteers who come for us to have a good time together.
So there will only be enthusiastic young people who want to write on their sports holiday.
So you start with any writing exercise
And then there are always a few
Which says "Yes, I usually write in English".
And that is
people with Swedish parents, they do not go in English school or so without them
Writing in English.
This is something that I was not so used to ten years ago but now I am the giant.
I talked to two 14-year-olds for not long time
Who told them that they are in the process of writing a book together.
Yes, what fun I said, pepper them.
What is it about?
"We write in English because we can do better."
And these 14-year-olds, I know them.
They have all Swedish parents, speak Swedish at home
so I asked “How can you
Say you know English better? ”
"No, but we're watching English series and is on Tiktok."
What is the book about then? "" Yes, this is a word I cannot in Swedish but scientist. "
I only "scientist!".
There I almost went into angry aunt fashion.
What is the loss of domain?
And that the domain was kind of everything.
Although not that the domain is exciting fiction?
Just those people, I can a little recognize myself in my teens here if I am to be completely
Wicked to myself.
No but if you have been flushed by
popular culture in a language
Then that domain becomes natural and the Swede sounds a bit like that.
Yes, so many people have read fantasy.
I would get into it.
So if you have a background in where you have read very fantastic just,
Not just fantastic, but literature with bombastic tone.
This something I've argued about in different contexts that bother me,
to Swedish language
or literature policy perhaps, not language policy,
have been a bit negative in recent years against the big -wise one,
which is more of in English language area and it can make you just when you take in so
In Swedish you feel a little pathetic.
But Ola, isn't that if you say "I love you" as a mother tongue speaker
So it comes to one but "I love you" costs no more than thanks for the coffee.
It is a huge difference, such as swearing, to say fuck as Swedish
It costs nothing for almost anyone in the room.
There was any shocked native speaker who felt the inappropriate
But all of you who are Swedes do not know the roughness of the swearing in the same way.
Don't it do with it?
That one is distancing with one's second language
And that can be an advantage with that then?
I was going to have fun now and say yes, we have even written professional books.
Sorry, we are in Lund, not Gothenburg.
But, so it is and not least with the word shit
Which is a very strong swear word in English.
Really,
Not to mention the so-called F-word that can make Americans completely terrified and
So people in Sweden pronounce it in school yards and everywhere.
But just shit, there I have to tell you a fun thing I was with.
I wrote an interview text, this is 15 years ago, and interviewed
A young lady who had been accepted as a priest.
She had been with the bishop and attended the education here in Lund.
So I asked what she was thinking when she came out and learned that she had been accepted.
"Ahh, I thought Shit what a thing!"
Of course, I could write that.
But this text would be included in a book that would also be made in English
So this text would be translated into English.
Then I realize what a dilemma.
She can't say it in English.
HOT DARN!
Oh right.
What will then be the right level for a Swedish
20-year-old's use of the word shit
But in English?
And since it was the bishop and a priest, it wasn't my idea, it was the brilliant translator
With Holy Cow.
Great!
You have to give them that, it was neat.
Holy Moly!
Yes but very good so.
Then we have concluded and it is really quite obvious that you are interpreted
for how good man is and one is valued meritocratically
For how good you are in the language.
You know that too Daniel, you have observed in
American Academic Worlds Now where one is starting to discuss whether to release
it a bit and let the traditionally black American English
where you turn on the negations and so on, we might start accepting it
At High School and at University.
What do you think about it?
I mean, I think
Accepting one may well do, thus,
But one should be aware of where it leads to.
Let's say you write a text that you want to be taken seriously and reach out with
So I don't believe that
It is a good method to write it on
Even if it expresses someone ...
Thus, language again conveys something, it conveys an identity.
That way you convey my identity.
But if you go into the academic world, I think too ...
You have to convey the academic identity, this is to reach out.
And then there are
All the unions, you have to like ...
I mean, right away when Ola said that deglossia
So he immediately talks about "I'm a little knowledgeable here".
It applies to both myself and ...
It's signal value and you ask, I think it's very important
Being aware of what you do with the language.
So I should not say that you should or should not.
Who should ban it?
But one should be aware that
how to write affects
What reception you get.
But the question is really, because to some extent you represent Swedish high school,
So it is what line it prefers, then drives.
I would tell my students to write you so but expect nothing
good job or any prominent career.
You need to learn the codes so you can choose,
Then you can be in the system and choose language or choose to go against the power
And do something else and then it is a conscious decision.
It is an important point that is because so fast
Someone thinks that now we'll make a reform about something
So there will always be some people who get stuck there.
There is one thing with the people who
mastered both for and after so well
so that they can only switch and, if necessary, switch back when they end up another social
context or in a more language conservative environment or whatever.
But those who get stuck, they are those who don't have
that double -speaking and can't do it.
And is told that no but now it is okay to write
What was not okay to write for a week.
Well, they think fun, then I do it but at the same time there is this large population
that has not internalized, got the message, to speak Swengel,
and they will so see just these people
And treat them in a certain way.
You often take this up with language simplification,
I have been discussion with different people about this, as some kind of ...
Equalizer then.
Yes, a class equalizer but I think it risks going to just the opposite direction
because what it does is to
those who bring with them both the traditional and the easy -going can
swim lightly in those waters and know
easily how to switch between a
One style form to another for example, one spelling method to another.
But those who don't have it
marks directly what they end up and get no help with that
learn to navigate.
This sounds a bit like this classic argument from the left in Sweden to
We should not have too much grades in school because it points out those who are weak.
The counter -argument has been that yes, we should have grades because those who do not have
resources with them from home,
It is their chance to get around formal meritocracy, it is a bit like that argument,
That it becomes a tool with the formal.
So the difference, without giving me into any grading discussion ...
The difference is that,
To take this example that I hope we will not talk too much about tonight
Because I'm tired of it, namely they and them,
You can benefit from being able to do that.
That there was a certain rating when you went to eight and you don't have much benefit from the rest of your life,
If I can be a crass.
But these language skills functions, you can actually use them for something.
I wanted to keep talking about American to
Actually, the written language is for us to have,
It should be a language that is a bit washed
From speech -speaking contamination, you might say.
Or you understand, there is a standard for it.
We pronounce all words different but we spell them the same way it is a type of standardization
which is certainly built on very much who had
The highest status when this was established but it is still the type of function it should have.
Afro-American variation of American English,
It has its own grammar and everything
So then the question is, you have to give it ...
Respects and everything, it's really cool!
Yes exactly!
But then the question is,
Should you then have it as a variant?
Then it should receive a language status,
Do you understand what I mean?
It's not just one ...
Not just a dialect status because a dialect is still written
When you write, do you understand what I mean?
Then it becomes Tornedal Finnish as well,
minority language status.
Thanks so much!
Do you think it would have a minority language status?
Is it like the extremely that,
That it should all the way to make it ...
If so.
Sure, why not?
But you, Ola, you mentioned it,
This whole question of objects and subject form for personal pronouns
in third person in plural,
That is, they and them.
I saw that someone had written so well the other day
"Those who cannot distinguish between them and they will get their judgment".
Elegant formulated!
Okay, now we take it.
We just take it, we have to anyway, you understand that.
Okay, Anna.
They or them, how should we do?
I think we have already been into it.
I agree with this, somehow we can't start school.
We cannot start with the teachers stop teaching it, it must somehow start
from the other side.
I have no strong feelings about them and them, they!
It was a unique position in the debate, I must say that.
The name, the language changes and
Soon we will change
To them straight over.
It has been good in spoken language for maybe 100 years when we have not made a difference
And we have nevertheless understood each other.
It's the central to me.
Ola, how should we do?
Thus, what I always want to say on this issue is that nothing is determined
And nothing is natural.
All this has to do with language ideological and language policy considerations
And that change has taken place has no moral implication in any way.
Which means we are in the unique situation that
We can choose and then I think we can well learn growing generations
To master that standard whether they speak as Finns or not.
Just that, for Finnish Swedes still do.
Well, not all but some do.
My grandmother who was very Scanian made the difference in speech.
But anyway,
What annoys me in this discussion it is when you make it
Like that there is some kind of pure automation,
that by the fact that
The majority speech has lost this distinction a long time ago,
Which is completely empirical correct, there is no discussion about it.
Thus, some kind of morality follows
to change the written language.
No!
It just doesn't!
Oh!
It holds against?
Absolutely!
And that is what I am committed to, this notion of an automatism.
But is it really a moral argument?
It is not rather about ...
Yes, but a little it is.
"You make it too difficult for the growing up ...".
In fact, 40 % of teachers have already stopped teaching elementary school or accepted this.
Then it is a choice they have made.
In addition, we can note that in the 80s, when I was a little PAG,
Then it was a lot of journalists who wrote them
And then they stopped it.
It is the same with the so-called modern spelling in the early 1900s
When they wrote "Say" for themselves,
Dan Andersson does so for example.
But not many people write plural forms now
Without there, there are some things that disappear.
The name of course and sooner or later you take such ...
It is a very good example,
It lasted a few hundred years in writing after it began to die out in speech
And then someone made a decision and then it went pretty fast.
We have had spelling reforms of various kinds, even in other countries.
But now I also want to hear what Sara and Daniel say here, how should we do?
I don't really have strong feelings either, but I see it as we stand a little at a crossroads.
That either we release them freely
or so we get
plague
teaching both young and old and somehow
Start promotions, as well as a Swedish tiger size on that campaign
There are studies, there are not much studies actually on
How much more mistakes are made on them and them, there are not so many.
I know that Lena Lind Palicki and Susanna Karlsson
have done but then they have done studies on
people who go for the third year on theoretical programs
in high school and it is perhaps a group that is quite
Easy to turn.
I have done
Own personal studies to have some fun on the weekend
So then I have been sitting and downloaded big text tjog
from family life.se and from flashback
And then I have taken texttjog from 2004 when family life started
and some from 2022 and taken out all of them and them
and compared to each other.
You can do this at home!
And then checked how many ...
It is a small ground, I only had a few hours on Sunday to do this but
on it turned out that there was not much difference in 2004 to 2022 except
in the case of a specific article.
Good audience!
There is a person at the front who said "I knew it!".
Well, for those who have temporarily forgotten a definite article,
So when you say
"The half -full glasses on the tables",
that, according to my little study, one
So it is more common to write now
"The half -full glasses" and there was not anywhere in my material from 2004.
So maybe something is happening and maybe we're on our way to this particular crossroads
Where we have to choose.
I happened to start one like that debate
In the media that dealt with you and them.
It was because one, I had a deadline
and two, I was so annoyed at that
A highly educated friend I have in my 50s does not know the difference, she writes the wrong time.
Then I thought, this judgment reform just can't come
so that we do not have this and that was what I would come to, that there is
not so many investigations into where it is heading with them and them
But there are surveys showing that those who become annoyed,
They become more annoyed at a misused they or them than a widely used judgment.
Can you match in passion Daniel?
How should we do?
I think I can match the passion actually ...
No, but like this: we might be at a crossroads but I think there is also that there is
Other perspectives on this.
It's not just them and them, it pretty much in the language
which is difficult.
I mean, it's not very hard to learn the difference between them and them,
Apart from your academic colleague.
But most people who have reasonable knowledge of the language handle it, it is not very strange.
What is required are teachers who teach the young people, the children,
to manage subject and object forms in writing.
It's no stranger than that.
The problem is something else that I see it,
That it becomes like an educational issue.
That we have such a large proportion early in elementary school
Teachers who themselves do not master them and them.
Then you are facing a crossroads.
Should we resign one because we have a teaching profession ...
I know, I stand out
Hakan here a bit as a teacher but I think ...
If so many
Teacher do not manage themselves and them
Without choosing to write them, it is clear that the children will write them.
So you get up to high school and so:
"Yes, we always had to write them, it went well ..."
I just mean that it's a question
And when we talk about these stuff we talk, I mean the SJ sounds,
Why should we spell the SJ sounds in seventy-eleven different ways?
It's pretty hard to learn.
Not for us anymore because we have learned but for the children, our only generation of young people
Must learn every word with spelling about it ...
Yes, you know how many SJ sound it is.
After all, it was a bit tricky, there are no direct rules.
But this is also associated with another thing,
Namely, the learning of what usually becomes our third language in Swedish.
Because if you can't these basic grammatical things
Do you get pretty tough to learn German if you try to do it when you are sixteen
If you are not clear to you the difference between accusative and dative,
A toolbox is needed to take on what often becomes our third or fourth language
After Swedish and English.
Or that's when you get it.
Now, not many people have read German, I do not know how it is right now,
But at least it's my experience that
That's when you learned grammar when you started reading German.
Or Spanish or French.
Because it was not needed in the same way, it is not necessary for one's own native language in the same way.
I think Saras
Students at the writing courses who want to write in English, do they have problems with They and TheM?
It really is no big question really
But there is quite a lot else that comes with
And maybe there are signs of something we don't want, I think.
Like a view of education, language.
Because it is not just remove your
Back compatibility as well.
By removing them and them we also give a whole new generation
It is more difficult to read everything that is written back in time.
There are such aspects, in the same way as we would pie SJ sounds
If we remove them because it's so hard
for young people to learn.
Because that is the only argument for removing, because it is a bit difficult.
Not only, it is also that we do not make that distinction in speech.
I listened to Mumin, it was wonderful but I know it's a minority Finnish Swede
But it is still honest.
You Ola, I am fascinated by saying, crossroads you agree,
But Ola said we are in a election situation as well.
Because something none of you have said
but as one often hears in the debate it is
"But they are unstoppable, it will still be so."
That is, that is what we can call the cannabis argument,
"People still smoke, we have to make the shit, it can't do anything else."
But I don't look at it.
I have flirted with that argument but then I do not think it is a natural force
Without me, I think more according to our tradition of language changes.
That the Swedish language has often chosen
the road that follows the spoken language.
It is a remarkable conservative position you take now.
Exactly, I was just going to say that on the contrary,
that the one who says no in this,
Now we shall stop following the spoken language in writing
As we have always done, well then is denn
the person quite radical and does not follow the traditional as we have done
With all our spelling reforms and the plural shapes, what you always take up is.
That said, lasting for 200 years after all.
So you think we can hold them for another 100 years?
No, but that is an example of
That we have not always been so quick on that.
Well, you should not be either.
No, you should not be, but it is not that we have a strong tradition of standardizing
the written language in that way.
The spelling forms were such
But the plural forms went more organically, where it was a
actor at a time as decided and it was only when TT ...
Exemplify now you are kind so we are completely on what you mean.
Who was now that removed them and in what order?
Was not the Teachers' Union who recommended to stop teaching it
In the late 40s?
And it was quite late, you usually say ...
Lucky I wrote a book about this!
It is usually said that with Nils Holgersson, the plural forms disappeared in spoken language reservations
And gradually, newspaper editions removed it and then TT removed it.
The Language Council, now I have not memorized the dates for this.
Sara is going to the sources in herself here.
Important years for the language police ...
1943 it is Dagens Nyheter that slips the verb plural forms and
Soon all the other major newspapers follow.
But that's big is when TT does it in 1945.
How does such an old form sound?
Well, yes but it is, for example, instead of saying the drops drops
As we do now,
If you say the drops drop.
We still have this in our Christmas songs, among other things, we come instead of us.
Crayfish require these drinks.
Just!
These are the old plural forms that were removed under certain frame screams
Especially 1945 when TT, the newspapers' telegram agency, assumed that they would now ...
There is a great fun submitter in the Trelleborg Post from 1945 about it
And then people had
not talked so on a long time and
After all, there are many workers' writers, for example, who had a very hard time,
Because they did not have that drill with them.
The fairs flower, to take an example.
But there is also such a thing, I hard think in that question
that it would have been pretty good about people
In school today learned to passively understand how those forms work
because we have so much literature written with that form of form
And then you can also avoid such
I school and things that hurt the soul when you hear.
It should be a star in a book I have!
Yes and the thing is that as this was so conservative thing under
So many years we have a huge literature that is written so and
It would have been pretty good to teach perhaps to high school students a quick overview of how this works
Because they will be confronted with something that is written like this.
I can say not only when they read
Strindberg without,
If they do now.
I teach in classic Hebrew and our grammar is written
sometime in the 60s
But it was written by a conservative shock called Ivan Engnell and he writes
With plural forms and my students they bounce on that.
Bounces but they understand them?
Most but I get to smile a little obliquely.
But then you can of course answer "but write new grammar then", of course.
But the point is still that we have a huge
Collection text written in this way
And you can actually learn things without writing yourself.
You can learn it as a literary ...
But it is fashionable to write about books now.
Last today the message came all Ian Fleming's Bond books will be cleaned up
From inappropriate languages and such.
But it becomes such a debate every time, because it is often about political things.
Now it was about the author Roald Dahl's books, that one would clean up in them,
Then there was a big frame scream everywhere.
Today, in a small note in Dagens Nyheter, the news will have the publishers have thought after
And should release both versions.
Yes, they should give out double.
Then no one reacts.
It's so upsetting!
Now everyone believes that now PK fascism has struck and so get 90 % of those who believe that
Now not that there was a language policy discussion that resulted in a compromise.
It does not reach out because it is not mass media enough and it ends with a note.
But that we write about and modernize children's books into a language like ...
So, it's not just that the plural forms disappear,
It is also that the vocabulary changes and it is no wonder.
We have made new Bible translations for the Bible to go and understand by modern ...
Not just why but partly.
No but partly and there is nothing controversial about this,
You replace words that are political and then there will be rebellions.
I also have to take a small lap and this has to do with one of your texts Sara
where you, and I think it was so good because I agree,
This is how the contemporary man works.
I appreciate the word "hen" very much,
Like a gathering pronoun.
It's very
effectively in writing, it is more human than “the”
And I don't have to write him or her in a text and can use them, it has a lot of advantages.
But then there are also those who want to replace the word "man" with "one",
Then you sound like Åsa-Nisse,
Such "Yes, no one knows how to ...".
It will be very strange and you have explained that in a text,
Why they are excellent idea but one is a bad idea.
Because you are right, I was going to ask you to repeat.
Okay, this wasn't I prepared for.
I can quote the text by the way, I think it is so good.
Take it you.
I don't think I write bad but I write that you become no less feminist
just because you use the word man
as generic pronoun.
It does not affect that way and man as a pronoun
And as a noun are two completely different words.
They are used completely different, used different grammatically and even have different pronunciations,
If one thinks about the matter
For the pronoun one can never be emphasized
while the noun one can be emphasized.
You can think about this in your head.
But that's it, there are two completely different words
And there is no one who would ...
If someone says like this:
"You should always have a package of tampons with you".
Surely no one thinks like this "what? Why should men have it?"
Without being completely ...
You also notice that on those who try
Using this, I call it the feminist-one.
To distinguish it from dialect.
It is noticed that they also usually slip, so to speak.
It usually tires with a man from time to time because you are so used to it
And because not means anything!
I get elite there, that is, I think they are a good thing
But you have not taken, this has Sara Lövestam taught me,
There are two words that mean, it's called homonym, and then I get totally crazy
Of that and Mello, it's my other such cane horse ...
But then I'll say, I'm for Mello!
Are you?!
Me too.
Yes and it is a very common way to shorten words and names of things.
But an extra L?
You shorten and add a letter?
How do you defend it?
Yes, Carolina becomes Carro with two R,
Clas becomes class with two s.
It follows structure we have.
You have to give up!
Yes, there you had nothing ...
Well, it's so strange.
Then I also have to ask this question,
Here then hundreds of cane horses and so you and I and everyone:
Why do we feel so strong about this Daniel?
Why are people so crazy about discussing language?
I mean in a positive sense too!
Are we passionate about this?
But it does not go back to what we started to talk about, that it is human.
This is why it is so important that
Language is allowed to live,
That we do not let language die out.
That people are allowed to speak their mother tongue and so on.
It is so incredibly close associated with who I am.
Therefore, it becomes part of the identity.
I was called radical because I think something, when you said not radical
but radical position but then I sat and thought
to hold on to them and them, yes but it becomes like part of an identity to think
Something about the language, it becomes one of me as a human being and how I express myself.
It was a small groove.
But how I express myself,
That's why.
It says something about who I am.
You wrote something before the debate, about language, about expressing oneself in a way so one is perceived
Smarter than you really are.
I thought it was so hard on because that's what it's all about, to be able to
formulate themselves, somehow
get into an environment.
For me, the language has been
part of the
My journey into the academic, in that environment.
To be able to
Navigate there and make it successful.
I know that when I write
So I will often reach.
I will often get
Hearing for my views because I can use the language.
I can convey my thoughts that way
And I suffer with those who can't.
When you tell you, Sara, about SFI students
which does not, who have all thoughts but who cannot convey them.
Therefore, language is so incredible ...
It is clear that it engages
As public then?
You have a language column in the newspaper and so,
You must have received some choleric emails over the years I think.
Can't you pull something out of the rock sleeve?
What do people get angry about and why?
There is one who writes to Svenska Dagbladet every time someone uses the word hen,
Still after eleven years.
There is a woman ...
Is it possibly paper letter?
It is both.
Then there is a woman who is very annoyed.
She writes to everyone.
I am both on the radio on the international and so TV4 and SVT so I get mail from different directions.
There is a woman who is very committed to that it is not called humans
Without it named people
and she writes to everyone
editors and points out that journalists are now able to talk properly.
This is a bit of a thing that I included in "Handbook for Language Police"
Too very often it is about there is a dialectal or ancient Swedish foundation for
Lots of what is considered language errors today.
It's a bit charming that someone attacks
A "language error" that is actually Stockholm.
Because it usually goes the other way.
It's not just Stockholm, this with you.
No, but among other things.
There is otherwise one
very scattered performance that as one speaks in
Stockholm that's right, which is - yes ...
But why people get so committed I think is about,
Now that I have immersed myself in this language police behavior,
It is that, yes, people go around and do this, they correct each other unpaid.
This something they feel is so important that they do this, you might risk their relationships,
one is not afraid of bad mood but you really want to say that it is not called
"Where are you?".
I think this is related to what I said first, the language is
nothing but an agreement
between all people who speak this language.
Up to 13 million who know Swedish to some extent in the world, we shall agree
and do we not agree on what words mean and how to formulate,
which ones should in which order,
Where it means ...
So this whole grammar
And the semantics.
If we do not agree then we cannot communicate.
After all, we are a large herd animal that has the opportunity to form huge flocks.
We can form larger flocks than any other animal on earth
by allowing us to communicate with each other.
Then communications fall, then we fall.
That was as dramatic as I almost spoke English!
I also want to think ...
Some kind of group thought there ....
My point has not even arrived.
It is not just agreement but it is also
What we think is right it has to do with our identity, what we have learned
in the time that shaped us as adults.
One usually talks about a linguistic golden age about the time we come out into adulthood and professional life
And teach us all these norms.
So that's the one we fall back on.
So we are 50-60 then the norm is still the one that was when we were 25-30.
Sara had a point she didn't ...
You can say that is the answer to what, what is it you want people to adapt to
But why do I think ...
Well, of course, it's about identity and a lot but also the pure
evolutionary meaning the language has
thanks to
We maintain these ...
When it comes to a child and says "Oh, I cut myself" so do you say "oh, do you cut you?"
"Yes, I cut myself".
That all this behavior is to get people into this ...
That was my point, I'm done.
Sorry.
Like this,
There are points in the absolute at the same time it is that,
I mean, we can communicate quite well with Danes and Norwegians and so on
Without starting to fight with them simply because we know they are following a norm in themselves.
So it's not just the question of group communication,
Because then one would never have been able to cooperate with a Danish
Or for that matter with someone who speaks a strongly different type of Swedish from one's self.
I would still like to raise some flag to,
I agree with all that said here I want to emphasize but
There is one more thing that makes people, myself included, become committed to this
Which is that the language is an art.
The language is not just a means of communication, it is obviously,
But the language has for a long time in human history been an active art object that
man, whether you really want to admit it or not, are seen as a stone that has to be plastered
To become a beautiful statue or a house or what you want to build with it.
It makes that when you hear someone say or even more when you see someone write because
Language Art is largely in writing about an exclusively,
so it becomes for some people then provocative
When one sees something that
violates what one experiences as an imagined path to some kind of beauty
And maybe even more so when it happens inadvertently.
It is one thing with the syntax uprising and such because then you see that it is conscious
or someone who writes
novels without using the letter e or such things,
Then you see that it is a conscious point with it so you can say
"Well okay, art points Yey".
But if one sees someone who breaks against
the default writing language not to make a point without
because they, he, she does not master elements in the standard writing language
Then it looks like ...
You know people who can
a thousand figures on Pi and so they hear Pi listed with a number is wrong in place
872, it's like it hurts,
Because the artwork is broken apart, subjectively.
What we have done here this hour is that we have established that the language is important of
political reasons, cultural reasons, aesthetic reasons, emotional reasons and identity reasons.
Case Closed as you say in pure Swedish.
Because we have two minutes on before we have to close for the day, a quick
Language Council to Lund University's students,
How do you take on the language?
What to think about?
What is an attitude for life?
The one you, it's not an easy -to -digest thing to stop, do you have something?
Yes.
Be interested.
That's my advice, so care.
If you notice that you can't a word,
find out.
Now there are even apps, you can have it on the phone.
If you don't get on a word
In Swedish and only comes on it in English,
Yes but take it another lap.
I do, it goes well.
Be a bit active with your vocabulary
And find out, if you find out once, you have it later.
Anyone else who wants to throw away with something?
I can link, I think exactly the same.
If you buy the idea that it is better to know two words than one word,
That it makes one a better communicator, so three words must be better than two.
It almost becomes a ...
It means that 10,000 words
is better than 5 and 40 better than and so on.
If you buy it then it must mean
That you have to do just that, gather words.
The more words
you can and master, can use
In your way of thinking, in your way of communicating must, with reasonableness
make you think a little better,
Communicates a little better.
It usually usually
Students have a hard time arguing against because they understand that here is something in it
And then you can also say that you will get better results on the college exam,
But that's another thing.
But do you have a better language you think better,
Surely no stronger arguments may be needed yet.
My friends, the clock approach the whole hour,
Had you who follow us in television had the wisdom to come here for debate in Lund
Then you would have been involved in a fantastic question time
Which will start when we have turned off the cameras.
So it can go, learn to next time and take you here, you are so welcome!
It will be something else then but just as exciting then.
You got to meet Anna Gustafsson, Ola Wikander, Sara Lövestam and Daniel Sandin.
Thank you so much for coming here!