After all, we are affected by what we eat.
But what happened to us as a species when we started eating cultivated food and having livestock -
- The place of gathering and hunting?
The new way of acquiring food changed all life.
Dinner and where it comes from -
- Have always interested man.
For three million years, our ancestors, the hunters and the collectors - took
- Everything they needed directly from nature.
But 10,000 years ago, when agriculture was introduced -
- The man's way of eating was changed.
It was the beginning of a revolution that turned upside down on our history.
A new era began - the younger Stone Age.
You master the fire, domestic the cereals: you develop over time.
We know that you bred and ate sheep, goats and pigs.
And also horses.
In the last ten years, archaeological excavations - have
–And progress in research and analytics technology -
- We are brand new things about the prehistoric eating habits.
With our methods we can see traces of milk for thousands of year old shards.
Thanks to these methods, the researchers have new hypotheses -
- If the connections between the diet, the body and the way man develop.
During the younger Stone Age, the nutritional value of the diet decreased significantly.
The skeleton shows signs of anemia.
The food is one of the basics of biology and for living creatures in general.
The selection pressure is severe on that factor.
How would the new way of life affect us?
It all began in the Middle East and spread during the younger Stone Age west-
- Against Europe.
Could the new food have changed health, demographics and social structure?
What does it say about our ability to adapt?
This is the largest known settlement from the younger Stone Age -
- In the current Turkey.
Typically for the time are densely populated settlements -
- And this is one of the oldest that has so far been excavated.
Carbon-14 dating of items found at the site-
-shows that people have lived here from the mid-7000s BC
French scientist Alain Froment has come to the excavation -
- To find out more about the latest finds and study them in place.
He works closely with his Turkish colleague who leads the excavations.
Here we see a wall of bricks.
With plaster.
Yes, the wall is polished.
And you see the hole after a coarse beam.
When you needed a new house, you tore the upper half of the house.
And so the waste was used as the new foundation.
Çatalhöük was discovered by James Mellaart, David French and Alan Hall -
- When they did an excavation in 1958.
With its 14 hectares, this is the largest in the Middle East and Southern Europe ...
Yes, even the largest settlement in the world from the younger Stone Age.
During the younger Stone Age, plants and animals were domesticated, one became a resident -
- You started producing ceramics and a new type of polished stone.
The younger Stone Age entered gradually and not simultaneously on the different continents.
It was the first time in history it happened.
We know they kept animals here from the beginning.
They had domesticated sheep, goats and pigs here.
They formed a large part of their diet.
And the same was true of the horses.
Because of the fat content, it was an important part of their diet.
Sheep and goats accounted for a large part of their protein intake.
The most startling with çatalhöyük is -
- How to grow wheat and other cereals.
All types of cereals were grown.
We find especially Emmer wheat and single grains.
In addition to Vicker, Oats and other cereals, legumes were grown.
Chickpeas, lentils and peas were important sources of nutrition.
During the younger Stone Age, they were limited to things that gave much more -
- question about calories, availability and production.
Through agriculture you can consume more - you can create new resources.
By getting a wheat on a meadow where it did not grow before, the earth is usually used.
You create resources where there were no before.
And you multiply the resource.
For example, if I sow a corn grain -
- Can I harvest 200 grains and have increased production capacity 200 times.
During the younger Stone Age, they concentrated on the foods that gave the most.
You were no longer limited by nature - you created your own environment.
This area is new.
We dug it last year.
And you think this is a street, so it's an urban structure?
Yes, and here is a new neighborhood.
- And these are the upper layers?
- The upper layers in this hill.
The settlement consists of 16 layers.
The oldest layers are from 7200 BC and the youngest from 5950 BC.
This is a period of about 1,200 years.
For that time it is very long, longer than for any other settlement.
Two factors helped the population increased:
The transition to fixed settlement ...
... and the improved access to food.
The hunters and collectors had few children.
Infant mortality was perhaps high or they regulated their nativity -
- By spreading the births.
But when people became resident, childbirth increased.
The world's population was 25 times larger in just 5,000 years.
4000 BC
Had Europe's population increased to two million people.
The excavations reveal what you ate during the younger Stone Age.
It is more difficult to find out how the food was cooked and consumed.
If we find out more about the cooking methods -
- will the image of our ancestors' lifestyle become clearer.
Archaeologist Anne Flouest is trying to recreate prehistoric recipes -
–And the Stone Age's Way of Cooking -
- With the help of the tracks from the settlements.
I will test the flint shavings that you have brought with you from Grand-Pressigny.
It cuts well, huh?
Incredible...
You cut to the food with a knife, ie by flint.
Then the ceramics were added:
Younger Stone Age's great invention, the first artificial material.
With the help of clay, water and fire, one made a vessel-
- So resisted fire and was waterproof, so you could start boiling the food.
When boiling, either during younger stone age or today, meat reacts the same.
Therefore, I let it cook for at least three hours:
It always takes as long for the collagen to break down so that the meat becomes tender.
When we cook the food we can also mix vegetables and meat -
- And you mix solid and liquid food.
Previously, grilling was the only method.
These combinations probably made a big difference to nutritional intake and lifestyle.
This way of working is called experimental archeology.
By recreating the cooking methods and the flavors -
–Can we understand the choices made by the Stone Age man -
–And why she preferred some dishes over others.
But depended on the new diet on a specific migration -
- Or did it spread when you started to live closer to each other?
Researchers at the University of Vienna are trying to answer that question.
They compare DNA from younger Stone Age groups in Europe and the Middle East -
- With those who lived before the agricultural revolution.
The first challenge is to collect enough good DNA samples-
- From the skeleton in the areas concerned from 10,000 to 4000 BC.
We were looking for the place where DNA would be best preserved.
So we experimented with one of the hardest legs in the body.
And it is the rock bone that surrounds the inner ear.
There DNA is a hundred times better.
With a small sandblasts clean and freely free the leg -
- Till we have isolated the so -called seashell, which then ground into a powder.
By analyzing several hundred samples-
- Can you compile a database with DNA from the younger Stone Age -
- Outside of bargains and age on the skeleton.
They compare the genetic material from the groups -
– With DNA from hunters and collectors who were in the same areas -
- For the beginning of the younger Stone Age.
Our research on DNA from ancient times shows that there was a population -
- Let us call it "hunter/collector", and a new one that we can call "farmers" -
- And that the new population took the place of the old population.
It may have been violent, or only moved the hunters/collectors.
But we see no genetic mix of the two populations.
These people came to southeastern Europe and brought agriculture.
Genetically, it is the same people.
They came in several waves: at least one through the Mediterranean and one via the Danau corridor.
All population groups in Europe and the Middle East during the younger Stone Age -
- So had a common origin.
The first cattle breeders wandered north and west.
They took over time over the location of the local people -
–And introduced their habits, livestock, seeds -
- Objective and cultivation methods and not least their food.
The researchers are interested in the major change in eating habits -
- So people have changed physically.
Were there bodily differences -
–Man between the older Stone Age hunters/collectors -
- And the younger Stone Age farmers?
It is one of the issues that Alain Froment has studied.
Here at Musée de l'Homme we store legs, especially from the younger Stone Age.
This is a femur -
- And it talks about an important aspect of health, namely the body length.
It is an excellent marker.
We know that the body length certainly depends on genetic factors -
- But also on the individual's growing conditions.
It not only tells about a person's age and dietary habits -
- Also without any diseases.
- Do you have another whole beam?
- Yes, this is also completely.
This is a hunter and collector from the older Stone Age.
This leg is from the younger Stone Age.
You see the difference in roughness between the two legs.
The hit the leg shows a strong, quite muscular individual.
You can clearly see the late brackets that have shaped the leg surface.
This leg is much narrower and has had visibly less muscle.
When comparing skeletons from older and younger Stone Age, some tendencies are visible.
For example, older Stone Age hunters and collectors were really athletically built.
They were quite powerful and long, they ate a nutritious and varied diet.
During the younger Stone Age, the body length decreased due to the transition-
–To a more single -handed diet, often based on a single cereal -
–And to less strenuous activities.
That is, arable farming and animal husbandry.
That work is less intense, but more repetitive.
You can also analyze the impression that muscle activity leaves on the legs.
Here I am looking for traces of damage of the osteoarthritis type type
- As the femur carries the body weight.
During the younger Stone Age, muscle activity changed.
A farmer did not live the same life as a stray hunter and collector.
His movement patterns were more one -handed.
The women had injuries to knees and ankles -
- which are compatible with the crunching position you have when grinding grain.
It gives a number of imprints on the pipe legs and on the joints.
Based on them, one can assess both the posture and its intensity -
- And thus the consequences for the skeleton.
Thanks to the settlement in Turkey, the researchers have access-
- Too outstanding archaeological material.
Many skeletons found -
- As the inhabitants buried their dead under the floor of their houses.
During the excavations made between 1960 and 2017–
- The remains were held after 815 people from the younger Stone Age.
Last year, another 15 were found, ie a total of 830 people.
There are very many.
The skeleton shows signs that health was deteriorating by the new diet.
The food covered the basic needs, but was less varied -
- And that led to deficiency diseases.
There were signs of anemia, so the anthropos wondered what had happened.
It is believed that there may be a lack of something.
The farmers' diet was poor on proteins -
- And rich in carbohydrates, so there will be a shortage of vitamins and maybe trace elements.
I am now examining the teeth of a woman who lived during the younger Stone Age.
A leg can tell you about someone's life-
- And a tooth or a tooth set can tell how that person lived.
If someone while the tooth is developing goes through a difficult time -
- With stress, starvation or a severe infection, then it is seen as the annual rings on a tree:
It leaves a mark on the tooth.
This front tooth is a bit attacked -
- Two premoors are very attacked and the canine is also attacked.
Iron deficiency leads to anemia -
-And here we see micropenations in the eyehole that is due to iron deficiency.
It's pretty clear.
There are criteria that people were in poor health.
It explains inhibited growth and a shorter body length.
Moving general health is visible traces of oral infections and tooth loss.
During the younger Stone Age, the flour contained grain of silica from the millstone -
- As the tooth surfaces ground and made them almost flat.
On the canines and the first cheek tooth, the beginning caries are visible on the dentist.
It is a gateway for infections: bacteria from the mouth can get in -
- And even cause sepsis.
Oral hygiene thus has a crucial importance for human health.
Through the supply of carbohydrates and the changed way of chewing the food -
- The general oral health was deteriorated.
Although agriculture and animal husbandry improved the lives of the people-
–Fick the new diet some negative effects -
- On their physical development and health.
The lifestyle brought the younger people's people closer to the animals.
They now lived with sheep, goats and cows -
–And all species attracted by the grain stocks, such as different rodents -
- And also dogs and cats.
When humans and animals live close to each other, new problems arise.
The proximity is clearly visible on these murals in Turkey.
Wild animals have always worn on huge amounts of viruses and bacteria.
During the younger Stone Age, people lived with their animals, it was a close contact -
- And because of the population increase, you see another pattern of infection.
As an example, I can take measles, which is related to this place.
In the beginning, measles, the wild form, was, so to speak, livestock plague.
It was the virus that gave rise to the measles virus.
It was probably during the younger Stone Age, through contact with wild cattle -
–As the virus transferred to man, and because of the large population -
- Lightly spent the virus between people and stayed in the population.
Younger Stone Age infection patterns differ radically from older Stone Age.
From the sheep came anthrax, pigs and chickens brought with them influenza -
- The dogs rabies, and the horses gave tetanus.
Now even tuberculosis, smallpox, malaria, plague - began
- Petty and syphilis to spread.
Over 180 diseases appeared together with the agricultural community.
Nevertheless, the population increased sharply during the younger Stone Age.
Perhaps the people adapted to the new threats.
Céline Bon is studying changes in the hereditary mass -
- Hos people who lived during this time period.
In paleogenetics you study DNA from ancient people in my case.
Their DNA is degraded, but we can still reconstruct different phenomena -
- including population movements, population mixing and so on ...
Adaptation to a new environment is evident from how genetic variants have increased in frequency.
The food is one of the basics of biology and for living creatures in general.
So we can imagine that the selection pressure is huge on that factor.
Change in diet changes the environments that people live in -
- So it leads to new selection pressure and thus to new genetic variants.
The world around us and how we live affects the population's genetic mass.
Gene variants that provide benefits are becoming more common in future generations -
- And some genes that have previously been silent begin to be expressed.
In this way, genetic diversity increases.
The first diet -related change we see is the increase of a variant -
- which brings light skin color.
The skin had been darker, but from the younger Stone Age it changed:
Almost 100 % of the population had the variant that brings lighter skin.
One possible explanation for that skin color is adaptation to the younger Stone Age diet.
The diet of the hunters and collectors was richer on protein and thus on vitamin D.
During the younger Stone Age, the diet became less varied, more starchy -
- And therefore less rich in vitamins and nutrients in general.
But vitamin D can be formed in the body when the skin is exposed to sun.
And light skin color makes it easier.
The lack of vitamin D led to dark-skinned population groups-
- With time developed a lighter skin color.
It is conceivable that when you no longer received vitamin D through the diet-
–Ativated a selection pressure that favored individuals with lighter skin -
-As it could more easily absorb vitamin D.
The light -skinned then spread to Europe.
It was not the only diet -related change man was exposed to -
- During the younger Stone Age.
Equally crucial was a new food that would be vital - milk.
As soon as you started breeding pets, you could consume their milk.
Man needs the enzyme lactate to break down lactose into milk.
When children stop breastfeeding reduces the production of lactase -
- In most population groups.
Then it becomes difficult to drink milk.
From the younger Stone Age, there is a selection pressure in Europe in Europe -
—To a variant that could split milk as an adult: that produced lactate then -
- In contrast to what is common in mammals.
There was a population that could drink milk throughout their lives.
But how fast did it go?
How long does it take for heritage to change?
At the University of Bristol, the researchers seek answers to that question -
- In ceramics from the younger Stone Age that has been found at excavations.
One must imagine that then was the ability to split milk vital.
This ceramic comes from an ancient cooking vessel.
When cooking in porous ceramic -
- Things fat and other lipids into the pores on ceramics.
With the help of these multi -thousand -year -old shards -
- Can you find out what was cooked in the ancient clay vessels.
With our technology we can see traces of milk in shards that are thousands of years old -
- Yes, up to 10,000 years old.
It's pretty impressive.
One grinds away the surface of ceramics -
- To ensure that the lipids to be analyzed are inside the shards -
- And is not a contamination on the outside.
You take two to three grams which are then powdered.
Charlie pours solvents on the shard that we have just crushed.
Then it all mixes.
And we will now analyze this.
Each time an association is registered, the curve goes up.
We see the difference between fat from ruminants and fat from non-packers.
We can also distinguish between milk and meat.
By tracking the remains of milk in ceramics from different settlements -
- You know which population groups drank milk, where they lived and when.
The tasks, and the research on gene changes during the younger Stone Age-
- Make it possible to map how and when the lactostolerance spread.
Preserving the production of lactas is the strongest selection pressure -
- In man's through today.
Sometimes that process took only a few thousand years.
The mutation is most common in northern Europe, that is, in the UK -
- Germany and Scandinavia.
It is less common around the Mediterranean.
For those who went over to animal husbandry -
- It was 2,000-3,000 years to adapt to drinking milk.
But the researchers do not know why that property -
- Is so common in some European groups and so rare in others.
There were groups during the same time -
- As a dairy products without having this gene change.
This shard was found in Poland, in Ludwinowo.
It is from the younger Stone Age, about 7,000 years ago.
The shard has been decorated by pinching.
One sees the imprint-
- Of the person who made the ceramics 7,000 years ago.
Very moving!
We have analyzed ceramic shards with holes in -
– Which is very similar to today's cheese molds -
- So we know they were used to make cheese.
It was during the younger Stone Age that you learned to process food.
For example, making cheese and yogurt.
They came in ways to reduce the lactose in the milk by acid -
- Or to remove it, by making cheese or yogurt.
The genes changed to fit the new diet.
At the same time, people learned to change the food -
- So they could use it.
Methods were developed to preserve and cook the food -
- So it became easier to digest and provided as much nutrition as possible.
Now we're going to grind grains.
During the younger Stone Age, the harvested grain began to be processed -
- By baking bread.
The bread was energy -rich and had good durability.
So it became a basic food.
It is starting to be clear.
We are going to make a whole grain loaf.
Wheat and milk are two super foods.
Wheat has sugar, protein, vitamins.
When baked it may lose a little, but younger Stone Age flour was whole grain flour.
Now we let it ferment in peace and quiet in the heat.
The new ways to process the food all have one thing in common.
They make it softer and easier to chew.
This has led to some unexpected consequences for man.
Foneticists at the University of Barcelona have discovered something strange.
It has been thought that today's language sounds much like the language of ancient times.
But in the 1980s, it performed the appearance of Linguist Charles Hockett the thought-
–Ad the languages spoken by agricultural people and those spoken by non-agricultural people-
- Has slightly different sound systems.
This applies to the labiodental phonemen /f /and /v /.
/f/
/V/
Fonemen / F / and / V / is much more common in languages spoken by agricultural people.
The idea comes from an appearance change.
During the younger Stone Age, people's lower jaw took new form.
Before the rise of agriculture, the children were born with slightly overbite-
- which was corrected when the lower jaw had grown completed.
Then the front teeth were met towards the tip-
- And it made hard and tough food chewed effectively.
Here we have photos that show the change in the jaw that we are talking about.
The first skull is from the older Stone Age -
- And there the front teeth meet to tip.
The other is from the middle age, and the bite looks the same.
However, this one comes from the Bronze Age, after the introduction of agriculture -
- And here it is clear that the bite looks like this, like mine.
During the younger Stone Age, when the food became easier to chew -
- ceased the change in the bite.
The lower jaw did not grow as much as before.
The lower jaw helps to shape the different language sounds -
- In the same way as the tongue, lips, nose and vocal cords.
The researchers have measured the effect of the change of jaws -
- When it comes to the muscle power required to create different language sounds.
When pronouncing the lab dials /f /and /v / -
- You actually have to put your lower lip against the upper teeth.
It is easier if the lower jaw is a little shorter than if it looks like this.
The first thing we did was run a so -called biomechanical computer simulation.
Through biomechanical simulation you can measure the load on the muscles -
- Which helps to get the sound in question.
Here is the lace-on-tip bite.
The sound produced is a labiod number.
And the model shows -
–To the load on the muscles when one / f / or / v / pronounced -
- Is higher with this bite than with this.
/f/
/V/
The greater effort a language sound requires -
- Desto is more unusual in the language.
The new diet changed the lower jaw.
Could this in turn have led to other sound systems in the language?
We are in spain.
We will probable not see the sagrada família.
ESTA MAñana He Comido Fruta Fresca a Trozos.
Ce Matin au Petit-Déjeuner, J'AI price des œufs, you bacon.
To test language sound hypothesis, you have statistical methods -
—Mold the frequency of phonemen /f /and /v / -
- Hos the hunter and collectors who remain today.
One has gone back in language history -
- To try to determine when / f / and / v / arose.
The important thing is that in the beginning, 8,000 years ago -
- were the probability of labiodental small, but they became more and more common.
The changes can be correlated with the production of more lightly owed food -
–The then with the introduction of agriculture.
There has been a language sound development -
- This can be linked to changed eating habits with the rise of agriculture.
The new food would not only change the anatomy of man
- and thereby the language.
The production of large amounts of foods that were easy to store -
- also fell consequences for the entire social structure.
At the Black Sea coast of Bulgaria there is an archaeological find site -
- Which testifies to profound social changes.
This burial ground is outside warn.
The first excavations were made in 1972–
- And they resumed last year.
This is from the middle of the fifth millennium BC, from Copper Age -
—They between 4,500 and 4300 BC, simplified.
French and Bulgarian archaeologists -
- Have participated in the excavations of this place since it was discovered.
The strong flow in human history is the transition to agriculture.
After a period of agriculture, the possibility of storing -
- And thus very quickly also the opportunity to store surplus.
When the younger Stone Age had lasted for 800–1,000 years in Europe -
- Specialized businesses, crafts.
The abundance of food enabled society to support people -
- which devoted itself to other than agriculture.
For example, they became warriors or craftsmen.
This is where you showed me that the grave was.
It was this one.
And this is grave 310.
308, 309, 311.
So far we have excavated 311 graves.
In grave 307 there are vessels with some stones.
Then we have a group of legs between them, under this skull.
In this vessel we found a copper needle -
–And a small necklace of ...
Oh, so nice.
Each item has been selected to be placed in the grave with the dead.
Therefore, it is of course chosen by the society that buried the dead.
We try to understand this society's values.
Great!
Laurence Manolakakis is a specialist in stone tools from the younger Stone Age.
Especially on strange objects of flint.
They have only been found in some rare cases among the gifts in the 311 graves.
They clearly show that the tasks were divided.
This is a miracle.
It is a dagger blade of flint.
It is the longest known leaf in this part of the southeastern Balkans.
It is 42.5 centimeters long.
It is almost evenly thick in its entire length-
- And is very thin, despite its length.
It is about great skill that was achieved after a long apprenticeship.
It is also about specialization -
- Something more than: "I'm very handy."
That is in line with what we know about the emergence of craftsmen.
On one of the burial grounds, a gold tax was found -
- Which is unique for this stage in the history of humanity.
Only specialized craftsmen who did not have to devote themselves to agricultural -
- Can have made these gold items.
The most important object is the spire.
The battle ax has a shaft -
- Which is enclosed in gold rings.
The necklace of gold beads is also very important.
But it is only in this grave that we have found pearl necklace -
– Which is not just made of pure copper, pure gold -
- The out of a natural alloy between gold and silver.
A new diet that arose during the younger Stone Age -
- Have changed us forever.
It has affected both our bodies, and how we think, speak and create.
The long flint daggers, ceramics and golden jewelry -
- was made by specialized craftsmen.
They foretell the next step in human development:
The Bronze Age - and the emergence of the first major civilizations.
Soon new inventions in the management of food would follow.
Humans began to refine plants, fruits and vegetables -
- To make them more useful and tastier.
New groceries, such as marinades for preservation and wine, became everyday.
Diet continues to develop -
- And helps to shape us into who we are today.
What should we eat now, then, to develop into better creatures?
How should we get to the next level?
We may return with answers to that, in some program in a few thousand years.
But this movie is on SVT Play this summer.
Now news from the world of science.
Although the Coronapandemia has sounded from, many are still suffering from the virus's suites.
Postcovid has been difficult to diagnose and treat.
But now researchers have found an important cause of the prolonged problems -
- With
Extreme fatigue and worse cognition that many suffer from.
Now it has been shown that some proteins -
— Which are involved in these systems for blood clots and inflammation -
- Is elevated or lowered in patients with postcovid.
And then you know better where to direct your drugs.
Researchers have analyzed over 6,000 different proteins -
- In blood from 113 covid patients, of which about half have developed postcovid.
The blood has been analyzed on two occasions -
- And then changes have been found in some proteins in those with postcovid.
This is a very important study.
After all, this is a new disease -
–And now we know more about which proteins and other markers -
– That differs for these patients -
- And then we can better think about the treatments.
So it is an important step forward.
Breaking uranium from mountains in this way is a dirty business.
After all, uranium is used as fuel in nuclear power plants.
But there is a more environmentally friendly way to get uranium: from seawater.
The seas are so large, so there are about 4-5 billion tonnes of uranium in the sea water.
If you pick it out of the seawater -
- So the fixed uranium minerals will dissolve a little to -
- So it becomes a Renewable Source.
The uranium is leached from the rock through rivers and lakes and then ends up in the seas.
But cleaning the uranium from the seas is difficult.
Now Chinese researchers have developed a new material:
A carbon fiber weave that captures uranus in electrochemical.
The yellow on the carbon fiber fabric is uranium.
You don't have to break a bunch of stone-
- Use you pick up the uranium quite clean from the seawater.
And unlike when breaking uranium from mountain-
- So there is no hazardous waste when cleaning uranium out of water.
But it is still an expensive method and not yet commercially useful.
The development of artificial intelligence is fast now.
It is often heard that it goes fast.
Where is the limit for what AI will be able to do?
In the next world of science we find out how AI really works -
- And what the experts consider to be the greatest danger of AI.
What kind of future are we going to meet - dystopian or fascinating?
In the future, robots can help doctors and nurses -
- Concentrate on the needs of individual patients.
"We solve everything with the help of AI! Cancer, Transport, Education" ...
Someone suggested AI to detect genocide.
I just: "huh?!"
AI can be used to distribute resources such as food and energy.
Within traditional symbolic AI, the machine is provided with knowledge.
Suddenly it turned out that deep machine learning works much better.
Mathematics try feverishly to understand how it works, but no one really knows.
- Are you often in New York?
- Mest at work, but sometimes for pleasure.
Texting: Birre Burman Swedish Media text for SVT
Translation: Ulf Andersson Swedish Media Text for SVT
Texting: SVT Language & amp;
Accessibility (C) Swedish Television AB 2024