Oh, damn!
Now you got something fun on film.
Do you see where it is sitting?
Hahaha!
-Hey!
Hello.
-Douglas.
Viktor.
-How's it going?
Well it feels good.
-You have something odd to show?
Well, it's a regular Subaru.
-An ordinary Subaru?
-What is this?
It is a Subaru Outback from 1999.
-Okay..
With a 2.5 liter engine.
-It looks a little worn.
Yes it is getting old.
-What is special about this car?
It has rolled 100,000 miles and a little more.
-Va!?
Right.
-100,000 miles!?
Jajemän.
It's like new.
After all, the meter starts again.
-The really has it rolled 100,000 miles?
Yes, and even tasted a moose.
-And crashed with a moose!
-I would just ask what is special about this car and now I got the answer.
-Here you see, has the moose taken in here?
Exactly, the front and head slid over the bonnet and then up the roof.
The moose pushed down the roof here.
I pressed the roof again and tried to make the best of the situation.
Also changed box.
-Ny box and adjust the roof was the only error?
Well, then the moose spun around and slid off the roof.
And flew in the back of the car.
It knocked out both boxes at the back.
And destroyed the C-pillar.
-How did it go with you?
Not a scratch.
Not even glass splits.
-Why do you buy a car that has rolled 100,000 miles?
It's fun.
It had not rolled 100,000 miles when I bought it.
It had only rolled 94,000 miles when I bought it.
Yes only 94,000 miles ..
Well ...
It would have been fun to drive it to 100,000 miles.
-How is it to own a car that has gone so far?
What breaks?
Well, I have had to change the gearbox.
98,000 miles had gone before it was changed.
Beyond that, there has not been much.
I haven't changed brakes on it.
Just changed brake pads and changed oil was 1000 mile.
-First owner how far did he drive?
He drove 94,000 miles.
-How many years?
He did it in 6 years.
-He must have lived in the car.
Yes, hahaha!
He commuted between Sweden and Germany to import caravans.
-How many miles there will be a year?
15,000 miles a year huh?
Well, it will be 15,666 miles a year ...
Hahaha!
As I said he has lived in the car.
-How has it managed in the varnish?
The clear lacquer has started to release a little here.
-Rust?
There is a bit everywhere.
-It looks okay for having rolled so far.
The bonnet is a bit matte because it is repainted a few times.
We can look at another fun thing.
The fuel lid, it has been refueled quite a few times.
Every time you pull out the handle it drops gasoline.
The gasoline eats the color so it will be like this.
Now you can save things down here.
-There is no sheet metal left.
In total if you count on inflation we have calculated ...
... that it is refueled for SEK 1.5 million.
-Hahaha, for real?
Yes.
There has been a lot of gasoline in the pipes on this.
-Here it says, 1 million km.
The last owner liked to feel where the caravan was.
-Back he until it stopped?
Yes then he drove out a bit and pulled on the caravan.
-This is also a bit innovative.
When you just put it straight on.
Yes simple.
-Yo real design.
-How does it look on the inside?
It has done really well.
The rear seat is like new.
No one has been sitting behind?
No, almost no one.
The previous owner has driven himself.
And I have not used the back seat.
There are no stains.
The steering wheel has seen its best days.
It is falling in particular.
He has probably been left -handed he who has run it.
-The owner does not seem to have pushed anyone either because the seat looks new.
Exactly, it is probably me who has used that seat most.
Here it says 999,999.
Yes the meter stayed there.
It has gone 1000 miles but I have had to count on the trip meter.
Every time it has turned over to 1000 km I have written it down on a note.
-Is there any documentation on the car?
The glove compartment can hardly be closed because it is so full.
Here it falls out stuff.
It is almost all inspection protocols.
All receipts and everything done with the car.
In recent years it has been good and only been a small fix.
The last inspection did not go so well.
Rust in thresholds rear that is too close to bearing construction.
And bad lanterns.
A lamp that was loose, fog lights that were broken.
Handbrake that took bad and the springs that were off both sides.
-What do you have for future plans with this car?
I'll give it to a friend who has crashed with his car.
He drives more or less the earth.
He has done it the Senate 1.5 year.
Now this car becomes a good candidate to travel with instead.
It is a little difficult to sell, hahaha!
It is difficult to explain the story in an ad.
-Is it time now to hand over it?
Yes, that is.
Now it will move down to the Netherlands.
What has to be done before it moves?
It should be changed cam strap and a brake pipe.
After that he may take it.
I liked someone here ..
Hello!
-Hey!
-How are you?
Good!
-Douglas.
Cow, nice to meet.
-So you are the one to take over the car?
Yes, Viktor gave me a Subaru.
Because I crashed mine.
I have another Subaru that I bought in New Zealand.
I lived in New Zealand for 3 years.
In 2014 I bought my first Subaru for 1500 euros.
It had gone 25,000 miles.
All other cars I have had have broken.
I spent a lot of money on fixing them.
Then I met a friend who asked if I wanted to buy his car.
Ah, I thought it will be a car that will break.
He said it is a good car and you can buy it for 1500 euros.
I bought it and started driving.
I continued to drive and it went through the inspection.
I drove over everything with the car.
Out in the terrain among other things.
I continued to drive without it breaking.
When I moved back to the Netherlands, I couldn't leave the car in New Zealand.
Because it never broke.
So I sent the car in a container to the Netherlands.
When the car arrived we drove to Switzerland, Italy and Austria.
Oh my God!
Then I came up with the idea to put a large map on the bonnet.
So I can show everyone where the car has been.
I started by making a stretch from Japan to New Zealand.
Then a stretch to the Netherlands.
That's where my hobby started.
Last summer we drove to Northern Cape.
On to Russia which was almost 1000 miles.
And made that trip in 18 days.
Despite these trips, the car worked without any problems.
I drove to England just to get a picture of the car with The London Eye.
And add England to the bonnet so people see that the car has been in London.
This year was the plan to send the car to the United States.
And drive from Miami to New York.
By then the car had also been to the United States.
The plan was to drive the car everywhere on the ground.
But two months ago ...
I drove on an icy road.
The car started to gossip and I drove too fast.
I drove into a tree at 80 km/h and everything broke on the car.
Even the crankshaft in the engine broke.
There was nothing to save on the car.
I felt bad because all the plans I had were now gone.
It was total chaos, I couldn't sleep or eat in a week.
Viktor saw pictures of the crashed car on Facebook.
And he contacted me and I have a car for you.
I have a 1 million km Subaru Outback.
You can get it if you want.
So now I'm happy again.
There is something special about this car.
It has a wonderful story.
It will be fun to be able to travel in a car again.
The year 2020 will drive this car all the way from the Netherlands to Japan.
Drive the car back to the Subaru factory where it was manufactured.
I'm pretty sure we can drive all the way without any problems.
-It will cost a fortune?
Yes, but I hope I can find some sponsors.
That people can help pay for gasoline.
-What is the plan when you arrive at Japan.
Will you drive the car home?
If Subaru wants the car, they have to take it.
But if they do not want it, I will bring it home.
And keep driving.
Or I send it to the United States and drive there.
I like to travel and especially in a car because you see everything.
If you fly, you see nothing between A and B.
And in a car you see everything.
-What wonderful project!
Yes.
Here we stand and are freezing to death.
It's January and he walks around with hooded sweater.
-Do you not freeze?
No.
Normally I have shorts on me.
-Hahaha!
I have that in the Netherlands.
And people look at me and say why shorts in the middle of winter.
That's why I have jeans on me otherwise people look so strange at me.
-You seem to like the car.
Absolutely, I love it.
I have big plans.
I will foil large parts of the car.
All stories with the car, even small details like the scratches here at the back.
All scratches have their own history.
It should be foiled but the history of the car.
On the bonnet I will put a new map just like the old car.
Who will show the entire trip from the Netherlands to Japan.
Text about the plans for this car and that we drive a Subaru with 1 million km on the meter.
About the damage here when Viktor collided with a moose.
The plan is to put pictures up here with text.
Write a story about the crash.
Here or there we foliate the tank card.
Down here we write how much money he spent on gasoline.
It is a wonderful story so people can read about how much he refueled for.
Many people ask how I can afford to travel around.
It doesn't cost that much.
Because I don't travel alone.
We share the driving and gasoline cost.
We do not take into hotels.
We have our own tents.
We cook all food ourselves.
In this way, it doesn't get that expensive.
When I drive through Europe, it is almost only gasoline that costs.
I buy all food in regular stores.
Which is cooked during the evening.
It doesn't cost that much.
It's more time you need.
Type one month.
The last trip I made around the Baltic Gulf took 18 days.
It takes alot of time.
But it's not that expensive.
-Do we see if it starts?
-It's Saturday so it may be a little tired.
No problem.
-Tidag leaving this car Sweden, right?
We have a trailer we will drive it back to the Netherlands on.
It took us 16 hours to drive here yesterday.
It will take us 15-16 hours to drive home.
-Is it possible for viewers to follow your travels?
I have a website.
Subglobe.nl
I came up with the name subglobe because I travel around the world in late Subaru.
That's why the website is called so.
On the Facebook page "Sunglobe - Team Legacy".
Can you follow all trips.
The goal is to drive to Japan.
And show the world ..
... that everyone has to buy a Subaru.
-It was very nice to meet and have a lovely trip home.
Thanks so much.
Bye!
There it goes.
The next stop will be Japan.
-How does it feel?
Boring but still very good.
It will be a fun thing of this.
And I had never done it.
-A funny story gets even better.
Yes it will be.
Now we see how the continuation will be.