-They, it was an odd choice of MC to drive on the ice.
Do you think?
Well, it's absolutely perfect.
It is an absolutely perfect motorcycle.
I get to use what I have.
And now this is what I have to drive with.
-It's a great hi.
Thanks so much, it's from 1948.
-What speed can you drive with this?
I drove 141 km/h as top speed.
-Oj, wow!
It is good.
-That is really good.
After all, there is only 40 hp on the rear wheel.
So it's not a racing machine.
-Have you been here before?
Yes, I was here in 2017.
I drove faster this year.
Now the mound got performance anxiety.
Now!
-mode?
Yes it is good.
-Can well mention first or mainly why we sit in the caravan.
-I think nobody understands how much it sounds here.
-We sit in the middle of the firing line and you will get an example of how it sounds here.
If we are to get some decent sound, we can sit in the caravan.
It is difficult to explain Speed Weekend for those who have not been here.
There are so many different vehicles and people who appreciate this weekend once a year.
This is the third year we are running with this.
The first year it had original wheel suspension.
I had skates mounted on the tires.
But then I only came 150 meters before it started wobbling so I keep overturning.
Last year it was rebuilt with a scooter and own swing at the back with the skate.
Now it is stable.
Now I am looking for more effect so I can go faster.
-What do you have average speed?
I think it was 92.35 km/h.
Last year it was 83 km/h.
Now we will turn more effect.
-What funny, good luck!
Thanks!
Now it feels relatively stable.
It's just a little semi-unpretable.
Now I will not go 200 km/h but it would have been fun to get up to 100 km/h.
My name is Rickard Eklund and comes from Åland.
-Alland!?
It will be a little turn to get here.
-How much did you get to drive then?
I just drove a scratch.
200 meters before the goal was broken.
279 km/h was input speed.
And 233 km/h out.
But I was probably up to 320 km/h when the engine broke.
Better happiness next time, hahaha.
Braked the engine of 920 hp on the wheels and just over 1000 hp on the engine.
I had problems with the charge pressure control on the straight stretch.
It could not hold on to properly ...
... I would only have charging pressure on 2.5 bar.
But the charging pressure was 2.7-2.8 bar all the time.
So I had about 100 hp too much.
We knew it would not endure.
And it didn't.
The top cover gasket went, the top cap Sprak and holes in the valve.
We'll see what I can find until next year.
It's just starting over.
-So you packed up?
We tore the engine yesterday to see if it was rescued.
We thought it was just the top lid gasket first.
We screwed out the spark plugs because the engine worked.
But the hole in the valve is difficult to rope.
We just let it stand so we have to pack up tonight or tomorrow.
This is the best there is.
It is completely crazy to drive on the ice.
And all the people who are here.
You find so much strange stuff here.
It is extreme in every way.
If you like jet parks, V8or or turbo machines.
There is everything for everyone and it's cool.
There is no other event that is like this.
It's only once in years.
-Why did it become such a machine?
I helped a colleague's brother change an engine on his motorcycle.
He gave me the engine for the job I did and said does something fun.
Then I found a garden trailer.
Everything you see that is original is as follows: the plate, bonnet, plastic and sides.
The screens are not original but widened.
On the ice I have driven 152 km/h on average.
The top speed is 162 km/h.
-Her God, on a lawnmower!
It should go faster.
-How is it to drive?
It is very high.
It's not like a go -kart because you sit high up.
Yes it feels because it is a high weight point and it jasses when driving.
The feeling is sometimes that it can overturn.
The last round I drove I kept running over the photocell.
The front wheels are not often in the ground.
So you have to plan if you are to turn.
It's fun, a terrified delight.
-Why Speed Weekend?
I saw that Hubbe Berg had built a garden tractor.
I was influenced and thought it was a cool thing.
It is well thanks to him.
It's a great event this.
I like things like this and I compete for myself.
-Is only me who thinks this looks fatal?
Stop, stop, stop !!
We lift the whole car.
-Is it ready -made?
Now it is ready with it anyway.
-What is wrong?
Do you have no gears left.
1-2 an is still the rest has gone home.
Maybe there are more gears on the scrap?
I thought there was an accessory for the oil so you got the gears back, hehehe.
-It was probably the strangest loading I've ever seen.
It should fit another car then.
That car has survived so far.
But, well uh ..
You should have fun loading.
-It looked scary.
Yes, the idea was good.
Just after I take this picture, the ramp folded.
We had to strengthen the ramp below.
Now the ramps weigh 60 kg each.
You learn as long as you live.
And if it goes to hell, it goes to hell.
It is quite easy to change the gearbox here.
Yes, do you change it now?
-What have you done here?
Have you operated on the track?
The idea was that I would have had another car.
But the parts did not come from the United States.
I have a compressor -fed Ford Mustang that I would have run with.
But it is not compiled yet.
I fly to the US in 2 weeks to pick up the parts.
-What practical!
Yes, it is cheaper to fly over and pick up the parts.
It is completely crazy that it should be so.
But you get some vacation.
Now we are 2 who go to the United States.
We have rented a Ford Mustang Cab.
So we'll see if we buy extra tires for it.
We'll see what happens because we don't really know yet.
-What is so good about Speed Weekend?
What is so good ..
..there are all strange vehicles.
It's all people and strange vehicles.
Which builds up all the fun vehicles.
There are special people here.
It's everything from super serious to completely crazy.
It's just watching the black hole, they are ...
..not really wise.
There are no revealing parts for what they do.
I had wanted to try everything.
It is an eventman for everything and everyone.
You can do so much more than just drive.
Talk to people and watch all the cranky builds.
People are nice.
-And you can fly airplanes.
We were going to see if we could take a flight later.
We tried the hovercraft yesterday.
So we try aircraft today because we are not allowed to fly ourselves.
We will come next year as well.
Maybe with a little dumber stuff.
You never know considering what we brought with us.
It is a water rocket park.
It's like an oversized PET water rocket.
It is an old CNG tank from a Volvo V70.
The idea is classified for 200 bar.
It is 2/3 water then put an air cushion on top.
It pushes out the water with a high force, which means that you go on the reaction force.
It is not an optimal acceleration position to stand on a kick.
And accelerate hard with a lot of g forces.
The best scratch I went 0-80 km/h in 6 seconds.
It is decent, though not difficult to remain on the kick.
But you keep up.
The fired would be quick to build.
But unfortunately, there was geek at the detail level in this case as well.
I would guess that it has taken 200-300 hours to build it.
100 km/h is the magic no for all my vehicles.
Faster than 105.2 km/h I would like to go because it did Mobacken Racing a long time ago.
It would be a milestone to beat their record.
-We can comment on how much it sounds?
-How long away can we be 300 meters?
We are enough.
300 meters in from and now the black hole will start the pulse jet the scooter.
I think we do.
Above all, it feels in the body.
I know it is heard all the way to Sandviken.
(1.5 miles)
It is great fun guys who offer themselves.
Now they will start soon.
This is enjoyable.
Great!
There you heard a knee.
Now they are in the fuel.
Now it's full gas!
Wow!
It is wonderful!
We have to check how long they will come.
As a currios, the engine type has not been used since the 1940s to something sensible.
And it was not used for anything sensible in the 40s either for the Germans it had for the V1 missile.
Well, that's the most famous ...
... the application that has used large pulse dough engines.
They were used with varying success.
The Germans shot many towards England and some arrived.
The V1 missile was called "Buzz Bomb" because of how they sound.
There are probably still people who were involved and can testify to the sound.
It was probably quite horror I can imagine.
This engine we have I think it differs 10% on traction.
We have found some different information but it is almost the same traction.
However, our engine is less.
There is a V1 missil at the Arboga Robot Museum for anyone who wants to see one for real.
I was there looking and that engine was much bigger.
It went much nicer and I can understand that because it was probably worse material.
And it would last longer.
Jadu, do not know why you are in the pulse.
It is really banal technology.
Basically simple but then it gets complicated when you peel it up.
Especially with the durability.
The biggest problem the last few years is to get the engine brackets to hold together.
The engine becomes 4-5 cm longer when it is warm and then also increases the diameter.
So it is wearing the engine brackets.
What looks good is that we have not found any damage to neither the brackets nor the engine after this weekend.
And it feels good.
We made no performance increases for this year, but put all the energy on the engine brackets.
And it seems to have succeeded.
We get a salary for the effort when sitting in the CAD program and calling and discussing.
There will be a lot of debate in between.
And usually it will be good.
Warning signal, thank you!
The black hole aims for going faster than last year.
Which was 241 km/h on average.
But be f-n, yeah yeah!
We get it, 258.52 km/h!
254.86 km/h on average.
New world record for pulse dots.
Congratulations the black hole!
258 km/h at top speed.
Absolutely senseless!
I didn't think it was possible today.
That was really good.
Congratulations the black hole!
Deeply impressed.
That was hard rock.
Cannon!
-Personal record?
Yes exactly.
Yes it was unsupported, I didn't really believe it but all of a sudden it went fast.
I'm not so used to high speeds otherwise.
And I'm not doing any other motorsport.
I think the course gets slim.
I put my thoughts down to beat a record.
But the second ride was absolutely fantastic and went well.
Then it goes straight and stable.
We haven't run it since last year.
Sometimes we usually spit on a motor show.
We have pulled down a bit.
It's a little too expensive to break just because.
We have lost the desire a bit because of it.
But of course ..
... it depends on who calls.
254.86!
Hahaha, what a sync ..