-Hello!
Hey!
-Now i am back.
Yes.
-We should see how long you have come?
There have been no huge progress.
I have received my water cut grill in aluminum.
And also the moldings.
I have been able to shape the moldings and they are not finished yet but should be rounded off and sanded.
All screws should be recessed.
And got rolled to this.
When it is polished on the outside, it will look like it is cast in aluminum.
It is because it is a bit dull but then it becomes when you water cut and then it looks more real.
-So you should polish it?
Yes just on that surface.
Then it must be so gray inside.
It took many hours to do but it will be good.
There are many holes.
Then I made a door.
And fit in the wagon hatch and it is almost done.
Except for it to be polished.
It is rough -cut.
Here I did a rough ... A test polishing.
Then I did in a different way on the other side which got much better.
So I have to do the other side.
Now it is water cut.
-Yes exactly.
Now the polishing remains.
It is very straight and nice compared to the other side.
That part took about 14 hours to grind.
-You're joking!??
No it took 14 hours.
-14 hours to grind the little triangle?
Yes.
It is another 5-6 hours with polishing before I finished.
-You're crazy.
It's lucky you don't have to pay someone for that work because then the car had become really expensive.
-It's totally crazy.
If you add 6 hours on that page.
-Then you have 20 hours of work on the other side.
-Yes.
-And you should be ready before Easter ... -Yes hahaha ... that's the idea.
I have made a door that is suspended in my own hinges.
I cut to it so the transition is not completely straight.
I want some turn on it.
Then I have had to weld and put in pieces to get a good fit.
-The whole door have you built up and knocked yourself?
Yes.
-You are good.
Well...
...stubborn.
On the inside I have tried to rose polish.
The same way as the dashboard but it was difficult.
I can't do it in the pillar drill because it gets too deep.
So I tried by hand but it should be dressed with leather instead.
With a compartment here in leather.
Was how you wanted to do?
Yes, it is difficult with rose polishing.
It is a hot thing if you have a computer that presses just as hard and has the same type of grinding.
Then you get smooth and nice results.
-How long did it take to make the door?
Yes how long did it take ....
Hmmm ...
One and a half weeks about.
From scratch then.
Then I had to do special tools.
When I have completed the plate I put this one.
So it stands out so much.
Attaches it down to so it is firm.
-Yes.
Then I knock with a plastic hammer around the tube.
And then you get this bend down.
-What bending do you want?
It is partly upwards.
And that it turns in.
-Yeah that it swings.
When I make the other door I get to cut away the welding and turn hold so it becomes mirrored.
Now these parts are welded in this bend.
The door itself consists of outer skin and these two edge moldings that you can bend.
A lower and a front piece where hinges are sitting that I had to reinforce.
And finally the inner skin on the door.
-Impressive!
Now the hinges are in place.
Here there should be a list that is in the height of the hinge.
A sealing strip or d-list as it is called.
It should sit here because I want the car Vättentät.
I should be able to wash the car without the whole inside getting wet.
-Yes you could also run in the rain.
Yes that is the most important thing.
That's about as far as I've come.
I have made some small details.
I didn't have these moldings before.
Sat the rear view mirror in place when you were here last?
-No it didn't.
It is stuck in a regular M6 stick bolt.
Then it is removable.
You put it first here ...
Now it should be below this so it should be put there first.
Then you attach the mirror so.
What is missing now is the passenger door.
And fit the rest.
I smooth out the body with armored file.
-Pansar file?
Body file says many experts.
It is used to get a smooth surface.
To get rid of small elevations that exist.
And after that I start grinding with sandpaper.
Should I grind with sandpaper now, it just follows the bumps.
The armored file removes the bumps so you can grind then.
-How much planes it huh?
You have to stand for a long time.
You have to be careful so you do not get oblique.
Then you cut a jack into the plate.
Then you have to plan the entire area so that the jacket disappears.
You can't just plan in the same place.
Then there will be a pit there when polishing.
If you have a pit or a jack, you have to plan everything down until you get to the same level.
This surface takes about 5 hours to plan.
Here it is smoother and then it takes 2-3 hours with armored file.
There are various grinders you can use.
I tried a machine that lacquers call pancake.
It is a little bigger and has oscillating grinding.
It makes this movement.
And it also forced rotates.
An ordinary Oscillery grinding machine does not spin it just vibrates.
This machine spins and makes an oscillating motion.
Then it is easy to get the surface smooth.
I have tried that machine on this page and therefore it became much smoother.
That is why I should do the other side.
And then this type of abrasive paper is used.
This abrasive paper is larger than ordinary.
So it takes a larger area and it is easier to get flat.
-What do you start with for abrasive paper?
This is 180.
From 180 up to 2000 I use.
With 1000 and 2000, I grind with water at the same time.
Then it becomes this surface.
I use window cleaning.
I think that is smoother.
It gets a little halter and does not chop as much and easier to wipe.
-This is crafts without its like.
Yes it is ... we can take the other instead.
This one is stuck.
It is instead of chrome or painting.
It has a tendency to be burned fairly quickly.
So it's better to make a cover covering over.
-Mm, such a cover you do in 20 min ... NO half an hour..hahaha!
-Crazy!
No it takes a little longer.
Here you get some cooling.
Yes.
It takes in the air here and releases it on the underside.
Then it gets a stream of air that cools down.
-Is this polished and clear?
No it is rough polished but should be finely polished.
-And the one on the other side is just ground?
Yes it is just ground.
I have started to polish a little neighbor.
-Do you drive a machine then?
Yes it will be a bench machine.
As I drive in 3 different roughness.
-The lights were stuck last.
Yes but I can't remember if this one was done then.
This one will be unpolished but the stripes will be polished.
Possibly the edge around.
I thought it looked a little naked so I turned sleeves.
So it looks like it is a screw and there is a little more life in it.
The screws will be replaced so there will be recessed screws with lids in brass.
Here will be brass washers.
-You have an eye for details.
That's the fun.
That is the icing on the cake.
-It's what makes the difference.
I think it can be good ... you can always hope.
-Here you have started sketching the rims.
Yes.
I want a different piece on them than original.
That is an original rim.
Spinnersen I do not want so I have also shortened this cover and made it tighter.
I am thinking about using brass in this pattern.
Also in the center cover where I engrave Chevrolet in brass.
And it should be press folds in the brass.
The same pressed brass as it is on the wheel.
So it will be like spokes that I should have on the rims with.
I'll test on a rim so I'll see what it looks like.
I'm a little unsure if it fits but we'll see that.
-You don't know first you have tried.
Just.
And then it gets a little personal piece on the rim but we'll see.
-The interesting, it will be fun to see when it's done.
-I guess you want to go on and work?
Yes.
Yes we are heard and on reunion.
Bye.