It could have been Alfa Romeo, but this particular body is very shy.
-As the idea that you should build one yourself is completely crazy.
Yes, that wasn't the idea from the beginning ...
... that's the only way to get something so I started.
-Hey!
Well.
-How's it going?
Well thank you, that's good.
I changed the light so I try to fit a lid.
I removed the lid and will fix it now.
-What is it for a car?
It is a Ferrari F40 replica of a 1988 model.
I think the F40 is the most fresh Ferrarin so I want one so I did one.
-Which car!
I've done the whole car myself.
It is a pipe frame and the body is made of sheet metal.
I have done everything you see.
-How long took this?
Yes, yes I started already in 2005.
I've done a little when there is time.
Which I rarely had.
Which all my friends know.
The car is an icon for me so it may take the time it takes.
I think it's fun to keep up.
-Hehris have you done everything yourself?
Yes, I ordered beams home and started making a frame.
Then I made a steel pipe chassis that I covered with sheet metal.
-Is the whole car a pipe frame building?
Yes it is.
Then you get the body and chassis as you want it.
If you were to buy a car and build on, it would be strange as the engine is at the back.
Then you have to buy a Toyota Mr2 or Pontiac Fiero but then the car will be completely wrong in the dimensions so it will be good.
Then you have to do it right from the start and do a chassis yourself because there are none and buy.
-Yes I understand that.
-What fantastic job you have done.
I am quite a lot of work.
-As the idea that you should build one yourself is completely crazy.
Yes, that was not the idea from the beginning.
It's the only way to get something so I started.
I have made the plate in this goat.
It is the only tool I have used.
A homemade sheet metal and a hammer.
-You're joking??
No, that's all.
-Is that the only ones?
Yes, a knee or tire to bend some sheet metal.
That's how it went.
Of that, it became this creation.
-And everything is in sheet metal?
-It's not a kit-car that you built together?
No, it's no kit-car.
I have made my own frame and built the body pieces and sat on.
It is a difficult body to build.
All is swinged and bent back and forth.
There is sheet metal here and all the way up.
-You can only look at pictures?
-You must have received the dimensions from somewhere.
Yes a friend of mine built a Lamborghini Countach.
And he thought I would build one for me but I said I wanted a F40 instead.
I had a Ferrari F40 toy car in scale 1:18 which I measured.
I have it in the cabinet over here.
It is this little car that I have peeled up from 1:18 to 1: 1.
And that's the one I've built everything after.
I haven't had a real car to build up but just this one.
-So you demolished a toy car?
Yes exactly.
So you see what the car looks like and then you have looked at pictures online.
It wasn't only a few years later I got hold of a real car so I could measure and the dimensions are very good.
-It's totally crazy!
-How many Ferrari F40 are there in Sweden?
I don't know for sure.
Know that there are 4 but there may be more.
It is difficult to find them because they are very rarely running.
-How many made Ferrari?
Ferrari made a little over 1100 cars but so people have crashed so you do not know how many are left.
-I see that you like the F40 because you have all kinds of toys in this cabinet.
I have been a few over the years and when you have found someone you have bought.
-And I kept stumbling on something on the floor.
Yes it is my granddaughter's car that she goes around in.
It was just a small MC battery in from the beginning.
So she was sad when the battery ran out.
We put in a 100 amp battery from a car so now she can drive all day if she wants to.
-I am completely mute and don't even know where to start.
-Where do you want us to start?
We can start on the inside.
-It's no car you just jump in and out. No not directly it is low and tight to get into.
It is very wide edge and high threshold.
In here, the frame is and it is a crash zone because there is nothing that receives on the page.
So it's a pipe system inside.
-You sit a little oblique with your legs.
Yes it is a bit like a Saab 900.
It is because of the front wheel is right here in front and so it was on the real car.
-Italen gorilla choir.
Yes exactly.
I've made my steering wheel straight instead.
The original is angled so it feels like you drive a bus.
This is a oscillate with a flat bottom so you can fit your legs underneath.
I think the steering wheel with a flat bottom is nicer.
I bought a Ferrari emblem and put in the middle.
I have chosen Sparco sprint chairs that I bought once in a while.
I think they fit well and the original also has red chairs.
I have used saber three -point belt.
However, not all pieces are in place.
Also has regular belts that are a requirement from the car testing.
A 6-speed box from an Audi TDI.
-Many people who build use TDI gearbox.
Yes exactly.
TDI gearbox can withstand much more turn from the engine.
It is a 01e gearbox from an Audi A4.
Curved sheet so it looks like an old -80s gear lever.
Yes exactly.
Previously I had a regular one but this fits better.
Volt, temp for cylinders & water temp.
Then there are ordinary gasoline champions, oil, speedometer and tachometer.
-What is it for buttons under the voltmet?
It is the fan and the heat.
It is electrical heat as there is no water element in the car.
Then you would have to pull a lot of hoses for which there is no room so it became electric instead.
-Should we check out here then?
Yes.
-What are you doing here?
I was not happy with the lights that sat here.
I rebuild so it should fit in and be nicer.
I had to remove the lids so I could change.
As you can see, it is a sheet metal.
When I cut off the lids, they got a little injured that had to be fixed.
-You have rebuilt so the lids should only be fitted?
Yes they should fit in and fix some of the plastic.
-Ah, awesome!
-This is not really clear.
In here, a disc should be fixed and inserted.
The inner screens come from a truck.
-Ok, inner screens from a truck.
I have cut to so it does not spray a lot of stone.
-What is hiding behind the cover plate?
Below there is a battery, fan to the compartment, brakes and oil to the clutch.
-What is that on a real F40?
It is the same.
-There is there no place for a golf bag?
No, original there is a spare wheel there.
But I chose that.
I could put a wheel down we the radiator but do not want to.
In the front I have done the same as the Lemans model.
It has a great intake in the middle.
I'd rather have it but still the original front but I don't want the headlights that sat original.
Then I chose to mix the original and Lemans front.
-The cooler sits right behind the gills in the front?
Yes it does.
Then I have chosen to make the hole in the front much larger.
Original is the hole much smaller than this.
I chose to make that hole much larger so that the air can go through easier.
This means that the car is pressed against the hill when driving.
My dad made a fuel cap.
He thought it was unnecessary to buy.
We turned up some tank caps that we could use.
-What is it for decal back on the screen?
It also sits on the real cars.
-Yeah, they do.
-What does it say?
Pininfarina?
Yes it was he who designed the body together with Enzo Ferrari.
-But so, that you got to all angles.
At first I thought it was angular.
But the body is round and bent in all directions.
It has been very difficult to do.
This part consists of a single piece but this is a lot of small pieces.
Small pieces so you could get the shape together.
-The door handle.
I am my own design.
This is actually a lock to a window area.
-What does it matter?
No, it works.
-Is it so it looks original?
Yes, that's what the door handle looks like.
-The inserts your finger here to open.
Yes exactly.
Is this car ready?
No, it will probably never be done.
I am a little stingy and always want to rebuild things.
Have always tried to build something cheap.
But then you find something more expensive that you screw there.
Everything works and it can be driven.
Unfortunately, we unfortunately no more can.
You will see the rest in the next section.
But until then comment, subscribe and like, of course we will see in the next section.
-What do the taillights cost?
Ah, they cost SEK 5000 each when I bought them.
-You're joking!!
It is SEK 20,000 for 4.
Yes...