Damn, what a moped !!
-Hello!
Hey.
-How's it going?
It is just fine.
My name is Mats Ohlsson.
Hi Mats my name is Douglas
-I have understood that you like mopeds?
Yes, that's my passion.
-What is this?
Well I have a son.
He is often in the garage and helps.
Have river and pick up apart and think it's fun.
-It's fun with mopeds and there were many here.
Yes it is well ... half of the ones I own anyway.
-What do you want to show first?
Yes, that is what I like most and it is Zundapp.
Zundapp and drag racing are my passion.
-Do you drive drag racing with mopeds?
There are competitions around the country and even the SM is included.
-How is it that you started with drag racing?
I have screwed a lot with drag racing when I was younger, kind of promod.
Also screwed up a bit with snowmobile drag racing.
I've always liked drag racing.
-What is you competing with?
Should we check what you have.
We can start with the veteran class.
Then you can have one here.
Sure you can have a finer but I have chosen it to look a little worn.
-Lite Rat Rod?
Yes.
Mechanically, it is in top condition.
All brakes and layers are replaced.
It is very nice condition even though it is not visible.
-70 numbers?
No all mopeds I have are 66or.
Sport Combinette 1966.
So it is -66 that applies?
Yes right now ...
I have a little newer too.
The mopeds that stand here are from 1966.
This is a 1966 Zundapp Sport Combinette Veteranmoped in Veteran 70.
There is a veteran 50, 70 and 90.
-Is the number of cubic?
Then you can trim to 52cc, 72cc or 92cc and that is the maximum limit.
This one is at 66cc with a super term Athena cylinder.
It is not stroked so I am a little far in cylinder volume.
It is possible to stroke up to 72cc.
-What does it cost to trim?
Is it expensive?
Both yes and no.
It is a cheap sport to be motorsport.
Motorsport costs money but this is cheap.
I crashed a motor a week ago.
The block burst and the gearbox ...
It cost SEK 2500 to cook.
-Oh!
A little drive and shoulders then you can drive again.
A car engine that breaks can cost SEK 75,000 to cook.
Absolutely!
Or more.
This one I bought far out in the woods a few miles from here.
The only thing I couldn't fix was the idea.
It was so rusty so now there is a tank in the tank.
-A tank in the thought?
Well!
-It could not be repair.
There is a smaller tank inside.
Aha!
It is just to keep the look.
-What is this?
It is flocked.
It was very popular in the 70s to spray on.
It is very popular today.
Yes it may have come back.
Flowed dashboards, yes and stereo stuff etc.
-The glue did not look so nice.
No, but it should look like this.
It must not look too "good".
-What is that?
I first drove with original loaf
When I shipped the moped to Lycksele for a competition ...
... but then it started to rain so then I had to pull on a bag.
So I wouldn't get wet when I competed.
The moped is slowed down.
15.7 hp on the back Christmas.
-15 hp!?
Yes 15.7 and earlier it had 15.4 hp.
I think it has a little more now because it is going better.
It goes well and turns ...
The last time I drove I had driven a little too low then I had 14,500 laps above the finish line after 200 meters.
Then I had to drive up.
-What speeds do you come up with?
I have driven 102-103 km/h at its best.
-You're joking!?
-On a moped ??
10.3 seconds.
-Do you run 200 meters?
Yes, 200 meters with a stationary start.
-How many gears do you have?
This one has four.
3-4 years ago, 3 drove.
It was such a big step between 2an and 3an.
It is not suitable for drag racing.
Not if you are going to perform good times.
What I remembered from when I was young.
Now I didn't have Zundapp myself ...
... was that the gear slider had a long stroke.
Yes you hit the knee in the elbow.
That is why we who compete have gear stops.
-The gear stop?
I never miss a gear with this.
It is rare and works great.
It takes time to adjust because you rarely get a gear when driving slowly.
If you drive fast, it will be easier.
-Then we take the next moped.
Which one would you like to show then?
We can take this one.
This is a new building for this year.
It is also a veteran 70cc the same class as the other.
In the veteran 70cc you can also run a liquid cold.
-Wide cold?
This one has Stage 6 cylinder from Minarelli.
It is also stroked.
If I were to drive with Zundapp's stroke, I get more than 72cc.
It is stroked to 39.7 and reed -fed.
It was this engine that I was broken earlier this spring but now it is up again.
-The here you also have gear stops on.
Yes I have that on everyone.
This one I can error for a gear but next year I hope I have adjusted it.
-When you compete do you have several mopeds with you?
Last time I had 3 mopeds with me but it is too much.
There will be more quantity than quality.
I can't give all the mopeds love between the runs.
One or two is recommended.
-How very screw is it vs run?
Hmm ... change drives and nozzles ..
..The rusty I have been running so many years so I almost do not screw it.
Just pushed up a cog last time and it was probably the only thing.
This requires ignition adjustment, mouth cut ... ... there are so many adjustments left.
It can take 10 hours of driving before it goes 90% of its capacity.
The rusty is probably 100% of its capacity.
It is almost not possible to drive anything faster with it.
It is difficult.
But this is much left.
This one should go faster than the rusty but it does not.
It's a long way to go yet.
-It's still a run -in period?
Yes much left to adjust.
-The idea looks a little different?
Yes it is older.
I think this idea is good looking.
-The elder What is the year model then?
1964 or 1965.
The pear tank is much nicer than the rusty one.
-Yes both are fine.
I see another thing.
If you straighten the handlebars.
-It wasn't that wide rule?
It's just a bicycle government.
There were many buttons to be a moped.
Yes...
Here is the water pump.
The temp meter.
And the electric fan.
-Is there a speedometer with?
No.
Only temperature meter.
And dead man's grip.
There must be when we run drag racing.
I drive with HPI ignition system so I can choose between 2 ignition curves quickly.
What job!
The tires appear to be the same as my mc.
Continental Type MC Tire
Need there to be some special brakes?
No, but it must work.
Often you have a long distance to slow down when competing.
Some paths may be a short distance.
Often it is enough to release the gas.
But it is important that they work if something happens.
We also have a third moped but it looks a little different.
This is the next class, Promod.
-Promod!?
Yes it sounds violent.
Promod is available in 50, 70 and 100cc.
Promod 100 is a cruel class and they drive really fast.
In Promod you can have modern engines.
For example, AM6 and derby engines.
And in this class there are vespor with variant operation and they are going really well.
When everything is adjusted, it's just full gas.
I have chosen to run a Zundapp engine on this with.
-What does a modern engine mean?
Yes you can have 6-gears.
Most of them are reed -fed original.
It is awesome and lightly trimmed engines.
This is a little more complicated.
-You hold you to Zundapp.
It would be to put on an AM6 engine on this.
Then I would rather get further down in the field.
This is a promod 50, ie 50cc.
The rusty is 66cc in the veteran 70 class.
This one is quite exactly 70cc in the same class.
And this Promod 50 and it is about 50cc.
It is also stroked to 39.7 to keep the cubic limit.
-This this has Wheelie Bars.
Yes but I have not used that ..
... since it has not adjusted yet, I do not have the need yet.
But when everything works, I need it.
The other mopeds can turn around because it is too short wheelbase.
May be very careful at the start.
60 foot I run in 2.2 seconds at its best.
When this is optimized it is for 2 seconds and then Wheelie Bar is needed otherwise it will not be possible.
I understand!
This moped is much longer.
It is a self-built frame that is extended 12-13 cm.
And the parts extended about 5 cm.
So it is about 20 cm longer than a standard moped.
I've seen 3 different things.
The rusty has the board forward.
Yes it is to get as far ahead as possible at the start.
-And you have turned the handlebar forward.
Yes it is true.
Here the handlebar sits in the right place but is straight.
It is straight and a little more weight back but it works.
And this moped has the board far down.
Yes has moved down the handlebars on the front fork.
To be able to hang as far ahead as possible.
The entire moped is cast in fiberglass.
We have done plugs from a moped.
The idea with?
The tank is in fiberglass.
Below is a small trump card here.
There are several who have it in Promod.
It is nitrous oxide fed.
-Näää.
-Hahaha!
So it looks here.
-What moped!
How long have you been building this?
I've probably stayed for 1.5 years.
Me and a friend named Magnus Lindelöv have helped me very much.
It is we who have built this one.
He lives nearby so we have garage evenings with a folk beer and fixes with the mopeds.
Cozy and it sounds great fun.
-How many competitions is that?
There are 4 SM competitions.
Geographically it has been Lycksele ..
Hudiksvall ....
Orsa and Ludvika and it has been different every year.
And this year it was a competition in Laxå.
That was driven.
-How many are you competing?
-We were quite a few last and then we were 33 in total.
It is not a huge hobby, but we hope it will come and drive.
-Can imagine it's fun to watch.
It's really fun.
-We have been to any competition with cars ...
... they are impressed and think it is powerful.
We are not dissected, they think it is cool so I hope more will start competing.
-What is the most fun to drive?
Right now it's the rusty one because it delivers.
After all, it is tested to the max.
The other two I have a lot of work left.
-Both?
Yes both.
I tested it chassis last year and had this engine on.
Just to test the chassis and then I used this engine a polini that I ported myself.
I drove 10.3 and 105-106 km/h with that engine.
In this chassis and then I discovered that it had to be strengthened.
Trying to build as easily as possible but ...
... that engine twisted the entire chassis.
The chassis was too clumsy so I had to reinforce.
Last year you can say that chassis work well.
This year I have used the real engine but ...
... I have had problems with.
It sounds strange and I have scrapped some membrane and blown packing boxes when I drive nitrous oxide.
This is how there is ...
-How many people drive with nitrous oxide on mopeds?
Yes there are some pieces ...
... there are also those who drive with nitro in promod.
And those who drive with methanol.
It is quite unlimited in Promod.
-How is the buddy at the competitions?
It is very good.
-Ing hard rivalry?
No, it's a nice level.
There is no prestige.
Everyone knows everyone and we have fun in the evenings.
-You don't reveal your secrets?
A little bit so maybe, gate times etc ..
-When you trim do everything yourself?
I try to do everything myself.
I have built some pipes but have not got it really well.
Recently, I have bought ready -made that I have modified.
Contracted header, shortened and extended and made adjustments.
So that it hangs like a snake in the ceiling.
Yes a little different pipes that I have tried over the years.
-How long holds a piston & cylinder?
That .. you talk about the rusty, huh?
I have been running it for 2 years and I changed piston ring this spring that's all.
Although it turns so much so it holds well.
-What is this?
It looks like...
Here I usually sit and port cylinders.
Isn't this a goldsmith usually use?
Well, it's from an old workshop.
It is a little small sometimes and I have not been able to port coil.
Now I have found this and I think it is from the 60s.
It is old dental equipment.
Now I come down in the cylinders so I can change the coil.
-Where can you find such old stuff?
Think it was at Tradera.
You had one more moped over here is it also a Zundapp?
Yes it is a ride moped completely original.
Okay a utility lashes.
-Year model?
1969 with the famous ...
... purse crushes the idea.
-HAHAHA!!!
Yes you see why.
Don't want to drive into something.
The "famous" purse crushes the idea, fantastic!
I was at a moped rally last year but I wouldn't be allowed to come again if I didn't trim.
So that engine will be on this fall.
-It must not be original?
No no...
... it's for old people.
-How has it been when you compete?
Yes you have stayed in them over the parts of the classes.
Become 1a, 2a & 3a.
Sometimes you go out in the first round that I did last weekend against a quick moped.
Then you are out of the steps.
It was against a teammate Jens Hägglund.
That bastard!
-Hahaha!
I have no problem with that.
He was faster than me.
It is worse if you miss the start or a gear and lose when you have a faster moped.
Then it does not feel good but if you lose to a faster moped it is easier to take.
-Is there any moped we can start?
Can start any.
We can start up the rusty.
Don't think people understand that there is a lot to drive when it looks like it does.
Absolutely, pick it up.
-Do you nice on that one?
No!
I usually train a lot of starts and get abrasions the inside of the thighs.
So it is not nice but all for the look.
14400 rpm.
Well I have alternated more sometimes.
Now it's cold so I don't want to torment it.
Damn!
Which moped.
15840 RPM, Jeeesus!
Is there any club in town?
Yes there is a club called RFR.
RFR?
Straight forward racing so simple it is.
There are some in Ö-vik, Lycksele and Bjäst.
Great name!
Easy.
Hahaha!
It sounds like a cross.
16320 rpm, it's totally crazy.
-This is like a cross.
Yes the light is deceiving.
Hahaha, really!
It's totally crazy.
I didn't get the camera when you drove past.
A little missed gears when it is not a sharp position and you have foppa slippers.
Normally, the gears sit as they should.
Not many people do not think it should go fast when you see it.
It usually is so.
It has a lovely sound.
Yes it is straight in the clutch basket.
So it wines a little neighbor.
What a machine!
-How should you go if you want to start competing?
There are 2 pages on the Internet and Facebook.
Facebook: Swedish Moped Dragracing and Lyckseletwostroke.se
There you can read and ask questions.
Check out past events.
Then I think you should start competing.
There are so many sharp mopeds ...
... which can be competed with.
It's really fun.
1000 thanks for taking the time to show the moped.
It is really appreciated and it has given me a new view of trimmed mopeds.
See you later!
I hope to see this on a hit.
Yes, I get to go on a meeting in between Sweden and drive a little.
1000 thanks!
We hear hello!