I say it is 50 shades of black and four shades of red orange.
Not very beautiful.
It will never ever become original again, I can say.
No!
Not after I was here either.
You and I have a project that will be one or two parts.
We'll see how many there are.
What is the thing we should do?
It started with someone who commented on your feature with the hint.
Yes, after the section, a viewer heard about it.
And I thought I recognized the name.
And then you answer to that guy, I chase him.
He was of course with Rat Bastard Crew Sweden and he has a Volvo 140.
Could it be something more iconic than even the right piece too?
It is higher front and lower rear.
I bought it in Säffle from a young guy.
He had a little tired of it and would renovate some cheva instead.
Threw it out and I snapped.
From the beginning, the idea was that I would do
an original renovation on it, but I first
When I got home with it he was in much worse condition
than I thought, even though it was inspected two days
before I bought it.
The last inspection in life for exactly 50.
So when I got home with it so I discovered
That two shock absorbers were stuck with just one bolt.
The other end hung completely loose and all four feathers were so exhausted
So they hung on the rubber impact.
Bad repairs a little everywhere holes in the exhaust system.
How it went through the inspection, I do not understand that at all.
Much like the inspection was ten meters away from
And looked through a dirty milk glass.
But it was inspected that way.
I fixed well what was most urgent as I thought
There are brakes and front wagons and such things.
But now there was no original renovation.
I actually had that thought for almost a year
That I would grab it.
It wasn't very rust on it.
However, the repairs were a bit like that you can say.
But roasting is, they are beautiful in some way.
After all, the rear screens are epic.
Hahaha!.
Someone has stood with a sledgehammer and walked on there
And then they have thrown over the features with putty spade with such stripes in as well as
And drawn so you see the marks after the brush strokes on the front screen.
Yes, it is beautiful.
It will be interesting.
He was probably a brick and not a car plate maker.
The one who was on this one.
Have you had a 140?
Oh, I actually had a 140 from 1973.
But the big blinker, yes I rebuilt it.
The first rat I did Horny Hildur was called it.
It had three antennas with fox tail on each, one on the roof
And two on each on the rear wing.
It went off in the middle.
It was a flight of 5-6 meters so lands a little hard.
Then the entire rear axle and the stays and the berries loosen.
Everything went off the entire frame to the roof that held it together.
So I hope this one is in better condition.
I think so.
What plane was it in your head now?
Without revealing what it should do, no one knows what to do.
Green is good.
That's what I'm thinking.
Acid-Green has lots of different Green Goblin I think there is someone called.
It's exciting.
It's a lot of strange colors.
And then I drive with my pens too, my Montana, Easter and Molotov.
It will be a claner version of the heap maybe.
Now we drive on.
It's a little time pressure so we can get ready.
Today anyway, so that we can continue to be finished tomorrow.
This will take a while.
Yes, it will take a while.
I have to think a lot and it is very busy and takes time.
This one, it will never ever become original again, I can say.
No, not after I was here either.
It says a lot that then it is run.
Then he is a work of art instead.
He has simply ruined the car, surely thinks some.
How can you do that way?
It's like this.
We live in a free country.
Yes, everyone is entitled to an opinion.
That doesn't mean I agree.
No, I really like it blowing that just flutter even though I tense.
And I who are so long stand on toe even.
Not just easier to mask the taillights.
Male like this.
The lighting.
You can only cover that lighting with some tape.
Yes, here you see how good the spring is to hold up
This standard stuff.
When the stuff is 50 years old.
Then it will be like this.
Then you have to have hefty pieces of wood or bumpers.
Original Volvo Planka.
Yes an original Volvo plank.
Yes, it must be easier to tape than to do this.
No.
That is the original color.
The original color is dark gray that was only available in two year models, 1968-69.
And just that it is a -68A is the only year model
as it was with white gallon decor and the white interior existed anyway
What I have been able to get together with the dark gray only.
So that was probably the reason I bought it from the beginning
And thought about doing an original renovation on it.
Stylish original color and it is a unique combination on Volvo.
Must love the finish on your taping.
This is something I can't buy any cars
In my days there have been some.
What is happening now?
Should it be covered?
Well, yes, this color will not remain.
Then we get to see a lot that ends up here on the wall
As you say it blows a little.
Here it blows from all directions.
But I like this garage is like unlimited.
It is the free ceiling height.
You can see it that way.
Can put this.
It will not blow away I hope.
Press it oh well it sits now.
So 70s plastic.
There you always had 50 trout you pressed between the list here
And there they pressed them with 50 trout.
Then it stopped sounding when you went over 150.
It started with seeing Doc down at Elmia
Actually, that he will be so awesome
To see what he finds for something.
Yes, he has his ideas.
He has it and they change themselves second by second.
So yes, we will see what results will be.
And the finish here, I really sanded down here.
Looks good.
You feel how polished here is really what I thought was dirt.
But it wasn't here.
That's how.
Yes.
You should have it there.
And today I have reinforcement of my mini me too.
He must be involved.
I teach him, I teach him everything I can.
I saw that he has already started painting on your car.
Yes, of course he has full access to my inside on the car.
The decor is actually as much part of as I am.
Or what do you say Killi.
Can you show how much you can paint in there.
It is completely new that yes will fix.
Now it gets pink in the car.
This is one of the onsets.
They are replenished these too.
Can you buy these on ...
When you fill this now that it starts to come here
Damn what it shines pink.
So now you can paint pink painted on the inside.
No, the inside of the door.
On the door I'm there.
Wow, make a skull?
Show what you do.
There is some color that sits on the doors now.
Absolutely wonderful to know that Killi has been painting everything.
He can help me all the time.
That is the best one can do instead of letting the kids
Just sit and wait and watch.
You should let them participate.
It is probably the most important thing.
Now we will start where we will start with a little dark green,
put on the sides
And then we will move to another shade and further and further.
Damn, now I'm so hungry at Start.
That was really green.
Hmm .. sorry.
Paint around the blinker so.
I can control a little indeed.
The cap is very good!
Got the tip calligraphy cap for it runs very wide
and it sprays a lot of color at once so it covers at once
Also as soon as possible.
Oh!
Yes, wait until you manage to blow all over you.
Now it is not visible, but I have the world's best increase in the back.
Do you have tubes or?
Two hockey pucks from Biltema.
Yes that is good.
Always works with hockey pucks.
I learn to be able to fill in the car fairly quickly
When everything fine is all that takes time.
Everything else you do.
Oh what a nice repair it was here.
Thought it would blow less here, though.
It becomes like a wind trap instead.
But I say 4-5 different shades of green that I should use.
It has already dried.
Oh I will have workouts.
But what kind of drying time is like this?
2 seconds about.
It also dries directly.
It is dry on the other side.
Which one should we use Sandra do you think?
It's not just six, it's two at the bottom
Also on each.
We are far from clear.
I want to get it reasonably uniform to begin with.
Pretty monotonous job.
It is.
This is what is boring to lay ground.
Yes, to base yes.
Do you take one more like that ....
null
Do you think the color is enough?
We'll see how it will solve considering a lot of colors with me.
But if I have 40 cans, I think I have a little to take off.
Nice to get it a little more uniform.
Will be easier to drive on then.
Looks like it's the grinc that you paint.
Yes, that's about this.
But the waffle, stop blowing, it blows in all directions now all of a sudden.
So there are throwing winds sometimes.
Hell how fast it dries.
The sun is shining on us and it pulls right away.
Now I run some half -paint this gray too.
Love that the cracks come out when I do.
Bird shit on the roof where it should remain.
What did you say?
The three spots with bird shit on the roof are the ones left.
We can remove them if you want, but it is optional.
You can do so.
But that's not right.
It's not art.
I was thinking about one thing.
How should you be able to paint the ceiling?
I stand with an open door and paint improvise and overcome,
So you do.
It is not the first roof I paint considering cards I am.
But it usually works.
Though the worst that it blows so hell
That we may be able to take something that is a little longer than me.
You never know.
In that direction?
Yes, in that direction.
Drive closer and so a little faster.
Then it goes down as much color as possible even though it blows.
It must not reveal anything.
Yes I know.
Then when I get back from work tomorrow, when it's done.
Wait, you haven't seen anything?
Well, I know it.
Is it a break now?
Yes a little break.
Coffee break here so.
I have well bombed the car some now with gray
And green in different shades.
Have started with some of the design that will be.
We are out in the largest garage available, nature.
And it blows something terrible in all directions.
At the same time, I think I don't blown so much,
Then I would not have had to use as many cans
As I used now when the sun is on.
Warms up the plate when you burn and it is in the montana color
From highlights where the bracket directly dries at once.
It really does when you paint the car.
Then comes the incredible work that you put into rust cooking on this one.
I wonder many centimeters with putty it is, especially at the back.
The rear screens are absolutely fantastic on both sides as well.
Looks like those who have a flood with bread roller.
But it is about the same as here around the door handles.
But the grinding looks like they have good on
With the sharp side of the angle grinder.
Under work they have put down type above all the final finish
They put down non -existent.
That's what I like with this whole nice lamp
After 73 ans' front screen also there with gigantic flashers.
DN is cool this one a real 140.
This is nothing you had done an original renovation on.
No, then you had probably changed every part of both rear screens,
The front screens, the bottom, the top.
It is fantastic!
I love this.
Yes, they have pulled a farmer's screw on both rear.
The boxes are stuck with a farmer's screw.
It's male.
Farma screw should be used for a lot.
My exhaust system sits up with the same screw.
But it was fortunate that they did not drill into the tank
or something.
It is usually quite long screws too, kind of one
and a half to two centimeters.
You can screw through a lot when you are doing it,
But they have actually succeeded in the rear window because they have not cracked the boxes.
It's a little cheating I think.
But now I have soon covered so all the old is gone.
I'll fix the front and rear end too so it's over, painted and clear.
Then I can start driving.
With the design I will run a bit with tape and stuff and put up lines and stuff.
It is going to be fun.
And chalk should also be used.
For once, I shouldn't even use anything
Detergent I think.
I don't think detergent with this time.
It was a shame that I didn't have it with me.
It's stainless.
I've had this front.
I like the grounding.
Yes it is amazing.
It is part of the whole car I think.
And if it works, it works.
It is a classic temporary permanent repair.
This one you mean?
Yes, it is the best ground ever.
It works, why should you change it?
It doesn't matter where I stand because it blows me anyway.
I'm sorry.
But incredibly advanced the opener.
Love this.
Why is a white in here for?
Ask any previous owner who has started a renovation?
No.
When I bought it had it had
Seven different owners in seven years.
And rolled 100 miles.
Many people have started and given up.
The deep sighs of the deep sighs believe yes.
Damn, this is going to be cool.
Where are you in the process?
I am long before what I do now I can say.
It is now that I think about lines and also some decor that I should do.
Now I'm going to draw some lines here.
I'll make a screen.
Just get just for
That I can make a screen.
So it is not Finlir who takes time.
It will take time this.
I really like the screen sitting loose here
And that it really finish.
Amen fucking moldings and sit loose.
Ah, it was a difficult line.
There you can say that it is starting to get.
So fun to start when you start with the lines,
Because that's when it really starts to what in?
It is starting to look really cool.
Then it should be shaded by 3D and then I will do some other stuff too.
Crackling and glitter spray.
But this is starting to be fun so now I put the first one with black.
Then I haven't really decided yet that some parts
won't be with black lines but i put black as a background only
And then another color puts over.
The gray becomes very very nice together with with black.
I think that looks great, but the green will need
Another color in the end I think.
So we'll see what it gets.
It will be a surprise I know.
I think it's fucking awesome.
I am terribly excited about what it will be in the end.
Right now it is green.
AAA.
A little gray, but I like that it is two tons so the ceiling will be.
Yes you but ...
I had hoped it would be a little plum lile or something.
Now I am not in such a period in my life.
That's just the beginning.
In that I will work tomorrow too so we can work completely undisturbed
And I can't see any difference in the result anymore.
And then it's a damn plum red stuff.
So it will be a completely different car when I see it tomorrow.
Should we leave then?
Yeah!
Then we continue tomorrow.
To be continued.