What you done?
After all, it was just tearing everything up.
I see it, but you would just fix a little neighbor.
Yes, it was probably the desire if you say.
But no.
Hello Hello!
Do you hear we were at Öland this summer.
Yes, very nice.
Check out Pers Sarolea where you had built.
You had some small fixes on yours.
Yes, it wasn't really like this I had imagined.
The fun here is that we would use this motorcycle as a reference
Before we went to Öland, so one would understand
What it was.
It was not intended that this should be a project.
No, but it was.
Yes, you see that it is still a motorcycle.
But it is a little bit picked.
After all, you had removed the lamp last.
Yes, I don't know.
Probably they have built this mound for them to have it as a pedistal
And just have something to look at because everything was resolved.
Every screw, nut.
I mean the connection and everything raged and.
Yes then i did not get the charge up and then i have been doing
And tried to get hold of a generator.
But this is this, a Miller generator.
Fairly common generator in England at BSA and Royal Enfield,
But they always had their switches in the engine block.
But Sarolea has her switch for the ignition then in the generator.
So that generator is pretty rare because it's just sarolea
that uses it.
So the only generator I could find.
I have tried to get mine started, but no, it is not possible.
It is a bit special with because it sits only a coil in this
so they must have a special charge regulator
and it is a regulator that is constantly lying
And pulses power into the winding.
So a modern charge regulator does not work.
So I bought a charge regulator, an electronic,
And bought new winding.
But no, I didn't get that started.
Don't charge anything.
And I have checked that it is properly linked.
And there is to buy.
One has found Europe down in Belgium and then guy there.
One?
One, he had.
But he knew it was unusual.
12,000 plus tax plus shipping and a little.
Yes.
No, it's not that fun.
I mean damn it is more than what half the bike is worth
so to speak.
So I went a bit and looked in the hides here in the garage
And then I found an alternator generator.
Admittedly 12 volts.
But 12 volts are no problem, it just gets better.
So I have reduced it as much as it ever goes.
Used the gable on the old generator where the switches sit
and made a small extension on the shoulder.
And yes, a small device so I get these drives there
for there is an interchange with it so that it should the generator spin
twice as fast as the switch does.
It is well because the generator needs a higher speed.
But after two weeks of crunching and turned and welded
Well welded, yes, I have not done with much pill I have actually got it there.
And there we have the generator.
This is how you can see the air intake.
There are small fans inside to take air out
And circulate.
Then I made a stainless steel cover.
To get a more smooth surface.
Have we had to cut it all the brackets and stuff.
So this generator I have made my own screws
that sits behind the drive.
Sitting four screws so that it is screwed
from this point.
Then you have to put on that drive after.
There you have the crankshaft.
When you kick, you see then it drives.
Then it goes all the way up.
Now these are a bit loose and on the other side you can see.
There we have the original house for the switches.
So you do.
So I have screwed the plate where the switches sit.
But it then spins.
Then the surface is against it.
So from this page I look almost original.
This is where you can see that it is a little more modern thing
Sitting there.
I think that does not bother.
And then even then under the generator here where I made a plate bracket
that has put a small rubber pillow on so that the generator is lying
And resting on a rubber pillow.
A little buckle.
That said, these engines vibrate a little neighbor
and then sits the generator screwed with four screws at that end
So easy that it lies and vibrates and then they go off after a while.
But if you put such a damper rubber, it is more steady,
Then it lasts for more miles.
Then it was the oil pump that was broken and it was the same repair on it
As I got to do on my cousin's Sarolea.
Here is a cylindrical piston with drive along
So on the inside here.
Now it is not possible here unfortunately.
But then it sits.
It inside that drive, it sits like a screw in that direction.
That goes on these drives and then it becomes that this one starts to spin
And then there is a screw there that goes down a track.
That is oval in this cylinder so when it spins
Then it starts to go back and forth like this.
And then you see in those holes it starts to pump oil.
There is oil here.
And so comes here.
But I think the oil is over now.
I've been pumping everything out now so now you can oil it too.
So these two channels, they go in.
In this cover.
It's the two.
And then a pump in oil there and lubricates.
The entire crank party.
The other one.
It goes up and lubricates them here.
It also goes up here.
And get up to the top.
And lubricate the lashes up here.
So you can say that this one becomes like a double pump.
One manages the crankshaft, one manages the drive and the top
and then it's the same thing it was on my cousins
That when you have oil pressure you see that this little stick here.
It is spring loaded.
Then he goes up.
Then I go down when the pressure disappears.
It did not go high for me without no.
It will be to mecca first.
Yes but you knew that.
Yes.
I would like to go through too so I know it really works.
I have not decided whether to disassemble the gearbox yet.
Should the oil anyway.
It's something that is safe.
And then possibly take that top lid and check out this
So that the valves really are dense.
But the engine has submitted to the motor renovator.
So I think it should work.
But when you looked when you picked this apart
So these drives didn't sit right.
There you see a small dot.
And then there is a dot there.
They should be in the middle of each other.
Similarly here.
Find a dot and a dot on it and likewise down here.
Most importantly, it is.
Here is Kam the drive.
It is very important that it sits right because it sits a dot on the instance dot
On this drive and it was not true that I got it started.
It was absolutely incredible for that drive where they turned
out and in so it was not possible to see any dots
At all on it.
Then they have missed the oil pump that it was so worn.
We'll see.
I will give him a chance to start up he
And see look for noise.
Then I hear something.
Every now and then we stop down and then we look it up.
Then it's equal to the wheels
Have known a little on the brakes.
When running with the handbrake and spinning on the wheel
So it chops like this and it will be because the spokes.
Is attached directly to the brake drum here.
They sit here in the brake drum.
It sits in the oaks here.
Then it is very important that you have the same tension in all the oaks.
For you have two oaks that are too much drawn.
Then the hole in here becomes oval and then it becomes that it chops like this
When it slows down the handbrake.
Sometimes you can actually hear.
It is tense and it is slack.
You hear that on the key.
The higher the tone the tensioners are.
So it is low.
It's not tense.
There you have a very.
I am a deaf, so it would have been worthless to me.
The rear wheel is not so dangerous.
There you can live with if it chops a little neighbor,
But the front wheel is quite unpleasant if you need to brake hard
And it starts to giggle like this.
So you have to fix that.
I have ripped a whole electrical system, all the cables and this.
It's not good MC cables because they are.
If you look at these, there are very few threads so such a cable
becomes very stiff.
The stiffer the cable you have the easier it goes by vibration.
This is how you want a cable that has a lot of threads
which becomes soft and compliant.
Then he can lie down and vibrate without such a thing.
The engine vibrates very much so then it is important
That you have the right cabling.
And it is also an advantage when you have 12 volts.
Then you do not need to have such coarse cables, but then you can go down to dimension.
If we say it was three square millimeters in six volts
So you can go down to one and a half when we drive twelve.
Then it is easier to get hold of soft cables.
It is removed.
There are some left that I will remove.
I have been able to buy a larger battery that is twelve volts
But it is the same height as six volts so it fits almost directly.
Here and there you see no major difference.
I took 6 volts, the battery was so big.
The miss does not adorn.
I get to rebuild the lantern here with the reflector.
But i have looked a little bit and i think probably curse me
that one can use lantern from a golf for it has about the same size
And then I can also have H4 lamp for here sits a holder
for a 6 volt lamp.
No, but that I think can work.
Then it is an advantage to get that name Lucas,
He who invented the darkness.
Maybe a little nicer if it says Bosch.
Now I get Verrenda Englishman after me.
You get every single one who drives English car by the type I drive English car.
There are quite a few who love English cars here in town
So I have to look back most when I move forward.
It will probably be alright.
We continue on it, then we have to check when we start it.
I look in here when it's time.
Yes, we say so long.
We'll do that.
Hello Hello!