A new student can expect warmth I would say,
Fun and exciting people with great integrity.
It is great fun when we get a visit from active opera singers.
Then they come here and guest teaching in masterclass form.
The best thing about studying here at the School of Music, I would say is the quality of teachers,
the quality of premises and the fact that you get so much time to practice,
Because I think that is very fun.
Students absolutely spend time across genre boundaries.
There are many occasions in the form of some courses being mixed instruments.
That's a bit what you do it for yourself, the time you have at school.
As a musician, whom I study, you do not have a lot of lessons a week, but
As I usually say, we have no leisure time, we have exercise time.
I have developed in the way that I think I have become a little calmer in myself.
It probably has to do with all the nice colleagues I have at school, which helps me a lot.
It feels like we all drive each other in a pretty good way.