The best thing about this education has been several things, but one of the absolute best has been the heat and community at the school.
Competent teachers, talented teachers like us ... We read so many subjects.
It is not just organ, but classic piano, hearing piano, singing and choir.
I have been very pleased with the quality of education in all subjects.
It may be that you have individual lessons on Monday and so practice on it.
Then you have Tuesday in driving, where you are in a group together, and then maybe you practice it.
And so Wednesday ... there is great variety every day.
Each day contains something else from the previous day,
which makes this education completely unique in its kind, both as a musician education,
But in general, I have never been so stimulated and inspired by my previous years at university.
My name is Noa Edvardsson and I study the last semester of artistic candidate in church music here in Malmö.
We have a very good position between our students.
After all, we have both a candidate and an office line that you read at the same time, so we can help each other and peep each other.
And then we have a very good collaboration with the churches here so we have to come out and play and substitute and get better.
Organ knowledge and precisely that width with these great teachers on all the instruments you have too,
I don't think there is anywhere else in Sweden than just in Malmö.
You are tired but happy every Friday because it is intense but always fun.