Do you eat candy?
I myself eat fish.
It is raw fish, as in Japan.
Real raw fish.
It spins like a cat.
It's brand new.
There are only two copies throughout Scandinavia.
Yes, Svindyr.
But if you want to be unique, it costs money.
- Word.
- Paul.
-New car?
-Yes.
You with, I see.
This is Lisa, my girlfriend.
This is Nina, my girlfriend.
God, what you are slim, Peter!
You have to bulge up!
That's why you don't get any girls!
Come.
- Would you like to lie with him?
-No.
You see!
Welcome!
Today we celebrate the 10th anniversary.
We offer Russian caviar in the delicacy department.
It is completely free.
Hurry to make a bargain!
Hello!
To me, it feels like a giant hand is throwing me up in the air.
How wonderful!
To me, it feels like all blood is being thrown back and forth in the body.
An incredibly strong feeling!
Yes, for me it's a bit like ...
... book sale.
It is important to be there on time.
Check out what a cool pattern!
You can see such a pattern before fainting.
Then Magnus said: "That's my crown!"
No matter how much money you earn, you have no one left.
We have received a salary increase, but do we seem richer?
You have the same old ugly clothes!
It's better not to have that much.
Money makes people weird, that is.
- It is not possible to get rich in Sweden.
- only on lottery.
But it is very simple.
Have you won the lottery?
We handed in 32-row ironing tips last spring, but we only got 6 right.
But Kristina had crossed the Joker box.
It gave 23 million.
-No...?
–23 million?
We have 22.9 left.
It must have changed your lives totally!
- I have not changed anyway.
- No, you're like you.
My God, you are multi -millionaires!
- We bought a new lamp for the hall.
- Yes, maybe it was a little unnecessary.
Many people usually give away some money.
- You have friends.
You have us!
- Yes, our Volvo is not so good anymore.
We have thought about it back and forth ...
I don't know how it is with you, Kristina, but now I have decided.
You will not get a penny.
That's what you say: Money just destroys people.
- It would be good with coffee.
- If you can afford it.
How lousy that they test makeup on animals.
What do they know?!
Surely guinea pigs do not have undergraduate cream?
How wonderful!
You play with the Royal Philharmonic!
How awesome to play an instrument!
- I have some musical talent.
-What are you playing?
I play on my own body.
I have played a lot for Kristina at home.
You should hear ...
Sprouting sound
Surely it is a delicious sound?
I curse my hand over the armpit like this ...
Do you play a lot in Europe?
- I came home from Vienna last week.
- You have to repeat a lot.
- No, I've always been able to.
- I meant Sebastian.
- I'm glad it's us, Leon.
- I too, Robyn.
What is so good about us is that we do not have to make ourselves for men.
We do not need to make up, have panties or breasts ... yes, breasts we have ...
- Can't we cuddle a little ...?
- It's real stuff!
We don't have to make up, don't have panties or breasts ...
Strong girls do not need panties!
Are you with me?!
- Yes, I'm with you!
-It is good.
- Now you have been mucking too!
- You are no more than human.
- Can't you play anymore?
- Do you hear?
It's always fun to play a little.
You start.
We played nicely together.
Go straight ahead and then right here in front.
Well, it's right!
I thought it was ...
Are there any problems, or ...?
-Is there any problems?!
–Rbyn ...
-No!
-Ouch...!
- Let moss, Leon!
Strong girls ...
--... Don't ask for the road.
- I love you, my little woman!
Tord?
Here is the report.
I have worked with it all weekend.
I think it seems a little bad.
I'm doing this ...
- There you deleted my report.
-That's right.
- Is this your mobile?
-Yes.
- There you put my mobile in mineral water.
-Yes, Loka water.
May I ask you to stand up?
Turn to me.
A little wider between the legs ...
There you kicked me on my scrotum.
- I will give you a Danish skull.
-Yes.
FIGHT
- What do you do, Leon?
- Nothing, I'm just standing here and ...
... thought of all the girls with string panties.
Look, just a strap in the ass!
You might think you were going to buy a pair of string panties.
-No!
- Sound mash, Leon.
- Strong girls ... --... don't have panties.
Now we look at the Wheel loader.
And you, we don't go here.
Stay!
As a customer you should feel that you are in good hands.
We stand for security ...
-Ah!
- I will kill you, yours ...!
That's one thing I've been thinking about for a long time, but never said, Carita.
- I think you have beautiful eyes.
-Per-Arne ...!
That was nicely put.
- Now I said it anyway.
-Yes you did.
That is another thing that I have never said either.
Those earrings ...
They don't dress.
- I have had since we met.
-Yes.
- Then I take them well.
- Do you want to do it, Carita?
-Yes.
- I love you, Carita.
I love you, Per-Arne.
But it's probably best that I take care of them.
Now it feels better ...
This is that the size does not matter any role is true.
If he has a small, you can still go in a cool car.
Honey, I've made a little verse.
It is about how it should be here at home.
"The doormat should lie against the threshold if I do not want to beg."
"And in the lower cabinet, woe and horror, there is a pink cloth" -
- "As used for sinks only, I don't want to be my wife to load."
"The toilet lid I close with haste" -
- "And the towel to the right when I cleaned my Task."
The last is an emergency rhyme.
Stop!
-Good day.
I want to talk to a priest.
- Yes, it's going well.
I am the priest, then.
Stefan Elmers steel.
Gun my name is ...
What can I serve with, Gun?
What do you think, Stefan, that you can be at service?
Maybe I should not think so much.
Do you want guidance?
- Do you feel for Jesus?
- Yes, they hung him on a cross!
Jesus died for our sins.
Now we need each grogg, Stefan.
- It is an alcohol ban here.
- You can't live by ban.
- If you ... - bowl!
Take it!
-Bowl.
-Bowl...
Is there anything that weighs your heart?
When you look at such a neighbor guy as you feel the heart as a bird.
I'm just here to help you ...
If you want to help me, just come and pick!
- It doesn't go for itself ... - Inger!
- Stefan!
-Do you drink?!
-Sorry...
Come on, Steffi, don't be so stiff!
Came back!
Hello!
Stefan!
What are you looking at?!
- Mom had some buns in the freezer.
- Mom's good buns.
She could bake buns!
- This day we will split the estate.
- I take a bun.
Mom wanted us to do it ourselves.
We can go through the house.
- It sounds like a good idea.
- We start with the most valuable ...
Wasn't there five buns?
This board is a genuine Wirhem-Wiik.
Here Mom has written a note: "The Tavvla ..." She has spelled wrong.
"This painting will his few. Mom, Stockholm in 1963."
May I look at the note ...?
- It says "Manpower" on the note!
- There you work, Hans.
- Mom liked a lot of manpower.
- Manpower was not in 1963.
There was certainly something called so.
Domus was called Konsum.
- Ohléns was certainly called Manpower then.
- No, it's called Tempo.
- How to explain it, his?
- It was a little chance.
But you revealed me ...
Then I remove the note.
- I love that clock!
-Me too.
Here says a new note: "This Wise ..."
Ouch.
A little chance.
- Here's nothing.
- It may need better light.
Wasn't there five buns?
There is something on the clock.
"This clock should Marianne have."
Signed "Marianne 1987".
No ... "Mom 1987 ..."
So, old man.
So yes!
Can't we do this as adults?
Everyone will probably be satisfied.
- What are you eating on, Ingrid?
-Nothing...
- It's Magnus Bulle!
- No, it didn't say "Magnus" on it!
It doesn't say "Magnus" on it either, so it's mine!
Tord and Paul ... We'll sing to Gudrun.
She is 40 years old.
- Yeah!
40 years already ... the years go by.
Kristina!
"God of love" in four letters?
"Phil"!
Dr. Phil!
Yes, it goes in.
"Tenderness", what could it be?
"Non-existent."
This one then ... "can get worse?"
"Nothing."
One to cute little stone!
Oh!
Look, a tuler!
God!
Look, what nice colors!
Come!
- River, which stone is the cutest?
-This.
Well.
Which one do you think is the second cutest?
-The.
- Yeah, do you think so?
- What is the second most cute?
- It, then it and then it.
Over and out.
Good night!
- What is it wrong with it?
-Nothing.
- What is it, Kristina?
- I don't feel really relaxed.
-Don't you like the Raff set?
- It feels uncomfortable.
Come on, don't be so stiff!
Program text: Helena Habermann (C) Swedish Television AB 2004