Last dance, last chance
SNORES
-Satan, AJ!
- They have called from the municipality again.
It is Björn at Getberget, we have to trace it.
Should we ask if Elin wants to come along?
Should she run in the woods in high heels?
She does not survive a crows.
Come now.
- But Leif ... - no but!
Departure sound
Fuck!
Hörtu, Leif.
Check.
Fuck!
- Is it Björn?
- I know int '.
Move.
It is smoking fresh.
Damn!
It's a bear here!
-Are you sure?
-Yes.
-What are you doing?
- I play death.
Up with you, snap skull!
- I run home!
-Silent!
You stay.
Hisses
- Hell, no, no, no!
- Introduce combat position.
Not on me, damn thick!
She is behind the stone.
Advance!
Are you ready?
Let's go.
Go, go, go!
Stop!
It's just me.
–Elin.
- I could shot the skull of you!
I was just joking, sorry.
You can not lie here and sound like a bear!
Don't know how a bear sounds?
- ELIN may know what the stool is.
- Maybe I know.
Hardly.
You have probably perfume in the armpit and skull there.
The animals you have scared away long roads' journey with screams and perfume.
- What have you come up with, then?
- Bajs sausage belongs to a bear female.
- Now we have to move.
- Can I hook up?
It would be nice!
We have no choice.
If we leave you, you become minced meat.
Come then.
Hurry up.
Sound like a pig in the woods ... - and you think it's fun, Billy.
Elin joked.
Yes ... now you are int 'among tile stoves, fools and trams.
What is it like to be in the forest with real hunters?
I camped alone here when I was ten.
When I was 14, I shot a moose.
I am as much hunter as you.
She says she is as much hunter as me ...
- You haven't read the hunting book?
- You mean this?
I've read it a couple of times.
We make quiz with facts from here!
Yes, I can read the questions.
We must have a price too.
This note that you ran from ...
I paid SEK 3,244.
If you win, then it's "fine".
If I win, you will pay back.
- Yes ... then drive.
- Fan, what fun!
Okay, first question.
"Which of the following is a hunting dog:"
"Jack Russell, Gray Dog or Shepherd?"
- You can start.
- You can train any dog.
It doesn't matter.
That's my final answer.
It is for the hell a gear.
–Line?
- The right answer is gray dog.
Right!
1-0 to Elin.
Second question: "What is the moose in Latin?"
—Leif?
Do you want to answer?
—The elig is ...
It's called ÄlgoSaurus ... Sus ... something in that direction.
Moose is called "Alces Alces" in Latin.
-Right!
2-0 to Elin.
-Woo hoo!
Bam!
"Bäm" ... I'm not going to read trams in some fucking fourth book.
I have a pain in the skull, I have been useful all day.
- So ... - then you won, Elin.
Yes, I did.
Should we play cards?
- We can do that.
- Billy, come and lie down.
Yes ... another time.
Good night, Elin.
Goodnight sleep well.
Oh my God.
Leif Öhman ...
- Billy: Where will this be?
–Leif: Get the sticks here.
Not like that!
-What are you doing?
- Hunters do not sleep half the day.
The clock is half past four!
But, Leif ... You're not angry for the quiz?
You do not learn that little book in your handbag as a real hunter.
In practice, you have no chance.
Come on something else we can compete in, then!
Okay, it's just for wilderness men, but we take you to the hunting track.
- Hunting?
- So she has to look at one and the other.
Oh, oh, now you have taken water over the skull.
Come.
Let's see...
-What is this?
- It is my and Leif's hunting track.
My record is 1.03 and Leifs in 54 seconds blank.
You have never seen a real hunting track?
Watch and learn.
-Are you ready?
- Drive, Billy!
3, 2, 1, drive!
Warning for scabies!
Oh, Satan's SKabbräd attack!
Pepper spray.
You beat your old record by two seconds.
Congratulations!
-What are you saying now, Lill-Stockholm?
–Ever, see-ri-east?
What are you doing?
No normal person fights against stuffed animals!
It's just sick!
- Yes, Leif does it ... - Yes, I see Leif does it!
So ... should we see who is the best?
Why not a regular, fucking shooting test?
Now the evasions come hail.
So this is not enough?
- A simple shooting test ... sure.
-Thanks so much.
Good.
Stick away and pick up two jars, then.
I am tired of the Stockholm Folleriet.
- You start, little Stockholm.
- Yes, I can start.
Satan ...
Complete!
Now it's your turn.
Move the jar to the little one in front of the big stone.
Leif ... should you really aim for it?
You can't shoot at a stone, it can be ricochet.
You can't aim for the stone!
Well, Leif!
Are you sick in your head?
It is fatal!
Do not you understand?!
That's enough!
Here is the bill!
I won this "competition".
BYE!
By the way.
That poop ... I can help with it.
There was no bear.
It was mine.
Cursed ...
Burner!
- Billy!
-Leif!
- What the hell has happened?
- I've been hit in the shit.
- It's no danger, up!
- No, I want to die alone.
- Creed yourself.
- We will take you to the hospital.
-I will die.
Hurry!
-Get up!
Come then.
- You have to take care of the farm.
- You will not die.
Wear me, I'm paralyzed.
Chill down and take it easy
Tag down a little while
Inhale and then out a second ...
Swedish texture: Karin Karlsson Hutt (C) Sveriges Television AB 2017