Tjena, it's Tord.
I'm getting a little late.
I email the report this afternoon.
Hello.
That's me.
I'm getting a little late today.
I email the report this afternoon.
It is good.
Hello!
Yes!
Yes Yes!
I'm coming!
- Is that this?
-I do not think so.
I have an avi.
- It has not come.
- It would have come a long time ago.
- Then is this this?!
- I should have a shirt, not a book.
- It's not even my name.
- Wait a little, then.
Be so good, here you have your shirt.
- It's not my name ... - fuck!
It is from Ellos!
Now we do this ... it will be good.
-Nice weekend!
- You can't close now.
You just stand there.
If you wonder where Berit is, she has gone home.
- Has the fourth gone?
-No.
- So it hasn't gone?
Has the four really not gone?
No!
- It's on Furusundsgatan.
- Aha, on the walkway.
- You have to try it.
What a lunch!
- Have you tried the pocket at the corner?
Is he tired?
It's a tape recorder.
He is with his dad today.
You have exactly the qualities and the know-how we are looking for.
I want to end by asking some more personal questions.
We say you got the job.
It's the first day.
You will arrive well in advance and are assigned a study room.
Then comes Andersson, the red cry.
It is his room and the light in his new room impairs his psoriasis.
-What are you doing?
- Return the room.
Well, I understand ... then I say ...
Nothing.
Good!
It's twelve o'clock.
Andersson proposes a lunch as a reconciliation gesture.
-What are you doing?
-Declines.
No, I do not.
I say he has to wait.
- He has to wait?
- He has to wait half an hour.
Good!
Very good.
A delegation from our New York Office asks for me.
What are you doing?
I say you are back soon.
No, I say you work ...
I say you ... I say nothing ...
It's totally shiny now ... I say you have lunch with the king!
The king?
Yes, you have lunch with the king.
It is good.
It's very good!
The job is yours.
What are you saying?
People are happy to get around, that's not it.
But the gays take our jobs!
Had it not been for all the gays I would have been a hairdresser tomorrow day!
Paul, do not throw the tea leaves.
I have taken a course so I can predict your future in tea blades.
It's about your career.
I see a park bench and a bottle of T-red.
Lodis.
It is a free profession.
Wait, I can predict my hands.
Oh!
It will go well for you.
I see your home, a big villa.
Here is your garage with your nice cars.
Do you see what it is?
A swimming pool.
Congratulations!
Do you know what Magnus's parents gave me?
A turned bowl!
The ugliest man ever seen!
I have been with ceramics for a long time!
Has anyone painted it on the dump?!
"I'll paint my little mushroom ...!"
It's an old Inka pattern.
I have made it!
I meant that you just appreciate the bowl if you are sober ...
I have been drinking ... and it will be wrong.
Don't drink and turn!
Magnus, is there more of something?
She is right in that. You probably can't turn if you have been drinking.
Frida ...?
-Just!
- You may have judgment.
How many demand police permits to slap New Year's rockets?
If I take home some college blocks from work, isn't that criminal?
- All takes home pens from work.
- We have probably all done something illegal.
Sure it is.
I killed a guy once.
It is well prescribed now.
You know ... A bunch of guys go to Copenhagen and drink too much.
- How did you do, then?
- There will be noise in the sausage queue ...
You push each other ... and so it goes as it goes.
–And it ends with ... dead?
- Knuckled, huh?
- All has done something illegal.
- But this is serious, Ulf.
Yes, but it was a Danish.
It may be a bit mitigating.
- More coffee?
-Gladly.
- It will be good with a little more coffee.
–And cake.
Delicious!
Magnus, can you take a little more cake?
- Magnus?
-Sorry?
May I take a bit more?
Otherwise, I'll kill you.
I was just joking!
It was an accident ... it's been many years ago.
I was packed too when it happened.
GROAN
Everyone found back?
It is important when surviving in the forest.
Now you have been looking for something edible for half an hour.
Should we see what you have found?
A little leaf ...
A stick.
Maybe you can suck on it ...
You should not eat this one.
It is directly fatal.
- Jasmine?
- It's a fly fungus.
You can also be careful with the glass bit.
Otherwise it was good.
Jim?
I have found a pizza.
You cannot always count on that.
- Jasmine?
- It's a capricciosa.
- It can probably be true.
It's a capricciosa.
- Do you know what I'm thinking about?
- No, Carita.
- Don't we go away on vacation?
- Her god, Carita, where are we going?
We could go to Varberg.
Should we go all the way to Varberg?!
What will we do there?
We can visit Varberg's fortress and look at Bockstensmannen.
-Who is it?
- It's a man from the Middle Ages.
He was found in a marsh.
Now he is in a booth in Varberg's fortress.
The hair is left.
The lips and brain are in a glass jar ...
No, Carita!
I don't want to look at that.
- No, maybe we should stay home.
-Yes we're allowed to do that.
- bowl on you, Carita.
-bowl on you, Per-Arne.
The lips in a glass jar ...
We cannot manage long without water.
Here is the creek.
It is a pulse vein in the ecosystem.
The water is filtered through stone and sand and becomes really clear and nice.
We should be happy about our fine water.
The Swedish rivers have always provided our countryside.
I can't imagine a more beautiful sound than rippling water.
You will not find a better thirst quencher at the finest restaurant.
I think it was Stagnelius who scalded:
"Lord, you let us taste your sweet water. It is caressing my throat."
A little salty ...
We quit for today.
It tastes good I can think.
- What is it for taste?
- Pistage.
Nice it should be!
When it is hot and summer you want an ice cream.
And so many varieties there are ...
Many varieties to lick on ...
- Can I offer a cigarette?
-No thanks.
I do not smoke.
But you are licking ... you have nothing against it?
–Wa?
- Should you come home with me?
- I have a big pack chocolate.
- No, I'm not going to come home with you.
There are many nice things at my house.
Many things to lick on ...
- I don't want to come home with you!
- There are grogg and wood too!
Have you never seen a Puma before?!
You have a lot of customer contact and we must appear serious.
In this context, your new style can be a load.
Do you think so?
Child cry
Are you a good, silent little girl?
Do you smile at mom?
Do you like Mom so much?
Gulli, Gulli, Gulli ...
Child cry
First, it is as if he suffers a great sadness ...
Then it is just pure unadulterated desire and joy!
Magnus first turns red ...
He smiles and begins to gasp.
Then it is as if he sees God and all angels!
My Ulf has never been to any Ulf Lundell concert.
- Now only Ulf guesses.
- Now we take them!
-A stick?
A flag?
A flower?
-Yes!
-That went quick.
- We know each other so well.
Sometimes I can almost read her thoughts.
Now we are, honey.
Now we take them!
Drive!
Old man?
Woman?
Married?
Marriage?
A couple?
Polygamy?
Study circle?
Square?
Prison?
Magnifying glass?
-Dog?
Wolf?
Matte?
Husse?!
-Stop!
-Damn!
What was that?
-Loyalty.
- It was not possible to see.
- How would you draw it?
Now it's Andreas.
Now I start.
-A fish!
-Yes!
It was much easier.
Fish...
What would you do if you won a million?
Then I would...
God, what a hard time.
I would...
I would travel around the world.
And then I would donate some to Doctors Without Borders.
-And you?
- I would buy a lot of bikes.
Then I would start a bicycle rental company.
But the tramps would go backwards instead of forward.
Everyone who rents bikes would roll at once.
It will look very fun.
But what is the point of changing the tramps so that people roll?
- That it looks fun.
-Yes...
But maybe it is unnecessary to spend a million on it?
Yes, maybe for you, but not for me.
-House?
-Yes!
Then it's me.
-Drive!
-An old man?
A girl?
Girl?
Cry?
Burning?
Explosion?
One can fly?
The Superman?
-No!
Do not you see...?!
-Stop!
- What should it represent?
-Enthusiasm.
-Enthusiasm!
- Yeah ...
–Okay, Andreas!
-Come on!
I'm starting ... now!
- Sun?
-Yes!
The sun?
"God, what a hard!"
-Perfect!
- We lead, huh?
- What a lot of good guys there are!
-I know!
- Check him!
One would have one!
-Really!
Should you go ahead and talk or hope he comes here?
Things like that is difficult.
I think you should go forward ... and be a little Palestinian.
–Wa?
- I think that guys like.
- How then Palestinian?
- A little mysterious.
-How?
- Storm, female and a little dangerous.
Do you think?
It sounds really strange, I think.
- Well I just said what I thought.
-Yes...
You don't have to be Palestinian if you don't want to.
I'm not an expert.
Vegetarians like animals but do not eat meat.
What a bad luck that almost all animals are made of meat.
The sea?
Storm?
Cinderella?
South America?
Dance band?
What the hell ... Light milk?!
- Merchant milk, then?
-Stop!
Nostalgia, Frida.
Drive!
-Square?
-Yes!
We won, huh?
Program text: Helena Habermann (C) Swedish Television AB 2004