I want a reporting of all the steps in the process.
The overall goal of the project is a pleasant indoor environment.
We will look at the organization ...
- Can't we just clean up?
-Okay.
The whole phone shakes.
- Sometimes my hands shake my hands too.
-SMS.
I worked as a plumbing installer.
It didn't smell roses, directly, when working ...
We have known a need, obtained information and made a purchase decision.
We arrive at negotiating discounts.
- Do you or not?!
- I can imagine a discount ...
- Night, Kennet!
-Hello Jenny!
Now I am here!
- What are you doing in town?
- We are 30 years now.
- Yeah ...?
- The valley!
We made a deal: If we were both singles at 30, we would get married.
- Don't you in Skåne?
- Yes, so I have no job here.
We can live on your salary.
Which side are you sleeping on?
That was not serious.
We were seventeen years old and very nice.
Don't you intend to stand for your part of the deal?
No, Kennet.
I won't.
Then I feel pretty stupid.
Maybe I should have tried to date someone in the last 13 years?
Yes, you might have done it.
I'm sorry, Kennet.
Shall we say 40?
What do you think about that?
I think I have become so thick.
I feel so plump!
- No, it's just in your head.
- stress can take physical expression.
That's probably why I feel bad.
It is burnout.
You have stressed too much.
This is certainly why I have not had menstruation in eight months.
- You should go to a psychologist.
- Yes, you get a little fun.
Can we get two beers here!
That could be gases.
You haven't tried Samarin?
-How is it?
You seem a little sad.
-What is it?
- It's Magnus.
- Should you move apart?
No no.
But he has become so thick!
- He exercises well and eats useful?
- But at night he jaws sandwiches.
Yes, they do it ... you have to scare him!
- You Ulf is skirting.
-Right.
I talk about cholesterol and blood fats ...
You have to scare him properly.
I'll help you, Frida.
I can not sleep.
I take a sandwich.
- You should not eat at night.
- Do you start getting thick?
No ... but it's dangerous.
Think of blood fats and heart.
- You can actually die!
- Of a night sandwich?
Get it together.
Is it to me?
Thanks!
Hope you sleep well tonight.
I bought ergonomic pillows.
-Good.
The old ones were so incredibly soft.
- These are very hard.
Knak!
Ouch...
It is then high time for penetration.
This is followed by a rhythmically offensive ...
... leading up to the final.
- You wanted to talk to me ...?
- Ove says you harass him.
Ove Lindgren claims that you have said derogatory things about him.
This morning, when he entered the meeting room, you should have said:
"Cut together, guys, because here comes the butt."
I haven't said that.
It's a lie.
We do not have to do people's sexual orientation.
No, I would never ... I didn't even know that Ove was a tail boy ...
–Yes - aft shooter.
He takes it in ... - thanks, that's enough!
Ulf ... I pull a line over this -
- But I hear more accusations I have to take action.
I understand that.
And I hear something I report to you.
Often this is about people being afraid of what is different.
There is nothing to be afraid of.
As I told Ove thiswater:
"Just because we work together, we're not going to shower together."
Right?
Welcome to Mansforum!
What do you prefer to do when you get home after the knee?
Beats me down with a whiskey.
Typically us men!
We love whiskey!
We will learn more about this noble drink.
Here we have a few different whiskey varieties.
We will get to know the difference between Scottish whiskey, which is made by barley -
–And Bourbon, made by corn.
Lagavulin, a classic whiskey.
Or, as the shots say: Whizzky.
"Whiskey" is Gaelian and means "the water of life".
OOOH!
-OOOH ... - How strong is this really?
–40 percent?!
- It's deadly!
We might be spinning in our heads!
-Come on now.
- We will try a bourbon as well.
Honey, what should we eat tonight?
Surprise me.
BUH!
- Overcurred?
-Yes...
So this was a bourbon.
It is an American brand -
- And it's called ... I look twice.
Jack Daniels!
You are out patrolling.
Then a gypsy comes on a moped.
What are you doing?
-Nothing.
-Nothing?
No, no crime has been committed.
You see an aunt.
Against her comes a gypsy on a moped.
What are you doing?
- Where do you want to come?
- You take in the gypsy, of course!
He intends to take the aunt's bag!
- You have to teach you the language of the street.
- See like this then, you who know everything ...
You infiltrate a messy that is exposed to shooting.
In the battle, a civilian is injured.
If you save his life, you clear your cover.
What are you doing then?
I take the gypsy on a moped.
It was guaranteed him who shot.
Amateur...!
Cohabitant, a small village before street
It is not far from Rio de la Plata
Almost at the edge of the blue Atlantic
and with pampas behind themselves many hundreds of green miles
There I came riding an evening in April because I wanted to dance tango
- You would come three hours ago.
- It's such traffic ...
Shit the same.
Now it is very hurry.
Take this drawing to Abro Architects on Rosenlundsgatan 24.
- Port code?
–2586.
And this video band is going to Hans Rosenkvist on Päronvägen 2B.
-Lasse!
You should be on Kungsgatan!
-Ready for delivery.
- The drawing to Rosenkvistvägen ... –rosenlundsgatan.
–Rosenlundsgatan 34 ... –24.
- The band is going to Hans Päronkvist ... - his Rosenkvist on Päronvägen.
- The port code on Päronvägen is 2438. - No, 2586 - on Rosenlundsgatan!
- No port code is needed on the pear road.
–Rosengren has no port code?
–Rosenkvist.
- I and name ... okay.
Then I take the band to the architects on Päronvägen and the drawings for ...
No no no.
You take the band to Hans on Päronvägen ...
Forget the band and concentrate on the drawing, which is going to ...
- The road.
- Kvastvägen?!
Rosenlundsgatan 24!
- Port code?
–2586!
You should be on Kungsgatan!
Where are you?!
–Okay, then I stick.
-Hello!
I would forget my head if it wasn't stuck!
I'm out.
–Rosenlundsgatan 24!
-Top.
It was this morning.
Should we go to the sausage booth and have some lunch?
- You get so stubborn by all the fast food.
-Fast food?
After all, we are pizza too.
- It takes over 10 minutes.
- We will eat Asian today.
Asian?
No no!
- I want to order a yakiniku ... –Jacki ...?
Put down the handset.
- We can take everything on.
- Put down the handset!
Put down the handset, I say!
Give damn in order Asian!
Jackinicku ... This is the last time you order that shit for me.
-Roger?
Now we drive to the sausage.
- You are not wise.
You're crazy!
Chinese with piss on the fingers rolling the route fish ...
Wait.
Mom had some gingerbread left.
"Mother Anna's" - her favorite place.
The funeral ...
I have some papers from Fonus -
- And a letter from the white archive, where mom expresses her wishes.
I had a long conversation with my mom where she said how she wanted it.
I have found a marble tombstone.
-It is nice.
- I love marble.
Hope!
It was expensive.
- Mom wasn't a marble type?
- No, it's so heavy and clumsy.
- Mom was not heavy and clumsy.
- No, she wasn't.
My son Jörgen could make a simple, slender wooden cross in the craft.
-Yes!
- Think, what a happy mom would have been!
Don't you think mom is worth more than a wooden cross?
Kista, then ... I've found a white coffin.
Mom liked white.
Oh, it was fancy.
Mom wasn't that much for fancy things?
She liked the simple more.
Mom read a lot.
Maybe you should make a coffin in paper?
There are fantastic nice chests in corrugated cardboard.
Mom loved corrugated cardboard.
- Paul!
Please stop.
-Sorry.
Hm, hm ... hee, hee ...
Paul!
I have to finish this today.
Sorry.
Paul ... Paul!
I don't want to put my mom in a cardboard box.
If it's about money ...
This is not about money!
In the white archive, Mom expresses a desire to be cremated after her death.
- The corrugated cardboard coffin is burned up ...?
- It's unnecessary?
- Does the cremation cost something?
-Yes it does.
- Ingrid, you have a compost?
-Yes!
Mom always liked so well in your garden, Ingrid.
She used to say that Ingrid had the finest roses on the street.
- Then it becomes organic too.
–And we don't have the coffin.
- Should mom decay in a compost?
- Yes, because Mom had wanted!
Piiip!
Paul ...
Thanks!
I was very close to my mom towards the end.
She never talked about compost or cardboard boxes.
- I want to give her a nice funeral.
- We also want to, Magnus.
I have a savings account.
I was going to save if I have children ...
But I can work extra on the weekends.
I can pay everything.
Yes, if you want it ...
Then Jörgen does not have to make a cross.
He is not a star on woodwork.
You would have seen what he came home with last - a stick!
- Yeah, then this was done.
- nice.
Did mom have more gingerbread?
-No!
-No...!
- Don't leave me, Torbjörn!
- I'm here, André.
Never again should I ...
- I want a development call.
- You start.
I feel that I am not heard for my ideas.
You're not listening to me.
What do you say about that?
What the hell would I do after lunch?
I don't get it.
Work?
I forgot that last week.
No, I have written up.
"You work at Wasa, Götgatan 13."
"Your office is at the bottom of the corridor."
So work is not.
-Do you have kids?
It can be.
- No, when would I have got them?
Although I was in the hospital a few weeks ago and met a doctor ...
Before I forget it - can we have a meeting tomorrow with the web group?
- Yes, that would work.
-Good.
I go home for lunch.
We are north now, huh?
See you!
Hide the paper.
-Hello!
We're not ready yet ...
- Are you already here?
We are not done.
- We are probably a little early.
Come in, come in.
The water is on.
I'll peel potatoes.
Lets see...
- What is said about Sjötunga Walewska?
-Good!
But we have no sea tongue.
It is probably better with something that goes faster, so we can get the cinema.
-Meat!
Don't we have turkey in the freezer?
- Giant idea!
I invite the guests to some wine for so long.
The house's white!
This would be clear today, but I got started a little late.
This is going to stand for 22 days.
Cheers and welcome!
Oh, fuck!
This is pure fox poison.
It is not possible to drink.
Can you help me with the table?
There it should be ...
SVT Program Setting: Agnes Malm Skoglund
The bus has passed.
We miss the cinema.
Then we would not have had to run!