Norrland - silence and calm's country part -
- With its high mountains and deep valleys.
But for two brothers in Sörbäcken, everyday life is neither calm nor quiet.
Their name is Leif and Billy.
Do you know what it is for day today?
- My name day?
- No, it's in the summer.
-My birthday?
- No, better!
We got the a-cash!
- We treat us and go to the grill.
-Yes!
A Parisian with extra mustard - damn what good!
Check out, Leif, a new girl.
-Satan, what a nice biscuit.
- We talk to her.
Stop and evidence!
It's best that I talk to her first.
- You know what to do?
- I say that about the bear.
Come in in three minutes.
Yes, serve.
Can you throw over the two million in my Russian account?
If they do not fit, you can take on my Swedish account.
And look over the investments.
The luxury house in Spain ... Have they built the pool clearly?
I'm between two meetings, so I hang up.
We will be heard, advocate ... the auditor, the accountant's lawyer.
Hello.
- Yeah.
- Well!
- intervened that you have an auditor's lawyer.
- Can you say.
- Cool!
-And who are you?
I am from Stockholm.
I'll move to Sörbäcken.
–Sörbäcken?
It was like hell.
-Yes.
-Leif Öhman!
- What does the municipality want help with?
- Now is there a bear in the kindergarten again?
-A bear?!
It is chaos.
The children and misses have hidden in a playhouse.
- They are terrified.
Can you help?
- I don't have the rifle with me.
- You might be able to strangle it.
-Bye.
I must take Ferrarin and go there.
She will move to Sörbäcken.
We go and check what a cup it is.
- Is she moving into the Old Table House?
- She has gone and died.
So the little snoser has inherited the kitchen.
We have got a new neighbor, Billy.
Let's see.
Here is the reg number ...
—Ydk 882. --... 882 ...
"Elin Grönstedt".
Check if she is on Facebook.
Facebook ... Elin Grönstedt ...
- Oh, my God, she is!
- Yeah!
What do we have here, then?
She works, and lives in Stockholm ...
- Check if she is single.
- Yeah!
Oh, my God, she's single!
Stylish biscuit.
Check...
"Now I move into the ghost house. Square, the forest, square, Sörbäcken."
Yes, it seems that the old marsh has gone and died.
I got a plan.
Get the steps, Billy.
Yes Yes.
Hi, Little Gåskorven, have you moved to Sörbäcken?
Now you should meet Leif-Inator.
THERES A KNOCK ON THE DOOR
Hello?
After all, you are!
I saw you at the pizzeria today.
I was in passing and wanted to say hello to the new neighbor.
-Hello!
Elin.
- Billy.
Nice.
So you have moved into this old ghost truck?
It's my grandmother's old house.
A little weird maybe, but no danger.
I would probably be a little careful.
There are a lot of old stories about this horror.
A lot of guests and demons who get around here -
- So I usually go a detour.
But there lives a man over there named Leif Öhman -
- As has contact with the other side.
-A medium?
- Just that - medium.
He can help with the guests.
- But now I'll go.
- Thanks for tips.
-See you.
-Hello.
Oh my God.
THERES A KNOCK ON THE DOOR
-Hello.
–Leif Öhman.
We met at the pizzeria today.
The millionaire that strangles bears.
- You might be medium too?
-That's right.
I could feel dark forces all the way from the house.
Oh oh oh...
Okay.
Oh oh oh.
- The spirits, take it easy now.
I'm here to convey peace, I don't want any conflict.
These spirits, what exactly do they want?
I'll try to contact them.
Now it's one here.
- Calm ... Hello ... Hello ...
They say you will find the love of your life here in Sörbäcken.
Who then?
He is 35 years old, likes fishing and hunting and his name is ... Leif.
But who is she you talk to?
Her name is Anna-Greta.
She is behind the cabinet.
Anna-Greta?
What a coincidence!
My grandmother is called Anna-Greta.
She is the one who contacts me.
Okay!
Damn what cool!
- Can you talk to Grandma?
- I should try.
If you hear me now, give me a sign.
Anything.
Give us a sign.
Shit, what scary!
Did you hear?
It sounds like there is someone up there.
-We go there.
- Well ...
Calm down, the spirits!
Now we come up!
We do not want conflict.
The spirits, do you hear me?
Oh oh oh!
You can really feel that there is something up here.
- Yes, it's best that we go down again.
- Is Grandma left up here?
It's a demon in here.
"Demon Man! Don't Hurt The Little Red Head Lady, She's Not Made of Fire."
"She's an Angel Without Wings."
Now I'm going to talk to Grandma.
Go to the light, Anna-Greta.
Go in there in the loop.
Good, Anna-Greta!
-So.
Now she is in peace.
Now we go down.
- The demon is left.
A demon!
He is strong!
"He's trying to kill me!"
"Move! Never come back, demon face!"
- Now the demon is gone.
- Yes, now we go down.
- Now the spirits are expelled from the house.
- Great!
- Remember what the spirits said.
- It is there by finding a man ...
I will think about it.
Thanks, Leif.
Thanks for your little ritual.
Just get over to me if you need help.
Bye.
What the hell?
You are a genius, Billy.
Women want security.
Who is her security now?
Yes, Leif Öhman.
Soon I have a little wife running around and cuddles with me.
Damn, Satan ... - Yes, who knows.
Oh, Jesus!
Look into Elin's window!
- I aroused the dear from the dead!
- What the hell are we going to do?
We have to warn Elin.
- Hi, that's Elin.
- I had some strong forces in me.
-What are you talking about?
- I woke up Grandma from the dead.
- You have to get out of the kitchen right away!
- Do you mean this grandmother?
-What the hell?
--Leif, she's no spirit.
- We thought she was dead.
-Death?
We haven't seen her in a long time.
She got a stroke last fall, so she's most indoors.
- She's not dead.
-I must go...
I just want to thank you so much for the Sea today.
It was rewarding.
It's burning here now.
Hello.
Oh my God!
Do you pick up like this in Norrland?
Yes you, Leif ... good luck getting her to wife.