Well, Leif Öhman ...
What are you sitting here for?
It got a little mess yesterday down at the pizzeria.
Well, with whom then?
Two guards flew on me, so I had to put them in place.
Damn!
What happened?
I pulled a double stroke in the solar plexus on the first.
Then I drew a judo throw ...
Leif!
What are you doing?
God damn!
Satan!
How did you do?
Damn, what a fight fighter!
Become a ragger!
We need someone like you.
- I don't know, I have the farm ... - hell, with us you don't have to.
The brother has a hard time managing herself as well.
The brother?
You mean he like you when you were in the hospital?
- Yes, but the doctors told him ... —leif!
Your brother betrayed you.
With us you will never be betrayed.
- I will take me a think.
-Do it.
- All your kings.
-Go Fish.
I do not believe that!
You cheat after all.
Shit!
It is Leif who has taught me.
Satan!
Leif!
What time is it?
-A quarter past eleven.
- I would have picked up him eleven.
-I have to leave.
Bye.
-Drive carefully.
Hello there.
Where the hell are you, Billy?
-Gosh!
Has the brother left you again?
- It may have happened.
- He might be hanging out with his new girl.
-I do not know...
Jump in the car.
We are running you.
Many shit in the family when a girl comes into their lives.
- Billy has done it a few times.
- We've seen it.
Shouldn't you keep up with us instead?
Your brother has been a pig.
- Damn cheaters.
-Svikar-Billy.
Switch-Billy, Svevikar-Billy.
Sweet-billy, fir-billy, fir-billy, fir-billy!
It is good.
- Drive.
Where the hell is Leif?
He must have gone home already.
Damn!
Leif!
Hi, Leif.
- Yeah.
Now it is suitable to come.
- Forgotten, I forgot.
You forgot!
You were well with the damned Elin.
- Yes, we played briefly ... –And you forgot your own brother.
- When I froze outside the prison.
- You just sat in the filling cell?
I mucked from the kitchen!
And not damn you were there.
Do you know who picked me up from the kitchen when I got out of there?
Skeva-Lena, Dunken and Jimmy with the knife.
- They set up for me.
- What do you do with your dad's old jacket?
You have chosen your path in life, and fate has chosen my course.
–What for course?
- Crime, Billy.
If you have once entered it, you do not go out.
It's your fault!
Is heard.
-Where are you going?
- Club house.
- Leffe.
- Well, the can.
You came anyway.
Come in for fuck.
Hörni, now he's here.
Stor-Leffe.
- Sit down.
- We have a new member.
- The fight fighter.
Welcome.
- Should we put on the club emblem?
- You can put it on the jacket here.
Lol!
On the jacket?
No, it is going into the skin.
- I don't know ... - for hell!
- You don't bangs?
All of us have one.
- I've been in a shoulder since the Judoast.
- Do you bake?
- Are you a fucking stupid?
- Are you a man or mouse?
-MAN!
Okay, turn on the tattoo then.
-Let's go.
-Good.
Get the machine, skeva-Lena.
Leif is so mad at me.
If you are so worried, can you just call?
Yes, I must do it.
Damn!
- What do you have for club emblems, then?
- A burning falcon.
The fattest tattoo you've seen.
You don't want something goofy, like flowers or hearts and such crap.
You don't have to worry about that.
- Yes, Leif.
- Hi, it was Billy.
- What Billy?
- You little brother.
He who went on a date when I was in hospital -
–And left me when I mucked?
Yes, but ... shouldn't you come home?
I am insisted in crime hugs and crime.
I'm beyond rescue.
And you have your girl, so shit in me.
-What is that sound?
- I tattoo a fat fucking falcon.
It burns and has itself.
I don't have time with you.
Hello?
- He hung up.
He said he tattooed himself.
-So!
- Is it ready?
Was it good looking?
- It was cruel.
- Do you have a mirror?
No.
Turn on this, so it can heal properly.
Good, Leif!
You passed the first test.
Now we will find a name for you.
What do you want to be called?
The king?
Yes.
The king, or maybe the king of death?
Well, the king will be good.
The king.
It will be fine.
Let's see...
Not everyone gets the "king" on the jacket.
Now Dad would have seen me.
- So there, then we were ready.
- Is it the king?
Yes, now it stands the king.
You can't have that hairstyle.
You have to look harder.
- He would fit in shaved.
-Shaver!
Now we'll make you look really fucking hard.
Should you shave everything?
You will look really fucking criminal.
So there!
Now we showcase our new member.
Leffe, or the king, now you buy four hull goals for us.
Look at me.
You are one of us now.
A teddy bear sausage with extra mustard, it is conditioner for the soul.
Four with extra everything, mustard and rub.
- But Leif, what have you been up to?
- Don't you recognize your own brother?
- You look like ... --... a criminal, I know!
I am beyond rescue, insum!
Let me be, for hell!
- Do you know what it says on your back?
- King.
King did not fit.
Be with your little girl friend and let me be.
Thanks for the burgers, the cock.
-What happened?
- We are doing some crime.
I'll keep watch.
Don't you realize that they drive with you?
Have you seen what it says on the jacket?
The cock ...
Come, Leif.
We go into the heat.
- But they said ... - come.
What have they done with their hair?
Eh ... okay.
My hair!
Satan, they have tricked me.
Cursed!
Calm down, you have us.
Ignore those fucking pigs.
The tattoo, then?
Is it a big burning falcon?
- No ... - yes!
A huge burning falcon.
- Yes, just that.
Shit.
-Really.
Now we are all together again.
You are the best I know.
Now we never have to be separated.
- Corner, I have to tell you one thing.
-What?
I got a job in Stockholm.
I need to move back there.
No, Elin!
Damn.
Do you have to move?
Can't stay here?
I've done everything to try to get some kind of income here.
It's not possible!
- It has to be a little driven.
- As you two?
We have both healthcare allowance and a cash register.
Although it means that you are unemployed.
Income as income.
It is important to get to know the right people here in the village.
The right people?
People who write the "cock" on their backs?
- Why did they write so?
- They wrote wrong well.
Yes, they did well.
Well, Billy and the cock, should we pull?
- Do you get it away?
- So there!
- I will miss you, Elin.
- I too, actually.
- I will miss you too.
- We get to visit Stockholm.
- Trying at Spy Bar maybe?
- I haven't seen that movie yet.
SWEDISH SUPPORT: Thomas Eriksson (C) Swedish Television AB 2017