Now Göran is shooting again.
Yesterday he pulled heating loops on the porch.
I immediately saw that there was something wrong with him.
- Why do you just O'boy for you?
- In this country ...
... no one can be pleased that others are doing well!
- I have to do it myself then.
- Don't go, I took the last one.
- Finter that you have shot, Gustav.
- Single, the snow is gone anyway.
Trust nature.
Everything has a meaning!
- In addition to you.
-Come here!
Look at our new neighbor.
What do you see?
- An idiot.
- Göran is shooting morning and evening.
Man's meaningless struggle against the elements.
His wife does not have to scoop out of the bathroom window anyway.
I'll take care of it.
- Max, pick up the snow shovel!
- I take care of the home and you garden.
- ORGETS, I want to change.
Sanda at the mailbox as well.
- Don't Max do anything?
- Yes, drink chocolate.
If you touch it there I will read the Post's staff magazine for you!
Max!
Today is Tuesday and it is your turn to scale potatoes.
I am allgeric!
Everyone is just trying to throw away their tasks.
Yes, it is best that you do everything.
- You have five seconds on you!
-One two...
Mom, there is someone who is shooting ... how did you do?
I said I had lost the remote control there.
Here are sandwiches and chocolate.
How was school?
Math interviews ... The gym teacher was sick, so then Eva and I went smoking.
-What are you saying?
- The truth.
Why do you tell the truth?
Our teacher says we should be honest.
So stupid!
Do you not belong to the open parent generation?
Do we do well ... you are 15 years old and curious about life.
You want to explore things that we may have difficulty accepting, such as smoking ...
... guys, snuff and sex and stuff.
- Should you have secrets?
- You can be a little low sometimes.
Grandma knows e.g.
Not that Dad is a postman.
Last time they talked, he was certainly the commander.
- So it was done!
- Are you already done?
Do not you trust me?
After 20 years of hiking, side by side ...
-Move!
-Okay okay.
It's cold out there ...
- Why don't guys make things clearly?
- People are half finished.
The body works fine, but we women are allowed to talk about what to do with it.
- Do you come and go to bed?
-I can not move.
Shot a little more often, so you don't get hurt.
Look at Göran!
- I don't want to look at Göran.
- Göran is not just at the TV.
Within six months he sits here next to me.
The doorbell rings
Lena, open!
Come in!
- Gustav!
Am I Disturbing?
- What you look happy.
Is it snowing?
I need your help.
We haven't been able to talk so much with each other -
- But I immediately felt that we would have nice contact ...
What is it that you want?
Annika and I have a wedding day on Saturday, but I have a problem.
I would like to surprise her with something nice, but I'm not so ...
-Shrewd?
- Not so inventive.
Whatever I do, she will never be surprised, so I was going to ask you.
You want help in amazing your wife?
You have come to the master!
Why do you think Lena has stayed with me for 20 years?
I'm not so successful, pretty lazy, voting for the guys ...
... but I have the ability to surprise.
Lena and I have celebrated 20 fantastic wedding days.
- Do you want to tell you about one?
-Do it!
How was it now ...?
Yes!
There is a guest house called Solgläntan -
- With mileage views of fields, meadows, sea ...
The helmet, do you mean?
So this year the snow is deep, the guests are picked up with horse and sled.
How complicated.
Can't you plow?
I'm trying to tell you about a great moment.
- Here is the brochure.
- "Make your own chips" ...
"Pension State Solgläntan - a weekend in paradise."
Timbered cabin, first class food, soft bear traps in the beds.
-Perfect!
Can I borrow the brochure?
- Yes, Lena orders new every year.
- Is there something I can ... - Yes, that's one thing ...
Lina is getting big.
We have to pay attention to her.
I am attentive.
I always drive her to the riding school.
She stopped riding a year ago.
That's why she got so angry when I let go of her at the stable.
She is getting new interests.
- I am easily scared away.
-What is that sound?
Max that snores ...
- What do Göran do on our porch?
- Some heating loops would in ...
-In the middle of the night?
- He is grateful for some good advice.
- "Always guard away matches"?
- We talked about how to show love.
- Did you know how to do it?
- I told him.
They are going to celebrate the wedding day and I talked about the guest house Solgläntan.
I described for Göran how nice it was there.
But we have never been there!
We have looked at the brochure so many times.
For ten years I have dreamed of going to Solgläntan!
I've wanted to have a TV in the bedroom for 15 years!
- We can go there next year.
- You have said that for a decade.
Göran wanted to make his wife happy on the wedding dance, and I gave advice.
Your own wife you shit in, but when it comes to Göran's wife, it gets speed!
We have had lots of nice wedding days!
- Mention one!
- I can name ten.
- Can't do not right now ... - awake me when you come to someone.
Have!
Gotland –91.
Then you celebrated the 15th anniversary with your lumpy buddies.
It was a wonderful atmosphere anyway.
- When was the French Revolution?
–1789.
Why did they have to kill so many?
There were positive sides too.
Look at that!
Big party, lots of people.
The looting of Versaille.
1,400 people died!
Here is a list of all romantic places where we celebrated our wedding day.
Can I see?
1987: 12th anniversary.
What a mood!
Gavlerinken ...
- Gavlerinken?
- Brynäs - play sand.
-Another example!
–1992 Don't forget ...
- Night Himpers, the snow, the ice ... - Boltic - Ljusdal it was.
3–2 ...
Do you see anything in common with all our wedding days?
- No ... - it's just sporting events!
You're right about that...
Have I ever said: Gustav, can't we go to hockey?
Not so clear ...
- Have I asked to go on a band?
-No...
Have I said: Can't we go to Pensionat Solgläntan?
-That sounds familiar.
- Then I should not disturb anymore.
Bye!
1994: Tomas Brolin's parents' home.
That night was magical!
Hello, the old man!
How are you?
- I think we talk so rarely.
-Sch.
It's good that you are independent, but ...
- Sometimes I want to know what you are thinking.
-I do not think so.
One should be responsive to each other's wishes.
There may be things you want to do that we do not know about.
Fishing and so ...
- Mom, do you need support and comfort?
-Yes...
I'm too small, talk to dad.
He left a note to you.
"Pettersson has acquired a big -screen TV. Coming home after the match."
-Come in!
-Hello!
What are you doing?
- Imagine on my husband.
- I always think about Göran!
Not the same way ...
- How is Göran as a husband?
-Wonderful!
He is safe, kind, honest and ... he loves me.
Am I so stupid so I ask ...
Tomorrow is our first wedding day and then we will go to Solgläntan.
- Want to see the brochure?
- I know it outside.
I have wanted to go to Solgläntan for ten years, but it has not been done.
- What have you done then?
- Wear hockey.
- Are you such a hockey fan?
-No.
- Have you told Gustav?
- Yes, then we went on a bandy instead.
But you have much else in common.
Your children, for example.
I would give a lot for such lovely kids.
How much do you have?
Honey, is this you are?
Oh, what I have longed for you!
The best moment at Dan is when even loved ones come home from work.
Back home!
Lena, it's your turn to shovel!
- What was it with her?
- Gustav, I want to talk to you.
-Where have you been?
- Run around a bit and thought.
- I should do it more often.
-Drive around?
The thing about Solgläntan was an idiotic idea.
It is we who need to travel away and do something romantic.
Göran and Annika are so new, they can have as much fun in the garage.
Not in our garage.
- So it was for us before.
- But why did you never say away?
I thought you perceived the signals.
You know you have to be clear with me.
- Do you remember Leksands shirts?
- As you burned in the boiler?
- Why do you think I did it?
- For they missed the playoffs?
- Did you know what I was thinking about in the car?
- Would it be good with a sausage?
I asked myself what I love most here in the world.
Sport or my wife?
It depends on what sport you talk about of course.
But I just came to an answer ...
That I am more important than bandy but not even hockey?
The only thing that matters is you.
-Do you mean it?
-I love you, honey.
From now on, there will be a change.
We will decide everything together.
Wedding days, holidays, tip ...
Tomorrow after breakfast we decide together what to do this weekend.
No, you decide!
You are planning our weekend.
- Did you know what you are getting into?
- I've never known that.
- Good morning, kids!
- Why is mom so strange?
We've had a small problem ...
Mom keeps the house and you meet us every other weekend?
Once you will understand how important it is to speak openly with each other.
-Hello Darling!
-Slept well?
Should we go to the Flower Exhibition -
- Eat lunch at Stadshotellet and then go to the cinema tonight?
- There's nothing.
- But I would have to decide?
I have changed my mind.
It's better that I decide.
Hello?
We want to know when to eat.
- We are in the middle of a discussion ... - at seven.
Max eats fish sticks.
We are going to Pensionat Solgläntan.
Göran and Annika take care of the children.
- Taxine is waiting.
Are you ready?
-No...
- Should we be alone with them?
- Max, calm.
We will be on Sunday.
Göran has a steam engine from 1971.
I have an air rifle from 1996.
Time to say goodbye to everyday life!
Hello then, Max and Lina.
- What are we going to come up with now?
- Do not turn, it can be late.
Stop there, Lina.
Where are you going?
I'm not saying.
Mom has said that you should not tell everything.
- Then I want to go out too!
- No, you are too small.
- So sweet he is.
- Lilla Gullesnutten.
- This one I never forget!
-Neither do I.
SVT program text: Maria Westin