In tonight's semi -finals of IFS ...
... quiz about all culture in Sweden:
The Syrian on the run from Özz Nujen - Filip Dikmen.
Humor legend from Degeberga - Petrina Solange.
The world's Swedishest Arab - Elaf Ali.
Landskrona's most attractive Palestinier - Farah Abadi.
The Somali radio pirate - Assia Dahir.
The dancing Korean Gold Detective Hanna IS Golden.
She goes humor ping pong between Gbg and London - Evelyn Mok.
The character chameleon from Botkyrka - Thanos Fotas.
Long as a flagpole, always with punchlines in progress: Ahmed Berhan!
IFS, the program with longer life than Filip Dikmen's music aid career.
It is time for the semi -finals in the quiz about all culture in Sweden.
Our semi -finalists:
The man who was so chill that we gave him another chance - Anders.
Her winning skull took her ... the influencer from Hofterup - Emelie!
The man who does not need any presentation-IFS amon from Uppsala.
Patrick!
- Anders, who do you want to talk to?
–Evelyn.
If you have a green hat a Chinese friend can ask you to take it off.
Why?
Because you look like a stupid.
No, this is how it is.
In Chinese culture, colors have different meanings.
You have red when you celebrate something, so you usually have red at a wedding.
White has a funeral.
So if you have green it means -
- That your partner has been unfaithful.
- Do you have a color for that event?!
- It's great.
Then you know!
If the guy has been unfaithful, you put on the hat - and then everyone grabs.
- You say: "We're talking about it later."
-Yes.
And then maybe you have to lie down.
-What are you saying?
- Yes, what do I say?
- I think ... she is lying.
- You think she is lying.
You don't think a green hat means your partner has been unfaithful?
It's true.
A green hat means that the partner has been unfaithful.
"A man whose wife has been unfaithful" -
- Bli in Chinese "to wear a green hat".
Do you have a color for "What the fuck is that wrong on you"?
It's the same as your eye color, Filip.
–Emelie, you who rip green ... - I start looking ...
- You Pult is green.
-Ah!
–Emelie, who do you choose?
–Alaf.
You are an Iraqi writer.
Another is Saddam Hussein.
-What?!
- Nice transition!
One of his books stands out a bit.
–Mein Kampf.
-It is called El-Mein Kampf.
We both stand out.
I am an Iraqi writer who writes in Swedish.
Saddam Hussein writes, or then wrote, with his blood.
He has a Qur'an written with his own blood - the "blood chore".
But how much blood was it?
That's how he died.
Americans tried to murder him.
He just: "I have a few lines left!"
I think it must be false, because he is a very special man -
- So it hadn't surprised me.
He used his blood, not the Kurds - it was still nice.
Elaf ...!
Pam-Pam-Pam, Elaf!
I say it's false.
I think so.
- You think Elaf is lying?
- I don't want to believe it.
But there will be no point, because Elaf did not lie.
What Elaf said is true.
It's totally sick.
It's true.
The blood chore is correct.
It has been discussed how much is in Saddam's blood.
He must have donated 27 liters of blood in two years.
It was rather three liters of blood mixed with chemicals.
Patrick!
-Welcome!
Who do you choose?
- Filip.
This picture is known all over the world.
What does it represent?
It is a figure used, among other things.
As a refrigerator magnet-
- And symbolizes the Palestinian people's struggle against Israel's occupation.
It's not just a refrigerator magnet.
Some use it as a tattoo.
- I think it's false.
- You don't want to trust Filip?
No.
There are no symbols in.
-You thought a McDonald's logo?
-Just.
Sodastream and stuff.
You got an applause for your joke, but no point for your reply.
It's true.
The picture we just saw adorns many homes and some bodies:
It symbolizes the struggle of the Palestinians.
It represents Naji al-Ali who was allowed to leave his home and means--
- That he cannot grow up until he returns.
- Anders?
-Thanos.
You are on vacation in Greece and see this.
What is going on?
It's not Greece, the man.
That is Hornsberg's beach.
When Ronna invades Hornsberg ...
No, what we see here ...
... it is a Greek ritual that men do when they have been unfaithful.
They are allowed to jump in the water and swim.
They come to the cross and kiss it.
It is a form of confession.
- Why are you so obsessed with infidelity?
- The wives in green hats are watching.
Their Chinese wives ...
After all, it was all of Greece's male population that jumped in. Seriously.
I think it's false.
They don't compensate for their infidelity?
Shunon has been in Greece.
Congratulations, a point.
It's false.
This is a Greek thirteen -day tradition.
A priest throws a cross into the water and you should find that.
The winner is said to have luck and blessing for the rest of the year.
Emelie?
I want someone who understands me: Petrina.
- What was the Senegal village for something?
- It's Yasin village's little brother.
No...
Senegalbyn was a human zoo on Gröna Lund in the past.
They took people from Senegal and put them there.
People went and looked at them.
They thought, "If we can't go to Africa, we may take Africa here."
And we came!
And that village then developed and became if's ...
- A human zoo.
Unpalatable but true.
- How long has Gröna Lund been around?
- It was sick human view ... - This was Black Lund.
In Gröna Lund, everyone is just unfaithful.
- I hope it's false.
- I want to.
But it's true.
That is sick!
Gröna Lund had the exhibition Senegalbyn -
- Where Swedes looked at real Senegalese.
Then they went to Gambia.
We know what happened after that ...
But this was true.
So unfortunately no point to you.
Patrick ... who do you choose?
We drive ... Farah.
Farah!
In 2018, the National Board of Health released a brochure that was noticed.
People lacquered on it.
What was it about?
They asked Dad to stop going to Tunisia and get married and have children.
It was enough with seven.
True.
No ... but that ...
Here, trauma is processed.
They released a brochure called "Hustla Soc is Haram".
They wanted to reach your target group and show that contribution fraud is illegal.
It was criticized for pointing out immigrants as a contributor.
- "To hustle ..."?
- "... soc is haram."
I think it's great.
-What do you think?
- That is true.
You think you released the brochure "It's Haram to Hustla Soc"?
It's haram that you think so.
Unfortunately, it is false.
It would have been an incredible brochure!
But it wasn't that brochure.
It was a brochure that was about child marriage:
"Information to you who is married to a child."
"That Hustla Soc is Haram" is great.
- They should do one.
- They should only change laws to Haram.
- Then people will start following them.
- Is it just Muslims who are rooted?
Listen, Södertälje has made Sweden change so many laws -
–P.G.A.
Your businesses!
Södertälje has just released the information -
- That their district court is driven by someone from the Södertäljen network.
Okay, Anders.
You have received a letter - a letter from Botkyrka.
Here it smells like immigrants.
Come along!
-Hello!
Hello everyone!
-Hello.
You want to be good looking in the suburb, because then you can be called a cat.
But are you ugly - are you called a bird then?
Do you call an ugly person a bird?
Skata maybe, but you mean bird overall?
- False.
- Anders ... it went like a treasure.
- You got no points.
It's true.
-Wait what?!
!
- DOGGE just comes up with it.
- Dogge cuts with the cap on.
Applaud if you heard "bird - ugly".
/A few applodes/
Applate if you have never heard it.
/Most applause/
Ahmed.
Sorry, in this case we feel sorry for Anders.
According to the jury ... Whether a few have heard it ...
- I had given points.
-No.
Right must be right.
- But we are the blasts here!
- Learn Swedish then!
- But he said ... åsödertälje District Court ...
That's him!
Okay.
That was the question you got.
It is a minority that heard it before.
There will be no point, but you are a Buddhist so take it with a heel kick.
- In tried!
–Emelie?
Assia ...
Director Hayao Miyazaki, which is behind films such as Spirited Away -
- Ville make her own version of a Swedish film.
A gay version of fast cash.
So fast cash.
Sorry, what a bad thing.
No, what he actually wanted to do was -
- An elevated, animated version of Jönsson League.
But it became a little difficult because he wanted to depart from the original.
He wanted to change the name of Dynamit-Harry to Kamikaze-Kim and hold on so.
The rights holders said no.
It would have been a rather exotic version.
I choose to believe that it is true.
You say the Japanese director wanted to do ...
—... his own version of Jönsson League.
- Can we get points now?
Please?
No!
You Kamikaze-Kim, your score.
He wants to make a Japanese version - but by Pippi Longstocking.
Patrick, how was the response after the first season?
-Fairly good.
- Treaty pussy?
- If you take a point, you move on.
–Yes.
The last panelist is Hanna.
Vamos Lá!
Para-Papa-Papa-Papa-Papa
Pa-para-pa-para ...
This Brazilian song is prohibited in Brazilian radio.
Why?
It was too bad.
But here in Sweden, bad Latin songs are zumbahits.
So it was a hit here.
No ... in 2020, President Bolsonaro banned the song -
- For its antibrara, anti-Christians and gay-friendly messages.
Like "para-paper-paper-papa-pary-papa-papa".
- I think it's true.
- Because you agree with Bolsonaro?
- You think it's true.
Yes.
He just ignored my question.
You choose to believe that it is true.
It means no point to you!
Sorry, patrick.
It's false.
The song is prohibited on Brazilian radio - for other reasons.
"Rap Das Armas", "Rap if weapon" is a Brazilian proibidão-song-
- which is forbidden to be played on radio as it praises weapons and crime.
In this case, they sing about the laws' takeover against the police.
There was no point.
- It was a lot of luck for you, Emelie.
Now we will run a rash question: the closest win.
When Jews, Sami, Roma, Swedish Finns and Torneda's were recognized ...
–... as national minorities?
- Do you love them?
Are you ready?
How about you showing them at the same time?
3 ... 2 ... 1!
–Oj ... –2021?
null
- It's always later than you think.
- All time before!
Always later.
Should we give them a little "drum role"?
- The correct answer to the question is ...
... 1999!
Congratulations, Emelie.
- Patrick!
Always a delight to see you.
You two have moved on to the next round, so we'll see you in the duel.
You know how it goes?
- Anders, the panelists you get to talk to are:
Petrina and Assia.
Bugg is called Sweden's national dance.
Romania's national dance has a name.
-Which one?
- The dance is called "Dansul Suedez".
And why does it do that?
It is then translated into "the Swedish dance".
This is because in the 17th century Sweden and Romania had ...
... great trade relations ...
They have had incredible contact with each other.
And after that Romania has had a great love for Sweden.
Many countries love Sweden.
Poland!
Sweden is mentioned in Poland's national anthem.
No that is not true.
This dance is called whore.
It is spelled so - "whore".
So if you are in Romania and someone says "whore!"
Should you not be sad.
They offer.
- But in Swedish it will be strange.
- It may be p.g.a.
your outfit.
It was the most sophisticated way I heard someone say "whore".
- Can't you say it again, Petrina?
-Whore!
But it is spelled "whore".
- Book it.
-WHORE.
So it is spelled!
So if you hear one a Romanian in Sweden say to their children "your little whores!" - -
- Then he means "your little dancers! You are so nice and dance so nicely."
-What are you saying?
- Giant.
Glad you are starting to understand the concept!
I believe in Petrina.
You think the dance we saw is called "whore"?
-Whore!
- You are doing absolutely right.
Congratulations, Anders!
You got a point.
Anders listed it.
We have never had a good relationship with Romania!
The dance whore is a kind of ring dance performed on, among other things.
Wedding and children's baptism.
Emelie, now we run your duel.
You get to talk to Thanos and Farah.
In the small Jämtland town Mörsil, the establishment Mcdragan opened.
- What did they offer?
- I don't think it's called as you said.
- Mörsil?
I don't think so either ... - it is spelled that way but pronounced "whore".
What did they offer on the McDragan?
It was a strip club that was opened by a man named Dragan.
He called the strip club something that everyone can recognize.
Mcdragan.
"I'm Loving It" he had as the slogan as well.
- Where do you recognize the mcragus?
- From McDonald's.
You drive past ...
You get hungry.
Sometimes you choose drive through, sometimes you sit there.
Sometimes you bring the children and wife, sometimes not.
No, it was a sports shop.
They sold adidas pants, slippers and t-shirts.
- There was what I got?
- It's your options:
A store for three Stros-enthusiasts-
- or a strip club ...
- You don't make it easy.
- Have you met jugs?
-I have.
- The stereotype, how do they usually dress?
And where do they usually go?
- I invest in the McDragan.
- As a strip club?
You believe in Landskrona's pride Farah - that the McDragan is a strip club ...
- Better than an adidas store, as well.
-Really.
It gives you a point.
Congratulations!
Dragan Bratic has opened several strip clubs.
In Mörsil, as Farah said, he had the slogan: "Mcdragan's - I'm lovin it".
The strip club was located on the old enriched Brinkeboda Wärdshus in Mörsil.
We will return to Anders.
You should talk to Filip and Elaf.
Filip and Elaf!
What does the Kurdish expression "Qozelqort" mean?
"Qozelqort" is Kurdish.
It is their word for "prosit".
- What you say when someone sneezes.
- Atjoo!
Exactly.
So "Qozelqort" ...
Verbatim it means "dust in the nose".
"Qoz el Qort" - "Dust in the nose".
So one of the seven dwarves is called Qozelqort?
It's only seven Kurds!
I think Elaf can “qozelqort” -
- For "Qozelqort" is an expression of "shut up".
Verbatim it means "drink poison".
Elaf ... - Tell me, Anders: "Qozelqort!"
Elaf!
- Anders?
- It was awkward.
My two colleagues are Kurds ...
When you get to work: "You know we are Turks, huh?"
It will be embarrassing.
I believe in Filip.
You got a point.
Elaf tried to sell it well.
Qozelqort means "shut up", "Drink poison".
I've heard it before.
Emelie, now it is exciting, because now the winning skull has to come forward.
The ones you are going to talk to are Hanna and Evelyn.
Evelyn and Hanna, what are we looking at?
My ovaries.
—Obefruit ... — - a little moldy?
Yes exactly!
No, it's a Chinese delicacy.
It's eggs ...
... as you have kind of preserved in clay, ash, a little salt.
You leave it aside for a few years or a while.
And so it becomes that the white part of the egg becomes like jelly -
- And the protein part turns green because of the salt.
And they are called millennial eggs.
"Century eggs", like my ovaries.
Why is so much Chinese food from the Fear Factor?
- You don't want to eat that.
- This is Jamaican scented candles.
They are cast in eggshells and contain in addition to paraffin plant extract.
Hence the green color.
Common in Jamaican homes, even as souvenirs.
You put it in the bedroom and light up ... the light!
And...
When you light the flame, it symbolizes that the guy can endure all the time.
The light burns for several hours.
So ... "More Fire".
"More Fire!"
–Emelie?
–Eh ... mm ...
I drive at Evelyn.
- You lied to me last so you might be talking the truth now.
You said I should never trust a Chinese.
It took hard.
- Don't wear a Korean either!
- You choose to believe in Evelyn.
That it is millennial eggs.
It is right!
You do that right in that.
Emelie, you got one more point.
That's what Evelyn described it.
It's a delicacy, millennial eggs.
But who cares about it?
It will be a rash question because we have had two fantastic semi -finalists.
But only one can move on to the final so we will drive closest to win.
What year did the Swedish-Iranian Arash release his first hit "Boro Boro"?
- Boro Boro ... - I thought some of you hummed!
Have!
Boro Boro ...
You got flashback to the Harem Nights nights ...
Are you ready?
Do you have an answer ready?
You show off your paintings on 3 ... 2 ... 1!
- I don't see what he has written.
–Emelie wrote 2010, Anders 2012.
The correct answer when Arash released his hit Boro Boro is 2004.
Emelie, you have won!
- Thanks, Anders!
Come on and you will receive your price.
And here you have your wonderful price.
You have got a green hat ... that you can get on you there.
Congratulations to our finalist!
Thanks to all who have looked -
- Our wonderful panel, audience and competitors.
We meet again!
Texting: Karin Esevik Sveriges Television AB 2024