Welcome to shrimp frozen!
We will visit a vineyard in Provence and look at the spring fashion in Milan ...
... and go on a art walk around Millesgården.
No, we were just kidding!
For those of you who want to know more about us, we have invested in new technology.
We have acquired our own overhead page.
On it you can write down information that you post on the wall.
Imagine what the overhead will mean for the distance work!
- But it's technically vulnerable.
- If the lamp hits then you stand there.
- On the overhead page you can read about us.
- I act as a stand -up comedian.
I think it is important to meet everyone in the audience as an artist ...
Then my unique talent comes to its right.
Hello!
Welcome here to my barbecue kiosk!
My ladies and gentlemen, directly from the TV: stand up comedian David!
Have you thought about this with sausages?
There are cooked sausages, narrow sausages and long and thick.
It's crazy!
HA!
After all, it's totally snappy.
And the sausages have skins!
How can the sausages have skins?
Are they sunbathing?
"Oh, it's hot, give me ketchup!"
And the skin just bursts: "Oh, I'm sweating, I'm a big sausage."
It's fun to see so many people here.
- What do you work with?
Ami has a sale on the leafy piece today - SEK 29 including strips and middle drinks.
It might be tough last half hour but it felt good!
We will introduce a new program point for guys: Now it will be a boy!
Tonight we will talk sports.
- We guys love sports.
- Girls like more animals and stuff.
- Yes, horses, skin creams and stuff.
- But we guys like sports.
- You don't coward for strong beer, huh?
- No, it will be good.
- I love strong beer.
Now we bowl.
-Bowl!
-Strong!
- Yes, it bubbles in the nose.
- Chips, maybe?
- Yes, nice.
-Delicious!
And I've done quiche.
- Oh, pie!
I love pie.
Surely it is fun with football?
Hammarby is my favorite team.
- So you like Gnaget?
- I've always been rodents.
I like Helsingborg best.
They are best at fit and dribble.
- They have one who is good at dribbling.
- A dark guy?
Yes, he can dribble!
- I don't like Helsingborg's clothes.
- No, green does not fit white.
- No, it's probably Hammarby.
- I always mix them two.
We will look at a nice goal.
NO!
--Wow, what a goal!
- Yeah!
Straight into the bar!
- Turn out that it wasn't offside.
- I hate offside!
- Why are you shooting offside?
- Shoot in goal instead!
- Should you have snuff?
- Yes, I love snuff!
It is with licorice flavor, huh?
Oh, what a good thing about snuff!
- More strong beer?
- No, I got spinning.
Handball is also fun.
10 minutes left and it says 2–2 ... How will it go?
you think.
And when they score goals, they remain in the ring.
- I start to feel bad about the snuff.
- We will end the boy talk for today.
Next week we will tip about good video films.
I will review "fried, green tomatoes".
And I have seen "flowers of steel".
It's time for close by.
Tonight's guest: Arne Weise.
Arne?
What is your best school subject?
Slant.
- Do you have any middle name?
-Yes I have.
Arne Georg Fredrik Filippo Gustavo Stina.
- Have you had a beard ever?
- Yes, but not on the face.
Which is the strangest place you have vomited?
I vomit every morning.
Everyone does.
- What animals do you think is ugliest?
- I hate animals!
Ugliest?
Everyone is ugly, I think.
Arne, do you have a touge?
Which one do you choose - string or boxer?
I prefer a dachshund or gray dog.
Thanks for coming here!
Thanks, Mona!
It is not easy to be a single mom and waitress.
In that profession, many dangers deceive.
- Be so good, next!
- I am called Kennet and is an alcoholic.
- Hi, Kennet!
I have worked as a traveling seller.
After work I started sitting in the hotel bar and having some drinks.
It became more and more.
Then I realized that I needed help.
Sörpling
Måns, your attitude to this treatment does not seem serious!
Where have you been this weekend, Johan?
In meeting with gluten allergies.
- Are you allergic?
- No, but it's fun to meet people.
We talk and jaw gluten -free bread.
- You are an association person?
- I think you should activate yourself.
I have joined a new association.
A bunch of guys who meet out in the woods and talk.
- Rotary?
- No, but it's conservative.
-What's your name?
-It's a secret.
- Are you a sect, right?
- No, but we have white marks on us.
- Is it religious?
-Yes...
We have different activities.
This weekend we are going to a refugee camp.
I think it will be interesting to see how other cultures are doing.
I have the program for next week.
Here we stand out on rafting.
Cross burning is this.
Well.
Yes, there is always something!
- We are going to a mosque and lunch.
-Lynch.
- Yeah.
Yes Yes!
- It seems fun.
- You can certainly keep up.
-Do you think so?
They have some tricky rules but if you come with me so ...
... can you talk to me.
Welcome to the garden corner again!
Last week we talked about hedge plants - boxwood and leagues.
We also talked about planting distance -
- And I tried to cut.
We have received nice letters.
One is from Bertil Magnvik from Tyresö-
- As he writes that he was missing Tuja.
"Well -groomed tuja hedges always give a noble impression to a garden."
"The dark green cones of the tujas give a full -bodied greenery and good lushness."
He also sends a photo on his own tuja hedge.
It is a magnificent copy that is manually cut.
It's just to congratulate Bertil on the success of his tuja hedge.
He also thinks I was very professional in my molding.
It was probably jokingly said, but I thank you for that praise.
But we're not going to suck each other's cocks yet -
- Look at our fine boxwood - it has received aphids lately!
You have to be careful even if they are very resistant.
This about this.
Now we will see an element that is about composting.
-Bullseye!
- Yes, but don't say "suck each other".
-No?
- It feels a little too strong.
Well.
Maybe I should say "praise each other"?
- Yes, we drive it instead.
-Okay.
We will be given food for the soul.
In 3 minutes a week you get a better life!
Lifecoach Henrik Elmér!
Thanks so much!
Welcome once again to the course "Meet Life with Henrik".
This is how you make a boring situation more fun.
One way to gild life is the pig game.
You have a teacup that is cut and oblong with two dots in the bottom.
When you drink you are similar to a pig.
It's fun to invite a friend to tea.
When he drinks I sound: grunts
Then it will be fun to invite friends home.
I'll show one thing.
I've told you about Gunilla that I was with.
Maybe someone is curious about her.
Here I have a photo of her.
Nämen Hello, Gunilla!
How are you today?
Ha, ha, ha, ha!
- Henrik, what is this?
- It's pork - Gunilla.
- Henrik - the bed ... are you sleeping here?
- Yes, but it's just temporary.
- You can't sleep here at the theater.
-I must!
I dare not live at home.
There is a madman in my staircase.
He's totally crazy!
A while ago, the madman started putting stuff in my mailbox.
It looked like regular letters from the bank and Säpo eg.
I realized that it must be from someone in the house because the gate is locked.
The worst thing was when there were letters that seemed to be from my mom.
This madman had written long letters with my mother's writing.
It was nasty and I wanted to know which of my neighbors it was.
So always when I met someone in the stairwell I said, "Hi, Mom!"
To see who looked guilty.
But everyone looked guilty.
Everyone looked like they thought, "Has he taken?"
I expected a plot:
That all my neighbors made letters in my mailbox.
But then I heard two of my neighbors talk about the madman in the house.
They also had problems with the madman.
Then we decided that I will live somewhere else until "psychot" has moved
One solution is to live here and the course is about finding solutions.
Next week you will know more.
Thanks!
Let us pray.
Father spring who is in heaven, sanctified was your name ...
Sörpling
Do your will, such as in heaven, as well as on earth.
-Sch!
- Do you use good deeds?
-Yes.
Last week I cut the neighbor's hedge.
Mm, that's good.
We chose this joke as the winner from the contributions to our joke competition.
The winner is Ulf Buller in Höör.
A piece of the Berlin Wall is on the way.
Coughs
-Cold?
- It's probably the flu.
It goes a lot like that now.
I went home from work.
I was going to rest, watch video and drink hot.
-Just right!
Customer number?
–2154.
So there.
You should see "the plane's planet", I see.
It's a real classic!
- Have you seen it before?
-No.
You are deceived by it is called "The plane of the monkeys".
They are on earth all the time.
Did you know that?
You don't understand it until the last scene -
- When you see the goddess of liberty sticking out of the sand.
Then you are surprised.
Get well!
Hello!
As on his student album ... Everyone came in and he said "Where is the camel?"
- "Has anyone seen my camel?"
-Good God!
- I have to work.
-Nice to see you.
We have to redo this!
Should we take a pilsner this weekend?
Yes, I'll call you on Friday.
- Tapped something?
- The wallet.
Have you seen it?
-No.
Did you have it with you?
- Yes, I paid the coffee.
- Have you forgotten it on the toilet?
- No, I haven't been there.
- You haven't stopped it?
-No.
Here it is!
It's my wallet - I see that.
- No, that's mine.
- No, that's my driver's license here.
Okay.
Wrong by me.
What is this?
I had 500 bucks.
Where are they?
- You paid for the coffee.
–25 bucks, yes.
Have you taken them?
How long have we known each other?
I am one of your best friends.
Would I steal SEK 500 and hide them in my stocking?
Ah, I took a robber!
I took a chance!
Here you have the money.
I had to test.
Now we will start to be seen regularly!
We'll talk about death.
I'm not afraid of death because I'm semi -Indian.
In India you do not die, but you become a cow, rat or something in that style.
You can drive past a Scanian cow and think, "I recognize him!"
We will look at my past lives.
I have a pedigree here.
2,000 years ago I was a manager to Jesus.
Booked him at Gig.
He often said, "Too badly paid!"
When we were to make the sermon, I had to chat:
"Come on now, Jesus! Everyone will see you, people from the Bible get there."
Then I booked him out at the taverns as guest - Bartender.
The trick when he made water for wine was brilliant!
But he was tedious.
I said, "Don't dress like a hippie! Sandals had before Christ."
Look at Judas - he can talk to people!
He comes in everywhere.
I have also been a PR consultant for Kristian Tyrann -
- The Kazakhstan in the 1800s and a dental hygienist for Martin Luther.
Most recently, I was a plumbing installer in Trelleborg.
Dear audience!
I am now going to recall one of my past lives.
- Does this take a long time?
- People like this, it's good TV.
David has been moved to a previous life.
He has become Gert Håkansson, plumbing installer from Trelleborg.
- Welcome here, Gert!
- It's good to be here.
Yes, Gert ...
... what is it like to be a plumbing installer?
I'm ... I'm not full, you!
There is a lot of work down in the basement, up and down.
And as I usually say: it doesn't smell roses there!
It's like onions on the salmon you could say.
- Onion on the salmon.
- You are early retired?
- Yes, it was ...
They said, "We'll put you on Hispan, Gert. You're going to Hospital."
It was gin and genever.
It was both Gin and Genever and Snaps!
My wife stuck, you.
I said, "Stick, you! I can't cope with you anymore!"
She stuck with Gunnar.
I went home to him and pissed in the hammock.
- Thanks for coming here, Gert!
-Thank you!
Yes ... Tommy was a good guy.
He left his wife Monika and their dog Rocky.
Well, I couldn't imagine that the band saw was so dangerous.
We honor Tommy with a silent minute.
Sörpling
We will talk about modern working life with debater Kerstin Bäck
Welcome!
You have worked as a traverse driver at a steel mill.
Now you travel around and lecture.
What is the most important message you want to convey?
A lot has happened in working life.
The women still have the lowest salary and there are few female managers ...
I'm not full, you!
I am nail soils!
The development has not progressed?
- I usually encourage women to ... - Should you with out in the woods and talk?
Should we talk a little, you?
I'm still going out and pissing.
Quiet now!
- Should women take more care?
- The men can't do it for them ... - you get a slant if you come along!
Sorry!
-I do not understand what you mean.
-You do not understand what I mean?
- I think you have anger within you.
–Lill there, yes!
- If you listen, you feel better.
- Learn to listen, yes.
Then you will feel much better.
Kerstin, I love you!
- Kerstin, I'm really sad.
- I love Kerstin!
We end the program.
Look next week as David has become himself!
"Who is clamping on my bridge?"
shouted the troll.
"It's just me," replied the little goat Bruse ... Sörping
Mon, you have to be quiet!
Otherwise, you may not be in here.
SVT Program Setting: Britta Landén Bergman