I'm too full.
You can drive!
- Britt!
Hello!
-Hello!
-It was a long time ago!
So you're here?
-Yes.
- And you're here and Saturday shopping.
- Yes, you have to.
Do you know, I would buy vacuum cleaner bags.
It's so difficult!
They do not have the right bags for Voltan we have at home.
I said this: Make the same bag for all vacuum cleaners!
- It would have been much better!
- Well!
- Be so good and get up again.
-Ouch...
Does the pain feel all the time or just sometimes?
No, they feel all the time.
Here is an X -ray of your abdominal cavity.
Everything looks normal except this.
- It's probably the cause of the pain.
-What is it?
It's a golf shoe that you have down here.
You see the spikes in the sole.
It's probably the plows.
It seems to be a left shoe.
It is not dangerous, but of course feels a little uncomfortable.
- Is it relevant with surgery?
- I think we wait a bit.
It can come out the natural path.
We wait and see, I think.
How nice you are in your hair, Inger!
-Are you still going to Maj-Lis?
- On the caluf, yes.
I was with her and made foil loops.
- But it became completely wrong shade!
- Night, you say?!
Stop the car!
What the hell is it with you?
You drive like a rake!
It was one -way over there!
You almost drove on the aunt!
Is it certain that you have not been drinking?
Look!
Do you see what I see, Per-Arne?
- Is it a bear?
- It stands a bear in the square!
- We should take a picture, Carita.
- Yeah!
Typical!
Once we have tried GHB for the first time -
- Then there is a bear in the square and I am too spinning for taking cards.
It's our usual bad luck!
Do you have the man with you too!
- Hallå, Inger!
-Nice to see you!
- They only had little after eight.
- You've been away for 20 minutes!
- men can't shop.
- No, they can't.
- Should you have foreign?
- Mulla Omar and his new wife are coming.
He is so fond of After Eight.
Last time he was at home he ate all up!
Do you know what, Inger?
He has problems with the prostate.
You shouldn't talk about it.
Last time he was at our house he went on a toilet eight times!
- Now we will shop further, Inger!
-Have a nice day!
- What should we have for starters, then?
- They had Skagen stir on coupon.
What the hell are you on me for?
It was he who drove!
I am a passenger.
Give him a fine!
Have you tried anervan that I wrote out?
I didn't think it had any major effect.
Here is the X -ray image.
You have had a headache.
We have not found any tumor, which is lucky.
But there is something little here between the brain halves.
It's a small, small drum set you have here.
You see the hi-hat to the right, here are three hanging pieces and double baskets.
When you feel pain in the head-
- Then there is probably a small, little guy here and drives on by just hell.
Is that normal, right?
It is not very common.
You can't say that.
Conny, don't put the tomatoes in the bottom of the bag!
He is hopeless!
I wanted tacos, but he says he can't tolerate them.
I think Mozzarella and Pesto are good, but he can't stand it.
Do you know what he said?
That he gets heartburn.
So yes!
We will have twenty.
We will talk about something that we men love - hunting.
- Hunting on brides, right?
- Hey, you just think of brides!
Sometimes I think of strong beer too!
No, of course I mean hunting in the forest for wildlife.
Yes, here we sit on a hunter pass.
- You don't coward for a hunter sandwich?
- No, you get hungry by hunting.
- Can I tempt with a strong beer?
- I love strong beer!
Here I have sushi.
I have ginger to sushi.
Should we taste this, then?
- It is good with white wine for sushi.
-I have!
And so I have wet wipes about sushi sticks.
It is important to have proper stuff when chasing.
Do you have a knife?
No I have not.
I have a garlic press.
- Don't I see like an aunt now?
-No.
It's nice.
We will look at how your ankle has healed.
Here you see the metal rail sitting along the leg.
Here are the screws.
Down here you see something that looks like a small fork.
-Do you know what it is?
-No.
-What is it?
- I have no pale fat fucking idea.
But I don't think it should look like that.
- What is hunting for you?
- The most pure nature experience!
The total freedom, where man and nature live in interaction.
The scents, the silence, the silence.
A shot goes off
I will quote one thing Jan Guillou has written.
In "Big Macho book" he writes ...
Should I...?
In "Stora Macho Book" Jan Guillou writes in the chapter "My Hunt":
"In the relationship between me and the deer there is no lie."
"The deer is superior to me in everything - except firepower."
"It's a formidable creature ..."
A shot goes off
Mobile signal
It's mine.
Help me, André.
How to secure the rifle?
Aj like hell, your fucking ...!
I feel tired and tough today.
I lack energy and feel hopeless.
It feels like I've had a impaired sight.
I'm foamy -eyed.
Then I got something else strange, hair in the palms.
I don't know what I've done.
Then it is as if my spinal cord has become strange.
- What do you think it is?
- Have you not done anything special ...?
- With yourself like ...?
- No, I've been alone this weekend.
I've been lying on the couch ... We just got TV 1000.
I don't know what it might be ...
- Should I pull in the strut for you?
-No!
- It was no bad cucumber.
-No...
- What does one cost?
–39 SEK/kg, it says.
- It was a lot of money.
- For goods turn so much in price.
Meat does not have the same price fluctuations.
- What do you say about peaches, then?
- It's delicious, I think.
I usually cook marinated peaches when the guys come to dinner.
Are you going home and watch a real peach?
Now I get a little curious.
Hello, Gullet.
The lady here wants to invite us home and look at "A real peach".
Exciting!
Is that something you grow yourself?
It was he who said it ...
I have to go home, I have a bread in the oven ...
- What a lovely aunt!
- Yes, absolutely wonderful.
Should we give that guy a handle?
I don't put my foot in that pool.
It is full of bacteria.
Yesterday, a kid kissed in it.
Imagine so many kids who have done so.
-20 % of the water is certainly pure urine.
–Fy phase ...
I've started doing it myself.
What the hell, the damage is done!
- Are you going into the water and kisses?
- No, I'm standing on the edge.
I can't relax when everyone looks.
Last time I was standing there for 10 minutes.
- But it ended?
- Yes, then came the pure flood!
It's the beer.
It runs straight through one!
No, I look like hell in this!
No, you are very nice.
But take a size smaller.
Give me flowers, fast as hell!
Give me a yellow variety!
Iris, pimpinella ...!
It's a cerise carnation!
Are you blind, girlfriend?
Give me gerbera!
-What do they cost?
–75 SEK.
Give me gear!
I'll have 25 bucks back.
I thought you were robbed.
You usually take things and go, only.
If I were you I would just take them.
–Out to pay?
- You usually do so.
- Oh, damn ... then I do.
- Do not glue the hundred.
Then I stick ...
Nice weekend!
Sayonara!
Welcome to the basic course in karate.
What is karate then?
- You learn deadly blows.
- You are partly right.
But if you have come here to teach you, you have come wrong.
For karate is about something completely different.
Karate is all about ...
...Control.
We will start by learning the most important thing - not to hurt anyone.
I need a volunteer.
- If you come up ...
You remember what I said about not hurting anyone?
Within the karate, we mark the beat.
There you see the difference between champions and beginners.
Try to mark a blow to me.
First we greet each other.
Highlights ... We greet and mark.
- The lesson is over today.
- Isn't that more?
- The clock is just ... - leave the room!
- This was fucking fun.
-Stick.
See you on Thursday, then.
-Hello!
The situation?
-Just great.
How about you?
- I and Johan were in Copenhagen.
- Fun that it is good between you again!
- What then "again"?
- Sure it wasn't that good.
If you are unfaithful, it is probably a sign that something is wrong.
- I have not been unfaithful.
- No, not you.
Has Johan not said anything?
It was over three weeks since I lay with him.
- Have you been lying with my guy?
-Yes.
It was only once.
He said it from the beginning.
Yes, that he could not afford anymore.
You apparently have a little scarce.
Tell us if you need to borrow.
Has it gotten better or worse during the week?
It's the same I think.
Here are the X -rays.
Here you see the left ham and here are right.
Squeezed between sits something that is probably the cause of the pain in the back.
It's a Russian thesis you have here.
You see the Samovar down here.
Then you have six teacups in a row in colon.
From the handles of the Samovar to judge, I guess it is from the 1880s.
Probably made in Sankt Petersburg.
What do you think it's worth today?
- I don't know ... - guess.
–5,000-6,000 SEK ...?
-No absolutely not.
I would say somewhere between SEK 18,000-20,000.
-Are you surprised?
-Yes.
It's a rarity you're sitting on.
It is rare to see them in such good condition.
God, how nice to get away a bit!
-When are you going?
-Monday morning.
Can you water the flowers, Kristina?
- What happened now?
- Kristina usually watering ...
Why don't you ask me?
"Kristina usually water ..."
We know each other since play.
Kristina is just with Magnus's friend.
Why don't you ask me?
- You are silent!
- I don't know ... - It's no answer.
Aren't I good enough?
- I didn't think you wanted to ... - it's clear that I want to help you!
Kristina ...!
Thanks.
Thank you, you!
- Come, Kristina, we go!
Ulf usually helps me with the computer, but Andreas works with network service ...
- We are not desirable!
--Ulf ...!
Ulf: We don't set our foot here anymore.
I usually put the water can on the sink.
THE DOORBELL RINGS
Do you open?
Hello!
I would need your help.
This applies to Fridas and Magnus flowers.
They are so many!
I really can't water them.
Can you do it?
Jenny does not want to water with Frida.
When it gets hot you are not so cocky anymore.
- Is the old Bettan that is shredded?
- I can't cook such old computers.
- Gee her to me, just.
- I can water.
Don't say anything to Magnus and Frida, please?
Should we do the job and you get the honor?
Next time we play TP we will go.
Is it okey?
-It is okay.
- Nice that we can trust you.
Bye!
- Can they trust us?
-Do not think so.
Oh no!
They are dead!
- Jenny has killed every flower!
- This is not good!
I have received viruses.
I would never have let Andreas pill with the computer!
- What are we saying to Jenny and Andreas?
- What are we saying to Ulf and Kristina?
Those who always want to help.
I feel really good!
Next time we play TP we let Ulf and Kristina win!
- They are useless at TP.
- Desto happier they will be!
"Which English teddy bear likes honey and is a friend of Nasse?"
-Mr. Nilsson?
- It's a monkey!
Nalle Puh is right.
Then we, Kristina.
YES!
Last Pluppen!
- "Which king died in Lützen?"
- Gustav III!
-It is right.
- Wasn't it Karl XII?
That's also right.
Program text: Helena Habermann (C) Swedish Television AB 2004
How is it going?
I look like a man in this.