- Here ... - here is my congregation.
- Here is your church.
- Here is my church.
- Here you can join?
-Yes.
It's my congregation.
You have been involved in not being allowed to stay in a congregation?
Just.
Church gates were closed when I opened my wardrobe door.
You opened your wardrobe door and then the church door was closed.
This is Robin.
He grew up within the Salvation Army.
He will never forget when he understood that he should feel shame -
- Over himself.
My pastor carried with him a very conservative view of -
- How to be a Christian, the Christian identity and what it means.
From him I was called leprosy sodomite for half the congregation.
It was a difficult betrayal to handle -
- And it aroused many wounds in a boy who just needed to feel loved.
This is Robin's story.
But it's not just about him.
This is the story of all children -
- which has been harmed by the religion their parents have chosen for them.
And those children are everywhere.
They grew up in different religious contexts, and they are many.
All children who grow up in religious home do not get bad.
But now it is about those who have done it.
Now let's listen to them.
Many of the young people we met have told about their horror for hell -
- If the fear of demons and for praying sin.
A bit into the conversation, with everyone we talked, it has also been about sex.
When the pastor made clear to the assembly his view of homosexuality-
- And people like Robin, the life of Robin changed in the congregation.
Man condemned my love.
If I didn't repent -
- I never get love again.
And what does it do with a child?
How the others in the congregation, the old friends, were against him -
- Also changed.
Suddenly in a place where I felt at home and could before and without-
- So small oil crosses appeared.
At the piano where I used to play, at the coffee table where I used to have a snack.
- What is an oil cross?
- At prayer you can iron oil on something.
It is an old practice to bless - as the last anointing for example.
You have walked around and lubricated and asked for holiness and protection.
It's a very nice thing to do.
But I didn't really understand that there was a connection to me.
In recent years I have learned that it was probably not a blessing for me -
–On protection from me.
There is so much shame and loneliness.
When you know something that many people appreciate should be wrong, bad -
- Or disgusting even, you do your best to hide it.
And when you start hiding things and lie about yourself -
- So you also hurt yourself.
It is difficult to describe how it feels when a pastor stands and says -
- That homosexuality is a disease.
There was no bisexuality.
The blame that I have a desire, a draw that is wrong ...
Instead of something wonderful - "I can love the one I want" -
- So it was like: "Okay, now my lifelong struggle is starting."
The feeling of shame when in that situation -
- It gets very, very strong.
And I took it out on myself.
"It's a disease."
"We'll love the one who is sick" -
- "But also help it recover with Jesus."
I thought that what I feel is sick and disgusting and wrong.
So it was a huge shame.
To hear it when you are small, it leaves very deep tracks.
And then I don't know if they heal.
When I became a teenager and started getting a sexuality -
- And realized that I was bisexual, then ...
... I was also good for God to hear those thoughts -
–And God would think I was dirty and sinful -
- And that I would end up in hell.
The shame followed me wherever I went, and it still follows me today.
I ended up in a very, very special self -harm behavior.
I bit myself, because it didn't appear.
With long sleeves it did not appear.
And I knew it wasn't leaving scars.
It's something that I know, that I can take out on myself.
I can punish myself based on what I know, based on what I am.
When I prayed to God as a child, I asked for God to remove me.
Not that I would die, only that I had never existed.
Because I understood that what I was caused to others.
"God who has the children in love, please, remove me."
During the teens, those prayers became much more destructive.
I was told that LGBTQ people-gay as they said in the church-
- Normally becomes happy.
"It is your fault if you do not change. The answers are in your actions."
"You are not praying enough, is not enough Christian."
"Why have you chosen to be a LGBTQ person, gay?"
"Don't you know that God wants more with your life?"
How does it affect a child who hears about himself in a church bench?
I think they become very unsure of themselves.
They internalize the image that there is something fundamental to them.
And unfortunately, it is getting more and more wrong as sexuality develops.
One thing that becomes clear here is that they are, because they are in religious systems -
- Experience someone hears their sinful thoughts.
God hears what they think.
How does it affect a child's development to live with that performance?
So, that you perceive that God is everywhere and see everything you do -
- Can be very secure.
Then you always have a wise dialogue partner, and that is positive.
But when you have this that is seen as a fundamental design error -
- So it becomes very problematic that you cannot escape from God's gaze.
"Hands on the blanket, God sees you" is an expression from the past.
So of course incredibly difficult.
The religious package makes the message -
- If homosexuality is wrong becomes more serious than a secular message.
What do you want to say to religious communities that speak so in the vicinity of children?
This means that the child gets really deep problems in the view of himself.
As they become adults, they will leave the religious movement -
–And then they may start to be able to accept themselves -
- After many years of unnecessary self -doubt.
But it's not just those who had a different sexuality -
- which has been frightened by what was preached.
Many have learned that sexuality is shameful -
- It is sinful to feel desire.
And in many communities it is clear what crime it is against God -
- Having sex outside of marriage.
At puberty ... we went to youth meetings, or teenage meetings.
There was a lot of teaching about abstaining from six-
- And to think clean and not have sex until on the wedding night.
We talked so much about it.
It was like someone took a piece of the apple.
"Now someone has munched on the apple. If several take bite from the apple" -
- "So it's just apple scrap left for your real man later."
- Oh, what a heavy.
- Yes, here's the stuff.
Student cap.
There is little everything possible here.
- How often do you look in the boxes?
- At all.
But I have done it sometimes, because ... the farther from I come ...
You take it up sometimes.
"It was as believer I was."
It's so hard to remember, it's so bizarre in some way.
What's that?
"Young women - personal growth."
When you turn 12, you start in young women's class.
This is...
... a program, simply.
They read this together on Sundays.
I still know it:
"We are daughters to a heavenly father who loves us, and we love him."
"We should stand as witnesses of God at all times, in everything and everywhere" -
- "While we strive to live by young women's values" -
- "What are faith, divine nature, personal value, knowledge" -
- "Freedom of choice and responsibility, good deeds and delay."
"We believe that when we accept and trade according to these values" -
- "Can we be prepared to strengthen home and family" -
- "Receive the Temple's regulations and enjoy the blessings of the elevation."
Every week we recited it together, standing.
- All young women over 12?
- Between 12 and 18.
I am raised in an innocence norm and purity culture.
-What does it mean?
- Very focus on sexual purity.
There were lessons with ...
... a bowl of dumle that you sent around.
And then there was some leader -
- As a stupid in your mouth, put it back and sent it around.
"Who wants the dumbs I had in my mouth? It's the same with your body."
Keep all the bids, keep all the bids
and find your security and find there your freedom
If you've had sex or even just kissed any -
- Then your body has been soiled.
And this is like a supernatural performance -
- For innocence does not exist, biologically speaking.
You cannot investigate whether anyone is innocence.
The idea is not really available.
But one creates like a double world -
- Where you can be dirty or clean.
Even masturbation is sinful.
Thus, you must not express a basic human need.
It was abstinence that applied.
They talked a lot in metaphors and pictures.
One that I clearly remember was that your sexuality is -
-As a white A4 paper-clean, nice and plain.
If you have sex, it's like you wrinkle together your paper.
And when you try to unfold it and make it smooth again, it doesn't go.
You will always see the wrinkle on the paper.
"Do you have sex, then you have destroyed something."
You were like a chewed chewing gum.
No one wants a chewed chewing gum.
You want a new chewing gum.
In ordinary believers in a church or Muslim congregation -
- Sin is often linked to the temptation.
The more limited man has been in his cultural -
–And the fewer revelations you have been allowed by their context -
–Desto greater is the risk of the foremost association with temptation -
- is linked to sexuality.
The sexual temptation is most evident.
Then there is something also that if you have power systems ...
Power that is really strong becomes internalized -
- So that you feel what the power says.
You take on the gaze of power yourself.
And you do this at a purely physical level.
One begins to feel shame -
- When you violate what society or the power structure tells.
You become your own police officer in some way.
There are few areas that come so close to ourselves -
- As it has to do with sexuality and forbidden sexual feelings.
The social religious power becomes extra tangible.
It can be perceived as churches and religions being completely obsessed with -
- To curb people's sexuality.
Is there anything in it?
Has it been an important task for the religious systems in our history?
Clearly.
From our perspective now, we have contraceptives -
-And it has been around for 60 years.
Before the 1960s, sexuality and reproduction were fully intertwined.
It made sexuality, very, very dangerous.
Women died in a cot, it became children who had to be taken care of, the divided.
Lived under more extreme forms, in poverty and had it more difficult -
- Then you couldn't really afford to release sexuality free -
- As you could after the contraceptives.
When you were 21 and would get married and get kids -
- Was it of free will?
Did you want it, were you in love?
I thought so, but it was just a slim part of me who wanted it.
So it was.
- How to think about it today?
- I am really sad for it.
I was not ready and mature to promise something like that.
It's something I have to live with.
I have been so sorry about that.
Everything in the Mormon Church aims to get you married in the temple -
- With a righteous priesthood carrier.
A righteous woman, if one is ...
It even stands here.
Everyone gets one like this.
-What's that?
- A patriarchal blessing.
I must not show it for someone really, but ...
But I don't believe this anymore.
So it is.
It says here that I will get married in the temple -
- And what kind of family we should have.
They talk about the eternal perspective.
One should get married in the temple and become this Union -
- As will be saved together in the seventh heaven, the Celestia Empire.
Everything revolves around getting married.
It is the ultimate goal of your existence here on earth.
What do you want to say to communities -
- As this look reproduces the innocence norm, on the chastity -
–And that has a mix between sexual feelings and shame?
The person's development will probably be damaged by the norms.
This can lead to them marrying the wrong person, at too young years.
Many of those we hear here come from Christian free churches.
What they say is similar to what we heard about honor -
- That we call honor culture.
What do you think when you hear it?
I have the same reflections on it.
Parent investment in our species -
- Is a very extensive project that lasts for many years.
We are also a social animal that depends on people around.
Clans or communities or so.
So rumor for the family -
- or the further developed family, becomes central.
That combination causes the parent to have an interest in -
–Ee make sure the offspring reproduces in a way -
- Which is in line with the investment in the child, and with a good social reputation.
Therefore, it is absolutely fantastic that we managed to do something for honor culture -
-In our part of the world.
It wasn't long ago that we were doing it ourselves.
The chastity norm is connected to a larger package -
- As we call the culture of honor.
As a child I learned that a woman has two choices:
Either she marries as soon as she arrives at puberty -
- Or she focuses on the school.
There is no world where one can explore your sexuality -
- or have relationships unconditionally.
Therefore, when I arrived at puberty, I chose to focus on the school.
I knew that as soon as I showed some form of interest in other things in life -
- So it would open the door -
- For the family's and the family's thoughts on marrying me.
And I was really not interested in that.
I learned that God all hears one's thoughts.
I learned that some thoughts were sinful.
I was very scared and tried to suppress different types of thoughts.
If I was in love with someone else, I felt huge shame.
It worried my parents that I would get rid of the innocence.
In Islam it is punishable.
One must not have sex before marriage -
- And my parents tried to eliminate every risk of it.
I couldn't spend time with guys, not have a skirt or shorts in the summers.
I barely had to be out.
This with guys was among the biggest sins available.
It was the biggest taboo.
Elaf Ali is a journalist, author and debater.
She has written a book about the repressions of honor she was exposed to -
- During his upbringing.
For me it was: "It's wrong with Islam - it's just Islam that's wrong."
Then I moved to Stockholm and ended up in a more mixed environment.
I met a girl who was a Mormon, which is a branch of Christianity.
And her expression resembled my so much.
She didn't look like me at all.
Free churches have a similar problem.
Many people say when talking about it:
"But how many honor killings have you heard of in the Free Church?"
In Sweden, hundreds of thousands are exposed to repressions -
- But how many do we hear about being murdered?
It is extremely, extremely few.
It is everyday oppression: you do not have your own choices.
And there are many similarities between those who grow up in the Free Church -
- And in other religious communities, groups and religions.
It is very similar.
Many stories are similar to each other -
- Wove in which community the children grew up.
But there are, as you say, degrees in hell.
No matter what community the interviewees have grown up in -
- It needs the courage to sit in front of the camera and express their criticism.
But it is significantly most difficult for the Muslims and ex -Muslims we meet.
I meet Omar Macram that started the organization Exmuslims in Sweden.
He explains why.
Apostasi is very stigmatized in Islam.
In most interpretations of Islam-
- Must those who leave Islam are killed.
It is also very difficult for parents to accept -
- That their children leave Islam.
Sometimes one has to choose between family and freedom -
–And some are not prepared to make that choice -
- So they stay away and are more "in the closet".
It is a difference between honorary culture and honorary norms -
- And religious pressure of children, which we talk about here.
Describe the difference.
There are some factors that they have in common -
- But honor oppression has not only to do with a specific religion.
It has to do with collective values -
- which can be cultural or religious, but often a combination.
When young girls, raised within the Free Church in Sweden, for example -
- Or within the Mormon Church, Jehovah's Witnesses or so ...
When they talk about an innocence norm, not to marry who they want ...
- Then isn't that honor?
- No, I wouldn't say so.
A big difference is that in the Christian environment there is a way out.
But within the culture of honor there is rarely a way out:
Something must be done to restore the family's honor.
Therefore, honorable girls often have protected identity -
- Or live in sheltered accommodation.
You are anonymous now that we do this interview with you.
Why do you have to be that?
Because one of the most dangerous things available is -
- When a woman in a Muslim context decides to leave Islam.
It can be followed by threats and violence ...
... and that's something I've received help and support with escaping.
Yes, sometimes the religious control means that the children have to break -
- With their family and the congregation, and on it follows threats of violence.
In some communities, those who no longer believe - are excluded
- Or that do things that go against religion.
Within Jehovah's Witnesses, all parents live under the same injunction:
If the children are excluded, as soon as the children must be big enough to manage -
- Break in touch with them.
A huge pressure on those affected.
When you were excluded, how did it go?
I went in there, and then there is a library ...
Then Dad said before they would go, "You understand what this means?"
And I said, "Yes, I understand what that means."
Texting: Ulrika Jansson Båving Swedish Media Text for SVT