Leif?
Leif!
Hi, Irja.
Nice ... oh, take it easy.
You are so handsome, so beautiful!
And so sexy ...
Yes it's me.
I mean, you are also beautiful.
- Wear, to the lady.
-What rare!
Thanks, Leif.
Is this your brother?
- Hi, my name is Billy.
-Hello.
Irja.
Yes, now we go home in the vehicle, and then I'll show you the house.
Come now, Irja.
Yes, yes ...
Here in the kitchen we eat a lot of good food with our friends.
What a beautiful house!
I love it.
-Do you like it?
- Yes, and the furniture is so beautiful.
I have built a lot myself.
You have to be tired after such a long day.
I think you will like the next room.
-Oh really?
- Yes, you ... yes.
-This way.
-Is this?
Voilà!
Here's your bed.
-It is so pretty!
- Yes, it's bedded to you.
- Where are you going to sleep?
-On the sofa.
So you get the room for yourself.
I'm a bit of a gentleman.
No no!
I want you to sleep with me.
Oh really...?
Okay.
I want you with me in bed.
Yes, but ... oh, shit ...
I have to shit ... no, brush my teeth.
- Did you have to brush your teeth?
- Put yourself, I'll be coming soon.
-Are you coming back?
-Yes...
Do you want children?
Do you want that?
Then we start.
God damnit!
- Hi, Baby ... - Hi ... Raring.
Time to go to bed?
No, I'm just joking.
Good night, Irja.
Nice to have you here.
I would really like to do it with you, Leif.
- But I have menstruation.
- Yeah?
Okay.
No problem.
We don't have to.
It is quiet.
But tomorrow it is over.
And then it's just you and me.
- The night long.
-Okay...
Good night, Leif.
- Good morning, Billy.
- Hi, Irja.
Do you bleed?
Where are you bleeding?
- If you bleed a lot, I have patches ... - but stop, for damn!
- What did he talk about, baby?
- He has a child's brain.
But the body is big, so ... he's crazy.
It is quiet.
You can sit down.
-Thanks.
-No problems.
- Okay ... there will be no picnic today.
-Are you sure?
- Go into the house, you are kind.
-Okay.
Why are you so tense, baby?
It's nothing, I'm fine.
Maybe I can help ...?
Yes, now we are alone again.
Wait.
- Have you been a naughty boy, Leif?
- Yes, I've been a little naughty and crazy.
A tuffing that you like hard hold?
Yes a little...
You really like hard time, I feel.
- Have you been a little naughty?
-Yes some...
- Have you been a little disobedient?
-Yes...
Death!
Fuck off!
Come on, I need ammunition.
Yes good!
Bomb that bastard!
Translation: Dan Olsson Swedish Television AB 2019