In tonight's section of Ifs, the question of all culture in Sweden:
The character chameleon from Botkyrka Thanos Fotas.
The Bollywodan -taking love goddess Meira Omar.
The universe's Swedish Arab Elaf Ali.
And "my fakking brother" Hassan Ali.
Sweden's most fun Chinese Evelyn Mok.
And brother O from Jordbro - Big O.
The Pang pod pod from Skåne, Cisalli.
Landskrona's acidest Syrian Filip Dikmen.
And last but not least our great leader Ahmed Berhan.
Love may be blind, but we have eight panelists, three competitors -
–And Sweden's best audience.
My name is Ahmed Berhan.
It's time to meet our competitors.
Representing pink, to everyday uncle blue:
Huddinge's own Axel Foley - Jonas.
Next to him - she makes you make up IRL, she cuts you online.
The giggling make -up Elin!
At the far end of Orange, with Zen-like Aura, HVB Buddist from Borlänge:
Anders.
Najs.
Jonas, you work as a police officer.
Everyone stopped their drug ... Who do you want to start talking to?
My brother Big O.
As many times as you have stopped me - and now you choose me.
I swear, brother, he has ...
This shabab he is Deli.
He gets paid just because he is shishko.
- No, but ... - a shisko calls another shisko.
But brother, I'm nice shishko.
I only eat Lahme.
Lamb meat, mom meat.
Now back to the question.
Olof K Gustafsson is CEO of Escobar Inc, Yani -
- And he claims that he works for the old cartel king Pablo Escobar.
- But I know the answer to that question.
- What happy you looked!
You like him.
He's cool.
It's true.
100 %.
As 100 as the coal in his bag.
It's true.
Congratulations, Jonas!
That's right.
He claims to work for the Colombian family Pablo Escobar -
- and represent them.
Congratulations, Jonas!
Elin!
Which of our wonderful panelists do you choose?
I've just looked at Love is Blind so I take Meira.
- You take Meira.
Najs.
-Pause!
Elin, I have to say you look really blat.
- I am called Andersson, I promise.
-Where do you live?
This is not love is blind.
Elin ... you chose Meira.
- Here's the question.
You may have heard Muslim friends say "Astaghfirullah".
What does it mean?
It is from the beginning an old and in my opinion very outdated expression -
–For a woman who has intercourse outside marriage -
- Or is unfaithful.
Nowadays it is used a little more sloppy in daily speech -
-And then means "horny goat" fixed for women.
You don't want to be an Astaghfirullah.
Marriage is sacred.
I know that.
Yes ... a horny woman, then.
But I ... trust you ... I think.
You trust Meira.
You think it's a term for ... Horny Gäris.
Unfortunately, Elin, there will be no points.
Meira lied to you.
Astaghfirullah means "I seek God's forgiveness".
It can also be used when someone is in a program -
- Where they are going to marry themselves ...
... without the parents having to choose ... then we say "Astaghfirullah".
- Anders?
-Thanos.
Thanos ...
Fuck his mom.
When someone says about Rasmus Paludan, we say Muslims "Alhamdulillah".
He is Danish, huh?
He used to sing i'm poor farmer -
- From Emil in Lönneberga, in Danish: Jeg your poor peasant region ...
While he burns the Qur'an.
- Not a fucking chance.
- You lied!
- You think he is lying.
You don't think Rasmus is an Astrid Lindgren fan.
- You don't think Rasmus can read.
- Can Thanos read?
-Oh oh oh!
-What happens?
You think Thanos is lying to you.
You are absolutely sure of that decision?
Sorry, no point for you.
Yes...
He used to sing Alfred's song - I'm a poor peasant boy -
- From Emil in Lönneberga.
It is extremely important to collect points this season -
- To get to the final.
There you have a chance to win the IFS buck.
- Jonas.
–Yes.
I drive the beautiful - Elaf.
Thanks!
Oh!
It was worth 6.5 hours in makeup?
Love is really blind, Jonas.
Really Blind.
-Ot really ... - so.
Elaf ... –yes.
- It is a swearing ... - Heams Skånskan: a "sviurdium"?
That's why Jonas wants you.
He has wanted to become a Swedish teacher.
Continue!
It is a swearing that Arab mothers use when they are angry with their children.
So you have heard it ... but instead of swearing your children -
- Smär they on her husband.
Maybe because they get married to him ...
It means "curse over your dad".
Should I say it once with feeling?
Yilan Abouk!
- I say it's ... true.
- You choose to trust your dearest?
Shouldn't you do it, right?
You do that right in that.
You just got one more point.
Congratulations.
As Elaf said, it is mostly used by mothers who swear over your dad.
There is nothing you heard at work when you have stopped any Arab?
- What is the typical swearing you hear?
-It's in Swedish.
-Type ... "Pip-kid".
- You have heard 100 percent!
- Very Polish too.
- "Kurwa!"
Congratulations.
- ELIN!
–Yes.
Second chance ... Now you think you should choose a panelist.
But you have received a letter.
A letter from Botkyrka.
Hello, good people!
I have to be a little quiet.
I stand here at the Alby Library in the heart of Northern Botkyrka
At this library, the Swedish law book is the most loaned book.
The question is: is that true?
-No I do not think so.
- You don't believe people in Botkyrka read?
And don't follow laws ...
Come on, Elin!
- I say "fake".
- You don't believe Dogge.
No, he is lying.
- You do it right. Congratulations.
- Fan, what a good thing!
The law book is not the most loaned book there.
It's Alfons Åberg.
- Anders.
- Hassan felt outside before.
- Hassan.
- Good there!
- What is Abu Hassan?
- Araba Araba is a nickname on him.
He is a very well -known driving school teacher, traffic teacher or whatever it is called.
He has seven binders.
And with those binders you can handle the driver's license without any problems.
–Okay ... - it's a legend.
But also real.
Yes, not where I come from.
There he is not a legend.
- Have you not heard of the binders?
- Not many Hassan in Borlänge?
-Yes it is.
But not him.
-Not you.
-What do you think?
-Lie.
Not a driving school teacher who was extra ambitious with their students?
You do that right in. Congratulations!
Abu Hassan was a character created by comedian and rapper Big Fred–
-As you could see with little al-Fadji.
We lost Big Fred earlier this year.
Rest in peace.
It was a beloved character that gave us words like Kahwa and subsidiary.
- Jonas?
–Yes ... I drive ... Evelyn.
-Hello Jonas.
Do you want to arrest me?
- We will take it after that.
When I say EuroTrem, what do you think?
EuroTrem ... it's actually such a Eurotechnoband -
– Which is ... they are quite sexual -
- In their music style and clothing and type texts and such.
It is a bit controversial because it consists of a father and a son-
- But it's not that surprising, because they are from Belgium.
- What was it called?
–Eurocrem.
- Cream?
- Cream!
-Cream!
- Cream in English?
I get it.
I say falsely on it.
I have said true at two, so now I run a false one.
If you get a point now you have "Aceat" this round.
It has.
Congratulations, Jonas!
EuroTrem is definitely not an incestuous dance group from Belgium -
- Without Yugoslav Nutella.
- Congratulations on the point!
- What do you choose?
- My brother Filip.
PAM-PAM-PAM!
- Hit me.
Filip ... if you are invited home to an Eastern European on a little mama ...
- What will you get then?
–Eurocrem.
Like this...
Eastern Europeans are a bit weird -
- So they have a several centuries old tradition -
- To test the man.
The mother -in -law should see if the man is approved.
So the tests are kind of chopping firewood, sip them down ... but also weird stuff -
- As the man half naked in underwear should carry the mother -in -law around the house.
It sounds like something they do over there.
So, it's tests for them to ...
- The warm -ups test the man.
- Mama.
I have no idea.
But I say ... true on it, I think.
-Are you married?
- Yeah ... no.
She began to hesitate!
"It depends on what Filip is going to do."
-Not married.
- But you believe in Filip?
- Yes ... — Lite on him!
- You shouldn't have trusted him!
- Fan, Filip!
Damn...
It is not a wedding tradition for someone to be tested by mother -in -law.
Momy is an Eastern European dish made on corn porridge.
It's porridge.
- Anders, you should get your last question.
You have a point.
Elin has a point.
So the question is important.
If you take it, go on to the next round.
--Cisalli.
- It's time for a video question.
What was it we saw?
It is called in my country Indian abortion.
- Namely too late ... - when you know they don't become a doctor!
It is an Indian tradition to throw a baby from 15 meters height-
- To thank God for listening to one's prayers.
- It should give the child lucky.
- What do you say, Anders?
Anders looked at me: "They threw out a child through a window ...!"
It's false.
You don't think they throw out the kids to give the kids lucky?
Unfortunately.
It was true, Anders.
It is a controversial Indian tradition.
One throws children down from a temple to be captured into a large white canvas -
- To have a long life and happiness.
Anders, no point for you.
Great for you, Elin.
You both have one point each.
Only one of you goes on.
Time for a rash issue.
And it goes so that we run what we call "closest to win".
How many in Sweden is called Mohamed?
It is calculated if the name is spelled with one m, two sts, U or O.
Do you have your answers ready?
Do you know someone named Mohamed?
–Yes.
-Yes, you work at HVB homes ...
Okay...
- The top.
–100,000.
-Oh!
Wow ... - Snip ...!
Come on now.
The answer to how many muhamed there is in Sweden -
- Is 50,874.
Anders got a point and has moved on to the next round.
Elin, thank you for joining.
- Now it's time for the duel.
In the duel you will not be able to choose, but I choose panelists for you.
You get two panelists on each question.
One panelist answers correctly.
The other is lying to you.
Find the true answer.
- Jonas, we start with you.
Your panelists will be Elaf and Hassan.
And the question is: When should Muslims be silent, according to Islam?
At the airport.
Especially on ... aircraft.
No no no.
Muslims should be silent when in the toilet.
And especially when doing number two.
So if I am e.g.
on the toilet and poop -
–And Big o is with me too ...
- It's a big toilet!
- Big o films!
We must not talk to each other.
We can write.
- Snapchat, insta, you know ... —Tinder.
Also.
Grindr.
All!
A non-Muslim is allowed to talk.
I can answer by phone.
So if you are a Muslim and the toilet paper ends -
- Can't you ask for help from outside?
- A Muslim has the water can ready.
- Otherwise, there we have it!
Or the shower hose.
When you are an advanced Muslim you have a shower hose.
Sometimes you get a shock when the shower beam is a little too strong.
Thanks, Hassan.
- Elaf?
The true answer that according to a more strict Islam-
- Man and woman do not make sounds during the mating act itself.
- My gut feeling says Elaf is lying.
- What does your heart say?
I believe in you.
The heart says Hassan.
-Love is blind and love is silent ... - He doesn't want it to be true.
But it's true.
"The heart says Hassan" is Jonas autobiography.
Jonas, you chose to trust Hassan.
You chose to throw your dearest.
You did it right.
- Fucking brother!
Me and you ... - you can't say brother to Shurta.
- He has eyes on me now.
- But he is shurta, brother.
In Islam, you should not talk in the toilet.
Do your thing and go away.
Silence when you look at porn magazines.
What is the matter with you and porn?
Every season - porn!
You should be quiet when this arrives.
Congratulations, Jonas!
- Anders ...
The two panelists you should talk to are no less than Meira and Cisalli.
What is the Russian equivalent of the term "love is blind"?
Love is blind, love is blind ...
"Ljubov 'Zla - Poljubish in Kozla" as it is called in Russian.
Literally: "Love is evil - because you might fall in love with a goat."
Can you say that again in Russian?
"Ljubov 'Zla - Poljubish in Kozla."
The real answer is really ... The equivalent of Russian is -
- God has opened your heart but at the same time cut your eyes.
"Love makes you crazy, stupid in your head."
I can say that in Russian:
"Ojski Boyki Nazorovje" ...
But, wait ... Cisalli!
- I am Russian too!
- "Ojski Pojski Kurwa" ....
- Who do you choose to believe in?
–Meira.
It sounds most likely.
It sounds most likely that love can make you fall in love with a goat?
It sounds more like a Kurdish expression if I am to be honest.
It is not such a program.
You think Meira gave you the true answer.
That love is evil because you can fall in love with a goat.
That's right.
Congratulations.
A point.
Nothing is more poetic than Russian love.
Meira was really looking for a goat.
Jonas, we move on to you.
You should talk to big o ...
--... and Evelyn.
-Abow, Aina again, yao!
Shabab, Jalla!
- What is Treif?
- There are three guys.
Everyone is called Leif.
Nämen ... Treif is the place for a soap.
From the beginning it is a Persian word for the Kläftans claw - "Amina Cevdet".
Now you use it to describe people who you think are stingy.
Maddafakkers!
What do you say, Evelyn?
- Treif, it's ...
It is the Jewish equivalent of Haram.
So if a Jew says that something is Treif, then it's not Kosher.
It's not okay, like.
It's haram.
- Filip has been Treif lately.
- She is happy to lie.
- Kosher is okay.
Treif is bad.
-You Are Treif, Mother.
This is ... Treif.
I should have heard it in the resort.
Jonas is currently going through encrocats in his head.
Just scroll through.
Evelyn.
You believe in Evelyn?
That Treif is a Jewish equivalent of Haram, which is not kosher.
Very kosher of you.
Congratulations, Jonas, you got another one.
Treif is what is not allowed.
It is mainly used if what one is not allowed to eat.
Anders, you know it says 2-1.
And this is the last duel.
I see who I got.
Yay.
Switch!
I have never seen any dissertation people so naturally in slow motion.
Your duel is between Thanos and Filip and the question you get ...
In 2016, Zlatan Ibrahimovic said he was going to leave PSG.
He could stay on a condition.
What was that?
Replace the Eiffel Tower with a statue of him.
It sounds like Zlatan, but I have another answer.
Are you ready?
Anders ... that was another condition.
He wanted his teammates to refer to him as The Lion.
- I can give you the whole back story.
- Do you lit on one with law education?
- He is trained to lie!
-Oh...
Society's dirt that capitalizes on people who end up at HVB homes.
Should you trust one like that?
They want it to go to hell!
Then they can get more money from the state.
Do we want such as Filip Dikmen in Public Service?
We will ask that!
Do you know what is true or false?
Vote for Thanos is photographed in the next election!
- This is the new Sweden!
- Anders, calm down the black shells now.
- You can invoice afterwards.
-I get Abiats-Nuva from this.
- What do you trust?
Thanos or Filip?
- It Filip says ...
I imagine Zlatan said so.
But I believe in Thanos.
- This will bite me back there.
- Why do you trust him?!
!
Anders, I cheer for you!
You put your cards on Thanos.
If you get points, it will be a matter of rash.
If you do not get points, it ends here.
I appreciate your zen-lug.
Because you get no points tonight.
Unfortunately.
The true answer came from Filip and the Eiffel Tower.
Zlatan wanted to replace the Eiffel Tower.
It went so well the last time he got a statue ...
With that said: Thanks so much, Anders!
- Congratulations, Jonas, tonight's winner!
Of course you should get a jar with EuroTrem!
A large applause for our winner, our panel, the competitors and our audience.
See you in the semi -finals.
- And see you next week.
Feel the best!
Texting: Karin Esevik Sveriges Television AB 2024