I know Astra is on her way up.
It is too risky -
- Even considering the interest rate announcement.
No, with the GATT Agreement in Risk Zone-
- Is it uncertain to invest in Latin America.
Yes ... and you don't forget to do the homework and put the milk in the fridge.
Hello then, Max.
Kiss!
KNOCK
Come in!
Hello.
All is well?
Yes, but there is a lot to do.
Was it something special?
No.
You enjoy the job?
A month as a manager - everything flows as it should?
It goes very well.
Unfortunately, you get harvested as chambers for a few more years.
- I have a little stressful ... –May!
Have you seen the latest courier?
-How lucky!
But look ... - What have you boiled together?
Solveig Nordenskiöld at Nordbanken: "With us your money is safe."
Huh?
She looks like Ulf Elfving.
Embarrassing with everyone who should be in the newspaper.
- It is enough to do your job.
- Not according to the head office.
You will represent our bank on next week's center spread.
- I can take it instead.
- Reminished manager at the rise ...
- I should be in the newspaper!
- What a perception of perception!
-What should I wear?
!
- Should I ask Elfving where he goes?
Quiet.
You should show yourself as you are.
You work at a bank for the small savers.
They want an article where the small savers can bring up confidence in the bank.
-When is it?
- In the morning at seven.
- Maja, book Grand Hotel's crystal room.
-It is local press, not satellite TV.
That's the difference between us, Rune.
I think globally, you municipal.
It is the humility they are looking for!
The interview, and major office manager, is done in your home.
Simple and relaxed.
In order to ... "show that our bank" -
- "Has managers who are quite common".
- Take the pictures in the garage.
-Good luck!
We keep our fingers crossed.
Take it easy, it's just the local press.
Just.
One more thing...
- That fruit bowl was very empty, you.
-Yes.
- I fill it.
- Make it, you are kind.
- Shit, shit, shit!
- Fifted Dan in a row it burns ...
They complicate everything!
- Warm the cup cannot fail.
- It goes.
Look here.
- There is Africa and there is Antarctica.
-What's that?
A boat?
It's the fish stick from yesterday.
- You can't cook.
- It is a matter of setting up!
- We have to cooperate.
- You cook the food, we throw it.
-Hello!
–20 buckets were, if you keep the color.
- MMM, how exciting it smells.
- Yes, we have eaten a hearty meal.
Yes, we are really big.
Do you know who will be in the courier?
You don't mean ...?
They brought my submitter on the roof on the stand stand!
- Now it gets up to the municipal guys.
- It doesn't apply to you, that applies to me.
They want to make a report on me in an article series about the banks' future.
The head office chose me.
There is a journalist and a photographer here.
-Wonderfully!
Here?
- The clock seven tomorrow night.
- We have to clean, we have to move ... - no.
Everything should be as usual.
- No weirdness, nothing unnecessary.
- Where are we going to hide dad?
- Are you not happy for my sake?
- Yes, of course.
- But where are my football trophy?
- They are not interested in it.
- You have already been in the newspaper.
- You rolled with the bike at Konsum.
I won the competition "The county's fastest postman".
Who came up with the idea of fifteen half -fat postmen on each post cycle?
It was a folk party!
Where is the article?
I framed it.
- It hangs well in the countryside.
- You don't go!
I have never been seen before.
I was never chosen for Lucia.
That place was important for Nettan Olsén - my God, she does not forget.
- Did you know what we guys called her?
- Yes, and you don't say that here!
- I and dad can go somewhere else.
- Don't interfere with this!
- Now it's me to be seen!
-Okay!
- Gustav?
- We should not be in the way.
I promise.
- Max ... is mom at home?
- She hasn't arrived yet.
-Where have you been?
- In the country and fixed a thing.
She kills you!
This shows what an equal family we are.
We are all in the newspaper sometimes.
- You can't look like that.
- It's your genes.
Hello, old man.
Now it will happen soon.
-Where is Dad?
-Where.
My God, I knew it!
-What are you wearing?
- Everything else is in the laundry.
The competition dress?
Stay in the background - it's me they're going to interview.
- I should show that you have succeeded with me.
- I can say that I am adopted.
The doorbell
- You put on something decent.
- Do you have a dress I can borrow?
Max - up!
- Josefin.
We are here for the interview.
-Hello.
Peo.
- Was it difficult to find?
- Yes, all houses are the same.
- This is Lina.
- Silver in the Örebro Cup.
- You get to train as long as you want.
-Thanks.
- The SM is starting to approach ...
This is how I live.
Simple and usual.
No weirdness.
Do you want a glass of plain water?
I don't know how you want to do ...
- I think we start.
- You can sit on the regular sofa.
The article series has received a lot of attention.
Okay, keep your thumbs up!
- Oh ... Hello.
Gustav Svensson was the name.
- Josefin.
There is my photographer, Peo.
- Tjena, Peo.
Excuse the upholstery.
I am the center in the postal team.
- Have you got coffee?
- You can pick up the coffee, Gustav.
- I am very proud of my wife.
- Gustav, coffee!
-Nice man.
Does he work at the post?
- Yes, he is ... distribution cases.
-Shall we continue?
- Yes, as I said ...
Your relationship with the customers ... the small savers lost on the crisis.
Here was coffee in long courses.
Vivalla Football Association 1973?
After the qualification in Division 6. There I am.
Sugar!
What would you like to say to those who doubt the savings bank?
I work hard.
After all, my task is not to suck out the small savers.
It was an original sugar bowl.
Skåne Cup –73.
- I found no sugar bowl.
- I saw it in the garage.
We have a match on Saturday.
Roofs are needed on the standing stand.
- But I've written a submitter ... - Garage!
We meet ICA 15.30.
I apologize for my husband.
The managerial job means so much else, with the EU and the borders that are opened ...
Who knows how long I sit here?
In an expanding market, we must be prepared for all eventualities.
- Forgiveness - 14.30 the match begins.
- Yes ... 14.30.
Imagine we have lived here for 15 years now.
I think it has gone so fast.
When we got here I wore my red -white dress and you had a stomach.
- I've really been happy here.
-I also.
Especially with the dish.
But life is not as you imagined.
Yes, only you plan.
The bank has a branch in London-
- And the leadership keeps an eye on those who show the front feet.
What would you say about moving?
I'm needed here!
What would you say if I disappeared?
-"Hurray!"
perhaps.
- I don't just distribute post ...
- If you knew what people entrust me!
- You help Persson with the rough garbage.
It doesn't have to mean anything, but I thought the interview went so well.
Please Gustav, listen now.
If we get the chance, we have to take it!
Imagine us in London!
A new life, a new country, a new language!
Do you think an interview in the courier gives you a top job in the banking world?
Nice that you have your feet on the ground.
Hello.
My name is Lena Svensson.
In Started My Career a Long Time ago in Sweden.
Sweden is a very cold country.
Budentralen.
Has it arrived?
The newspaper.
The article about Lena Svensson, bank manager.
Yes, yes ... no, I don't think so.
Was it today it would come?
–60 courier ordered.
- I have not ordered.
Let them lie down because you have gone up here.
- Have they come?
–60 each that Lena has not ordered.
It was good that you came.
We will talk about the future.
Nothing is determined yet-
- But I may need to stay more time abroad now.
- Should we read first?
- Lena, you look really nice.
Who stands outside the window with a trophy?
Lena Svensson, the boss who does not let the success rise to her head.
Everyone's money is equally worthy.
"I work hard. My task is after all to suck out the small savers."
- Read what it says.
-I did it!
"My job is to suck out the small savers," says Lena smiling.
I didn't say!
I didn't say suck out the small savers, of course!
You have to believe me!
We believe you.
The question is whether the small savers do.
-What should I do?
–Singapore 6 900 ...
- The head office burns me on a bonfire!
- Not if the small savers come first.
Do not answer!
Cancel all meetings.
I barricades the main entrance.
I'm kidding.
- It's enough if we lock it.
- How should I come out unseen?
There is a gap in the elevator shaft ...
Calm down, it's a wrong quote.
You have nothing to be afraid of.
And I was going to London.
Everything was clear.
- London is cheaper than Singapore.
- Fun, Rune.
You are of great help ...
-Password?
-Open!
- Open, fuck!
-Right.
No one cares about the article.
Mom has been home for two days.
- But today she opened the blinds.
- What are you afraid of really?
The media's impact beats blindly and ruthlessly.
Think of Stig Malm, Hans Holmér ... The list of innocent victims is endless.
- And here comes the last in the line.
- Many people want to hurt your mother.
- We have a solution to the problem.
- Wedding beards and bulletproof vest?
Personal letters to the small savers or a dementia.
- In the garden they are waiting with rope.
- I am not ripe for such jokes.
- My submitter came in.
- Have you written to the courier?
Better.
Express.
Lol!
"Hello, B.O. I think it's too damn" -
- "That journalists are allowed to write anything without being imprisoned."
"Mom is innocent. Mikael Jackson too. Lina. I love horses."
- A law -historical moment.
- Fint, Lina.
- It's going to be no London now, huh?
- But you dreamed, that's the important thing!
- What had I been without dreams?
- Helt Normal, maybe.
Yes exactly.
Who wants to be?
Keep the dream alive!
- I will improve in my English.
-Good!
- Everything is not about career.
- The course ends in May.
The London chief is coming in August.
Then I'll show up for big tasks!
I'll arrange with dementia.
The magazine can photograph me down in the pub.
I take the tweed suit and sit in the English armchair with a little sherry.
Heading - "Lena Svensson speaks about the felvitat and the future Europe."
Then dad cooks food again.
Texting: SVT Sub -text (C) Swedish Television AB