Was there anyone who wanted a big one?
Damn!
Oh oh oh.
What a fantastic day here in Fjällbacka in Bohuslän.
I'm going to meet my friend Sofia B. Olsson -
- As will guide me among the raw materials in this region.
Then we go out to Kalvö and meet Åsa, who is an oyster farmer.
Sofia and I, who is also a chef, will be allowed to test two kinds of oysters:
The invasive Japanese oyster, also called gigas-
- And so the Swedish classic oyster Edulis.
Welcome to Kalvö!
Hey you.
We have an oyster bank from the 17th century.
An oyster bank must be managed, it can't just lie there and die out.
We are much like ordinary farmers.
We are thinning, moving oysters so that they are not on each other -
- We look at how they feel and so, of course, we harvest them.
Then we will see if the waders fit.
We must have them when we pick oysters.
Are we done?
Then we go and pick some oysters.
-What should we do?
- Now we will look for gigas.
It is quite difficult, because now there is a little sand over them.
Then it is great with the water binoculars.
You go ahead, stop and push it down.
When the sand settles you look clearly and then you pick up gigs.
I want some bautastor too.
Every oyster is like a work of art.
- Now my bucket is full.
- Yes, it looks fully.
Don't forget that we should pick Edulis as well.
We have prepared a bit, because they are at 13 meters otherwise.
I thought we would not have to go down to 13 meters today.
You can take the blue tamp, so you get to work a little.
Oyster farmer for a day.
I may need to fight a little.
Here we have them, yes.
This is the Swedish, Ostrea Edulis, which is the origin of the origin for us here.
They have been here for thousands of years, long before the gigas came.
So now we have two kinds of oysters.
Before cooking, we take a trip around the island and look for more ingredients.
- Here we have beach cabbage.
- Look, how nice.
Fresh and fine.
But you can't pick everywhere now, huh?
No, they are protected in some landscapes-
- But here in Bohuslän you can pick beach cabbage.
--Wow!
–Shit, what a view.
I would like you to tell you more about your passion for these wild ...
... new, invasive, oysters.
Is it something I love to talk about, that's it.
They came here a couple of years ago.
It was very much: "The Japanese giant cheese invades."
"They threaten the domestic oysters and mussels."
But after a while I thought they are damn like the French oysters -
- As everyone loves, and realized that it is exactly the same species.
Then it gets really interesting.
We have oysters here on our coast -
- As no one wants to be in the water, and no one eats them ...
At the same time as we import type 6,000 tonnes of French of the same species -
- To Swedish restaurants every year.
It's not logical.
We have to use these oysters.
Sofia works a lot with Japanese flavors, and tops her raw oysters -
- With
Algae, sour soy sauce, apples and honeysuckle flower.
They become a snack when the guests arrive.
I myself make a chilled soup with almond potatoes and leeks -
- As I taste with oysters and tops with, among other things.
beach cabbage and apple.
Hope that our oyster -loving guests will like our ideas.
I want guests now.
-Welcome!
- Welcome out.
We have controlled some lovely oysters.
It was delicious.
You knew all the flavors.
–What do you have with you now?
- Now I come with the soup.
I made it with almond potatoes and flavored it with oysters:
Mixed a lot of raw oysters in it.
What flavors!
Fantastic.
It is fun to show that the oyster -
- So can act as a flavoring, and not just be in their shell.
It wasn't stupid.
I would never have been able to find that myself.
It's really amazing.
The guests seem satisfied, but we have an ace in the rock sleeve - grilled oysters.
-Oh!
--Wow.
Now comes the last serving of the oysters -
- Which is grilled in their own shell.
They get a great taste.
Then some other shades emerge.
A little more nutty and more sweet.
A smoky, amazing taste.
Mums!
- Are you satisfied with the food?
-Absolutely.
It was fun cooking.
Pretty simple, pretty much raw material.
It was fun.
- They seem very satisfied.
-Really.
Now you want to move to Bohuslän.
Is it always like this?
I agree with you.