Oh.
It's not so careful.
Are the lights lit?
Well, you are already sitting.
Frida had thought of another table placement ...
Liljeholmens was too expensive ...
Sit down for so long.
You may apologize for the wrong music.
I'll come, I'll just ...
Stan Getz fits better.
- It would have been another table placement ...
–Eh ... - this is going to be good.
Excuse the mess, we have not come in order.
We'll repaint.
It will be white, fresh.
- Frida?
It is not decorated at all, there is no decoration at all ...
A little mood ... - No, it's going well!
Spruce and rowan berries, but you have to think away ...
You really have to apologize what it looks like.
You can sit like this for a while.
It would have been another location.
Did I say that?
And the wine ... broccoli was out of consumer, so then the food idea burst.
So then it became Retsina, but think Chardonnay.
And I was going to have been with Andreas, but Jenny got ahead.
So Magnus and I have to continue.
A little wine?
Your Inner Landscape Has to Be Clean, or you will never find inner Peace.
Wait a second.
Keep Talking!
Different Measures will help impurities flow away.
At the center, we have adopted ...
Guess Who I Am.
"Hallo, Halli Balli ..."
- You see?
--No.
I'm you!
"Halli Balli ..."
Peter, if you had to choose ...
If you have to choose between Ylva, me and Tilde, who do you choose?
Tell me!
Sure I have the biggest chest?
Ylva has done her in Estonia.
Stupid, huh?
They can inject anything.
I have done mine in Örebro.
Is it your car?
It will be SEK 600 in fines.
You could say that if you get a p -bot, it can be a bit like ...
... anal sex.
You park your cart in forbidden zone-
- And get to lighten the scrotum.
Why aren't you like other boys?
Plays football and cuts cars ...
I'm worried, Jesper.
I'm so worried about you - for us.
Up to fight against the qualifier ... - Stop!
I am only interested in state affairs.
And food ...
-Thanks.
-What are you doing?
Seriously speaking, this music ...
This is the music we have!
If we dance to this on Storgatan's day, we will be laughed at.
We must have something tougher.
-No!
It's not Milkshake's music!
- Shit in it then, do it.
Then I am not.
Come, Salle.
No.
I like you sharply, Maggan, but my place is with the dancers.
There I belong.
It is my life.
- It's so I breathe.
- Are you coming, then?
Okay.
This one was cool, I think.
God, what a great thing.
A "D", like.
It's kind of a toastol.
- Is it a toastol, Peter?
Welcome to the "gender in focus".
We will talk about female sexuality.
Men and women are the same in a lot, but girls turn on other things.
Does the expert have any tips?
How to win a woman's heart?
I can answer that question with a single word: clitoris.
- Clitis, clitoris, clitoris.
-Clitoris.
But purely, if I want to get a girl interested ...
Then you stimulate the clitoris.
We know that many guys have a hard time finding clitoris.
We will show.
This is the clitoris ...
- You have drawn a schematic picture ... - Yes, that's right.
It is here.
If I have understood it correctly, the clitoris should sit ... here.
That's right.
Many guys are looking for wrong, maybe here ...
So it is wrong.
It sits here, in connection with the genitals.
A bit like the man's purse.
I hope we were able to help you guys at home.
Thanks!
- I'll probably touch me now.
- No, don't go home!
One is worn to ...
- No, it's a day tomorrow too.
- What stiff you have become.
- The magic is here.
–Wa?
That she has a stomach ...
My ladies and gentlemen, I get to present the dance group in front of others:
Milkshake!
Thanks!
But Jarmo, you are also crap.
No...
Then I say you are pretty dishonest.
I just say what I think.
I actually do it!
Peter, stop there.
Do not write Jarmo clearly.
Drink plenty of water and try to rest, as long as you are healthy in general.
Yes, otherwise I'm healthy as a nut core.
It's just vision ...
- Sometimes it disappears.
- Flims it?
No, it doesn't flicker.
It gets carbon black.
As if you put a bag over your head.
Check it ... I think you should do.
That sounds tough.
It is.
It is the worst in traffic.
The day before yesterday I was out on the E4.
I was blind for half an hour!
- It was pure luck that nothing happened.
- Make a routine check.
The worst is when it lasts for a week.
The job is suffering.
And so it has started to bleed from my ears.
- Testing can Jang.
It should help.
- No, I don't like martial arts.
... then I don't do nothing anymore ...
- So you can't do ... - I listen to you!
-I mean it!
--... for you to do nothing!
You can play later.
I have to do nothing ...
THE DOORBELL RINGS
Who could it be?
Hi, I'll check the ventilation.
There has been information about it.
Yes, but now you have to wait a bit here, and then you come in.
Come in!
I can take the rest and come back late ...
Will not be on the question!
You are hungry, who has worked all day.
I just ate.
- Then we should have each grogg ... - we?
No, I'm on duty.
Well.
But you...
I pour it into a jar.
So you can drink it when you're done ...
These are my flowers.
A fern ... and this vase I got from my work buddies -
- When I quit Wissels.
Is not it nice?
He is peeing
-I must go now.
The fans ... - No, you stay!
Have you ever seen such a neighbor?
Look, have you seen such tits?
Hello?
- You have been Key Account Manager ... - Yes, for institutional customers.
Are you the best at private or public customers?
It is difficult.
Public business is often larger to the volume ...
It is about building lasting relationships.
I'm pretty good at that.
This sounds great, I think.
I think our CEO also wants to talk to you.
We set up a time.
It says you have worked as a disc jockey too ...
A friend ran a club - Visage.
- I don't know.
- It was niche against synth music.
So you have worked as a disc jockey at a synth club.
If I say "The Number of the Beast" ...
- It's a hard rock record?
- Yes, with Iron Maiden from 1982.
One of hard rock's most classic albums.
Excuse me, but I wouldn't call it a classic.
Here at the company we do.
Depeche Modes first album from 1981 is a classic.
So you are synthesis?
Yes.
Then unfortunately I have to ask you to go.
Only tatters listen to hard rock.
Synthesis, then?
Four gays and one computer.
What the hell is that?
To stand like this!
Do you want to look at synth dance, then?
Like this!
Stop!
What are you doing?
He is synthesis.
Idiot in sight!
Hello?
... Sure she'll live in a hundred years
Hello!
Hello, Elsa - Britta.
And when she has lived, and when she has lived
And when she has lived in a hundred years
Yes, then she should be shot, yes, then she will be shot
Yes, then she should be pushed on a wheelbarrow forward!
So it's time to come.
Are you new?
- Yes, it's Jan.
- I don't want to know what you are called.
- Yes, I am 85 years old today.
-Oh.
You have to congratulate.
Then we will see what to do.
There has been a small accident in the bedroom.
There is no danger - just a little kiss.
Hang the sheet on the line in the bathroom, so we save on the laundry.
-Okay.
- Yes, we do!
Excuse me to bother this late.
Can I interest you for a machine that improves the indoor environment?
- I don't know ... - I like to demonstrate it for free.
You can say a little jokingly that Nasa in the door can be likened to ...
... anal sex.
You have to nag to get in.
But well inside you will receive an abundant dividend.
God, what it is guilty!
What you are cool, little old man.
Is it nice when I tear in the stump?
What a nice scalp you have.
Last summer, Marianne went, that's my daughter ...
Then she went to Latin America on vacation.
I thought, what should she go there and do?
They probably have their own problems without her.
Don't just stand there!
Sit down, for God's sake.
And then...
Then she comes home here and is completely broken on her face.
She is scaling her nose and her hair is tough.
And so she wears a poncho.
A poncho with fringes and llama ...
Not only that.
Next to her stands a man.
A small, small man.
With a similar poncho with llama and fringes.
And long, black, dark hair.
I thought that, my God, she has adopted a girl from Peru.
But she said, "Mom, this is Carlos. He came with me from Peru."
It is a full grown man standing next to her!
It is not wise.
And a few days afterwards I broke the femur.
So horrible.
I have to hurry, because I will visit many others ...
Oh Lord Jesus, I have to go to the toilet.
- The Laxy Comprehension has started to work.
- But the sheet?
Yes, now you can use your wise brain, young man.
-Is it going well?
-Of course.
Move.
Yuk.
Opp with your arms!
- Paul?
Can't we see you in our spare time?
-Absolutely!
And hang out more privately.
Yes, and drink a beer.
It's so stiff here in the office.
- Can we not set a time?
-Yeah absolutely.
Then we'll see ... I like to drink beer with you when fuck goes on dry land.
It's a little early for me.
I can imagine...
... when pigs fly.
So you mean the day when ordinary pigs have learned to fly?
Otherwise, I have a gap here when hell freezes.
- But never, what do you think about it?
-That's a good idea.
I write: "Never meet Paul in his spare time."
It feels good.
See you never!
God, a sushi sign that burns up ...
Can I have it, Peter?
What is this?
Can you tattoo Robinson - Jesus?
SVT Program Setting: Annika Wiehager
You?
I can not sleep.
Count sheep, then.
I do that all day.