No ...!
Is it true?
Congratulations!
How was it, then?
The first time we did it was the lightning and light.
Absolutely wonderful!
First time with my new guy ...
We were beyond time and space.
There were only us all over the world.
Wonderfully!
The first time with Ulf was a bit like ... coffee on the food.
A smooth cup.
It was at a sausage kiosk in Jönköping.
I ordered a thin bread roll.
I was behind him in the queue.
Maybe you should ask first ...?
Is it ok if I light a joint?
Is it okay to smoke a little?
Grass!
I thought we would play TP.
- Then it is more fun to play TP.
-I do not know...
- It is clear that you should try!
- Yeah, damn!
I remember Roskilde –92.
Someone in the tent next door had a hash.
The smoke came straight into our tent.
We got like crazy!
- Do you remember that, Kristina?
Kristina was completely gone.
We danced naked at the campsite.
- Don't remember that?
-No.
We were not together then, Ulf.
You were in Roskilde with that Annika.
-How is it going?
Do you get the Hulk momentum?
- The hole.
You see nothing.We have to get closer.
These are sensitive types.
Not a sound!
The alarm is howling
There we got a bastard.
Talk to damn lower case.
We sneak in.
Don't stand there and look stupid.
Come now!
A little fluffy music so we get in the right mood?
Put something with him ... what is his name?
Bob Marley!
La - la - la ...
This one is absolutely perfect!
- Do you have to be in Amsterdam?
-Oh God...!
We were in a coffee shop.
- Coffee they don't know what it is.
- So you have tried ...?
No, we never went in.
We turned.
Otherwise, we would have become high as ...
You were another person at that time.
Young and stupid.
What 'damn is this?!
I have been blown.
This is tea, for damn.
This is not grass!
Coffee?
Now we will round off.
We thank Liselott with an applause.
It has been fun to teach the flower language.
Now use the new knowledge.
As a farewell gift you get an Alstroemeria from me.
Does anyone remember what it means in the flower language?
It means "I wish you happiness and prosperity".
Does anyone have a flower to me?
Thanks.
A pimpinella!
- What do you want to say with it?
- I am naked and vulnerable.
Well ... - Jim, do you have a flower for me?
Thank you.
A lemon balm!
Is anyone remembering what it means?
No.
We look in our compendiums.
It means "I want to enjoy your body".
Was that what you wanted to say, Jim?
No.
You just took a flower at random.
I leave you with a poem by Edith Södergran.
I am the last flower of the autumn
I have seen the autumn's star worlds, I have seen light from warm hearths
It is so easy to follow the same path I am the last flower of the autumn ...
Jim is feeling bad.
He ate up a crocus.
- Here we sit and wait for the bus.
-Yes.
It is 08:36.
08:41 it will come.
Then we have a little while together.
You… when you sit with your legs at cross-
- Can not happen that you squeeze "the little" ...
... and the little bag that is under?
–Wa?
- The little bag with the little balls.
They can also be squeezed.
But maybe he is not small, but big?
-What are you talking about?
- It may be big.
- You are sick!
- So you don't talk!
So you don't tell a lady!
Lasse, I know what you are doing!
Who is this blonde Siamese?
Can't you answer, Lasse?!
Should we drink coffee during the meeting -
- Or should we take a break and drink coffee then?
We take the meeting first and the coffee later.
- Should we say so?
-Yes.
Paragraph 1 on the agenda:
Farm cleaning ...
Can't you get a little cup of coffee during the meeting?
I get so hungry!
We have decided to have the meeting first.
I am waiting for after the meeting.
- I have Marianne on my speaker list.
- The resting can have a cup of coffee anyway.
How should we do now?
-I am waiting.
- There are buns and fruits too.
-Okay.
- Be so good, Marianne.
The farm cleaning is neglected ...
May I take a small banana?
We have decided to take the meeting first.
The farm cleaning has been extremely ...
Vilgot may take a banana if he wants to.
Vilgot - a replica on this.
A banana would be good.
Should we decide that Vilgot may take a banana?
Yes!
I record this - that Vilgot takes a banana.
I'm not going to take anymore now.
- Don't you have a cup of coffee?
- No now, Gunnel!
After the meeting.
- Can I continue now, Torsten?
-Yes.
We must decide whether to buy new outdoor furniture and how much they may cost
It's no idea.
No one listens to me.
-I'm listening to you.
- I also listen.
- No, you don't listen!
- See your bun, Vilgot.
Let's return to the meeting now.
- Continue, Marianne.
- Jysk Bäddlager's website has ... –Oj!
Now it is half past eight.
Time runs away.
I explain the meeting ended ... Yes, Marianne?
In any case, we must determine time for a new meeting.
We decide on a new date and then we drink coffee later.
Or should we drink coffee first and make the decision after that?
Nämen Lasse, you must not smoke here!
-Is it true?
-I promise.
Can I order?
CAN I ORDER?
Would you like to adopt?
I do not know.
But ... yes, of course.
If you can't have children, so ...
Would you adopt from Sweden or from another country?
Yes ... I don't know.
God, what a hard time!
But it does not matter.
It's a child you want.
And you?
I would adopt a potter.
–Wa?
- A potter from Österlen.
-What then?
An adult ...?
-Yes.
She is to be called Margareta.
She will make small ceramic bowls with dots on.
-Why?
- I like dots.
But why should you adopt an adult?
- Because I like her.
- But she doesn't exist.
You've only found her.
And you don't adopt adults!
No, but you can dream?
-How is it at work?
-I'm tired of it.
I'm thinking of resigning.
Start your own, move abroad ...
- I want to go to Syria.
- Yeah?
What will you do there?
Flags.
There is a damn potential in flags down there now.
They burn American flags every day.
It goes to a damn mass.
You should move to the Middle East and sell American flags?
Brilliant.
Yes.
But Kristina is so negative.
"There is no public dental care in Syria."
But the last word is not said yet.
Maybe she's afraid to move there?
But what is she afraid of?
Women are a mystery.
- We kick off the conference.
- I thought we would be more.
It just becomes you and I today.
We will look at the results of a fresh survey.
What does our skills profile look like?
I want to say that we have many competent employees.
But you are a disappointment, however, you, Tord.
"Stupid like a log."
What is it?
I asked the following question to all employees:
"Who is the stupid - Tord or a donkey?"
The result is striking.
There is not much to talk about.
- Is this fresh figures?
-Yes.
Now we will change the subject.
We will talk about our indoor environment in the office.
How is the air in the office really?
We had a pretty good air - until you started, Tord.
The air is basically unbearable today.
- It was!
- I would like to push in one thing ...
I brought an information movie with me.
The earth is a wonderful place, where we can live in harmony with nature.
But in order to get there, we have to deal with a problem that can ruin everything
Evil has many faces.
The problem with Paul is growing more and more.
I asked the prime minister what he thinks about Paul.
How would you describe Paul?
Tycoon.
Drive with people, do not listen to others.
Unpleasant.
- Do you find that Paul is cash?
-Maybe a bit.
- Do you find that he is good looking?
-No!
If you compare me to Paul ...
From the most beautiful beautiful to the ugliest ugly.
What are you filming, Tord?
I want us to talk about one thing now.
It is important to me.
Now, now, now!
What should we talk about?
-Do we have to?
-Yes.
You talk better then.
-Hello Hello!
- Don't larger yourself!
- Mid heart has broken.
- Does it feel like that, Barbie?
Why?
You don't love me anymore.
I love you, Barbie.
Oh, what I love you!
Kiss!
Not like that!
I do not believe you.
Why don't you believe me?
What has ...
- Why don't you believe me?
- The front, maybe.
But not anymore.
-In order to?
- The birthday present was so boring!
It was six months ago!
I haven't been able to pick it up before.
I have been ashamed!
I got a pair of long -distance skates!
You said I got to buy what I wanted
- Yes, but not a pair of skates!
–And what did I get when I turned 30?
I got two packages of ice cream boats.
The year before I got a dish brush, the year before a baskets ...
Can't we swim in the swimming pool?
... and the year before I got lunch vouchers.
Before we part, we should lighten the mood a bit.
I have invited a very popular comedian here - Pontus Enhörning!
Are you Tord?
Oh, you were ugly!
And what you smell!
And the mustaches look like laces that have run out of your nose!
Haven't you got fuck yet, Tord?