In tonight's section of Ifs, quiz about all culture in Sweden:
Our Turkish brother from Jordbro, Big O.
Babylon's emerald, Elaf Ali.
Lustigkurren from Uzbekistan: Ato Karlsson.
The Albanian Bus Rings Queen, Laura Ukaj.
Humor legend from Degeberga Petrina Solange.
Landskrona's most famous person after Farah Adabi, Filip Dikmen.
Sweden's most fun Hijab, Kaeli Abdi.
Let half Medina shine: Sami Rekik.
Long as a flagpole, always with Punch Lines in progress, Ahmed Berhan!
Welcome to IFS.
As on the track, although we just go the blue line.
My name is Ahmed Berhan.
Here are our asylum seekers, the contestants:
Frida!
Mikaela!
Today he is orange: Mattias!
The quiz goes for this.
You choose a panelist and decide whether what it says is true or false.
Today we start with no less than you, Mikaela.
- What of the panelists do you start with?
-Oh!
Filip.
Love, Mikaela.
Good choice.
- Filip?
I can't do anything, the man.
- It's called Persian.
–And you ...!
You say parachute jumpers because they appeared from nowhere -
- Set your food ... stingy fucking who has overstayed their Welcome.
They showed up from the sky and robbed our crap.
- So is something bad?
-Aah.
Well, I'm probably saying it's false.
It sounds like something you have to be strong and good at.
It does not rhyme.
You think it's false?
Unfortunately, there will be no point.
-Is it true?
- Why would I lie to you?
It is a phenomenal expression of a spinner.
Chatrbaaz - when you get an unexpected visit.
Persian culture has the thing with "take, take, take!"
But as soon as you go, you are a fucking chatrbaaz.
"He came here, he took everything."
Mattias, you work as a subway informant.
- Traffic informant in the subway.
- People recognize your voice.
- You give bad news.
-Unfortunately.
Rarely anything positive.
Give examples of how it sounds at work.
"Traffic information for traveling on the subway's red line towards Ropsten."
- "We have a delay ..." - you are, the man!
Yah!
Do me a favor.
When you go back to work on Monday-
–As the traffic information you should give:
"Now the inspectors are in Gullmarsplan, Akalla and the Western forest."
"I repeat, the controllers are there ..."
- Is it for your sake?
-It would be appreciated.
- What in the panel are you starting with?
- Then we take Petrina.
You gather outdoors or adjacent to a mosque.
You beat yourself.
Some go very long.
They cut themselves with swords and stuff.
It is so.
It sounds a bit extreme.
-It can not be true.
False.
- You don't believe in Petrina's explanation?
Unfortunately.
There will be no point for you either.
The tradition Ashura takes place once a year.
This is an extreme variant, but it is a real tradition.
- Thanks for your attempt.
- I've seen it live.
- Mom took me to the mosque.
- So everyone hit you.
- Frida, do you bring home the first point?
-Let's hope so.
- Who do you choose to talk to?
–Alaf.
Bleach.
We in Sweden are happy to drive with "brown without sun" - -
–But they put bleach in their skin creams -
- So they get moisturized and white.
Win-win.
Or not.
Elaf really does everything for this citizenship.
Win-win.
- Frida?
I have heard that it is considered nice to be pale in Asia.
You speak the truth.
You know what?
Win-win for you.
Congratulations, you got your first point.
Bleaching creams are a major industry in Asia and other parts of the world.
According to an article from vogue-
- If 2027 comes the white cream industry to be worth around $ 24 billion.
POFF!
So much white cream and not a single white face.
Michael Jackson.
- Mikaela?
-Yes.
Then I drive at Big O.
- Big o?
- Ha, Brakam?
The symbol is found in both the Jewish and the Muslim world.
It's mum's ear files.
No.
No its true.
This means that mom sees you.
Brother, I'm 32 years old.
Still I get ear files from mom.
The eye in the middle means that mom sees you wherever you go.
So sharpen yourself!
The brother, you can sit in Amsterdam in a coffee shop and kickish a fat.
So comes the hand from nowhere and ... Yoop-Schlap!
That it is the mother's eye does not sound reasonable.
Only why it is certainly true.
An eye, it looks like tears ... just the mother's eye?
No no.
- I think you are lying.
- Strange voice: Aha.
- You think Big o is lying to you?
-At least a little bit.
Are you mom?
Your eye is strong.
Congratulations, you got your first point.
Brother ... Sami, show, show!
It was a hand with an eye in the middle.
Muslims call it Fatima's hand.
In Judaism, it is called Miriam's hand.
It symbolizes divine protection against evil and is considered to be lucky.
Ahmed, I've had mom and ear files with me for a while.
-It is here.
- Najs!
- damn.
- Many Muslims who now only: "Haram!"
Congratulations, Mikaela.
- Mattias, should we try to jump into the scoreboard?
- What do you choose?
--Laura.
In the Middle East, Shahahata is an obvious part of childhood.
A baby oil soaked with garlic that you lubricate and out of the kids.
This is done to keep the spirits away from them, protect them from the spirits.
You laugh.
All of us are protected here.
I have not received that protection.
-It shows.
- You looked around before you said it.
- "I'm not protected."
-Alone.
It feels like it could be true.
- You probably wouldn't lie to me.
- The man, she is Alban.
- Broke, don't try!
- I think that's right.
You choose to trust Laura?
Shahahata is a baby oil with garlic odor to protect against ghosts?
- It sounds ... - it's false.
You would have listened to Filip.
I'm Alban, the man.
Shahahata means slipper.
We are honest.
When you get beaten with a slipper - still a good day.
- It's every day.
- There are alternatives.
- Frida?
I say this: Take back the 90's.
Sami.
- Sami, time for a video question.
-It's time.
This is show dance, and what a damn show it was.
I was honored to work with you last week and learned the word "Naknemo".
Dermot had behind the back of anise learned some Arabic words -
- To pay tribute to him in live broadcast, because Anis's father is Arab.
So the word means "dancing angel" in Arabic.
Would he have reacted like that?
I think you lie to me.
His reaction would not have become it, if it meant that.
I think it must have been a little more naughty maybe.
- Naughty?
-Yes.
- So it's false?
-Just.
Congratulations, Frida.
You've got one more point.
Naknemo is Syrian.
Filip, do you want to tell me what that means?
Nakno means "I fuck", emo means "mom".
-Is it true?!
Did he say that on TV?
-Sick!
I can't believe that you record a program and say Naknemo.
Check out the camera and say it again.
- Mikaela?
- I drive on Kaeli.
Yes, Ahmed.
Norwegians.
Epafolket, Raggardunk ...
- Oh, Raggardunk!
- Kaeli, what is the real answer?
Finds actually.
It's Finnish and means "my friend".
"Moi, Moi, Warya!"
- Should I show?
Moi, Moi, Warya.
-Yes.
Moi, moi?
-No.
Warya.
- I might not say it right.
- Moi, Moi means "Hello, Hello".
-Yes it's true.
- You trust Kaeli.
You believe it?
That Warya is Finnish?
It really isn't, Mikaela!
It sounded so.
You first cheated me with Norrland and then Finland.
Warya is Somali and is used when shouting on someone, like "Listen!"
–Warya, Warya!
–Mattias go to work tomorrow:
"Warya, that's problem. Inshallah, Fatima's hand looks at all of us."
"Traffic is back in 5 minutes."
- Mattias, now we drive.
- I welcome Ato in the game.
-Thanks so much.
We know of Gammelsvenskbyn in Ukraine with many Swedish kittens.
Also in Japan there is Sweden Hills.
An ambassador was visiting there.
He commented that it was similar to Sweden.
To pay tribute to him they created a village -
- There they celebrate Swedish traditions such as midsummer and cancerous disc.
It could do Japanese because they are polite -
- But I still don't think they pulled it that far.
- I think you get untrue.
-Okay, Mattias.
Then I know it.
You do not think there is a place called Sweden Hills.
-No.
- You should have done that.
- Unfortunately, that's true.
-I told you.
The first shovel was taken in 1984. It looks like a village in Dalarna -
- And you adopt the Swedish lifestyle.
- You got a reversed full pot.
- Something should get it, in some way.
We will see who wins the round.
- Frida, you have a question left.
As you notice, all panelists are already selected.
This means that your last question and your last panelist will be ...
/Cheer and applause/
It's like when I leave Kastrup.
Always randomly selected.
But now you don't have to undress.
Frida, you can get a full pot if you answer correctly.
-It would be nice.
- Giant.
It would be.
Pertrina?
That's what Ebba Busch screams every time she comes.
Wasn't it a reporter on the evening leaf who pretended to buy a home?
So he asked the broker, "Does there live some Arabs here?"
The broker must have replied: "There are no Arabs, just ..." that quote.
- Have you been looking for a home in Malmö?
-No, I have not done that.
That sounds totally sick, but just because it is certainly true.
You believe in Petrina and have received another point.
You got a full pot.
Malmö is a place where Arabs are included as a variable in the housing search.
- Malmö represented.
- The one who applied for was Elaf actually.
--Wow!
- We have rounded off the first round.
Mattias, unfortunately no final.
Thank you for joining.
A large applause to Frida and Mikaela who have moved on to the final!
Najs.
This round is about coming first to 5 points.
What is different is that if you answer the wrong, the score goes to the opponent.
Frida, you combed home full pot and may inaugurate the final round.
- Who do you choose to shake hands with?
--Ato.
-Yey!
-Hello!
- I said "Ey".
- Do we get like this on TV, right?
Kaeli, do you think you are with the gynecologist?
- It's so uncomfortable down here.
-Oton, time for a video question.
/Whistling cars and shots/
- What did we see in the video?
- An ordinary Monday night in Malmö.
Brother, don't talk shit about Malmö.
That is a regular wedding day.
They celebrate love by shooting some pang-pang.
It's a nice thing.
Apart from the shooting, it sounds extremely-
- I think it seemed to be some kind of celebration.
But shoot?
-Yes.
That's how you show love.
- It sounded like high bangs.
Cute that you call it firecrackers.
It's true.
- Congratulations, Mikaela.
You got a point.
- Frida, I always speak the truth.
It was Eskilstuna in November 2022 when celebrating a wedding.
You shot some shots.
It is difficult to find fireworks in November.
- Mitt and Filip's wedding.
-I'd rather die.
The first time you see someone throwing yourself after the bullets.
- Catch as a goalkeeper.
- Mikaela, congratulations.
- Should we see if you get a point yourself?
-I'll try.
I'll probably take ...
- Petrina.
- Petrina?
The king was criticized for what he said about the throne when Victoria will take over.
Another classic royagoof is:
Because he can't read.
He just turns leaves all the time.
He is looking for the pictures.
It was well that he was criticized -
- For he praised the dictator in Brunei for his fine relationship with the people.
Then the people felt: "He is a dictator, we have no nice relationship."
Mikaela, what do you say?
I know he apologized for what he said about Brunei.
But this was about a slant as it is said that he may have done.
- Oh, what diplomatically expressed.
- I got careful here.
I say it's false.
You do that right in. Congratulations, you've got one more point!
A gear.
Brunei was one of the king's bloopers.
Here, questions were made about the king and his friends' sexy party habits.
- Frida?
- I choose Laura.
A picture of Albanian Airlines and that is our flight attendant.
Okay.
It is a traditional attire that is used for weddings.
But you can only have it when you are married.
That was difficult.
It is very nice, but you can only have it when you are married ...?
-Sure, why not?
It's true.
- You believe in Laura?
-Point!
-Thanks.
What Laura said is true.
The suit can be seen at Albanian weddings.
It is called Dimija or Dallama.
Only married women are allowed to carry it.
I want to go to an Albanian wedding where people dress like Power Rangers.
Is it common?
If you go to every Albanian wedding, do you see that suit?
Very popular 2023. But if you see me in such a ...
First I die before I wear it.
I thought Albanian wedding suit was Adidas three lines.
- We do that after work, the man.
–SHOTS FIRED!
Mikaela, your turn to shine.
- Then I take Filip.
- Hello, Darling!
Have you missed me?
Filip?
They promised to open an old, classic nightclub in Sundbyberg.
A local club, previously closed.
They promised to open it with the guarantee that it was run under ethnic Swedish.
It sounds crazy, but now I will think of a club that lay there.
–And that ... —Mannen, you have lived.
It can be so sick that they go out and say something like that.
- Did you have fun at that club?
- I don't even remember what it's called.
- Garbo?
-Exactly!
–Ahmed has also been there.
- We don't have to talk about it.
- Do you believe to believe ...?
- We might be there at the same time.
- We might be ... - a printer!
- Hed is married.
- You choose to believe in Filip?
- Unfortunately, there will be no points for you.
-Lucky.
Im happy for that.
- It was so sick.
- Congratulations, Frida.
You got a point.
SD works specifically, but they did not want to open a club.
They wanted to demolish the new bridge between the marsh and Rinkeby.
!
- Frida?
- What do you choose?
- I choose Big O.
October 2022, a school was reported in Upplands Väsby.
The students were not allowed to smoke Äzi in the classroom.
The name, it was a teacher who during a geography lesson -
- Said that Kurdistan does not exist.
I also want yeah shono, but ...
The students forward it to their pears.
Then it became Chorba outside the school.
Chorba, soup, yes.
- She will have a hard time with that.
- Does that let go of reasonable?
- Yes, strangely enough.
- Frida does not admit Kurdistan.
Unfortunately, it's false.
The point goes to Mikaela.
The school saved by moving students to a barracks.
As by chance, the newly arrived students happened to end up there.
By chance.
- Mikaela?
-Yes.
Then I drive on Sami.
Sami?
The 1994 World Cup evokes happy memories of many Swedes.
They had to be 1.40 to enter the arena.
No, joking aside.
Chile was ported.
During a World Cup qualifier against Brazil, the Chilean goalkeeper-
- To get the victory.
He cotted himself in the face with a razor blade -
- And blamed the Brazilian audience who thrown fireworks.
- It sounds really sick.
-That is sick.
He may not have brought a razor blade on the football field.
Roberto Rojas was called the goalkeeper.
-89, I think it was.
-It was -94.
-Exactly.
He is lying.
- I try to fool you a little more.
- You think he is lying?
Then I can only say: Congratulations, Frida.
You've got one more point.
- He is doing so well.
- It's sick, but true.
Chile's national team was banned from the World Cup after goalkeeper Rojas fake -
–That he was damaged by fireworks -
- By cutting yourself with a razor blade on the face.
-Oh my God.
-What to say?
3–3.
Frida, you have a chance to take over.
Who do you choose to trust?
- Kaeli.
-Yes.
My mother's disappointment over my life.
I said "comedian", she said "what?"
The name, the knife in the heart is a suburban musical.
The knife in the heart.
Knit?!
It's not even SFI.
These are immigrants for Swedes.
Let me be.
- The knife in the heart was the first ... man!
The knife!
A KNIFE.
Knife-en.
Repeat after me!
I have dropped out of school, as you notice.
One more time.
The knife!
Yeah!
- You made SFI happy and satisfied, the old man.
- I am so happy now.
The knife in the heart is the first suburban musical on SVT.
For you blats who do not know what a musical is: a high school music.
She just explained Musical with musical.
What are you saying?
Do you think the knife in the heart is a suburban musical?
It could be.
But no...
-What are you saying?
True or false?
- It's false.
We chance.
You chance that it's fake?
The point goes to Mikaela.
The TV series from 2003 is about young people in the Gothenburg suburb of Bergsjön.
The first suburban musical.
And thank goodness, the last one too.
Mikaela, I just want to remind you.
If you answer correctly now, you have won everything.
- It would be totally ... - we cheer on you.
- You can only choose one panelist.
–Alaf.
-Yes, Ahmed.
- A picture question.
The man in the picture came to Sweden as a 20-year-old, as a refugee-
–And started as a berry picker and square seller.
Today he owns Åhléns.
It would be wonderful.
Perhaps.
Owning Åhléns would be fun for him.
Nämen, yes.
Yes!
It's true.
The man started as a carrier and now he owns the whole Åhléns.
Yes.
You did that right in. Congratulations, Mikaela!
Ayad al-Saffar was born in Lebanon by Iraqi parents-
- And came to Sweden as a refugee in 1984.
He started as a berry picker and street salesman.
In 2022 he bought Åhléns.
But we should not talk about him but about you, Mikaela.
Congratulations!
Frida, thank you for competing.
- Come here, Mikaela.
You didn't believe it, but Fatima's eye was with you all the way.
Mom's eye sees you.
You have received your diploma.
Congratulations!
-Thank you very much.
- A big applause to the winner.
The contestants, our fantastic panel, our wonderful audience -
- And all of you at home.
Thank you for looking.
Thanks!
So fine.
Texting: Cristel Nyqvist Swedish Media Text for SVT