Art...
... or weirdness?
Sweden's art history is part of the huge story of our country.
We will with some impacts show art-
- As depicts changes and creation power.
We are in northern Skåne, in Loshult's parish on the border with Småland.
I think it's best to go through.
When the railway connecting Sweden was built over 100 years ago -
- Stone was taken away.
One day, the builders made a remarkable find.
Yes, there ...
Probably it is this, because there are wedged stones here.
There are several who are wedged.
It can be imagined, because here is a hole that they dug out.
It was a Bronze Age find -
- A largest in the country that has been found in one place.
Neck rings, and I can't remember everything.
And so what they call Loshultsmannen.
Two such, yes.
The Loshultsman is really two old men in a hat.
And are there swimwear they wear?
They are a bit naive in their production method, but they are expressive.
You also see the powerful calves, which go back on the rock carvings.
They have had arms - you have holes after your arms.
They have probably had hands that have worn something.
There is a high likelihood that they have had each cult ax -
- Culture as the cult axes found in the find.
The findings from Loshult are not only made up of the bronze men.
Here are belt plates and shaft hole axes -
- With decor found in southern Europe at this time.
Here is a neck collar, which the women have had around their necks -
-In the 1400s before Christ.
Again, it's the fantastic spiral deck -
- With connected spirals that run along the entire side.
The spirals are something that probably lives in our lice buns today.
The Bronze Age is a time of increasing trade relations and new knowledge.
The alloy of copper and tin - bronze - has a low melting point -
- And can be formed into gear, weapons and ornaments.
Now the image motifs are given three -dimensional form.
They wear hats with the board.
On both sides of the boards there are small holes, probably where horns have been sitting.
It is also a god symbol in almost all of Europe.
If you have horns, you are some kind of religious leader or chief.
It is a mixture of crafts, art and religious symbols.
Probably the old men have stood on a small altar -
- Or at season cult, funerals or other life stages you celebrated.
Yes, a remarkable find.
One of Sweden's largest, that is.
But was it really the builders at the railway who found the objects?
The land belonged to the potato farmer Mercury-Viktor Svensson.
An old reputation was ...
... that Viktor Svensson found the find two years earlier and hid them there.
But we have no evidence of what it is.
But it is written that it is not the right finding place ...
... where they found this.
It has not been there at all times, but it has been added there and hidden there.
Texting: David Hallerby Sveriges Television AB 2023