Hello!
Well, so now the moving class goes again.
We were going to get away in a few hours, so I pack a little.
- We have a small farewell gift.
-To me?
You look nice!
Thanks!
- It's my old piss spot ... - it's a vase, a nice old vase.
-Is not it nice?
- It's super nice ...
I'll fix the best place of honor for it!
Think of us when you see it.
We should not be long -winded - we just wanted to say hello then.
Hello then, Leif!
Oh!
Bye.
Billy!
But we hear, we have each other's phone numbers.
Yes.
Release now, Billy.
It is enough.
- We will miss you, Elin.
- I will miss you too.
-Drive carefully.
-I will.
- Hi, Elin.
-Bye.
"Entered property. Kronofogden."
What the hell ... - Move you!
- Kronofogden, that's Annika.
- Leif from Sörbäcken here.
Someone has put a sign on our farm!
We have tried to get in touch with you for a very long time!
You have a debt of SEK 454,000, so now we make foreclosures of the property.
Unfortunately, if you do not pay as soon as possible, the house is not yours anymore.
Cursed!
Now they are going to take the kitchen off us.
Come.
- Cursed fucking parasite ...
If we sell the living room furniture and the kitchen table we have SEK 1,400.
But if we ... if we sell my clothes too, then?
No.
You can't walk around naked.
And we have consumed SMS loans.
Damn!
If we sell all stuffed animals then maybe it goes.
- We will probably find something else.
- But what should we do?
-What can I do for you?
- We thought to hear a thing with you.
Mm.
What, Leif?
Is it possible to get raised a-cash-
- Or maybe even get it in a lump sum?
Can you get it paid prematurely for six years?
- Then we promise we will fix a job.
- No, it doesn't work that way.
No!
It will never happen.
What is happening here, then?
He has hardly had any feeling from his chest and down since he was little.
Last fall, he got scabies in a wound on the leg -
- And became paralyzed.
We would need an insurance mantle of half a million approximately.
Paralyzed?
Oh, Satan!
He is not paralyzed.
You are open to five.
It is only two o'clock!
Barring bastard ...
What else can I do?
I have checked banks, SMS loans and debt restructuring ...
- Is the coffee ready soon?
-Yes.
Where should we go now, then?
I do not know!
Sometimes life takes unimaginable turns.
We must live in the forest ...
It smells burnt.
Turn off the plate!
-What have you brought?
- I was inherited by old grandmother.
-In the forest?
We can't give up ... - silent.
... and only three are in Europe.
It is a ming-vase from the Qing Dynasty.
What the hell!
It's my piss spit.
Decor in underglaze blue and weapon for the family grill.
Fantastic fun to see something like this!
You may be wondering what the value is.
At the right auction, it would go for between SEK 400,000 and SEK 500,000.
Oh my God!
Lord Satan!
Oh my God...
Jesus ... if you have heard my prayers - thank you!
God, Buddha, Muhammad ... everyone.
You've heard my prayers!
My parents' home is saved.
Thanks!
- But we have given it to Elin.
-Damn.
Hi Elin.
It's Leif.
Have you left?
How far?
Two miles?
Stay there.
We have to talk about a thing.
Stop the car and we will.
Five minutes.
Good.
Hello.
Hell ... Half a million for a Piss Pot!
This is just a copy.
It is valuable, but an original is worth almost two million.
Hi Elin.
-What is it?
- We gave you the wrong gift.
- The vase?
-Just.
So we'll take it back.
Leif, you can't give a gift to someone and then take it back!
- We have another.
Where is the vase?
-Are you nuts?
It's my vase!
Get the vase here!
Billy soon breaks down.
The vase was mom's, and then you should move.
He can't handle it.
I get the vase here!
He soon gets a nervous breakdown.
Yes...
- It's a nice fucking vase.
-Gently!
My God ... - here.
- Here is your new gift.
- Take this one instead.
Here, Elin.
Sorry.
We will miss you.
Oh, there were no bad stuff.
What details and what shine!
Where have you found this?
- It has been under my bed ... —Sist!
- It has gone for generations.
I think my dad turned ... or bought it in Borlänge.
Will there be any business?
We thought about half a million.
500,000?
- We can go down to 450 ... - no, I'll take it for 500!
Do you?
Yes, then we have done a deal.
What fun to do business with you!
-Thanks.
- Stand still, I get the money.
-What is this?
- The whole our debt, every sausage.
Now you have to stop the witch hunt that you have conducted.
So bring out the paper on the kitchen.
Okay ... then you can write on here, then.
- Do you let us be late?
- If you continue to be debt free, yes.
Good.
- So there, then.
Then we can go home again.
- You heard, the Crown Magistrate.
Our home!
Our home.
Right.
- We managed it, Billy.
-Yes we did.
We are the best!
An antique dealer in Sörbyn today made the biggest chop of his life.
He has come across a ming-vase valued at SEK 2.1 million.
But what the hell!
He cheated us on the pot devil!
Yes, he may have cheated us on the pot.
But it's not time to be greedy.
We still have the house, and we have each other.
That's the main thing.
You are right in that, the big brother.
Our home - yours and mine.
What the hell is it smelling?
It smells like gas!
Damn!
I forgot to turn off the gas stove.
What the hell ... Cursed!
Damn.
Sorry...
- Curse, Billy!
- Conduct, Leif!
That was not the point.
SWEDISH SUPPORT: Dan Olsson (C) Sveriges Television AB 2017