Here is the track.
God, I get a pulse from this.
It's stressful.
There is no clover game anyway.
It's one with paws.
Now I'm in Härjedalen, in Nysätern.
Here we will both look for a bear, and cook bear.
Now we will release the cows.
- Good morning!
Good morning, rubber.
These are our mountain cows, mountainous, which are created to walk on the mountains.
- I thought they would storm out.
- Come then, Svensson.
Come, the old man.
Here at Sonfjället's foot, Marika and the man Pekka run a livestock year -round.
They make cheese butter and brass butter of the cows milk
And all the animals go loose and live in harmony with nature.
But the bear does not look here because there are kisses?
No, he goes around.
We look at the horses and dogs that he goes around here.
The horses stand here and froze and want to here and seek shelter
Because they don't like the smell of the bear.
Yes, it's about Björn.
Marika takes me out onto the mountain to look for the mighty animal.
Maybe we also find something to use for cooking later.
For the first time, I will cook a dish with bear meat as a base.
Now we will look again a Björnide that will be up here.
-An old?
- Yes, an old bear idea.
Here was certainly the entrance, and this is how the hole was in.
So all in there they lay.
Wow!
Imagine that there has been a bear with two bear cubs in here.
It's powerful.
I have found some juniper we can have for the bear later.
- Oh, check out here.
--Wow!
- In the first chanterelle place at home.
-Is that so?
How fun.
- This was almost better than Björn.
-Yes of course.
Here is the track ... of something with paws, which have pressed the grass forward.
Yes, there you see something big.
God, I get a pulse from this.
It's stressful.
There is no clover game anyway.
It's one with paws ...
... that has gone up.
Closer to Björn than that we never came, despite thoughtful scouting.
Time to give up and go into the kitchen to cook dinner.
Soon 14 hungry locals will come and then the food will be ready.
I am a novice with a bear, but you have probably eaten a bear since you were little.
Type grown up with breakfast, lunch, dinner - bear.
No sorry.
I have to punch holes that myth.
Then this will be even more exciting.
I'm super peppy.
I have with me the chanterelles and juniper from the forest
And I was going to use both the rice and the berries.
I will make some form of pot -fried bear with root celery and onion
And bake some lovely lace bowl with chanterelle butter.
- Now we will eat bear every week.
-I hope so.
It'll be fun.
We drive pretty rustic, I think.
Then we put on the lid.
Here we have the bear pot.
Now it has been breaking up for five hours in the oven with some red wine.
It is root celery, a little onion and so this fired single branch
To get a little more depth and smoked tone on it.
You are embarrassed to taste.
- Do you want to taste some of the bear?
-Yes!
- How good?
-Bullseye.
God so tasty.
Is this dessert?
We want to hear more about it.
I am building a bear idea.
Now I have made a bed on spruce.
It is spruce syrup, digestive and sliced butter.
Then I have made a crowberry and blueberry mousse.
Then we will put on some snow.
Then we have some lingonberries and crows.
- We believe that.
- This will be a success, I think.
Welcome, welcome!
This is like a baptism of fire for me, I have never cooked Björn before.
But I gave myself on a safe card, a pot -fried bear roast.
It gets musty and very taste - like Härjedalen in a small box.
-It sounds good!
- Yes, delicious.
- It was delicious.
- Yes, really good.
- Yes, it smells so good.
- I take it, me.
It actually got really good.
Surprisingly good, I think.
- Yes, Fyfan.
You did well.
-How fun.
You are welcome.