I have the jacket full of broth.
Want to see my broth now?
It's broth everything.
In that book you can learn how to navigate your inner countryscape.
You can have a dedicated copy, if you like.
I do it special for you.
It would have come yesterday.
Oops...
- Should I throw it there?
- We must try ... Absolutely.
No, this should not happen.
Absolutely.
Sure.
I have the whole order here in front of me.
In the computer, but ...
What had you ordered?
It's a bit sad.
They have put me on a project with Tord now.
No, I should not say idiot.
But he's a little after ...
He is sluggish in some way, and as I said ... he does not smell roses.
If you think you have had garbage standing in the apartment ...
Yes!
Old milk that has been in the sun and buzzed - just so Tord smells.
But you have to fight.
It is good.
Thanks.
Hello.
Okay, Tord ... where were we?
God, what he is looking.
He thinks I'm a photo model.
Everyone thinks I'm a photo model.
"Hello! Okay, I look like a photo model, but I'm not."
Cranky, right?
It's the same thing.
Real models do not look like models privately.
They just look like photo models when they have a lot of makeup, but I then ...
I swear, I have no makeup at all.
I still look like a photo model.
But you ... you couldn't work as a photo model ...
If you look at my neck - it's long and slim.
But your neck ...
It is more compact.
- Yeah, though I haven't thought ... - did you know what?
I gotta go.
I'll meet Natalie.
Take, da.
La, La!
-Damn!
This job, then ... - what?
I think you feel so exposed.
Home - Sweet Home.
- Do you have a home computer?
- Yes, I have a computer.
Have you connected it to this worldwide intranet?
- Interior, yes.
- Of course it's fantastic ...
I'm going to New York.
I sent an electric letter to the travel agency:
"Hello. I want to travel every now and then."
So it was clear.
- Giant practical.
-Certainly.
This with data is getting big!
You can put everything possible on data.
Pen and paper are soon passé.
Computerization has been going on for a long time now ...
- You have also joined the internet?
-Joined?
I email and so ...
After all, we can start sending electric mail to each other.
You can send message on the mobile phone as well.
- A voice message?
- No, text ... do you have a mobile phone?
I am writing to you - a little message ...
- Is that morse alphabet?
- No, it's usual text.
"Hello!"
Now I send it, and you can read it on your mobile.
Where do you mean I can see this now?
- You may have a slightly newer model.
- It goes so fast now with everything.
Can you be a little quieter!
There are those who have a ten -point stent tomorrow.
- Do you think this is a microphone?
-No.
Why are you talking in it, then?
Hello!
God how fun!
-Welcome.
-Thanks.
Now we will stay here together!
-Yes finally.
- It's a third, huh?
- No, it's a second.
-Okay.
I thought it was a third.
- You thought so.
- The most important thing is that we live together.
Yes indeed.
Well, you have it like this ... you like to have it like this ... plot rich.
Well, I do.
Yes, think ... The taste is like the butt - split!
- But you, Lotta ... - Linda.
God, sorry!
I'm so stupid.
Wind.
Pax for this room.
I already live here.
I have done really well for you in the living room.
No, I'm going to live here.
But, God ... Oh, Fy!
Shit, what a disgusting aunt!
She has no hair.
I'll remove it.
No, it's my mom.
She died of cancer last year.
Ugh then.
But you ... in that case it is well on time that you forget her.
- Yes, that's it.
- Gum!
- Ta, then ... –la, la!
I also think you should have equal pay.
It's not that...
Still, I think men should be men.
I don't want to come home and find my guy who beds or something.
We are different in nature.
We are.
But that doesn't stop me from driving a car for example.
I have never been to New York.
I'm going to go up in the Statue of Liberty, the World Trade Center and ...
After all, the World Trade Center has collapsed.
Huh?
What the hell are you saying?
- The tower have collapsed!
-Yes.
Do not you know that?
What in ... How did it go?
Some terrorists flew straight into the towers.
Is it true?!
How the hell can I have missed it?
- Yes, it's a bit strange.
- Her god, it's a great thing.
That they don't take it up in the media!
It can have consequences for ...
- It has been quite a lot of talk.
- But I look at the news ...
But you are a little drowsy forward nine.
I must have nodded ... I still think I'm hanging out.
- What should we do this weekend?
–Wa?
I was going to go a round golf ...
I asked for help with the summer tires and then you were so stiff in the back ...
But now it's better, actually ...
Great - Stina sat on Gärsgårn and the rods came and look '
Big - Stina got pissed and screamed: Have you never seen a yard?
Hello!
-Hello.
- Don't you see it's an overall party?
So we eventually lean ... Don't extinguish!
-Bowl!
- bowl on you, Per - Arne!
You had mixed it well, Carita.
Do you think?
I think it tastes a bit strange.
Do you think so?
Yes, when you say so, so ...
- But isn't it more like an odor?
-Yes it is.
But what in the name of the Lord is what smells?
Carita, you know what I'm sitting here thinking about ...
I wonder how long since it was we really managed hygiene?
This is what is allowed to stand back when there is a lot with other things.
It is as true as it is said.
One cannot catch everything in the world
I mean it.
Yes...
Why has Astrid Lindgren not received the Nobel Prize ...
As much as she has done for all children!
Who had I been today-
- If I didn't fall asleep to Emil, Alfons, Pippi and all the fairy tale characters?
This customer meeting we would arrange ...
Can't we keep it a little easy?
We go out to the Japanese SPA: ET–
–And we have a meeting during the day and party in the evening ...
The problem with that proposal, Tord, is that it is ... bad.
- Giant!
-Okay.
We do this instead: Review in the office, we go to the theater ...
... and then we end with a good dinner out in town.
Wait a little, I'll just make a note.
-Today's date?
- The 24th.
"Dear Diary! Today I heard the stupid suggestion I ever heard!"
"Colleague Paul, as I mentioned before, surpassed himself in stupidity."
"Good God, give me the power to stand out with his stupidity and his bad smell"
Sorry, where were we?
-How is it?
You seem a little low.
- Robban's mother was visiting.
She has a fucking need for control!
I do not decide in my own apartment.
-I'm going crazy!
What should I do?
- Such there is hard.
There is a plant called Spik -Club.
Take 100-125 seeds from it.
You cook a strong chili, and put on plates in the kitchen.
You sprinkle in the seeds in her plate and black pepper on the others.
Then she dies guaranteed.
Much safer than putting someone performing a staircase ...
Or you can just try to explain to her what you feel ...
I have a fox in a box.
How would you say human being get happy?
You have to find your inner Landscape and Learn How To Navigate It.
Then you will be able to experience positive energy and also spread it.
Because Happiness is in the Universe.
You are the universe.
I'm just a little tired and weird.
"Universe" ...
Time flies!
Next month we celebrate a wooden wedding.
- How much is a wooden wedding?
- Five wonderful years.
We are in our seventh now.
What is it called?
Ash...
Dung!
No, it's been great years.
There you have something to look forward to.
- You have just met.
- Sex months.
- It only gets better over the years.
- The relationship deepens.
You get to know each other ... as you didn't do in the beginning ...
You get very close to each other.
- More bread?
-It is good.
More bread?
Hello...
This community is very important in the relationship.
I usually say that ...
Kristina and I are not just married.
She is one of my better friends.
A relationship becomes what we do.
We have to take the time for each other.
- Dare to be a little spontaneous ... - and not plan to death everyday life.
Maybe take time off for some weekend, leave the kids, go to some spa or so ...
Just a flower or a friendly word means a lot.
It must not be a slentrian.
It is true that when you have ... it is easy to take someone for granted ...
... when you have seen a person every day for decades ...
That we dare to be spontaneous ...
As I usually say "we keep the flame alive" ...
Curiosity is the best spice.
Do you only have that spark ... then the whole relationship matures, huh?
- Lite as a nice wine ... - or an old cheese.
- Yeah ... - yeah ... yeah!
OH!
-Coffee?
- Yes, it wouldn't have been so stupid.
- Now it is enough ... My eczema is burning.
- Now you are clean and smell good.
Then it's your turn, Carita.
No, it's expensive drops, this.
I've been thinking about one thing, Per -Arne.
Why is there so much evil?
Yes, say that ...
When a man lives in exclusion ...
... beyond all glory and fairness, dirty and dan ...
- Then she becomes an evil person.
- So you mean I'm evil?
–Wa?
No.
I thought of Hitler.
- Well, the ...
Yes, this is what it looks like.
Nice neighbors are too.
I usually sleep here, but you can sleep wherever you want.
-I will take it.
-Nice.
Talk to lower case letters about this.
I must not rent out in the second place.
-Obvious!
-You understand...
Good good.
You can take the macaroni.
See you the day after tomorrow.
The keys.
Hello!
Oh!
Cozy ...
I don't think we can be together anymore.
Do you want to break up?
Why?
Frida, I've worked too much.
It has not been so good lately.
- You must be able to talk about it.
- It's not about it.
- Have you met someone else?
-No!
What is it then?
Magnus, you have too little penis.
- Do you end up for my penis?
- Yes, I tried.
It does not work.
You said the size has no significance ... Is it too short, right?
Partly that, and so it is too narrow.
- Helt absurd!
What is it really?
- You have too little penis.
There is nothing wrong with my penis.
I have a completely normal, Swedish penis.
Magnus, your penis is three centimeters in erected state!
Excuse me ... that's not true.
You know that.
- We have measured it!
-Yes.
It was probably four centimeters.
-Often!
- Okay, but it's still small.
- Many people have less than that.
- It would be a squirrel then.
Okay.
It may be a little smaller than the average, but ...
This with penis enlargement ... if I work overtime and sell the car -
- So maybe I can afford to go to the US and operate myself.
Do you want that?
-What do you want?
- If you want to, I do.
Do you really want to do it for me?
- How long will it be?
- It gets eight to nine centimeters.
-I love you.
-I love you too.
Yes.
Paul ...
This is your conscience that speaks.
You talk too much.
You do away with it.
Your wife thinks you're embarrassing ...
- Yes, this is what it looks like.
-It is really pretty.
Big and nice.
Here I sleep, but you don't have to.
- This is what are we taking it?
-Absolutely!
But be very tense ... It is not on the inner list to rent out in the third place.
- Of course ... it was eight, huh?
-Yes.
-So.
- And so the keys.
Then we will see you tonight.
Bye.
--Wow, that's huge.
- Here we can take place both.
SVT Program texting: Lisbet Olofsdotter - Arvidsson
Stop buying those hip -hop discs that you still don't like.
- You don't get cool anyway.
-No...