You, I can't get in today.
I'm on my way to Dalarna.
I'll pick up a lamp.
And then Dad turns 70, so I go up to not have to hear the nagging om-
-"That I never come up, not even on Father's Birthday."
Party, are you crazy?
In my family you only eat cake. "Cake, cake, cake."
Hello!
I told Father that I heard the car, but he didn't hear any car.
Hello, mother.
-Have you changed car?
-Yes, it's probably six months ago.
-Gruits, father.
-Thanks.
-What can this be?
-You have to open and see.
-How could it drive?
-Good.
I'm just a little tired.
We celebrated my promotion yesterday.
-But it was the worst!
- Did you hear, father?
-Yes.
-Do you not triggered?
-I should remain on Ericsson.
But instead of programming, I should become something called a system architect.
That's really good.
Much better salary.
In Bali, there I drank coconut.
Can you understand?
They pick them directly from the trees.
The men climbing 'the very highest up-
-And they threw down the nuts.
It was fantastic?
Nämen Margot, now you have to open your mouth!
Father mine is celebrating years, so I was hoping to get away in time.
You and I usually help each other, right?
Now you make me happy!
Right?
Imagine how happy I was now!
Now she has finally found home!
My little little sister!
Hi, Ida!
How big you have become!
-So you look!
Are you going to a funeral?
-Thanks for that...!
I don't understand that black fashion.
No one will be happier about it?
Now you still stay for a few days, so we get raw about you?
I have to go tomorrow.
Do we have to talk about when to go?
Is it fun just that I'm here?
Why don't you take a few days off?
Damn, let's do huh!
-Do you follow down on society?
-I haven't been able to eat yet.
You know, it's a children's party in the village cottage, so we will not come in until one.
-What will we do there?
-Duka to the party.
Ida!
Don't you play that song?
- We lay stomach aid the whole family.
So Ida has done a song ... - Ida, tell Grandpa what it's called!
"Stomachflu".
I haven't heard anything about any party.
No, it's a surprise party.
- Father, you haven't heard anything?
Ida!
Play now!
-Gunilla.
-Where fuck are you somewhere?
I'm just trying to get some file before going with the bus.
- Health!
Mm.
Bye.
I don't understand what Gunilla would to Falun and do.
She sits in a little second.
Tommy helped to put up shelves.
Her children did not have time.
He said the kitchen was so small that you could barely turn to.
You had to back out of Dass.
What are you going to do with such a nice car, you who live in town?
A guy car!
-Ericsson had a collaboration with ... -There is Ingvar!
-If!
Where are you going?
Tracking an injured moose.
There is some fucking skull that has put two shots in the ass on.
You learn to go there and clean up after the boys ...
-It wasn't the day before you saw you.
-Mor is so happy - the little girl at home!
If you are really kind to uncle-
-Im I make sure you get a couple of bags of moose meat to Tjockholm.
Mine he works Å. - Fucking idiot.
-Af.
Do you know where the flower shop is located?
See you at Hemköp in 30 minutes then.
Hello on you, Olle.
-Isn't it Mia?
-Yes.
-I am Eva's sister.
Eva in your class.
-Yes!
-Yes ... What about Eva, then?
-Good.
She got twins this spring.
She has four children now.
And you?
Have you got anything small?
-No.
I work so much.
And so I don't live with anyone.
So you can do too.
Thank you.
- I am in a little hurry, because we should have a party for father.
-Yes, I heard it!
-Yes ... Yes, greet Eva, then!
-Yes, have a good time now.
-Yes, you too.
It took 30 minutes.
The others had been hunting for several hours.
But I couldn't get there until I saw behind the barn.
So I shot, and then I went.
-Do you have coffee?
-Yes please.
I meet 'Eivor and Mia.
-What did you like about the car hers?
-Uj uj uj, it has to go well for'na.
-And condominium she bought Å. -A, FY FAN!
It costs gold money.
Shouldn't you show the gift card?
-Where do you have Kerstin, then?
-She well strokes the fine costume.
Surely that is what you have in love with?
Oh, fuck!
-Then the V -75 was finished ... -check there!
Isn't that Mia Sundin?
Mia!
Do you pick up Gunilla at the station, then Ida and I go with Tommy?
But, but, but, but, but!
Oh, what a long time ago!
How long ago is it I got to hug you properly?
-How is the job?
And the new apartment?
-Good good.
But oh, oh, oh, how good you are!
-You look like a TV personality!
-Mia!
-Do you pick up Gunilla at the station?
-Yes.
Look who I find '!
My favorite girl.
- Hurry to Gunilla now.
-So how are you doing?
-With me?
Great!
You, nice hat!
But for the hell, the mother.
You have to go to Bali sometime!
It was absolutely wonderful!
Such an incredible experience.
I was going to go there when we were in Malaysia, but we stay 'in Singapore.
I've never been abroad.
Me and Håkan never went anymore than Norway.
Now I feel that such a sun trip you want to do every year.
Right?
Yes.
Then you have to be happier.
-What's going to happen for shit today?
-Mäh!
Surely it is so?
After all, some shit has always happened on Kalle's birthday.
-It's ten years ago today.
-Don't talk about it.
-Why not?
He is dead.
-Barbro doesn't like it.
-When Tommy cut his hand?
Last year?
-No, it was two years ago?
Last year Ida got an allergy shock.
Yes, what she shift 'color!
From red to blue in 30 seconds.
Arvid knew what he was doing when he shot himself on Kalle's birthday.
Otherwise, no one would have remembered his day of death.
But imagine what happy Kalle and Anna will be when they have brought home Mia.
I was at the grave.
-I ids don't go there, me.
-Morsan, it's ten years ago.
Too bad about.
It was a pity if.
He didn't belong here.
-Hello!
-How did it go?
-Good.
Hello all happy!
Don't look, then!
Congratulations, father!
Flowers from Bali.
Can you understand?
A little girl, no more than six years, sold them on the street.
And fool 'tourists to buy the shit!
Yes, it's Mia.
Well!
Gunilla, do you want coffee?
Yes ... but you, they are in my computer.
No, you don't need a password.
Mm.
No, there is no danger.
Just call if there is anything.
Well.
You sound like a Stockholm fuck!
-Yes, I happen to live there.
-But you happen to be born here.
Therefore, is it a bit strange that you suddenly speak some Marsian?
Try to be taken seriously when you give a presentation on a dialect-
-What makes people think they should play the prisoners at the fort!
Then it is better with the Marsian - then they think they should go on a space trip!
Have you seen any celebrities in Tjockholm, then?
Yes, I saw Gunde Svan at NK.
He try 'hats.
Oh, fuck!
But I just have fun with you!
-Where are you going, then?
-To barn and pick up some stuff.
But can't you sit down a bit?
Father and I have something to tell.
Yes, we thought ... Father and I, we talk 'this morning.
If you want the plot down by the lake you get it.
Yes, you can build something!
It doesn't have to be anything big, just a summer cottage.
Just so you can have something your own when you get up.
-If!
-You don't have to decide now.
-What people it was here, then!
-Mia has got the plot by the lake.
Yes, Mia.
Take the plot you and sell it to the highest bidder.
There are many speculators, you see.
Or what do you say, Eivor?
-Where are you going, then?
-I go out in the barn.
Well, now it became quiet.
But was there any coffee, then?
Huh?
Helena, tie the shoes!
Johan, do you help Ida with the drink?
It gets too heavy for '.
Go before you.
I'll come later.
I want to be 'myself.
What are you doing here?
I thought I'd wait for you.
I want to be 'myself.
Eivor?
You can only tell you what it is.
Mia has got the plot down by the lake.
You...
Open now.
-We don't need any empty.
-It's about our girls.
Helena would have had it!
It is so typical that they give it to mia-
-She who didn't even want to have it.
Eivor ...
Surely it would be fun if Mia wanted to build something?
Then she comes a little more often.
You are as much help as usual!
Will you come, then?
Surely the others shouldn't have to do everything?
There is Eivor's girls!
-Dina, then?
When are they coming?
-Lasse is on course.
Victoria is coming.
She sleeps with Håkan, she has said.
You know, they are disappointed at me-
-To I split 'the family.
But it will probably be good.
After all, I haven't asked how you feel!
It has happened so much.
I never thought my life would be like this.
-Do you have any contact with Håkan?
-"Menopics" he calls me.
But that's what you are, right?
-You seem to feel great.
-Do you think?
No, do you think so?
-Hello!
-Gunilla, what good!
Come and take hold!
-Hello!
How's it going?
-Good!
I've made potato salad.
Hi Aunt!
-This is my boyfriend Johan.
-Hello.
Who has picked up my old fur?
I thought it was mother's.
-Don't gloss to put it back.
-No.
But how did you place the tables?
-Tomy and Ingvar, Blow balloons!
-Stina, do you help me with the tables?
Have you seen these?
I thought we could put them around Father's place.
-Not you want to have pink flowers!
-But they are so nice.
Yes, yes, you do as you please.
But I don't think he appreciates it.
Have you set the potato salad?
It was fun that you would like to build.
I did not believe.
-I just promised to look at it.
-Yes, but that there was interest.
I did not believe.
Fun - then maybe I can get help with mother and far-
-Now when Gunilla settled in Falun.
I like it so well!
But you would have seen what flowers they had in Bali.
If you get the chance, go there!
That's the best thing I've done.
Some of us do not think it is so special to fly and danger.
-All may not have that need.
-I have always had that need.
When we turned 18, no one asked if we wanted to plug abroad.
-I arrange 'it myself.
-They had never released us!
But what the hell is this?
That they put a dirty cloth in the cabinet!
In public spaces, people shit in everything.
-No, isn't that the feature?
-Do you need help?
He couldn't piss for a week, there was a completely stop in the machinery.
After three days he squeezed out a fever drop.
-No, now that fucking ... -I can get a little warm?
-Iven cat skull ... -What is it for the phone that rings?
Oh God!
I bought mobile!
Is Barbro at home?
- You, I just stick to Barbro for a little while.
Hello?
Yes, hello.
Mia!
Barbro has weight napkins.
Bring them!
-Do you remember any Eva in my class?
-Eva Bäckström?
-Was she with her front teeth?
-Yes.
-What was it with her?
-Hene's sister came to me.
I didn't recognize.
I didn't know who she was talking about.
It's not that strange.
You haven't lived here in fifteen years.
Barbro, you should add underfloor heating.
I have done that in my hall.
And in the bathroom.
Who was it that helped you with it?
Any nice guy?
I have no guy.
I'm just working.
I don't have time with love.
Listen ... What about you, really?
Huh?
It's been a bit much, just.
... no interest in taking care of the forest, they should just hunt.
-No children can come.
-But Viktoria, then?
-The train ticket became too expensive.
-I must have it known before?
Is it good that they have their own lives?
Right?
I think that is good.
-Where are you going now, then?
-To dass.
Not cry.
Don't cry, not cry ...
You are strong.
You are brave.
You are good.
You are good!
Barbro?
Why are you always so kind to me?
Because you need it.
Silent little girls who go for themselves-
-They you have to keep an extra eye on - even when they grow up.
You, no one has asked me anything.
Not even mother and father.
But they talk a lot about you when you are not here, you should know.
It's just ... I don't even think anyone knows what I'm working on.
-But Eivor and Gunilla, then?
-Are you kidding?
Eivor is not interested in something that happens outside the Rättviks limit.
But you must tell them what you do, even though they do not ask.
-So do everyone else.
Grind on!
-But isn't it sick?
My family doesn't know what I do.
No one has been greeted me for several years.
Everyone is complaining about me coming here.
But if I moved here, they would be interested in what I work with.
Because that's all that counts, to live in Dalarna ...!
-Imorse I got the plot by the lake.
-What are you saying?
You would have seen Eivors mine.
For me, she is happy to take it.
-You can at least look at it?
-But stop now, you should support me!
-But it is a nice piece of land.
-Can Barbro ...
-Do you know what Mia has in the hall?
-No.
-GOV heating.
-Oh!
Yes, it was the worst.
But you, you have to show Mia how nice you have done.
Yes you have to.
Take out and show!
-But I'm not done.
-I am used to doing it myself.
-What nice you got it!
-Thanks.
-Have you started hunting?
-No, it's dads.
But you...
-Bore your girl here too?
-Camilla?
No, we're not ... she moves'.
-Do you haven't gone through everyone in the village?
-No.
-No will probably be left ...!
-Oh really?
You mean that?
You ... you always chatter about how important it was not to stay.
It has not been a situation ... Dad died and the mother is getting old.
You are starting to get old.
Yes, but I might be one then.
One that remains.
Damn, it's Eivor!
I am going out.
I'll stick, see you later!
Is she pregnant?
-I was out yesterday.
-It was to be small.
You!
Say nothing to Eivor.
Let's see how I do.
Do you know that Skagg is going to Africa and drilling wells?
He does not get a buck.
But he learns to get a huge tan.
If you are going there, you should go as a soldier.
Hell, what they get paid.
-What is it for a bride who runs here?
-It's Mia Sundin.
Do you come and help me in the village cottage?
Eivor will bring Mia on a walk.
-She should show the plot.
-What empty?
-We could go together somewhere.
-To bali then, or ...?
I will have to work a lot ...
-But how do you really live?
-Yes, a little different than you ...!
-"You"?
-Yes.
You have a family.
You never go to the pub.
You are not moving further than Rättvik.
I have divorced and been to Bali.
Yes, but you married the first guy you got along with.
Yes, I married the first, best guy, and I am proud of that.
Because up here you do not get tired of your man.
Here you hold together.
Here you stand out - this is what is called a relationship.
This is not a fucking green grove.
This is love.
Deep love.
Love that costs a little.
If you dare not on such love, then you should not have any man.
Have you calmed down now?
So I should thank and receive the first best guy to show his interest?
And hang on with some sad old man half life, as Gunilla made-
-As to prove that probably fuck you stand out, because it is apparently love.
You probably run as soon as someone gets close?
-You don't really know me!
-Nog I know you, you.
You would see me one Wednesday night at three in the taxi from Stureplan-
-So damn drinking that I have to ask the driver to stop so I can vomit.
But do you think I'm naive?
If I could afford to take a taxi once or get full so I spit-
-Then I would have been damn happy.
You don't even know what I'm working on!
-But not so aggressive.
-What do I work with?
-You work with data.
-What "data"?
-Yes, you work with data.
-"With Data" ...!
After all, it was fucking mature to be mimicked.
Yes, but I am apparently not particularly mature according to you.
You know nothing about my life, you just know.
Not a shit!
You stand on the site, just so you know.
Oh really?
You're going to throw now?
But you can forget that!
-What the hell are you doing?
Stop now!
-Now you...
If you mush me I'll fuck you kill you.
If you don't let me go, your bastard ...
What the hell are you doing?
What are you doing?
You should always help the person who is in the downside!
-Where are you going?
-Ingvar's cabin and pick up the light trail.
-What the hell are you doing here?
-I would pick up the light trail.
-Has something happened?
-I had forgotten the lamps.
-The Kerstin is stomach sick, so I flee.
-So she's not going to the party?
What the hell do you think?
She spits!
I must see if I find the light trail, then.
What was it with him, then?
You, thank you for saving me.
What ... what do you think about the scooter, then?
-I got some money on the trot.
-Yes, it's ripe with flames ...!
You have to have a hard time.
Here they think there is something wrong if you live alone.
-Isn't that, then?
-No!
Oh!
Well, we'll see you in the village cottage.
Hello!
But dear someone, what frozen you look.
Father, let Mia crawl into the bathtub and warm up, so you can jump in late.
-I's going well?
-Eivor wants to do the last yourself.
Hello...?
I thought you might want a drink?
Yes ... yes, gladly.
Then you should be at peace.
Haven't you changed yet?
-What are you sitting and pills with?
-Forsan's clock.
-I thought I would get it started.
-Yes, yes ... do you help me with the blouse?
Why did he kill himself?
What kind of question is that?
We don't have to talk about this when we are going to a party.
-But we never talk about.
-There's nothing to talk about.
Dress up now!
-Open!
I have to go in!
-Can i take your black sequin bag?
-Eivor, have you seen my pants?
-I stroked them.
They are in the laundry room.
-Mother!
I can't find it!
-Dum kid!
Open!
Then open!
Mother?
Why was I so much lonely when I was little?
You wanted to be alone.
Has father said that we are happy to help you if you want to build?
How nice you are, mother.
-If!
-Like talkative as always ...!
Hello Hello!
You say I don't know anything about your life.
-But you don't know a splash about mine!
-Mother?
Now I have said mine and you have said yours.
And now it's Father's evening.
Mother!
Grandpa is coming now.
He's here now!
Is everyone here?
Can everyone stand here, so he sees us when he comes in?
Yes please.
Pour one for me.
-But where is Kerstin?
-She is stomach sick.
-But what's the matter with her?
-She is just a little stressed.
Try to have some nice yourself instead.
It's a party!
Yes, may he live, yes, may he live, yes, may he live in a hundred years!
Of course he shall live, of course he shall live
Of course he will live in a hundred years!
-I don't know what to say.
-After a grogg you will probably come on something!
Well, then we have thought like this: you have to sit where you want.
We have the buffet here, and in the bar there are beer, wine and soft drinks to the food-
-And then you can get a grogg if you want.
There is a huge Clas Ohlson in Stockholm now, at Sankt Eriksplan.
Do you know where Sankt Eriksplan is located?
We glaze in the porch last summer, but it got so hot-
-So I carpenter 'a new porch together.
Now you can sit both inside and out.
Now I'm thinking about putting a roof on that veranda ...
... because then you could actually build another porch ... without a roof ...
Then I have a glazed, one with a roof and a free porch.
Then you have everything.
Well ... I would like to bring a quadruple live for Kalle.
-He live!
-HURRAY!
HURRAY!
-The bowl, father!
-Bowl!
And thanks for the gift, Mia!
He received a gift card at Clas Ohlson of SEK 5,000!
I am a little buddy who gets so bad with food
For the one I live with, for the one I live with, he is called Kalle
He gives me herring every da 'and I don't want that
I want red wine, I want red wine and gorgonzola
... a second of 53 square meters.
In Furudal they have wolf all the way to the knot.
Thanks for it, the government!
/ Phone signal/ Excuse me!
Do you have a glass of water for father?
He falls asleep well before the cake if he continues to drink at this rate?
-What speed it was at Mia, then.
-Yes, she has fun with his and none.
But dear!
Haven't you put on the brewer yet?
Oh oh oh!
Yes, it was a nasty afternoon.
But now I have taken some groggers.
But you, I have to hang up.
I have to check a thing.
Yes, we hear.
Well.
Kerstin wants to be separated.
She said it this morning.
Damn women's hours, just have to mess up and think ...
Is it something you have ...?
She said something before the summer, but damn, she babbles like all the lovers!
If you listen to half you get hurt in the head!
The livestock cottage belongs to her family.
-They she never forgives it.
-You want to go home?
Oh!
Here is the entertainment!
Mia!
Do you pick up more spirits?
It will be a surprise.
Father doesn't know about anything!
-Ida ... -No!
-Get the violin now!
Grandpa will be happy.
-No.
Not now.
Tommy!
Do you pick up Ida's violin?
How nice that you could come, boys.
You thank and bow.
Have you got a snap, right?
-You can't go in with that one.
-Why are you so mad at me?
But you know how people are.
They think they should be blind.
-It wasn't what I mean '.
-Jan-Olov, do you help Mia?
-How do you have it at your table?
-Good.
Great.
Will you have one?
Do you remember when you were in love with me?
Oh, what a good thing it was to have you after me all the time.
You could glare at me for hours.
-Stop!
-I barely had to go on a dough.
You, I was six years old.
I just thought it was exciting to be with someone who is older.
I'm still older ...
This is my family's gift.
A little snuff dash 'to me that you are single now.
Are you?
You, concentrate on the spirits now.
-They wonder where the spirits are.
-We just should camouflage it first.
-It's going well with the brides, I see.
-In ...
There is a certain craving down the village.
You mean that ...!
Are you interested, then?
I!
No, for the hell.
But ... are you single, then?
-Where is the spirits?
-It will.
-So you are single?
-Yes.
But he, then?
He who was up?
Who stood on the ass when he would try to go scooter?
-Do you not in law, then?
-"In law"...!
We hung for a while.
-What is being called!
Right?
-Yes...
-Now he's fine, Dad your.
-Come out now!
-Where have you made of the spirits?
-It was a damn ...
God, how nice he is!
He's so nice.
-Jan-Olov?
-No, the dark in the gaming crew.
Is not he?
He could imagine, right?
-Are you drunk?
-No, my God!
Or, I'm well.
But it does not depend on it.
I can't be drunk to mother and father!
But Gunilla, you're actually an adult.
Hold the funnel now, and I'll pour.
But I don't feel adult.
I have to get a break from being an adult.
So that's why you parted?
He was unfaithful to me.
I haven't told anyone.
-So I threw out ... -But why haven't you told you?
You know how people talk.
I don't want to hang out.
The children would be disappointed on the '.
It is better that they are angry with me.
Stina and Helena will sing now.
I blown in my pipe, then a little pigeon came forward
Her name was Rännar-Stina, I took in my arms
I was with one in Bali.
Absolutely amazing guy.
He was called Riffer.
Do you understand what a nice name?
He was so positive.
Such a really generous person.
He dare 'show emotions.
-Do you want to see him?
-No, we take ...
-He came from where you plugged.
-San Francisco?
As he touched me.
As if he liked my body.
Do you understand?
He thought I was fine.
Håkan never liked my body.
I never think he did.
-How old is he, then?
-Trettrettvå.
-What is it?
-Nothing.
-Is it something with me?
With us?
-No, Tommy ...
-Eivor?
-I can't bear to talk about it today.
We'll take it tomorrow.
Next weekend we take the kids and skis and go to the hut-
-And we sleep there one night and fire and grill sausages.
You know?
Oh ...
-What?
-Oh, there was nothing.
Go out with the barrel!
I take the bucket.
I love you, Mia.
I've never said that.
Hi, Kerstin!
It's Eivor.
How are you?
You've always been so strong ... brave.
You have managed yourself.
Then it will probably be easy to forget to say that.
I love you.
-You, do you want a beer?
-Yes please.
Focus now.
Get it together.
Ingvar!
-Now you should go home.
-Is the party end?
-I have talked to Kerstin.
-Iven love!
I'm not going home.
But oh, oh ... how was this, then?
What the hell do you want?
Why are you never satisfied?
Why should you just look?
Why can't you just live?
-What are you talking about?
-Iven egoists, that's what you are!
And read weekly magazines about the lovers who have strangled their men ...
Now I do not understand...
When you finally dare to make a decision, it was to leave your family.
Uh, uj!
But Ingvar ...
I'm going to the hospital on Monday.
Whatever I do, it will be wrong.
I try to do well, but it just gets wrong.
And then I am called MES.
And now that I've finally taken hold of myself ...
... everyone thinks I'm an egoist.
-Have you given up already?
-Damn.
The party has barely begun.
Now damn, Serru.
Now it is time for someone to gain momentum on this liquid.
-I just wanted to tell you.
-It's clear that you should do it.
-But ... -I don't know if I want to talk anymore.
Not ... Not right now, at least.
Then we don't.
Now that I've found myself ...
... then I'm just a man who people think is embarrassing.
Nämen, God ... are you sitting here?
And here I stand crying.
You can't do that at a party.
Right?
"Keep Smiling!"
You know, everyone said in Bali - that I was so happy.
/CHAIN SAW/
It wasn't a day too late.
-What the hell are you doing?
-Yidy cat skull ...
Ingvar, now you let Helena drive you home.
Then you talk and Kerstin tomorrow.
This does not solve any problems.
Nothing gets better because you trap trees that actually belong to the village!
Fy damn, how sad you are.
That's how the bells stop.
So damn unnecessary!
Damn, now it went like that again!
How can you be so fucking cuddly?
You and Jan-Olov remove the Christmas tree tomorrow.
And we take off the light trail.
-I don't really think you see me.
-You, I see you very well.
-What do you see, then?
-You dont want to know.
Stay here - and at home with mother ...!
And not have your own family or child ...
I see everything I don't want to be.
If you can't have children, then?
The feature?
When should you start hunting, then?
Say like it is - you can't tolerate see blood.
Other things were with you.
I have to say, now on the 10th anniversary of his passing, that I am impressed.
Not everyone dares to shoot the hood.
Mia, are you holding here?
Come the mother, then we dance.
Well, now I want a dance!
-I can not take it.
-It does not matter.
I'll probably dance anyway.
Mom, you're fine.
Nice in the hair.
CAKE.
It's time for cake.
-Has anyone seen Ingvar?
-Let he be.
-You don't know why he's so there.
-I know that.
-He sat and bull on.
-Is Ingvar sad?
Press down the lights now and we're no longer talking about it.
He you dance 'with ...
-Bjernulf?
-He is married and has three children.
You do not need to worry.
Gunilla already has a guy.
In Bali.
An American.
-You can no English?
-No, but it didn't matter!
-Yeah.
So you should move there now?
-Are you crazy?
Press down the lights now.
They can go to hell, those bastards ... fucking lovers ...
Hello hope in the cabin '!
Nämen ... what the hell ...
Well, then shoot!
Slide now!
... then he should be shot, yes, then will ...
The fjin, your little fjutt hell ...
Well, shoot now!
Well, what the hell ... Aim upwards so you don't destroy the wall.
Damn amateur, shoot now!
Shear!
It's cake now!
What are you doing?
Huh?
I don't belong here.
-I'm like my dad.
-You are not like him!
-You are strong.
-I'm not strong.
It's a shame about us men.
-I am 37 and live at home.
-You don't live at home.
You have your own!
You live here because you want it that way.
But it's sick!
Sometimes you may want sick things.
I can't even shoot myself.
Dad dare 'at least.
It was a pity that he had to kill himself for someone to understand.
But he dare '.
He...
He was not brave.
He was so cowardly that he was allowed to kill himself.
It's lucky for him.
If I had him here now, then I would kill him.
I would do it slowly, so he got to know what it is to live-
-and what it is to be dead.
-Morsan, huh ... -din cowardly, pitiful, pathetic ...
... who would rather ruin the lives of others than deal with your own!
-What is Ingvar going with the rifle?
-What the hell!
Fucking Ingvar ...
-Is not I told you to go home?
-The the thief would push the hood off.
I'm not going to feel sorry for you for another minute after what you have done to us.
You dare not share with you, though I was there all the time.
I'm so tired of feeling sorry for you.
Your son believes that the only solution is to slap the skull into pieces.
-NA, Barbro!
-Shut up!
And you?
I'm so damn tired of hearing your whining!
I am tired of hearing your nag and see you neglect each other-
-As because you are so damn fucking stubborn.
It's not a shame about you, Jan-Olov.
It's not a shame about the men.
It's just a little easier to think it was a pity for someone.
Then you don't have to be angry.
Mom, I love you.
Just as you know: Your sister is pregnant.
Congratulations!
It's not congratulations.
It's crap.
But what does he say, then?
Dad?
It's not a father.
It is a 19-year-old with dreadlocks who is a DJ.
He is the son of my boss.
And he shouldn't be a father.
-Do you think about having an abortion?
-Yes, it's clear that I'm thinking.
-Where are you going?
-Go to bed.
So you're going to be throwing now?
Mia?
We must try to solve this together.
Well, now will good Eivor help me too?
What an honor...!
-This have you longed for?
-You think I just want you badly.
Not just me - you wish it goes to hell for Gunilla too.
How can you say that?
It is clear that I want you well.
So you have supported Gunilla in her divorce?
So you are happy that she finally got to experience really good sex in Bali?
Been cheated and exploited, you mean?
I am happy to be tricked and used if it is as nice as in Bali.
I wish I was fooled evenly.
Mia, you just know that ... I actually don't have it so easy.
But how can you say so?
You have family and children and someone to live with.
-I just have myself.
-But you don't want anything!
You don't want a guy.
You don't want to do with us.
And not children.
You are never prepared to bet.
And if you don't bet - then you get nothing.
-You, it's not that easy.
-You spoken fucking kid.
I understand that you drink liquor, spit and go taxi.
Can you imagine me on a Wednesday night-
-When I lie and cry quietly in the wardrobe so as not to wake anyone?
And I have such a fucking panic for everything - everything - hangs on me.
Make sure mother comes to the doctor, calm father who is worried about Gunilla-
-Help Barbro change curtains, chatter on Tommy about the car.
Don't demand, just exist, be ...
But say no, then!
There is no workplace where you can come and go.
This - it's life!
Why can't I like my work?
I enjoy my apartment and the city I live in.
Why can no one live in any other way than what you do?
Listen to yourself!
It's always "me, me, me".
It is always your dreams that will come true.
So it has always been.
Your parents are getting old.
When you have time with them, they learn to be dead.
You cannot also be forced to dedicate life to our parents.
I want to help, but I have to do it my way.
It's not so easy to come here when you make me feel so useless!
Mia ...
I admire you.
I want to say that you are good.
But everything that comes out is just strange, hard, nasty words ...
I...
I want to be close.
I want to be with ...
Eivor ...
-Eivor?
What is it?
- Get Tommy!
/ Shot/ Download Tommy!
Hurry up!
Tommy!
Eivor has become bad.
I shot it!
The cat!
I shot the fucking cat skull!
-What the hell is she arranging the party for?
-The doctor said it wasn't.
Gunilla, we have to fry the sausage.
And the beets?
Where do you have them?
Take it easy, mother.
I'll bring them out.
But they must have food!
Gunilla, you have to help Tommy clean.
Of course I do.
I make a mushroom pie, which Eivor likes.
/Telephone signal/
Yes, hello?
Hi, Kerstin.
It was a heart attack.
We may talk more another day.
Hello.
Yes, I have to go ...
When should you be in the hospital?
Gunilla tell '.
Tomorrow.
Is it ... Is it urgent?
Then maybe you can help me make a mushroom pie?
-Yes, is this you are?
-I would just pick up the lamp.
Have you thought about anything ... how to do with the child?
I do not know.
I...
At least I was going to contact him ... Yes, the guy.
I don't know more.
-In addition to what Eivor would have thought.
-I have you never cared about?
-How can you give up someone so close?
-Debt do you place yourself now?
No.
I am only marveling at how you can be so customer.
-No had nothing in common.
-Yes, everything.
She never did anything for you?
-But she tried.
-But what?
It's just to remember as she was.
Stubborn, bullshit ...
...jaundiced.
So damn ... she was hard.
Sour.
She was so damn much Dalarna.
-As to have that folk costume ... -like a little leash.
-I loved her.
So much.
But I couldn't say that.
-Are you on your way?
-Yes.
You ... I was just thinking ...
I don't think I see you so well.
I think I decided on who you are too long late-
-And you know, it's hard to change when you have decided on something.
It's strange how everything happens at once.
You do not know what to believe.
They called this morning ...
... and ask if I wanted to drill wells in Africa.
There was some dropout.
He wonders if I wanted to come along.
I'm back in a year.
Contact us if you are craving more.
Do you hear what silent it is?
SWEDISH SUPPORT: Lina Egeberg (C) Swedish Television AB