-Thanks so much.
-Thanks.
Welcome to shrimp frozen.
We have had a stressful week.
- We have had a premiere party with Johan.
- It was fun to suck in praise.
I walked around and wrote autographs.
I almost wrote a girl on the tits.
Some guy's new shirt - my name straight over.
After all, they become cursed.
"Stick from here, fucking idiot!"
It's hopeless.
But there were a lot of girls.
Yes, it was very glamorous.
I had sex with a model.
It was on a scale of 1: 3.
I myself built it.
- A aircraft model?
-Yes exactly.
It was quite painful.
There are tricks to get a good party.
Some companies rent out look -alikes.
Then you can take someone who looks like Bruce Willis or Julia Roberts.
- We had a look -alike at our party.
- Did it work well?
No, he wasn't so similar ...
Hello.
Johan.
It's my party.
- We probably haven't met before.
- I'm Phil Collins.
Hey.
Phil Collins.
- Phil Collins.
- Phil.
I can feel it coming in the air tonight
It's Another Day For You And Me In Paradise I was flown in this morning.
I can feel it ... many ask: "What is it like to be Phil Collins?"
"How does it feel to be such a famous guy?"
I am like ordinary people.
Oh, Lord!
Oh, Lord ...
- Do you have Tonic?
- Yes, there at Phil Collins.
Phil Collins is standing over there.
The old man in gray beard.
"Quiet in the studio! I don't sing a tone if it's not quiet in the studio."
That is my style, so I want it.
- Have you had a good week, Johan?
- Yes, I've been hanging out with my friends.
We meet in a cave in the forest and read poems for each other.
We met during the boarding school.
We had an incredibly good teacher.
He always said, "Catch the day, guys. Suck the marrow out of life."
Unfortunately, he was forced to quit.
But then we stood on the benches and said: "Oh, Captain, My Captain!"
You think of "Kill Poets Society".
Yes I do!
God, what stupid!
Right.
I've slept so badly tonight.
-What have you done?
- I've been out with the guys.
We stand out and camp and sit around the campfire in the evening.
Someone brings out a bottle of whiskey.
We sat and played guitar and suddenly a banjo answered in the forest.
Bo -Ro -Bom - Pom ... Hell!
My friend went and checked what it was.
He was raped by two foresters.
He screamed like a pig: Ouuuiii!
Terrible!
Then Burt Reynolds came and shot them with a bow.
Don't you think about "the last journey"?
- Oh, yes!
Sorry.
- You are burnt out.
You work too much.
-What have you done then?
- Not anything, sat at home with the acid.
Our neighbor girl is completely crazy.
She is strong.
She is the world's richest girl.
She has a whole jacket with money.
The police come home and harass her.
They are called Kling and Klang.
She just raises their car.
Pippi Longstocking.
It is a book by Astrid Lindgren.
What's with you?
-Always!
- You work too much.
- You also work a lot.
- Yes, I can't rest at home either.
My two step sisters drive with me.
I'll dust, clean, wash.
Fortunately, I have nice mice and birds.
They sewed a dress for me.
- So dangerous was it not?
- Yes, but the whole scare sounded sour.
That they pay for such crap!
And so you have to talk to them later.
I hate going backstage when the show is bad.
Twinkle Twinkle Little Star
How I wonder where you are
Far are you attracting my vision
- Is it your daughter?
-No.
How good you were!
You sang so nicely!
Does anyone have chlamydia?
Raise one hand.
No?
You seem a little insecure.
There is nothing to be ashamed of.
I was on chlamydia test.
That was interesting.
Tops with which you pee your ears - they are available in many sizes.
Did you also receive a yellow form -
- Where you fill in the name of everyone you have had sex with the last month?
They are called for sampling.
If they do not come, they can be punished.
I thought, "Here I have my chance!"
I wrote all I am annoyed at:
Gudrun Schyman, Arja Saijonmaa, Phil Collins ...
That explains the notice I got to the Veneric Clinic.
It's fun with bus and hood.
You know when Jehovah's Witnesses come home and knock on the door.
Then I do not get annoyed like others, but I find out where they live.
Then I go to them and knock on: "Hi, I'm from ordinary people."
"Here's a newspaper I've done."
I am on the subtle revenge.
If I get a lot of money, I'll buy a lot of accordion groups.
Then they should be placed in every street corner in Peru.
They send their guys here.
We will talk a little about bus and hide.
Before the program we called and ordered a taxi in false name.
Has anyone in the audience made any fun bus or hush?
Do we have anyone here?
-Hey.
You have made some fun bus.
- Yes, it's fun with horror.
It keeps a young to the mind.
I can take my favorite.
I go down to the cemetery in the middle of the night and park at a tombstone.
Then I pull a line from the car to the tombstone.
Then just gas.
In the end, the whole stone overturns!
Imagine the next day when people come ...
Great fun!
And I usually go to someone who is in a respirator at the hospital.
We will move on.
- Yes, you may have something there.
- Yes, I'm here with an anonymous lady.
- What are you finding for Unfog?
- I usually bust in my workplace.
We take turns getting coffee in the dining room.
My colleague Ulla usually just wants a sugar bite in her coffee.
But on Thursday I got full in fank -
- And when she didn't see, I instead put in two pieces of sugar.
Oh.
Bus and Hyss can also have a best before -date.
Everything doesn't always work.
My nephew is five years old.
He wants to cuddle with - scare life out of the kid.
Last time I was thinking of ghosting.
It worked when my brother haunted me.
I brought out a big sheet and painted two large, disgusting, red eyes.
He will call the police, I thought.
I entered his room at night.
"Bu! Uncle is ghost. I'm so dangerous."
When a five -year -old in 2000 sees his uncle in a sheet of two spots -
- He doesn't call the police.
He called via directly.
When a five -year -old calls via directly and asks how to remove stains -
- Then it is they who call the police.
You easily get lost in our new, fast society.
You may need a guide.
That is why we present with great pleasure our lifestyle consultant - Henrik Elmér.
Thanks so much.
Welcome to part two of the course "Meet Life with Henrik".
Last time I said you could order the booklet.
It has not come from the printing company -
- But it only gives me the opportunity to demonstrate my positive attitude.
The great art of life is to find solutions to small problems.
Some of my friends have married.
Then it is important to fix a neat kidnapping to the tail sex.
Then you want to surprise him with something unexpected, but it never works.
He realizes it's tail sex.
So now I'm planning a tail sex for a guy who shouldn't get married.
He is surprised.
Another example from life is this when you are on the toilet.
Outside you meet someone who you have to greet and your hand is wet.
The person you say goodbye says, "It's not a kiss? - No, it's water."
Why can't you be honest there?
It's weird.
He sounds strange
I do this when itchy in my throat.
It is also problem solving.
If it scratches your neck, you scratch.
But itch it inside most people think that there is nothing to do about it.
Then you can do this ... because if you drive down your fingers you vomit.
Which is unsuccessful for us into love.
When one comes close to a woman -
- So it is the same feeling as after vomiting - it is positive.
Imagine if you get so close to a woman and then you vomit.
It must be fantastic.
But maybe you should let the girl vomit first.
Girls are so whimsical.
You never know how a girl should react.
You follow a girl from the pub and think it will be cozy.
But when you come home to her, she changes herself and gets angry.
Last time I told you about my BC
Girl Gunilla.
She was so there.
She lay all night, whining about a guy she went home.
In the morning I got to comfort him.
And I did, because I think you should take care of each other.
We will continue next time.
Thanks.
Is Henrik a good lifestyle consultant?
I think he is pretty good - at that price.
We don't give him much.
- He is kept away from the streets.
- He's weird.
- You should not talk shit, Johan.
- No, that's the worst thing there is.
My friend Martin talks shit about everyone.
He's an idiot.
- It's so fun that they are together.
- It has been looking at each other.
Malin has always wanted to have a relationship.
I am going to go to the toilet.
I don't want to talk shit, but do you know that Johan's family does not have Christmas tables?
No ham - nothing.
Isn't that a little sick?
It is a holiday that you should celebrate together.
How deep can you sink?
- Johan, was it good to pee?
- Should I take the next round, right?
- But Erik, what a schyst.
What a schyst.
It's awful with those who talk shit about others -
- But Erik was happy when his mother died.
How swine can you be?
His own mother.
He inherited money and everything like that.
It was almost as if he stood and laughed at her funeral.
Now he is raising with her blood money.
- Erik, always just as generous.
- You can trust.
- I should buy cigarettes.
Excuse me, but ... Johan - it's a real asshole.
- I heard that.
- Are you paranoid?
I didn't mean you.
I don't want to talk shit, that's the worst thing there is. But Johan is an AS.
- Well, don't you have a cig?
-Yes.
Phone signal
No, it's Håkan.
He is the dullest and most boring bastard I've met.
Do you know what he did on holiday?
Nothing, type.
Tjena, Håkan.
Lucky you call.
I stand here with some idiots.
You have to come here.
I can't cope with them.
Everyone just talks shit.
Do you know that Erik's brother is working on Skanska, despite this with Rhoca Gil?
Håkan, are you left?
Yes, show up here.
Yes, unfortunately - the evening is destroyed.
That idiot comes here.
- "Thelma and Louise." Have you seen it?
-No.
I was completely put when I saw it.
It is the end that comes so unexpectedly.
It will be SEK 45.
Thank you.
A fifth back.
Then we will find the movie too.
There we have it, yes.
So ... they both die.
They drive out for a cliff with the car - with diligence.
It is not wise.
Welcome back.
We are fortunate to get paid to stand on TV and trampling.
Many people find it difficult to find what to do in working life.
"What is right?"
It will easily be some prestige.
I had a reunion with the high school class.
Everyone has new, cool jobs.
One is Global Key Account Manager.
He sells vacuum cleaners throughout Sweden.
Another friend is a layout - outlaws.
- I have worked a lot with advertising.
- You have distributed advertising.
I never liked the advertising industry.
There is so much to hold in your head.
Gate codes and ...
- It's so cold in the advertising industry.
- Yes, you have to take a jacket on yourself.
I have wanted to work with computers.
This summer I would work at a company.
I would work with the data.
But it was a guy named Data, Datan Manevski.
He packed cucumbers.
It's a shame it didn't work.
It is important to activate yourself.
Last summer I traveled around the countryside and inseminated cows.
You know that with the rubber glove.
I was doing that for three weeks.
I was forced to quit when a farmer saw me.
I've had a real job.
I was an IT consultant at a web agency.
What I like best about the new economy is the distance work.
The computer was my work tool, with it I came to the company's network.
Communication is done via e -mail, but I had a separate fax as well.
There were video conferencing.
You see the little camera.
The living room became my coffee room.
It's just a matter of discipline.
But you do not get away then when you have no one to babble with.
A good thing about working at home is that you can dress how you want.
After a while I realized that you can do the work from the bedroom.
The important thing is to deliver on time.
The more time you save, the more efficient you work.
The network economy is based on being online all the time.
I handled all my purchases online.
I never had to leave the apartment.
The disadvantage of the new economy is that people are connected all the time.
You have to force yourself to be free.
The less time you spend outside the bed, the more efficient the day.
You never have to leave the bed.
You can take care of all needs from there.
The disadvantage is that many miss the exercise.
You get some sleeping wounds.
So it will be if you want to keep up.
- I take them here.
-Where are you going?
I'll polish them.
- Have you paid?
- No, it's on an invoice.
- I'll probably check that.
- You get them back on Tuesday.
I have not heard of that.
- I talked to Evy.
-Who?
-What is her name?
Elsa ...?
- There's no one like this.
- I have talked to the manager.
- I am a manager here.
No, I took a robber.
If so, it goes.
So you do, right?
Yes, yes ... Hello then.
It is said that many of our needs, fears and desires -
- Dives into our dreams at night.
We have studied some dream interpretation and will try to interpret our dreams.
My most common dream-
- Is I sit on a train that is on my way into a tunnel at full speed.
But it derails just before, then it lies just asleep.
You have to get it up again and get into the tunnel, but it is not possible.
-No what is it?
That is very typical.
You have travel fever.
You are worried about going train down to Skåne.
It's a concern.
I dream that I have a very beautiful rose that I want to water.
But as soon as I touch the water hose, the water sprays out.
Then you stand there with a slack hose and the rose dries again and withered.
I have a theory.
It's a little embarrassing.
You are worried about the declaration.
The rose is the tax office and the hose is deducted.
You need mental keys to solve it.
I often dream that I am a snake that will eel me into a tunnel.
- There is chocolate.
-Chocolate?
It's a cocoa tunnel, you might say.
I try to squeeze my head, but I get rid of.
I have a similar dream - that I am going into the big Nutella Valley.
But the guards stop me all the time.
I say: "Please, all my friends have been here."
But I don't get.
- I don't understand what it might be.
- You are burnt out.
You work too much.
- Eriksson went up 2 % today.
-Is it true?
Yesterday everything went down.
The IT shares pull up the entire index.
It is private individuals who account for most of the sales of IT shares.
That bubble bursts at any time.
Hello.
- Don't be so sure.
IT companies in the United States are much higher valued.
- You have spilled something on the shirt.
- Yes, you have something at the collar.
She is so ego.
When talking, she interrupts and changes the subject.
She has neither artistic talent nor social skills.
-I have drawn.
-Can I see?
What is it?
-It is a horse.
-How nice!
Very nice!
You have drawn four legs and one head, but you have forgotten the tail.
I think it's great.
She would not recognize a horse if it bit her in the ass.
It's time to say thank you and hello.
Yes, but next week we have a top program.
Robert Gustafsson is coming.
- We have had fun.
- Have you had fun?
Yeah.
I haven't had much fun.
I have a hard week.
The husband is sick.
You bring that bag here.
- You can come back next time.
- No, you, I don't think so.
Okay.
Yes, yes ... thank you.
Don't forget: You are the audience, we are the comedians, here is the stage.
- Oh bite!
–Wa?
- Wait wait...
- It sat like a spear.
-What was that?
All programs have a "catchfrase".
Peter Harryson has: Hi, Mom.
We have: You are the audience, we are the comedians, here is the stage.
Well!
It means nothing.
We talk through that.
- Bye!
SVT Program texting: Barbro Magnusson
CRYING
Come out now, Stefan.
It is not the whole world.
Sharpen now, Stefan!
You can't bother the whole.