Wake up ... Wake up, Gustav, it is quarter past six.
Wake up now.
People want their post!
- I dreamed that I was a zebra.
-How fun.
I blasted under Africa's sun.
Completely free.
Not a clock radio in sight.
My only duty was to be zebra.
But now you are a postman and you are in a terrible rush.
I do not want to.
It is ten degrees cold and today the sponsorship week begins.
- Gustav, then something new happens.
- Yes, everything takes twice as long.
They go well with you to learn.
They see the profession as any job.
When it is in fact a religion?
Not everyone is created for this profession.
We have a great responsibility.
A miss, so the postcard is wrong ...
- I don't want to, I don't want to.
- Ask someone for help with the trainees.
Pettersson has never taken care of any trainee.
You are right.
This time he may take responsibility.
I've had enough.
Maybe you should call someone and announce your decision?
Gustav!
Okay.
Okay...
I'm tired of this.
Nothing new is never happening.
Yes.
The hot water heater is broken.
Then I don't have to shower anyway.
-What are you doing?
- snowball war with Kasper and Olle.
- They are only eight years old.
-I know.
They didn't have a chance.
- Nothing happens this year.
- Gustav slipped into Olsson's garage.
- It's the third time that is happening.
- But now some tires take the bumps.
-How are you?
- Gustav's internship week begins today.
Last year he was a sponsor for the one who would jump from the water tower.
-Why?
- He wanted a new sponsor.
- Did Gustav have to stand every year?
- He said he would say ...
Do you avoid the trainee?
No, it was hopeless.
- Pettersson then?
- He wasn't even there.
Sara, Kaspers and Olle's parents are looking for you.
They looked angry.
- Don't you see people exploit you?
- Next year I hit the table in the table.
Oh, I have to at a boring party.
I thought he liked the letter carrier party.
Drink Sangria out of the post horns ...
It is at the staff parties.
This is for the students.
- December is not his month.
- There is a nice story about it.
Have you heard the story of the family chanterelle and uncle Frost?
I think I will hear it now.
The best chanterelles knew where to wake up and extend to the sun.
But one morning there was no sun anymore.
- Father Frost had arrived.
- You've heard it?
A wild guess, only.
They pulsed through the snow to find the heat again.
Chanterelles cannot walk, Sara.
This is a fairy tale!
They went and went ...
Finally, they arrived at a glade in the forest where there was a small house.
- They went in there and warmed themselves.
- No one opened, so they froze to death.
- Have you not intended to write children's books?
- We have to keep us away from the cold.
- Otherwise, we are the chanterelles.
- You don't want to ...
- It's not getting late.
- What a nice jacket!
- Do you have shaving water on you?
-Oh really?
Maybe it came a little on the chin.
- Hi, Gustav!
–Lellinor ...
I know we would meet at the intersection, but it was so cold.
My trainee that I talked about ...
Sara, our neighbor ...
There is my wife Lena, we are married to each other.
- We should give us off.
- I have to say goodbye.
We have had so much fun.
I don't understand how he can be so helpful.
-I understand that.
-Hello Darling.
We will not be late.
Come now, Gustav Gubben, we are late.
But God, how good she was!
Did you see what skin?
- How to look in July ... - She doesn't live for that long.
Is she sick?
-Where is Dad?
- You have no dad anymore.
- Sara says you are jealous.
- Sara is wrong!
I want higher monthly money.
My teacher said: Children should require their right.
Then he can pay your monthly money ... then I have to raise Linas too.
-She already has 300.-A 14-year-old has greater expenses.
--P pills and folk beer?
- Now you go to bed!
- I suppose the discussion is over?
-Really.
Good night.
-How did it go?
- I should have as much as you.
- I'm always four years ahead of you!
- Not intellectually.
- Hi, kids, dad is at home.
-Hurray.
Hello there.
Are you already at home?
The night that is so young.
Almost younger than your trainee.
--Ellinas are a bit sloppy.
- Did she give you a goodnight kiss?
- It seems like you were jealous.
- Why would I be jealous?
Tell us about the party.
Were there any others there than you and cute Ellinor?
It was probably the most boring kick I was on.
Everyone was glowing.
- You have a serpentine left in the neck.
- Bosse tried to revive it.
Don't you think I see what you are doing?
I'm just saying Nettan Olsén.
You carry like when you and the other guys ran after her.
- You and I weren't even together!
-No.
So you could swing after her!
You carried her from the school bus into the classroom.
She had slept poorly and was tired.
It's ridiculous!
Ellinor is my trainee.
- And you love her.
- How can you believe it about me?
This is part of my job.
To lock Pettersson in the toilet?
You had agreed that he would take over your trainee.
- You have apparently changed.
-Yes...
I have a simple question: Why?
- kids, go up and go to bed!
- I want to hear how you get out of it.
- In bed.
- Come, we listen to the stairs instead.
I had to.
Pettersson is a bachelor.
His gaze was nasty!
- You are pathetic, Gustav.
- It is actually a matter of morality!
- What do you have there?
- You mean the rose?
To you...
"We'll see you tomorrow. Puss. Ellinor."
- Good morning, do you want coffee?
- Don't make yourself.
It's just me.
- Do not pick up Max today.
- Have I ever forgotten to pick up Max?
Okay, once.
But there were berries in the forest and he found home.
- Max wants raised monthly money.
- What do kids have nowadays?
Ask Ellinor what she gets.
Gustav Svensson.
Tjena, Pettersson.
It's fine.
Tired of her?
Not really.
500 bucks?
Not a chance.
Ellinor needs me.
Our relationship is based on trust - a word that you do not understand.
- Hi, Gustav.
–Stig on, just ...
I have to ask you one thing.
Your new trainee ...
- Lena is not so fond of her.
- She was Miss Mälardalen three times.
Four.
She has a good chance this year too.
Do you think she can be a hair model for me on Saturday?
I need a good picture.
I can hear with her, but she is quite fully booked.
- What is she going on?
- Sorting and shipping lists.
- She becomes a fantastic postman.
- Then she does not have to harrow as a photo model.
Honestly ... Don't you think Lena behaves strangely?
How would you react if Lena started working late with a stylish business economist?
I've been thinking a lot about it.
I would make myself a shrimp, turn on Eurosport ... no, I'm kidding.
I enjoy seeing Lena like this.
That she still gets jealous!
I see it.
But don't drive it too far.
- I will tell you the truth.
--Ellinas are with children.
You should accommodate.
-Stop.
You think I'm old -fashioned.
- You think you have to marry you first?
-Listen.
You know who Pettersson is?
- He who looks like Sean Connery!
It doesn't belong here.
He's dangerous!
If I had not been, she would have been lost in his arms.
How lovely it sounds ...
- Pettersson is divorced!
-I also.
See for yourself!
All normal instincts disappear.
- There are only unsorted drives.
- thank you, Gustav.
I like you too.
- Ask her if she can sit model.
- Yes, when I hear from her.
Postrone Svensson ... Pettersson?
700?
Never!
Ellinor wants to be with me.
Thats how it is.
It felt strange to meet Ellinor.
- Gustav is not a seductive type.
- Don't say it!
When I met him he had a red suit and spoke Italian.
- He summer job like Piccolo.
- Now the sponsor week is soon over.
- If two days Ellinor goes home.
- One to complete!
The batter is soon over.
I say that, it's been a long time since I ate these pancakes.
- Hi, are you home before?
- It was a surprise, I see.
I borrowed some eggs and margarine.
- I thought we would get something in the stomach.
- A straight right, maybe ...
- You probably have a lot to talk about.
- Lee, should you have a pancake?
- No, I think about what I eat.
- It should be a bit to take in.
- I never get up a single pound.
-Poor little thing...
- How does it feel to go home?
- Gustav and I may be a couple.
The management has talked about extending the sponsor week.
-How long?
-I do not know...
"A six months," they said.
- Then you have a chance of extension.
–Postverket is not afraid of news
Every new idea should be tried!
We were the first in Europe to have winter tires on the bikes!
Pioneers are what we are!
Now we are going to work.
Hello then, the old man.
I'm back at ten o'clock.
Kiss Kiss...
- What a good looking thing she is!
- Are you so young sometime?
Eat up and shut up.
- Lena, take it easy.
- It's the third time he has been looking at me.
- The long looking.
- You have the clock behind you ...
Surely this proves nothing?
I want to know if I'm still attractive.
- You are shitty!
- But not like Miss Mälardalen, huh?
Look, where Jesper comes!
Focus now.
Hello Sara.
Full speed as usual?
Nice with a place for all ages.
-What do you mean by that?
- This is my friend Lena.
- You said something about ages.
- You can have fun together regardless of age.
All men are equally age -fixed!
On the contrary.
Age does not matter.
- No, they can be as young as possible!
- It's probably the best you go.
- Hi, Jesper.
- Stick, pork!
- There he got!
- Iidiot!
- Yes, they are all like that.
-Get it together.
- I've been out before.
I know how it goes.
–What is said about a dance?
- It's not a dance venue.
Shit in it then!
Is it the guard at the bank?
It's Gustav Svensson.
Can you check if my wife Lena is working over?
You don't want to leave the TV?
You want to know who the killer is first.
You're sure she's not left?
Thanks.
The service is the killer.
- Are you awake, Gustav?
- Yes, I looked at the hockey match.
They must have played for a long time.
She is half past two.
- Why are you coming home this late?
- I have been with Sara in the pub.
- Concern stamp!
What have you done?
- Dane.
- With who then?
-Yes...
Jesper ... a young, charming guy I have danced with quite a lot.
I have cried with worry, while you have been in your arms at Jesper.
- Not all evening.
A dance.
- Yes ... and then?
- Stefan, Tore, Björn ... - Is this true?
What are you worried about?
Is little Ellinor cold?
Obviously I'm getting worried!
"I stand out for a while. Don't forget that Lina will be confirmed this summer."
- I wanted to scare you.
- You have succeeded.
- No thing has happened.
-Is it safe?
-Yes.
Good night.
- I also have something to tell.
- Something fun.
- Was Leksand?
- I have renounced me Ellinor.
-It was the worst.
- Pettersson had to take over.
-Why?
I thought it was best.
Ellinor is in love with him.
–What are you grinning at?
-Nothing.
People fall in love with each other at the post office!
Even if you think it sounds strange, I'm actually a little happy about it.
Imagine you are still so terribly in love with me!
I didn't think you could be so jealous.
It was a nag ... I haven't been jealous!
- You were the most jealous I've seen.
- Then you haven't seen much, Gustav!
You would have seen yourself recently.
You were crazy angry.
I wasn't angry.
I was calm as a file bowl.
No problem.
I recognized your mine from this summer when I won over you in ping pong.
You have never won over me in ping pong.
-Yes.
In two straight sets.
-There are five-set matches that apply.
- There you have no chance.
–21–5, 21–6.
21–7.
Texting: SVT Sub -text (C) Swedish Television AB