Fy Satan!
What a fucking weather, Leif.
Have you been out, right?
Shouldn't we go down and swim?
We can sneak up Andersson's boat and go down to the floating bridge.
What are you saying?
We can bring the fishing rods and fish a little.
Leif?
Leif, how are you?
God damnit!
Leif!
How are you?
Your liver values have shot a lot in the ceiling, I see.
-You have to change your way of life.
-Oh my God...
-Do you just eat a canned potato?
-Yes.
Poor little boy.
You should see that it will be preparing soon.
Yes ... I don't think it will work out this time.
Totally fucking broke.
They will take the house away from us now.
Uh-oh.
-You have to eat more varied diet.
-OK, I understand.
Print some pills.
I don't have all day on me.
There is nothing I can do just like that.
Oh my God!
Did you get your fucking medical certificate in a cheek egg?
Here you have paid taxes all your life, but you get no help.
No, for Leif Öhman you do not spend any resources on.
How did it go?
Yes ... I'll die.
I'll die, Billy.
-What are you saying?
You should not die.
-Do I not?
Do you mean that the women's corner lied?
Or have you gone and become a doctor?
-Give me a second statement, then.
-Take it a little quiet.
Calm?
- Do you also think I should take it easy?
We take the opportunity to take it easy, then!
I don't care about my disgusting liver from Chernobyl, who have been able to heal.
You know what?
I have also become a communist physician.
Well, then we have a chubby who suffers from chronic obesity.
He looks like an albinogris and completely lacks brain cells.
Well ... sorry.
Bye bye, nice times you get to go wherever you want
But only if you promise it is because you want to
If it is somewhere that you are actually afraid
To let me in yes, then it's not right
You may be able to take my liver.
What should you put in there, then?
Do you know what these pictures have in common?
No.
They are all taken here in Sörbäcken.
I have only left the municipality four times.
I have always loved Sörbäcken, Billy.
But I've always dreamed of traveling and seeing the world.
Imagine how many times you and I have talked about going Finnish boat.
We have.
We would have our own cabin, eat breakfast buffet and have women ...
Who runs around the kneecaps on us at Karaokken.
I know.
Now you stand here with a route Dadel to liver and wait for the liaman.
We do, just.
We just do, Leif.
Come on!
If it is your dream to travel we will pack and stick.
Wow.
What a good idea.
We have a debt of 600,000, and it is absolutely fucking empty in the account.
But be sure to book a luxury cruise so we can shop.
You can pay with monopoly money.
It's run, Billy.
SEK 50,000?
Even you have to understand that it is not possible.
Okay, I'll put the cards on the table.
Leif is seriously ill.
I don't know how long he has left to live.
I want to make his last time nice and invite him on a trip.
Please.
I'm sorry.
There is nothing I can do.
Move you, for fuck!
"Remove you," I said!
-Okay...
Put down!
Several shots
Damn!
Police ... a ... no!
112!
-Sos 112. -It's a robbery here.
-Where are you?
-At the bank!
-What bank?
-On...
To the train station!
Drive!
Hello?
Are you still there?
Here is a cutting schedule you can use.
Burial becomes too expensive.
I don't want to leave you with debts, so you can cremate me in the oven.
-Leif, I've done something stupid.
-Splace this bastard at 300 degrees.
Stop the head here and it goes well.
For hell, I've robbed a bank!
It was not me who robbed the bank.
There were two others.
When they were to go, they dropped the bag, and I took it.
What have I done?
-Where was anyone seeing you?
-I do not think so.
-It's not possible.
I'll submit it.
-But ... stop and evidence!
-Release!
-It's the bank's money.
No.
Yes, though ... This is like when you find a wallet.
You can choose whether you want to take the content or not.
-It's a little worse anyway?
-You are a hero.
You have taken from the rich and given to the poor.
-Are you sure?
-It's clear.
Trust me.
You are pure Rama Robin Hood.
This is a gift from above.
-Do you think?
-I have had anxiety every night.
I have prayed to the gods, Muhammad, Buddha and all the fucking men.
Here is the reward for all prayers, and you are the envoy.
-Sörbäcken's little Robin Hood.
-Okay.
-I have goose bumps all over my body.
-It's damn cool.
It's like being in a movie.
-Where do you want to go?
-To Stockholm, maybe.
And then the ferry over to Finland.
-Commissioner Hermansson, coffee.
-Thanks.
So there.
I take eight logs snuff, and I have refueled the second.
Leif, you may not shop on chalk anymore.
Chalk...
Keep the change.
Or ... Throw on a mash tray too.
Extra mustard.
Money Talks.
Is it Biggest Loser final in town?
-Tjena, can.
-And the little pig is included.
Well ... where the hell are you going, then?
We are going on a caravan holiday.
With the mash tray in the highest cut.
It's going well for the fat brothers now.
Gosh!
Thanks, Leif.
I needed some gasoline money.
You may have a nice holiday.
Here, take the sausage.
Take the sausage!
In the Summertime When The Weather is Hot
You can stretch right up and touch the sky
When The Weather's Fine, You got women, you got women on your mind
Have a drink, have a drive go out and see what you can find
-Are you thirsty?
-Absolutely!
-A to the brother.
-Thanks.
Fy fuck.
-This is life.
-Yes.
It won't be better than this.
Shit.
We stay here until tomorrow, then we go down towards ...
Turn to hell, what a grid.
Satan, what a fucking puma.
Not she, the brain.
She!
See and learn, Billy.
Servant, brides.
You should greet the neighbors.
-Jasmine.
-Wind.
Leif.
Fine.
-What do you have plans tonight?
-We thought about having a barbecue party.
How fun!
Me and my brother also thought to have a sausage party ... sausage grill party.
So that ... maybe we can merge our sausages?
No thanks.
We will manage.
My brother and his friends are coming soon.
-It gets too crowded on the grill.
-We have its own grill.
But no thanks.
If you apologize, we'll talk a little private now.
Well.
Thanks.
Yes, the can ... Where was you at the moment of the robbery?
Is there any fucking echo in here?
After all, I was home watching TV.
-Where is this banknote from, then?
-Min back pocket.
The banknote has a serial number.
It tells me that it comes from the robbery in Sörbyn.
I got it in gear when I was shopping on the station.
Both you and I know what a little fucking piss rat you are.
I'll put you there for this, whether you want to or not.
-We shall see.
-Shit that it should be so.
-Really.
-Jasse?
Didn't you buy worn?
-It's you who would do it.
-No.
What should we drink tonight?
-There are some slices left.
What a fucking garbage.
-They have beer.
-Jasmine, you have to put on the charm.
-Fan either.
I would rather be without.
-You have to take one for the team.
Talk to us a little worn.
Go and talk to us a little bit now!
-What heroes you are!
-Hello.
Leif.
-Kalle.
-You are welcome.
Here we have stuff.
Hey.
Kalle.
-Hello?
-Wo?
-Is anyone at home?
Do you have a name?
-Billy.
Tjena, Billy.
Sit down.
Sit down!
I fuck you recognize you.
-Where did you make the bump anywhere?
-I didn't do the lump.
Wait...
Now I know.
We attended the bartender school at Kos.
No, I haven't been to anything like that.
I have a strange face, which makes people recognize me.
-Where is it from?
-Who want the first one?
Glass is crushed
Have you robbed a bank, your fucking?
-Yeah ... do you have any boyfriend?
-No.
Neither do I.
No girl.
I like to be free.
I do not live in celebrity, like any monk.
-I can have sex and stuff.
-Yeah.
-I have to talk to you, Leif.
-Not now.
I converse with Jasse.
-It is important.
-What is so important?
Have you got hair on the scrotum, right?
Leif, not now.
This is really important and private shit.
Come!
Not now, Billy.
He's a little behind.
Maybe we can merge our parties and travel together?
Someone has taken the bag from the caravan.
Yes, that bag.
Come.
Fuck off!
Sorry, I have to ... we'll hear soon.
-What do you mushrooms about?
-Augoze, Leif.
Billy, what do you mow about?
What are you doing?
Adrian!
Start the car!
Billy!
-Jump in the car!
-What happened?
Cursed, Billy!
Stop the car!
Cursed!
Billy Öhman!
Open the door!
-Hello!
-Quiet.
What the hell are you doing?
Has it been struck in the brain beam?
-I can explain.
-I will explain one thing to you.
I am a virgin.
I have never felt a woman's skin against mine.
-And my brother got a free game!
-It were the robbers!
-No, she's my soulmate.
-She didn't.
Kalle and Adrian, for fuck!
It was they who robbed the bank.
I saw Kalle's tattoo on the wrist.
They are.
I know that.
Listen ... You don't cry?
-Do you, Leif?
-Shucks.
-What should we do now?
-Give me the pain tablets.
We forgot them.
-forgotten?
-Yes, they remain at the campsite.
That was exactly what you needed.
Get the car key here.
-I can drive.
-You have been running enough.
Get the car key here.
-Are you sure it was he?
-Yes.
They pulled away in a blue Volvo, and another gang followed them.
Door knocking
-What quick you were.
-Polisen, open the door.
Open the door now!
What the hell...?
No, no ... damn!
Hell.
Satan!
Cursed!
-Billy!
-Drive, drive, drive!
I didn't get the money with me.
I'm sorry.
I panicked.
Sorry.
I wanted us to get a nice last trip-
-But everything just got shit instead.
Do you know something?
Although everything happened and we have the cop after us-
-I don't sing a single second.
You tried to do something extra for me.
It happened, but you tried.
Do you know what the best is?
That I have been with you, the brother.
Tomorrow we go home to Sörbäcken again.
Gone well, but at home best, the brother.
Yes ... sorry for not losing the innocence, Leif.
-I'm really sorry.
-It was a joke.
I was joking, do you understand?
Sure I have ... yes.
What are you saying?
The latter in is a goat cock.
Swedish texture: Helena Johansson BTI Studios for SVT