In tonight's section of Ifs, quiz about all culture in Sweden:
The Syrian who moved Özz Nûjen - Filip Dikmen.
The talk mill from Pakistan - Adeel Faqih.
The Persian humor priestess - Zinat Pirzadeh.
The Kurd who speaks better German than Swedish - Big O.
The zucchini turk from Alby - Thanos Fatas.
The sweet version of Saddam Hussein - Elaf Ali.
The Serbian Humortorpeden - Branne Pavlovic.
Humor Sweden's Yao Ming - Evelyn Mok.
And as a black cream on the mash, our program manager Ahmed Berhan!
Send a text message to SOS and say it burns in Studio 1.
The atmosphere is "mmm"!
You look at the quiz about all culture in Sweden.
It's time to meet our competitors.
Next to me, from the sump - Frida!
All the way from Gothenburg - Mattias!
And last but not least - Gunilla Persson!
The game goes like this: you choose a panelist, I ask a question -
- And you decide if the panelist is lying.
Frida, we start with you.
Who do you choose?
I want to start with Evelyn.
I feel we have some connection.
Sweden sees itself as an innovation country -
–And Poles as a craftsman.
But they are inventive.
Which of the following was not invented by a pole?
I think it was a collage - hard to find a picture of black jobs.
Here's how: Poles are innovative.
They have invented some stuff, but not all.
What have they invented?
Stuff they can use in their operations.
It is the bulletproof vest, the floor mop and the Walkie talk.
But, Frida, have you ever seen a pole with a tops?
- It's the one to go away.
- I want to say false on it.
You think it's false?
Congratulations!
You got your first point!
The correct answer is the floor mop, which was not invented by a pole.
They are just good at using it.
- Mattias?
- I feel a Connection with Elaf.
OOOH!
You choose Elaf.
- Elaf?
Mattias, the answer is finished toilet paper.
Why?
Because during the Sabbath you must not do ... you must not work -
- And to demolish toilet paper is counted as work.
They prepare by tearing a lot of paper so that it lasts all day.
- Mattias?
- I know you can't work.
After all, it is quite a baroque that it would count ...
- you?!
Baroque?
- Yes, what does it mean?
It's crazy - crazy.
- What does Baroque mean?
- It's a barracks with an o in.
It is so unlikely that it must be true.
You say it's true?
I have to do it, because it is so unlikely.
Mazel Tov!
You just got 1 point.
There are 39 jobs you are not allowed to perform during the Sabbath -
–Bl.a.
Cook, light and extinguish lamps and tear things like toilet paper.
- Drying.
- What is Baroque?
I want an answer!
You may go on SFI.
- Can anyone explain, the man?
- Extremely very strange.
- Gunilla, welcome into the match.
-Thanks.
-How are you?
-Good.
You are called Gunilla Persson?
What do you think about the other Gunilla Persson?
Is she worth your name?
She is not worthy, I think.
Gunilla came to Ifs and said, "There can only be one!"
Just right!
You can only choose one panelist.
Who?
I really wanted to choose Evelyn.
We met in the entrance, so I ...
It was another Chinese, it wasn't ...
But then ... The first to take me in the hand of the participants was Adeel.
!
Immigrants who come here when they are 16 are 36, so there will be a diff.
I was three months when I came to Sweden.
I had a beard then too.
Joking aside...
What a positive question you got.
How fun.
Thanks, Ahmed!
We die early.
It's as you might think, maybe ...
Swedish -born lives about 4.5 years longer than foreign -born do.
- What do you say Gunilla?
-It is difficult.
We are all humans.
No matter where we come from, I think we should live as long.
So it so.
Easy for you to say, living longer.
I want to say it's false.
Because I think it should be.
- But the game is not about it.
- Well, not?
-Shucks!
No, but ... - But what do you think?
I think foreign -born lives 4.5 years shorter.
You should have gone on what you were hoping for.
It was false.
Overt European immigrants in Sweden live longer than Swedish -born.
For men, the difference is 2 years and for women 1.5.
In your face!
- Frida, who in the panel do you choose?
- I chop the last girl - Zinat.
- Zinate.
-Hello.
If you feel scratchy, many Iranians say that Nabat is the cure.
A combo of petroleum jelly and cannabis, which you use when feeling bad.
You roll it together and put it in the rectum, so everything will be fine.
Ehm ...
I'm just kidding!
Just kidding.
I'm just kidding, actually.
Nabat is incredibly nice and liberating.
It is so that when you feel bad you should bazza alone.
- It means that you ... - bazza alone, it means this ...
We have just introduced a new word: "Bazza alone".
I'm more confused now!
And women can too!
One should make sure to satisfy yourself every day of the week -
-And when it gets very moist or sprayed ...
... and everything comes out, it means you got all the bacteria!
And then you will feel good.
It's Nabat!
- I see your total confusion.
- What is I going to answer?
Nabat in Persian means that when you are sick ...
Then the recommendation that masturbation can get out of you the disease is much faster.
You recommend "On the Low" to go home and ...
-Just!
-Oh God...!
It sounds unreasonable ...
But it feels like it can be true.
You choose to believe that Nabat is a health course in the form of masturbation?
Fy damn, what stupid!
It sounds stupid because that's not true!
Nice, Frida ...
Zinat, on the other hand, sold it very well!
Nabat is a saffron club ...
That's what she said.
... that will solve stomach problems, counteract muscle pain and provide energy.
But it is not clear where to stop it.
- I could have got it right?
- A half point.
- Mattias, who do you want to talk to?
- I think Thanos ...
What is Dalkurd?
A Kurd from Dalarna!
Dalkurd is the name of a valley horse painted in Kurdistan's colors.
And ... /laughs /
It was painted by an artist named Bawer Elmek ... /Laughter /
Shut up!
Can you be silent now?
- He lived in Mora during the 80s and 90s.
–Dalkurts ... - Dalkurd.
-What did you say?
–Dalkurd.
Not Kurt!
So ... me ...
Tricky.
It will be no on it.
It's false.
What do you think it is?
I have no idea whatsoever!
But I don't believe in a valley horse.
You think it's false?
You don't trust Thanos?
Congratulations, you got 1 point!
No, Dalkurd is not a valley horse in Kurdish colors.
Dalkurd is a football team called Dalkurd FF.
It was formed in Borlänge by Kurds, 2004.
- Gunilla!
You want to choose a panelist?
-Absolutely!
But you won't be able to do that.
Do you know why?
You have received a letter.
What pillows.
- There you are!
And here I am - Dogge Doggelito.
Live from Northern Botkyrka.
Sometimes in the resort you hear the phrase "Abow".
- It was smart.
- So what do you think?
Do you think Dogge ...?
-He is lying.
- It doesn't feel like "Abow" ...?
- I say it's false.
- So "Abow" does not mean "I bow"?
I bow to you.
Congratulations to your first point!
Thanks!
That makes me happy.
"Abow" does not mean "I bow", that means "it was la 'fuck".
- Yes, that sounds so.
- Big o, put an abow.
Abow, yes ...
Najs.
- Frida, now we drive.
- We drive at Branne, then.
- Branne?
The cartel.
Joking aside, it's ...
This is true.
These are the oil riots Johnsson.
They are so called.
They run a bunch of petrol stations in southern Sweden.
They have ... they really buy oil.
God, what a hard time!
I want to say no on it.
-Okay.
-I do not know.
I got to learn ...
Another girl who was here said that you should not trust jugs.
--Wow!
- So you don't trust Branne?
-No, I do not.
-What the hell?
Unfortunately, Frida.
No point to you.
Branne did not lie.
The Oil Heakers Johnsson is a family business -
- As sells fuels, lubricants - you name it.
They established themselves in Småland and have small stations where the big ones closed down.
Isn't it a bit racist with the sheikh picture?
Arabs' equivalent to Blackface?
-What do you think?
You are Arab.
- I think it's najs.
- If you don't make fun.
- Then it gets wrong ...
- They can't have fun with Arabs.
- You don't get that!
Then it becomes bomb.
It just says "boom"!
Unfortunately, there was no point.
We move on to Mattias.
- Wear.
Both Filip and Big O are ... - do we criminal out?
Super good guys, I thought.
I choose Filip.
Filip, who said the winged words:
It was the Left Party's Catarina Wahlgren -
- As the city council ended with a rap on equality.
She said, "We are all born with different spoons in the mouth, the man."
In other words, she said: "Ant Wan, who are you to sell arenas, the man."
"I'm also here to sell rap" - Catarina Wahlgren.
The thing about politicians singing is not super -uncomfortable in Sweden.
- So I trust you.
-It's true?
That is absolutely right.
Sure it's true!
For those of you who do not remember - 2021, V's Catarina Wahlgren - finished
- A speech in the municipal council with a rap.
The text was about inequality and that we are born with different spoons in the mouth.
Of course, we should look at it now.
We are all born with different spoons in the mouth, man
And EY, we were born in Stockholm, Sweden's richest region
at least on choice of care
What?
Gunilla, you have 1 point.
So has Frida.
So if you take this question, you move on.
It hangs some on it.
- Then Big "O" must be very kind.
- Big "O"?
- Best Gunilla ...
- Big o ... –Jalla, brother, Jalla.
Gunilla, what is different is that they are pork.
It's Haram, Yani.
- If you want to be Jetski ... - the man, it's a pity for her!
That's enough, the man.
What is different ... what is different is -
- The meat there is not beef or lamb.
Do you understand?
It's pork.
So if you want to specify… /Laughter /
I try to!
So if you want to pecificerra ... must you say: "I want beef or lamb."
If you want to be halal, you want to chill to you ...
Applause!
-What are you saying?
You look skeptical.
-Yes.
Kebab is definitely not pork.
God, what it's hard!
I actually think that can be true.
You think it's true?
Do you know what, Gunilla?
Congratulations!
You got another one.
It is true that on some parts of the west coast, the kebab is made of pork -
- For those bastards have not learned what a gyros are.
The largest Islamophobic hate crime in Sweden is -
- Selling a kebab made on pork!
Gunilla, Congratulations - you have moved on.
Frida, unfortunately ... Thanks for being competing.
Fun to have you here.
Now it's time for the duel.
The duel goes like this: I choose the panelists that you can talk to.
For each question I choose two panelists:
One speaks the truth and one is lying.
You should find the true answer.
Mattias, your first two panelists are Thanos and Evelyn.
Thanos and Evelyn:
It was a beef.
Dr.
Alban was angry that he felt they harassed him.
They made sketches where they imitated him -
- And bush and talked like him.
He said, "This is not okay."
- That was what the beef was about.
- A Chinese Dr.
Albanian...
- It was stable.
- No, this is how it is ...
Dr.
Alban was in a radio program at SR–
- Where the host refused to say "Doctor".
He referred to Dr.
Alban only as alban-
–And Dr.
Alban very angry because he is a trained dentist.
So he thought he should be addressed as a doctor.
Have!
It was the sickest thing I've heard.
- Do you trust Thanos?!
- Mattias, you are an accountant, right?
- Yes, accounting consultant.
- You count money.
-Yes.
- What sounds more logical?
The thing is that both are very logical.
That is the problem.
But do you trust the Greek or Chinese?
You buy that Dr.
Alban is a trained dentist?
You think he stands and says, "Can you gap?"
I know that Dr.
Alban is a dentist, so it sounds likely.
I actually think ...
Because you questioned Dr.
Alban's dentistry ...
- And Evelyn is "in my heart forever".
- You act on the emotions?
White men are usually attracted by Chinese women.
We will get a happy ending.
Evelyn, Mattias chose to believe in -
- That Dr.
Alban lacquered for refusing to title him Doctor.
- Unfortunately, it is false.
-No!
It was Thanos who told the truth.
Beefen between Dr.
Alban and Sr-
- traded about the program "Pippirull", where they bush and mimicked him.
It was a good while ago, but we have got them to send a video greeting.
Hi, Ahmed and all the comedians in Ifs!
Mårten Andersson here.
I want to say sorry, once and for all.
I apologize for the bus ring - but there are only 200-300 pieces.
I say sorry!
Or as you would have said:
"All, they 'don't work. They' not stable. Hop. Stop!"
No point this time.
Your two panelists are Adeel and Big O.
Adeel and Big O, in Kosovo there is a groom tradition - with Hi Dhander:
Jalla, Paki.
In Albanian ... before the wedding so ... Some Albanians like ...
Veva ... I'm Paki and can't.
So before he gets married, relatives and friends have to give him one last round.
He should get hit, so he knows what to expect if he does something wrong.
- I helped you last time.
-Yes.
-How?
- Let me talk to the point.
Okay, Gunilla ...
It is an old tradition to tattoo the Albanian bird on the back-
- So me hi dhander is a very old method -
- To show that you are married to both woman and country.
You yeah both.
So every Alban has a bird on his back?
- We take it then.
- You can't fool her that way.
I helped Shurda last time.
What do you feel, Gunilla?
Do you believe in Adeel?
- That you abuse the groom?
- You raise him.
Or do you believe in Big O, that you tattoo the Albanian bird -
- As a symbol of both woman and country.
- No, I believe in Adeel.
- You choose Adeel?
Gunilla ...
You are from the resort.
Congratulations!
You got your first point.
High five!
Me hi Dhander is an old tradition for some Albanians before the marriage.
The groom meets relatives and friends -
- As the groom beats, as a last raising before getting married.
Mattias, we continue with you.
You should talk to Zinat and Branne.
Talk?
The last Swede lives at that address - Adam Tensta.
It's ... sorry, it's Mattias, right?
It is the first Swedish Halal slaughterhouse that was opened.
It is also open at holidays, like Ramadan.
It is open to the public during holidays.
Then you get to see the slaughter, if someone turns years ...
No, it is actually an apartment there that is a museum.
Any Svenne can go in there and see how we lived in the 60s.
Before the Babs arrived.
If we really cultivated potatoes in the living room -
- Or if it was in the nursery.
I am completely lost here.
I have no idea how to think.
- Branne told me that there ... - I think he took what I said.
You can focus on zinat.
I just renovate the memory.
Zinat told me it's a museum apartment -
-So you can see what it looked like in Tensta in the 60s.
Thanks.
I'm going on ... Branne.
Actually ... It sounds least unreasonable.
You choose to believe in Branne?
Unfortunately, Mattias.
There is not a halal slaughterhouse in an apartment ...
... in Tensta.
The true answer is what Zinat tried to tell.
It is a museum apartment where you can see how it was in Tensta in the 60s.
- Gunilla, should we invest in full pot?
-Yes.
The last question - you get Filip and Elaf.
When you hang out at Möllevångstorget in Malmö you can hear the term "Gawad".
Well, this word you hear at the end of the day.
When you hear it is time to find fruit and vegetables -
- For that means sale or good price.
You hear the vegetable dealers scream, simply.
Incorrect.
The correct answer is that "Gawad" is a belligerent -
- But it has a meaning in the form of who says it and not against whom.
When some elderly people say it is more negative than when someone younger says it.
Come at me bitch.
What should you say now?
- But what does the word itself mean?
- HALIK.
-Pimp?
- Factically, here you get it.
What this means is Elaf's manager, Halik, as you have to pronounce correctly ...
With the enthusiasm Filip has, I believe in Filip.
- You chose to believe in Filip?
-Yes.
Gunilla, you got a full pot in the final round.
"Gawad" means pimp in Iraqi.
Elderly people use the derogatory -
- But for younger people, it's more like "Player, Player, Player" ...
Congratulations, Gunilla!
You won here tonight.
- A huge applause for the winner!
Now you will get your prize.
The chairman of Dalkurd FF, Bawer, is here.
Sweden's first Kurdish Dala horse!
An applause for our winner -
- Our fantastic panel, the wonderful competitors and our incredible audience!
Thanks!
- See you in the semi -finals.
- See you next week.
Texting: Cecilia Täng Sveriges Television AB 2024