- When will the party then, Lina?
-Tomorrow night.
Everyone should sleep over.
Sleep over?
It's only 50 meters there.
You know how it is at those parties.
-No.
What about those parties?
- Yes, what about those parties?
- We talk, have fun ... you know.
- No, I don't actually.
- You never tell.
- Then I would never go!
- We have never forbidden you to go.
-Yes!
You were eight years old and wanted to go to Bajsk beer party!
The upbringing is difficult.
We're talking about getting kids, but ... is it worth the trouble?
No.
I'm kidding.
You do not get the community you have with your children otherwise.
If you don't get a dog ... you get to sleep over if everyone else gets.
Good, then I don't have to ask Dad, huh?
He never lets me go!
Now he just thinks about that match.
- This morning he trained towards my door!
- Go up and tell him then!
No idea.
I just have to stand in goal ...
- What is it for the match you are talking about?
- Gustav's boys team has some anniversary.
It feels pretty good.
Two quick draws, past the defense ... goals!
- Tough resistance.
Most the green ... - it's important with preparation.
Where have you made of all the food?
- No danger, I ate it up.
- What are you celebrating?
Exactly 25 years ago we played final against Backlura.
Ha, what a match!
- It stood 2–2 at full time.
- Gustav decided everything.
- He shot five meters outside the goal ... - How did you track all friends?
- If it is important, you are happy to lie in!
- All lives here in Vivalla.
That is not really true.
Jalle went directly into the world.
New York, Tokyo, Paris ... He knows how to live life.
- So he won't either ... - He has his life, much to do!
- Dad, I have to ask ... —s.
I have to go out on my round.
What he is ambitious!
Which round does he take?
The light track?
He takes a lap around the square by car.
He says it fans so nice.
He doesn't listen to me!
You know it's something he always listens to.
Fuss.
Have you never thought about becoming a professional?
Yes, but I do not regret that I chose the family.
-You're lying!
-Yes.
I can't cope.
Should I set up the cones right away?
- No, I need some proteins.
- I thought you would lose weight!
-I do.
I only eat the cream.
- Dad, I think you make the victory goal.
- Have you had something broken again?
-No.
We rarely praise dad.
I go and run push ups.
- Line, what are you doing?
- I want to go to that party.
- Yeah ... it's just going?
-No.
I have to get to sleep over too.
- Dad will say no.
- It's just going in and saying it!
- He actually understands more than we think.
- You are right, max.
Thanks.
Idiot!
... twenty, twenty ...
... twenty -two, twenty -three, twenty -four ...
-Dad!
-... twenty -seven ... - Hello, old man!
- You have said that we should be honest.
- Awesome.
Did I say that?
On Saturday, Ulrika will have a small party.
Thanks, old man, but I have this match.
Listen!
Everyone else should sleep over.
I would also like to do it.
You know everyone!
It's Jeanette, Sofie, Tobias, Marcus ... the usual ones.
–And Petter?
- Why are you afraid of Petter?
Sit at the back with you at the cinema - I just don't like that!
How do you know we have been to the cinema?
Do you spy on me?
- "Spying" has such a boring sound ... - Can I go or not?
- What does mom say?
- It's okay if you like it.
May I decide?
Oh, damn ...
Then I decide ...
... that you get to sleep over.
I am overprotective sometimes.
If I'm going to have fun, you will too!
Svensson.
Gustav Svensson.
Postman, yes.
Jarl?
Jalle?!
Is it you, Jalle?
Where are you?
On an airplane?
Do you come here for the match?
- He comes to the match!
Good hotel?
Never come to question!
Silent!
You will sleep here with us!
You get to meet my family.
No, they have nothing else for themselves.
-What then?
- My daughter jumps with joy.
Sure, Jalle.
See you there, yes.
For phase, Jalle.
Hello then, Jalle.
- Jalle, Jalle ... it was Jalle.
- Yeah, it was Jalle ...
He is coming here.
You get to meet your dad's best friend.
- But the party then?
- Party it will be!
When Jalle starts - oh, oh, oh ...
Hello.
Gustav, you have a match tomorrow.
I was going to go out with Annika.
Will you or I tell you?
You!
Guess who sleeps on the couch tomorrow.
- You, if you arrive late home.
-No.
Jalle!
Jalle Norén.
My BFF!
He is on his way here.
He called from his private aircraft.
-Perfect.
Then I go out with Annika.
-You do not understand...
Jalle should only stay for a day and must feel welcome.
- You think I should fit up with you.
-No.
He should meet my family.
- But you have time with the other, so ... - gustav, it's Annika's poetry evening.
- You don't like poetry?
- I'll do that!
Understand me ... I want to show you!
You are the finest I have.
So you said when you wanted me to repaint the boat too.
- Remember how nice it was!
- I have friends I want to meet.
- Jalle is my best friend!
- You haven't talked about 25 years.
This is what girls never understand!
We do not need to meet.
Jalle and I have each other here.
- Heart sits on the other side ... —oroa not!
- I fix what needs to be prepared.
- I haven't said yes.
You didn't do that when I freed either.
-What's that?
-My Life.
Don't read anything more fun?
Here I have collected the best memories.
What summer we had, Jalle and I!
Here we have just climbed into the neighbor's oak.
- What madman.
Hanging in one hand!
- Where are you?
I had just lost.
It was the first summer we met - then we hung together every day.
Here Jalle turns fifteen years old.
I was there evenly.
- There, down in the right corner, I stand.
- Jalle was the girls' favorite?
I was not far behind!
When the picture was taken we would meet some girls.
- Was that why you looked so happy?
- No, I had just eaten.
Here's the pictures' picture!
So we looked just before kick off at Backlura.
–25 years ago ... then you were on top!
- What you look young, and slim!
-It's not me.
I'm sitting there.
- Sensors that I didn't see the match.
- But you came on the banquet.
- You offered beer in the dressing room!
Here!
Look!
Do you remember?
- My old Amazon, 57th.
- Of course, I remember.
It was the nicest thing I knew when we went to Björkudden.
Just you and me.
What memories ...
Yes, such cars are no longer made.
You look at pictures, and then the feelings and the mood come back.
Okay.
I ignore Annika's poetry evening.
Do you mean it?!
What would I do without you?
Here.
A list of everything that needs to be fixed.
I will help you if Lina is allowed to go to her party.
- Maybe she meets Jalle for a while.
- You don't follow?
- Gustav ... - I promise.
19.00: Jalle's arrival.
National anthem, followed by short welcome fireworks.
- Card Welcome Fireworks?
- We save the big for the dessert.
Yes Yes...
I promise, I follow another time.
Your poems are very nice.
The one about the tortoise and the tissue too!
Greeting Göran, and good luck!
Hello.
- Hi, has Dad talked to you?
- Yes, this morning.
I will serve from the right and not in a hurry when I show slides ...
I have to go when I'm done.
Well, I will be half past two ...
I make sure you get away.
It is a dinner in all simplicity.
Where should it stand - the friendship standard?
We'll keep it up when they arrive.
Nämen ... does he have no sense of proportions?
Wait until you hear the welcome speech!
- Are you ready?
FANFARE
The gods of the Olympics may be faded when Jalle ...
Turn off!
Now you forget what Dad has said.
I'm going to make a nice dinner.
Just be kind and pretty dressed.
-How is it going?
Is everything ready?
- You would help with the pictures.
- I and Göran have arranged one thing.
- Pentecress Opera?
Dancing bears?
Look out through the window.
Nämen look, an Amazon!
Yes!
EN 57th.
All original.
Jalle will not believe his eyes.
- A friend of mine owns it.
- I will take care of it as my child!
Göran, take the car and stick!
- Feel free to take Jalle over on a drink.
- First, he should see 1,100 slides ...
Yes, you want to show how nice you had it these years.
It is mostly short at Gustav at work.
In such a thing where Jalle and I cruise around the square.
We planned the future.
What ideas!
If we held together, we would have gone as far as possible.
- He does not seem to be handicapped alone ... - and now you will get together again.
Just an idea ... Nothing strange.
-What then?
Europe's largest grocery store!
- What is Göran talking about?
When I got an idea, Jalle hung on.
I thought we could do something new.
- As Europe's largest grocery store?!
- Don't hang up on the wording.
- Now it is a place to knit.
- I have to go too.
Feel free to come over.
We will be in a couple of hours.
Don't be sorry if there is no department store.
One must be realistic.
He may want us to do something in the US instead.
Is Petter there?
Who is he dancing with?!
Ingela?!
!
Try to lock her in or something.
On toa or something ...
I hurry as much as possible.
- Where is the maximum somewhere?
- I thought he was in the kitchen with you.
Max!
Come up from the basement.
They are coming soon.
I don't want these clothes!
It's Dad who has fixed them ...
- You don't look wise!
-You look great.
You look like a successful dwarf.
- Lina, put out the napkins.
I have to help Max with the fly.
- Hi, has he come yet?
- Don't you read poetry?
No, I got so curious about Jalle.
Does he have his own jet?
- Have you talked to Gustav?
- No - Göran.
- That Gustav is best ice cream with one!
- Yes, it is undeniably a mystery.
- You would leave them in peace!
-I will.
Did you bring the camcorder?
- No, really not!
- Then I have to take this one.
- Now they come.
- See how he looks - then you have to go.
Lina, pick up the standard.
- Max, stand here!
And the text ... the melody is "SJ, SJ, old friend".
Jalle, Jalle, old friend think you're here again!
The years go by, but you consist, our very best friend
-HURRAY!
-Look here!
- But where is Jalle?
- On the way to London.
- He had some important meeting.
- But dinner then?
Eat it up!
Should we take the song again?
- But Gustav ... - are you very sad, dad?
No why?
Everything I thought meant something when I was young was just air.
I didn't recognize him.
When I offered a beer he declined no.
- It wasn't good for the figure ... - it's true maybe ...
He was also not interested in me.
-That's weird!
- What did he say when he saw the Amazon?
- He didn't see it.
He has a driver.
- This car is as nice as yours.
- What happened to it really?
- Unfortunately, it disappeared.
- It went through the ice.
- We were delayed and took a new road.
Dad tried to embrace over Vättern.
-What are you doing here?
You miss the party.
- I can be here with you instead.
Don't feel you must.
-Good!
- Max, where are you going?
Save the cake from Göran and Annika.
- I put a little under your bed.
Eating is the only thing I'm good at.
- No, you know many things.
-Like what?
You can all Östergötland's postal code by the way.
I forgot to ask how it went.
We won.
3–2.
I made the victory.
- Then you must have become a match hero!
- They carried me on the shoulders around the square.
- Did they orde it?
-Yes almost.
They dropped me outside Consum.
Gustav, can you get to Björkudden now in the winter?
You and I can have an anniversary.
You and I and an Amazon from –57.
Should we check out our old place, at the dock?
Lena, I like you.
Hold the hat, Mrs. Svensson!
Hello, Lena ... - Gustav ...
I have something that can cheer you up.
A poem that I would have read ...
Start!
The sun is rising - the morning red sea is resting, silver scrup ...
Start, your bang!
SVT Program Settling Karin Esvik