In tonight's section of Ifs, immigrants for Swedes:
Sweden's most fun Chinese: Evelyn Mok.
The Roman-Jewish horse dealer: Chang Frick.
The world's Swedish Arab: Elaf Ali.
The funny Persen: Behrad Rouzbeh.
Skåne's moral conscience: Petrina Solange.
The infamous Greek from Alby: Thanos Fotas.
The queen of PK elite: Bilan Osman.
My Fakking Brother: Hassan Makaveli.
Sweden's second best celebrity dancer: Filip Dikmen.
And of course: La Camilla Henemark.
So it is our program manager, the incredible Ahmed Berhan!
Welcome to the IFS, the program which has a wider range than the caramel king.
My name is Ahmed Berhan.
You look at the quiz about all culture in Sweden.
Give a warm applause to our competitors.
Tonight we have Peter, Lisa and Johan!
The contestant chooses one in the panel that I ask another question.
It is up to it to decide whether the panelist is lying or not.
We have been drawn about who is starting.
They are a small advantage to start.
The lucky one who won the draw was no less than Johan.
Johan, which of the panelists would you like to start talking to?
- Filip!
- I choose Petrina.
Najs.
For the bomb belt is not done in XL.
You have to stay in trim.
Do you know what I love?
Hassan just: "Did she know?"
It is so.
It is embarrassing if you are at Kastrup and stand there ...
It's like Advent for Christians, but you count on Muhammad's birth.
As simple as that.
- Yes, what do you say?
- I don't believe it.
No.
You don't think Ramadan is the Muslims Christmas calendar?
You do that right in. Congratulations, you've got your first point!
Ramadan is the month when Prophet Muhammad received the Qur'an.
Muslims are fasted to show humility to God.
Cruelly.
Congratulations!
Peter, it's your turn to shine.
- Camilla, for AIK?
Does obviously feel?
-No.
But, for the hell ...
Good choice, Peter.
This is very embarrassing.
You've probably heard of it.
It is not said who it is.
It is actually Pernilla Wahlgren.
I sat there and everyone looked at me.
- But Pernilla screamed this.
- Racism is white.
- Peter, what do you say?
-No.
I do not think so.
You were too fast, too obvious.
You just snapped up a name.
- But I was there!
- I don't know if you speak the truth.
Camilla, typically Sweden to pull down one when you have self -confidence.
You think Camilla is lying?
You do that right in that.
It was embarrassing.
- Stretch for everyone who screamed.
- I was, that was me.
I don't know what flew in me, but she mumbled something on American -
- Or some other language that someone said was Scanian.
You are just casually Anna in Jimmie Åkesson's spirit.
I've never been so happy to be dark -skinned.
Anna is blonde.
- Who did you scream for?
- Anna Duck.
As soon as you said Anna Anka, I heard someone in the audience: "That's right."
"She's going to speak Swedish."
Thanks, Camilla.
Peter, congratulations to your first point.
Lisa, who do you choose to talk to?
- I got some Connection with Elaf.
- I think you are very beautiful.
--Oooh!
-Elaf, you have to stop fucking.
- I don't.
- You have to get grades in the program.
- Each program.
- Tyd, quiet!
It actually means golden snake.
And mothers say it to their sons.
That is why Iranian guys have such good confidence.
They have to go around all their lives and hear that they have a golden penis.
What do you feel, Lisa?
Does it sound Persian?
- You have a fact here.
- Do you show, right?
I'll probably buy it.
I have absolutely no idea.
It is difficult.
But I trust what we built up.
That's right.
It's the most Persian I've heard.
That is absolutely true.
You have combed each point together.
- Johan, who do you choose?
- Hassan.
-Brother.
Let's go.
Newborn Kurds.
I will explain.
I've had to live with it all my life.
You enter puberty too fast as a child and get a beard.
I was a bearded child.
That's what bearded children stand for.
When I was a bearded child
- Yes, what do you say?
- I think it's false.
Just right.
Clearly he lied.
It is a term used derogatory about asylum -seeking guys -
- Which lies about his age.
- Peter?
- The car.
- I was so shocked.
- He was ready.
The stereotypical image of a Swedish is light hair, light complexion and blue eyes.
We don't really know that.
But what we know is that it was the same people -
- As the children's friends did not invite dinner.
So much we know.
I just wanted to tell the truth.
- Tradition is tradition.
–It goes way back.
Did you want the answer?
Sorry.
The answer is ...
They looked much like me, but with blue eyes.
It was black people.
But they had blue eyes.
-What do you think?
- No, I say.
It sounded too ... hope it.
/People are unmatched and laughing/
-Okay.
The explanation is ... –Wakanda, stand up!
Okay!
I offer it.
-Okay.
-It is okay.
Come come!
It was too widespread.
It felt like I had it.
Then when you just ...
I was hoping you gave me a hint that it wasn't so.
- Then my answer.
- Unfortunately, Peter.
It's true.
According to Genetics Research at Uppsala University -
–Aded the first people to populate Sweden 11,000 years ago -
- Blue eyes, but dark complexion.
Now, dear viewers, two of our bolts have broken -
- Because the energy in the room is on the fucking top.
You still have the colors that you can see on the scoreboard.
Let's move on.
Lisa, your turn.
Who do you choose to chew with?
- I put my fate in Philip's hands.
-Yes!
In the commute between Stockholm and Södertälje you often hear the word abri.
"The controllers are coming!"
The background to the word, now I look at you Lisa ...
It really means inspector.
It is used blates in between -
- To warn of the police, security guard or who it is now.
It does not in itself mean that the inspectors will -
- But if you hear "ABRI, ABRI" it is a warning signal for a superior.
I don't have so many reference points on the word ...
You're lying to me.
Abri, you do that right.
Filip lied to you.
Abri is Syrian for my son.
It can also be insulting if you do not know each other.
Congratulations, Lisa.
You got one more point.
- We move on to Johan.
-Thanos.
-Hey man.
- Hit me!
-Thanos!
-Comfortable.
Throwback.
Brand clothing comes and goes.
The bomber jacket had both tough place guys and Swedes.
Adidas pants have all been wearing.
Canada Goose too.
But the shoes I find it difficult to see them on locality guys.
- So these are those shoes.
-Okay, the bombs are going away.
- The bomber jacket goes away?
- You say I ...?
- Do you think that Thanos is lying?
--What are you saying?
- The shoes are definitely included.
- It's the tough place guys.
With the fat sole?!
- I just want to ... the fat?
- Tranos, I have the picture.
- You have the picture?
- You wore them.
Let them laugh at you, because you got one more point.
-Thanos!
--Habibi!
The shoes, jacket and pants were something used during the 90's.
But the winter jacket we did not start baking, I mean to buy, until ...
... 00s.
Congratulations to the score.
- Peter, your turn.
- Weera, now we do it together.
Beckna means sales.
You sell.
Most often you refer to cannabis and other forms of drugs.
A longer, you might say, or Santa Claus maybe others call it.
–Oda definitions.
-Thanks.
So true.
It is right.
- Yes, I say.
- Congratulations, the man.
Clearly you get points.
- Good worked, Peter.
- Lisa?
–Evelyn.
Hello!
He has a very giant name.
I don't remember it, so I read it.
I think it's African, but I'll read this.
-Are you ready?
-Yes.
Rochandienelyshiaonnevehesh ...
Walla.
She calls demons, the man.
I felt the same.
I just: Is that the beginning of The Grudge, right?
These are dancing demons.
-Okay, continues.
- Fuck, is it longer?
- Has the Swedish Tax Agency not said no?
- It's long.
Okay...
- Should I take it from the beginning?
- No, we only have 28 minutes.
Nickname only.
Koyannishkoyati ... Koyannishkoyatsius ...
Do you know what, Evelyn?
So you don't get a stroke ...
Good work.
- An applause to Evelyn.
- Lis, what do you say?
- I have difficulty with artist names.
So that...
Yes, that is true.
Who finds ...?
Or?
You believe ... at what Evelyn just read for you?
- Well!
- Is it Califfa's name?
- It's false.
- Obviously as hell it is false.
There was nothing African in the name at all.
Kaliffa's real name is Olle Kaliffa Karlsson.
Unfortunately, Peter, you have no chance to move on to the final.
But Johan, you can bring home full pot.
Time to ask the last question in the first round.
- To Chang.
--Le Chang.
A religious question in the SD country Skåne.
There are two pilgrim walks.
One goes to Ullared, one to Thailand.
When you go to Thailand, you know - the lady on the purchase.
The largest group in Sweden is Thai.
I swear, the man.
No.
I don't believe in that.
You don't believe in Chang.
You do that right in. It's false.
The correct answer is women born in Syria.
86 822 persons were counted in 2021.
They have passed the Finns which today are in second place.
That, my ladies and gentlemen, means that Lisa and Johan go to the final!
A large applause to Peter who is allowed to leave us now.
Fun to have you with.
It wasn't enough.
Thanks.
- An applause to Peter!
Now, my ladies and gentlemen, it's time for the final round.
First to five points.
But there is a twist during the final.
If you answer a question incorrectly, the opponent gets the point.
Johan, when you won the first round you start the final.
Camilla.
Here was tried.
We knew that.
Good there.
/ Whistles/ shit!
It is happening now.
I'm probably the worst immigrant in this group.
It's not something I consume.
I have heard that it is sunflower seeds that they eat and sprinkles around them.
Immigrant chips, also called.
- Pipas.
-It sounds good.
- But I think you are lying.
- Maybe it, maybe so.
- You think Camilla is lying?
-Unfortunately.
- You don't think Ortenfolk likes chips?
- I'm convinced.
There you did away with it.
Camilla did not lie at all.
Pipas, as many here know, are sunflower seeds.
Johan, you didn't just miss a point.
Without Lisa, Lisa got a point.
- What do you choose as the first panelist?
- Petrina.
Swedish women after a trip to Gambia.
It is Gambia's largest export product.
No one there has them.
Only Swedish women have them.
This is then ... I think it's the Cocalero Indians from Bolivia-
- As you sometimes see playing at city festivals.
It's their national costume.
It's Latin American.
Not African, as you might think.
I have a mom who has traveled a bit in Africa ...
But...
Lisa was such a bit from getting in that dress today.
There is a risk that I will do away with confidence.
- But I say you are lying.
- You think Petrina is lying?
Obviously Petrina is lying.
2–0.
False.
It is a Somali dress called Baati.
In the past you only had it at home, nowadays you also go out in it.
It's comfort clothes.
- Johan?
Which of our panelists would you like to talk to?
Think gold.
Gold Penis.
Behrad, my brother.
That's when the eldest son has been able to afford to buy his first BMW.
No.
Nowruz is a ceremony that you have after the male circumcision.
It means taking the bit you got, it can be of gold -
–And put it in a special type of bowl ...
I hear that this sounds strange.
Then you light candles around the bowl and sing songs.
Then you send around it in the family -
- And so everyone can say their wishes to it.
-What do you feel?
- It sounds solemn.
We have something similar in midsummer.
- Sprinkle around foreskin into a bowl?
-Yes.
But it is not called so.
The small frogs, the small frogs are funny to see
-Just.
- But you dance around a cock after all.
-Yes kind of.
- Check you who have taught your Swedish culture.
Good black shells.
-True or false?
- False.
I have to get a point now.
Sure it's false.
Congratulations, you've got a point.
--Nowruz is New Year's Eve.
Ish.
-Yes.
I love how specific we are.
New Year's Eve.
Nowruz falls on the spring day equation and is celebrated for 18 days.
- Lice, who do you choose?
- I choose Hassan.
Dishdashe is ... sorry, all Arabs out there, all men.
But they hate to wash and be in the kitchen.
I think everyone agrees.
And it's half English, half Arabic, where the dish is disk -
–And Dash means hatred.
It's disk hat.
It is common at Arabs to say Dishdashe.
Men should not wash.
It has become a thing and it has come to Europe.
- My guy.
- And I love it.
It sounded a little too easy to be true.
So I think you are lying.
Lisa, you do it right in. Clearly Hassan is lying.
Dishdashe is a traditional Arab costume.
- Johan?
Time for you to shine again.
Who do you choose?
–Alaf.
- Yeah!
Swedish snoopes are in 24th place in size.
Danes, because they are such fucking cocks.
No, according to recent statistics this year, it is Ecuador in South America -
- So has the longest, and that is then in erected state.
Permission?
You say so?
Stand.
Shit the same.
It's type 18 centimeters.
Ish.
But not in gold?
It's far.
Also feels like someone from Ecuador has written the survey.
-What are you saying?
- This must be false.
- You don't trust Elaf's cock knowledge?
-No I do not think so...
- Unfortunately, Johan.
It's true.
- Aaha!
I like that the whole audience was like this: "Wait a minute!"
/ Piper/ Ecuador!
I'll go there.
Me too.
Because you answered wrong, it means that Lisa got another point.
If you are observant and your math is on top, you will see you have 4 points.
The final is first to 5. Reply correctly, so you have won the entire competition.
- Much of games.
Who should you trust?
- Who do you choose to put the cards on?
Maybe I should trust Hassan's judgment on Filip.
Thank you!
Were you forced?
Hijab just covers the hair.
Okay.
Niqab covers everything except the eyes.
Imagine Ninja Turtles reverse.
Hello!
Superstar, superninja here.
While a can cover everything.
Think hide and seek.
- Eyes too.
- Giantbra.
Show again.
Blind.
Peekaboo!
You are the most educational duo I met.
It feels sunny.
I think that's true.
Filip gave you the truth.
Congratulations, Lisa.
You have a point!
Not only that.
You won the whole competition!
Applause for tonight's winner Lisa!
You don't go from here empty -handed.
You get your IFS diploma.
And a flower.
Give a huge applause to our competitors, this fantastic audience -
- To your home and last but not least our incredible panel!
Thank you to all of you who have looked.
Feel the best!
Texting: Cristel Nyqvist Swedish Media Text for SVT