In tonight's section of Ifs - immigrants for Swedes:
Gothenburg's best Somalis: Assia Dahir.
Greek from Alby: Thanos Fotas.
Sweden's second best celebrity dancer: Filip Dikmen.
The world's Swedish Arab: Elaf Ali.
The Kimonotwitch Radio Patcher: Victor Linnér.
Sweden's most fun Chinese: Evelyn Mok.
The tour leader who became Punchline winner Ato "The Champ" Karlsson.
Youtubing Sphinx from Malmö: Megic Mike.
Worship from Västerort: Melody Farshin.
The gold boy from Rinkeby who keeps it genuine: Martin Mutumba.
Last but not least, our program manager: Ahmed Berhan!
Welcome to IFS.
The only SVT program with more mythomaniacs than a party leadership debate.
My name is Ahmed Berhan.
You look at the quiz about all culture in Sweden.
How about applauding today's competitors: Pia, Christer and Frida!
We drew backstage about who would start.
And Christer won.
- Are you ready to pop that Cherry?
-Absolutely.
Well then.
Which of the panelists do you feel you can call in a scam?
Since I have a black -yellow heart, I have to trust one.
Don't start with color so early.
What the fuck, man!
Mutumba.
You are from Västerort?
You should know the question.
There is one who is always late.
- For example, melody.
-You're the one to talk?
-What are you saying?
Do you trust Martin?
- Just now I can't do it.
Very well done.
It is definitely not a person who comes late.
A collective name for people from Eritrea and Ethiopia.
But also people who don't like to arrive on time.
Congratulations, Christer, you got the first point of the evening.
We continue with the next competitor.
- Frida, who do you want to chew with today?
I probably want to start with Assia.
The subject is close to the heart.
The word drug ...
It is a Gothenburg word.
It comes from thicks.
When they get completely cuddled, they get Lockjaws.
The jaws keep on like this, squeeze and drugs.
The word drug comes from there.
- "Damn, what we crap we are."
I do not know her.
Assia, thank you for your reply.
- Frida, what do you feel?
Do not know.
I don't feel ... crack?
In and of itself ... there is there.
But I don't think it's true.
It's false.
- It's false?
-Yes.
You should have trusted Assia, because that's true.
!
I thought drugs were old, but it's hose.
You thought: Gustav in, he and his guys rode there ...
It's true.
All my friends from Gothenburg are drugs.
- In itself, when you say it.
-That's right.
Frida, there will be no point.
Better luck next time.
Over to the last participant.
- Pia, how does it feel?
- Can you pick a point?
-Hope.
- What of our panelists do you ask?
- Melody.
--Shoo.
-Shoo!
Street cred.
What happens?
- She was prepared.
- Pia is the cool teacher.
- We will be bonding in the kiosk later.
-Absolutely.
Melody, you like to cook.
You're good at that too.
There are different things Suedis have at home to feel multi-cult.
Nah.
What is common is that these are spicy products.
But the National Food Agency has required an adaptation to Swedish taste buds -
–And babies.
If you really want to offend a black skull, invite an indian -
- On chaite, naan bread and curry spice on the side.
Melody, you are so damn right.
It's true.
- Pia!
- Forgiveness, I took your role.
Sorry, I took your role.
That was not the point.
Sorry, did you want to say something?
Old school there.
I like that you wirely with melody and want to get a good foot with her.
But her answer was false.
-No!
–The correct answer is:
All are double words.
Both parts of the word mean the same thing.
Chai means tea, salsa sauce and curry spice mix.
-You are welcome.
-Yes!
Christer, you started strongly and are the only one with points.
We see if you can increase your lead.
Who do you want to chew with?
–Alaf.
–Yes.
Something you say when you are tired of someone or want it to shut up.
We often say it to each other in my family.
Verbatim it means "eat poop".
- What do you say, Christer?
- It sounds aggressive.
I think so.
Do you think I sound aggressive?
Just right.
It literally means "eat poop".
Elaf, does your family tell it to each other or just to you?
- We say it to each other.
- They haven't said it often enough.
She just told me it out.
Excuse.
His interpreter is coming soon.
This is IFS, not SFI, Mike.
- Frida, ready to get a point?
-I can try.
The only thing you can do.
Who do you want to chew with?
–Evelyn.
-Hello Hello.
-Skåne.
-No!
No, but it used to be Spain.
Thailand is now the country where the most Swedes live.
It has been about 100,000. Everyone is the ones I met on Tinder.
Apparently, they could afford to go to thailand.
Do you think Evelyn tells the truth?
True or false?
False.
Very good job, Frida.
You've received your first point.
Welcome into the match.
The real answer is the United States where there are about 150,000.
Then comes Norway, Spain and the UK at 90,000.
In Thailand, only 20,000 live and everyone has mastered at Evelyn.
- CHRISTERS HAS POINTS, Frida has points.
-My turn.
- Now we take it.
Who are you talking to?
- I want to talk to Victor.
The art student.
You have smoked grass with all three, huh?
Nah.
All three have shares in the Swedish weapons industry.
It does not surprise me, but I think they have been in prison.
A racist hop there.
- Pia is a gangster, the man.
- Forgive again.
Not really.
You got a point.
Congratulations!
Everyone has been detained when they were in Sweden.
- Cheritr, who do you want to talk to?
-Thanos.
Bazz is English, buzz me.
Then it became Bazz, which means letting me in.
Suburban guys denied the pub can say to the guard:
"You bazz the svens here, but you don't bazz us."
A girl has dated a guy and he doesn't let her in:
"What about your guys? You bazz them, but not me."
Does the guards usually bazz you?
Christer?
In other words...
- You have incorrect information now.
-Okay.
It took.
It felt.
-I apologize.
- Zucchiniturken is lying?
You did absolutely right.
It was false.
- Should we tell us what Bazz means?
- Frida was there and said, "I know."
You were on zucchini.
So Bazz is to lie with someone.
-It is right.
-Point!
No, wait, wait!
You just connect it with zucchini.
It is another program on another channel.
Christer, great work.
- Frida, do you want one more point?
-I can try.
-Believe in yourself.
Who can you read?
- Filip.
- Oh, damn!
- We had eye contact there.
I was hoping for Pia.
She is a gangster, but we drive on Frida.
- Pia is a real brother, a soldier.
-Wait!
Can you regret it?
I love Pia.
- Filip!
A street war between hairdressers and wedding fixers.
No.
Södertalje requirements were a major fight in the 70s-
- Between 30 Assyrians and 200 raggers.
"Sweden's first ravage crawler".
What did they argue about?
Who hated blacks most?
Assia, that's what united them.
"I'm white! - No, I'm white!"
Frida, is the Södertalje requirements what Filip said?
True or false?
I don't know if there are 200 raggers in Södertälje.
It doesn't feel that way.
-This is 70s.
- Before the others came.
- False.
- Can't you do your Swedish history?
Obviously not.
What he said was true.
It was so.
This is the only program where we applaud racial riots.
You, Pia, now we drive.
- Do you also want to test Filip?
No ... - He is used, I was saying.
-Ouch.
- Use me as much as you want.
Pia just: "No Sloppy Seconds for me."
- I want to talk to Ato.
- Hi, Pia!
Hola, Hola!
Racism just goes on.
- Thanks, Pia.
I thought we clicked.
- She thinks you're chile.
- What are you for something?
The Champ, I'm going to ask you a question.
- What is the question, Ahmed?
- She made you Chilean.
- Hola, Cómo Está?
- She thought his name is Watto.
ATO can go to Hollywood and play 13 breeds.
-Alla's job, brother.
—Racially ambiguous.
Ato ...
That you are a bell.
Snitches get bitches.
I think so.
- brother, which place are you from?
- Blue the line, brother.
Can we change places on Pia and him?
And have Pia there instead.
-I did not hear.
I'm a little deaf.
- Nitches get bitches.
I heard you.
--We or white?
-White.
What is to have a white tongue?
It is a discreet way of saying that you have bad breath.
- Did you hear that, Pia?
- I just have to take it in and ...
Since they laugh so much, it must be false.
- Pia thinks you are lying.
- The teachers have never liked me.
Pia is absolutely right.
Thanks.
Thanks for the help.
I swear to my mom, Pia is a brother.
- Can you become my grandmother?
No no!
I can become your girlfriend.
/Bus whistles and applause/
Megic!
That's really good.
Finally you can get a residence permit.
Time for the last question in the round.
Christer, your turn.
Let's see if you are a hundred bump and get everyone right.
- I try.
- He is good, that Christer.
- Mike.
- Day for an image question.
/GIGGLING/
Countries where Russia will open their anal.
- Open what?
- Arens anal.
-Invade.
-Okay.
Can't you Swedish, right?
The blue countries, that part of Europe-
- Are the countries that invite people to food at home.
And the red ...
I am not invited.
You are not sure to be invited.
Do you think Megic Mike's response is true or false?
- I don't believe in Mike.
- It's false?
I said from the beginning that he does not believe in Swedes, not in immigrants!
You could get a full pot.
It is right.
Memen went viral this spring during "Sweden Gate" on social media.
The red colors were countries where you are not offered food, and the blue ...
Wait!
My sister took the student today.
Mom has invited all of Ystad to food.
- I swear, she has invited the whole of Ystad.
- You got your answer.
It rounds off the first round, my ladies and gentlemen.
Awesome work, all competitors.
Unfortunately, one was less amazing.
Frida, good job, but time for you to tag home.
Our two winners who go to the final round are Pia and Christer!
Pia, Christer ... In the final you should come first to five.
But there is a twist.
If you answer wrong, the score goes to the opponent.
Pia, how about you start the round?
I can try.
I do as if I drive on Filip.
Tell them, Pia, "My Brother".
Hey!
Filip?
Can you explain to the room and the Swedish people:
Qhap is a hose for a type of salesman.
Very driven person, ambitious.
I would say that the equivalent in Swedish is an entrepreneur.
A man with entrepreneurial spirit.
A good example of a Qhap is Thanos.
Great Qhap.
Superpopular.
Ten out of ten.
Thank you for the explanation.
- Pia, what do you say?
-True or false.
- Filip, why are you lying to me?
- You took badly.
I feel shame.
- Don't make so against the elderly.
- I think it's false.
-Just right.
You were doing right.
Nice.
I skip the true answer.
Those who google can google.
- CHRISTERS, YOUR TURN.
–Alaf.
Elaf ...
- Are you Elaf or Enough?
- Let he say wrong!
- People usually say Enough to Elaf.
- LOVE.
Elaf Love.
Because the film contains many black characters -
- And takes place in the hood.
SF thought it would attract many with immigrant backgrounds, noise.
They became worried and took in guardians.
Why does no one laugh?
/LAUGH/
- Chrier?
- Tragically, it's certainly true.
Yes, you are absolutely right.
True.
Their motivation was that the hip hop film attracts a certain audience -
- Which is not so used to going to the cinema.
Therefore, kids, you always download film.
Pirate Rise.
1–1.
Very good job by you.
- Pia, are you ready to take it further?
- Yeah.
We drive at Assia.
Deli is an abbreviation for delicacy.
Etymology comes from when Italians immigrant to Sweden.
They worked in "bad jobs", many felt.
A racist gallop.
They were called "fucking deli" and "chark".
It's true.
Have you never heard "Fucking Salami Slingers"?
-Some ...-if you should say the D-word ...
... you have to censor it.
–D, e ... hm ... i.
- Does she mean Negroes?
- I don't think so, but fuck it.
- Mike, no!
-Mike, you're on time-out now.
That's why your mom didn't invite you to your sister's student.
Mike also works as a security guard at cinema in Malmö.
We will return to you, Pia.
Do you think Assia's response is true or false?
- I think it's false.
- I think you are false.
- Hey!
- You think it's false?
You are doing absolutely right.
You've got one more point.
Congratulations, Pia.
Deli is a hose for someone who is stupid, stupid.
Cruelly.
It now says 2-1.
- CHRISTMAS, ready?
Who do you want to take?
- Melody.
- Salaam Alaikum.
- Aalaic Salaam.
Yes, yes, yes!
It has been my dream to say Salaam Alaikum in SVT.
Melody, when we are still on linguistic courses from other countries.
You invite someone to a juicy dinner and ask them to swish for it.
No.
Making a Swedish is this situation -
- When two ethnic Swedes try to duck each other, but happen to meet -
- Get eye contact: "Fuck, I don't want to see the person!"
They panic and make this snuff greeting "Hello" reluctantly.
- It's the scenario.
- What did you say it was called?
Hacerse El Sueco.
To make themselves Swedish.
- Can you say it again?
-You are on time-out.
I have to start trusting people, so I trust Melody.
You did completely wrong.
The true answer to Hacerse El Sueco is playing stupid.
You pretend it is raining.
What is the fucking back story for that?
Are Swedes notorious to be stupid?
No no.
They play stupid.
Sweden has been war before.
They have played neutral.
- Thanks for the homework.
- Yeah.
Because you were wrong, Pia got one more point.
Pia, see if you can pick one.
I would like to talk this time with Martin.
Martin ...
They wanted our blondes.
They were good at iron handling.
The king and nobility milked them on the kids.
-It's true.
- Pia, the history teacher.
- Good, Pia.
-In the 17th century, she was there.
Completely correct.
They came here in the 17th century to work with iron.
They were incredible blacksmiths.
- Christer, your turn now.
But according to our beautiful score board, it is not in your favor.
Even worse, if you answer wrong - what happens then?
-Its over.
- Then Pia wins.
Try not to pamper your family.
Who are you betting your card on?
–Evelyn.
- Hi, Christer!
Environmentalist Ali Khalil wanted to become an ambassador to the Emirate Dubai.
- Chrier?
- Yes, but ...
Yes it's true.
Unfortunately, Christer.
The answer is false.
Ali Khalil wanted to get building permits to build a mosque.
You have not only lost the point, but Pia has won the entire competition!
Pia, came here.
- More applause for Pia!
Congratulations, Pia!
Awesome work.
Here you get a diploma.
- Lite flowers.
-Thank you.
Thanks to the audience, our incredible competitors -
- Our fantastic panel and everyone who looked at home.
See you again next week.
Feel the best.
Texting: Cristel Nyqvist Swedish Media Text for SVT