-Tell me now.
- Heads dress up as a police officer.
He arrests me, puts on me handcuffs and body visits me.
- This is a bit embarrassing ... - Stretching!
Magnus usually wants to dress up for Santa Claus.
I'll sit in his lap and whisper in his ear.
Then I can open the package.
What sexy.
Ulf usually plays that he has been raped by bears.
I get to patch up his butt.
Then we don't come much anymore.
The feeling of sitting in a suburban apartment with cable ...
- Is it a new record?
-Yes.
Dr. Kosmos is called.
Magnus got it from John.
I have never cooked this before, but we have a vegetarian here ...
Well, you are a vegetarian?
I feel better about not eating meat.
Yes, you get a little damn with meat.
Like after the Christmas table.
It is almost so you want to vomit.
- Johannes lives in a collective as well.
- Yeah ...!
How many do you live there?
- We are ten people.
- Ty you live together - as in the lump!
There is something certain about spending time with only men.
- There are girls there too.
- you?!
There is something certain about spending time with women.
Kristina and I socialize ...
Do girls live there too?!
What do you say about it, Jenny?
- They are his friends.
- We are not together because we live together.
It would feel good to have a small harem.
It is probably good with things like that, but you yourself are a little too selfish.
No thanks.
I do not drink alcohol.
- You don't chop, then?
- No, I've stopped drinking alcohol.
- But I like to take mineral water.
- mineral water ... we haven't.
- I go and buy.
- I can take something else.
Of course, you should have mineral water.
But it's closed down there ...
- I take the car.
- No, you have been drinking!
- Water is going well ... - We can order a taxi god.
Yes!
We ask the taxi driver to buy mineral water in the on -call shop.
It's not necessary.
It costs a lot of money ...
- You should have mineral water!
You are a guest.
- Cider goes well.
- No, you should have mineral water.
- Yes, yes ... nice it should be.
The doorbell
It is the taxi driver.
They only had mixed juice.
It cost SEK 430.
Take wine, John.
You can take a little!
You live with a lot of girls.
And you drink red wine.
No, not red wine, but you are in the process of hash and stuff.
Then you can't stay in the skin.
I wonder what Jenny thinks about it.
Or are you gay?
Do what you want in the collective.
But now you are among people, so give a damn in Frida.
Give damn in all the girls here!
Except Jenny.
You talk about being a vegetarian, but you have a leather jacket!
Take some wine now and be like a human being, for damn!
What a fucking shit music you have with you!
I'm changing!
I have a question:
When you go naked and you have a stand ...
Yeah!
This is called Rock!
You don't have that in your fucking collective.
When you drive on a deer with the common car, what do you do?
- Do you club it, or do it suffer?
–You, Ulf ...
Give damn my guy!
Why don't you drink wine?
Do you want to fight with me?
Huh?
- Now you calm down!
- He has a knife!
Go from here now, John.
It will be best.
Go now.
Thanks for tonight!
I will call you back.
He is waving a fucking knife ...
I am really sorry.
I had no idea he was so crazy.
- Is it the first time?
- No, I have a season ticket.
Me and the lady will be in shape.
You can't be a thick on the beach!
The lady is over there.
- Hello, Britt!
- Yenny!
Hello!
-Hello!
-Hey!
Ulf my name is.
-Hello...
Are you Jenny's new guy?
It is important to keep up with the turns.
- We have to go now ... - I am kidding.
Clearly you should try yourself!
The last guy she had with her on a couple dinner was a real kuf.
He lived in a hippie collective, where they danced naked and smoked drugs.
However, he could not take a regular glass.
He looked down at us others.
It was me...
No, it was an idiot.
Vegetarian with leather jacket.
A hypocrite!
- Now we should go.
- We will be seen on a couple dinner sometime.
Hello!
- Per - Arne!
- What happened, Carita?
Death was here to pick me up!
I sat here.
Suddenly the door went up and then a black angel stood there.
It said, "I am the angel of death and have come to pick you up."
"Can't I live a little more? Think of Per -Arne who will be alone!"
The angel says it cannot take it into account.
I have to come along.
I'm starting to travel, but then I get an idea.
- Here is your party -chip bag.
- As I have saved all week.
I say to the angel: "If you get this chip bag, can I live then?"
"Yes," the angel says.
And then it takes the chip bag and goes.
- So, what a lucky thing, Carita!
-Yes.
- But then I have no chips ... - no, you haven't.
RUSTLE
Damn death!
My new guy usually calls me his beauty.
- I am Magnus "sweetheart".
- God, what a cute!
Yes ... once Ulf called me mom.
Do you know if there is any mailbox here?
Oh!
Come on!
I don't want any child.
I don't think about 30 kilos.
In nine months it will be three kilos about Dan - like my laptop.
It's nothing.
You are a lazy woman!
If the whole world was like you would go down.
- I should cuddle on the child, not you.
- I have thought about that.
Check this out.
-What's that?
- A empathy - stomach!
If I manage to have it at work for a week, we can have children later.
I think we should call him Ove.
Gosh!
A new!
- What the hell is this?!
-Sorry...
- Now it will be good with lunch.
- Yes ... Grandma has made my lunch bag.
–What do you have for a sandwich?
- salmon, pesto and salad.
Do you want to change?
I have lung mash and beetroot.
No thanks.
- You have pasta salad.
Do you want to change?
-What have you?
–Leverk sausage.
-No thanks.
Surely?
If you get such an egg inserted on the purchase, then?
- They are sour.
- I am craving pasta salad.
- Do you have any dessert?
-An Apple.
Do you want to change?
I have a pig foot.
I take the apple.
Hello!
I'm not pregnant.
It's an empathy.
Oh!
I put the cup on the empathy.
Sure you don't want to change?
Good morning...
Gosh...!
The old man ... what a cute!
What's nice ...
Boxa!
- What kind of essence.
It thumps in the head.
-Are you hangover?
Yes, it was quite late yesterday.
I drank way too much.
First drink, then wine for the food, and then coffee and brandy.
- And then drinks all night.
- What was you like?
- It was just me.
- You sat at home yourself?
I don't like to drink among people.
You do so easily.
It is important to have a healthy relationship with alcohol.
For me it is a relaxation agent.
I only drink if I am tense.
- You must not end up in an addiction.
- Spit is like medicine.
If I'm nervous about meeting new people, or driving a car ...
Or as a reward.
After a tough morning at work, you are worth a tuting.
- But never, never before lunch.
- And never take bottles to work.
- I drive with this one.
- A shampoo bottle?
Conditioner.
It fits pretty well.
It is conditioner for the soul.
It is important to be creative with such things.
I drive with this one.
Bowl!
Tuesday?
Not that.
Wednesday...
What you are cute, Peter!
You're not like other men.
You're like a girl.
Like a girl with underwear ... no, like a girl with a beard.
Hello?
What are you doing, Goran?
- I just tag my name.
-Let's see.
What fat!
I embroider all night.
If I cut off my arms, I would still embroider.
It knocks
It's the mother!
Put away the embroidery.
Do you have any special properties that make you suitable for this entry?
I'm good at organizing.
I am flexible and interested in new ideas
What are your worst features?
In that case, it would be that I take the job too seriously.
I bring the job with me in my spare time.
- And so I abuse heroin.
-Excuse...?
It discourages some employers, but I have chosen to be honest.
It is another good trait: honesty.
But the job is most important in my life.
That and the heroin.
They come in split first place.
To be completely honest, heroin is most important.
Just that ... How do you think people who work with you perceive you?
I am perceived as very alert, straight and clear.
Except when I took heroin.
Then I am vague, incomprehensible and sometimes violent.
You have worked with one of our competitors.
Why did you stop there?
I needed new challenges.
I was not allowed to develop my full potential there
And so I used to steal stuff from the company - computers and stuff.
I needed money for heroin.
We have received the information we need.
-We will keep in touch.
-I keep my fingers crossed!
Can I "postpone" in the lobby?
-Rather not.
-Okay.
Then I do it in the park.
Wait!
What you are cute that helps me test this, Peter.
You are a spring, huh?
My pigeons against your pandas.
After all, they are three.
Yours are just two!
It's flowers and basket and everything ...
But the pandas come from Africa.
They are dangerous.
They can king - fu.
But the pigeons have weapons in the basket.
They can shoot all the pandas!
The pandas have bulletproof vests and laser guns.
They shoot the pigeons!
Do they have it?
Laser?
Yes!
But then the pigeons' relatives come and fuck your mom!
Yes, it's a deal.
Shit!
Excuse me, but this card seems totally sick.
If I had been an animal I would have been a rabbit-
- or a nail sculpture.
- What a nice place!
-Exciting.
I rarely come out.
- Serve if you see the waitress.
- Yes, she stands with you.
Oh!
How nice.
-Do you want to order?
- What do you have for food?
It says in the menu.
You have it in your hand.
Oh!
How nice.
A lot to choose from ...
- We have to think a little.
- Do you want to drink something for so long?
- Do you serve wine?
-Yes.
The wine list is later.
-Where?
-Where.
Oh!
How nice.
Then we take the house of the house.
- Can you get water?
-Where.
Oh!
Exciting!
- What good it was!
-Yes.
- I would like salt.
- It's standing there.
Oh!
Yes ... "Salt".
Sorry I was so impossible before-
- But you can take off your stomach now ...
Here comes the bill.
- Currently, can we pay?
- The note is there.
Oh!
How nice.
Program text: Agnes Malm Skoglund (C) Swedish Television AB 2004
- Do you need a personal trainer?
- No, it's so expensive.
I had it for a while.
He brought out a barbell and told me: "Lift."
Then I said: "This costs 5,000 per semester. Help to lift!"