The attackers will not show any consideration.
A brutal assault.
What happens inside the walls tonight affects the islanders for generations.
We are now in the time of the metals- the Bronze and Iron Age.
The hunt for metals causes chiefs and warriors to leave the Stone Age -
- And go out in Europe on long and risky trips.
And what they bring home is changing the lives of everyone in our country.
It is also a story full of violence and war.
This is the story of our country.
About the people and forces that have shaped it -
- Endure from the ice age until our days.
This is the story of Sweden.
The Bronze Age, a mythical era that lasts in Scandinavia for 1,200 years.
No written sources are found -
- But the people who lived then have left traces in many places.
It's about magnificent burial chamber ...
... enigmatic rock carvings ...
... and about things left in graves or sacrificed in lakes.
It is tracks that tell about a time when bronze changes life here.
At this time, a young woman with a boat comes from Europe.
Her trip takes her to the Tierp district in northern Uppland.
There you will find her grave several thousand years later
–And the gifts she brought with her death - the Tierp woman ...
During the Bronze Age, prominent women move far from home and family.
It is thus a marriage system that you call Exogami.
The men mostly remain -
- But the women are embraced and move into the man's family's household.
Thanks to DNA, we can say with certainty - -
- The women come from somewhere else.
Some come from Germany.
In northern Germany there are signs of women who have come from Hungary.
At the early Bronze Age, this pattern dominates all over Europe.
Marrying into a family with power is a way to create alliances.
Alliances are needed in war, but also for trade.
During the Bronze Age, trade in metals is absolutely necessary.
So these alliances are of great importance.
In Scandinavia, when we look at the objects in the graves -
- So men are most visible, and they usually have the most wealth.
This indicates that it is patriarchal during the Bronze Age on the whole.
But there are things that indicate that those who come in with new knowledge -
- In principle, women are during the Bronze Age.
There were women who could have incredibly prominent positions -
- Not only religious and ritually, but also politically.
Most people were farmers in the Bronze Age.
But the Tierp woman belongs to the top layer of society.
The shiny bronze objects she has must be an impressive sight -
- But her clothes are also unusual.
In the Bronze Age, Wool was the new.
They dressed in coarse woolen garments, but it was the new, expensive.
Only the upper class dressed in those garments.
The Tierp Woman's most unique objects are the six pendants.
It is not Nordic objects.
They probably come from the Lüneburg area in Germany.
It is an area that has strong contacts with Scandinavia.
It is very likely that the Tierp woman will come from here.
Bronze causes you to travel far, marriage and alliances are included in Europe.
There is a huge demand for bronze.
It is a product that is used for so many different things in society.
The bronze is a fuel that drives society to completely new levels.
The important thing with bronze-
- Is it being used in jewelry, implements and weapons.
Very quickly it becomes necessary.
Bronze is made from copper and tin, which is not extracted in the Nordic countries -
- The outer must be imported from Europe.
To do that, you need to build a commercial network.
Tierp's large village is strategically located in northern Uppland-
- With control over the fur exports of the Norrland coast.
They had contacts against both north and south, and built up wealth.
It became attractive, and can explain why the Tierp woman ended up here.
The upper class desire for bronze is almost insatiable.
It is always needed more, as the dead bring this in the graves.
Many bronze objects are also sacrificed in different ceremonies.
Sacriving things is a way to get the higher powers friendly.
You put the sacrificial gifts in watercourses such as swamp, marshes and lakes.
Probably the water is perceived as a gate to the world of the gods.
An exciting detail is that you often sacrifice things in pairs.
Twin gods and the twin theme are central to the Bronze Age.
This is an expression of this particular duality in reality.
That there are two sides of everything.
Good and bad...
... sun and moon, light and darkness, life and death.
These forces are needed to create balance in existence.
We can see it in rock carving motifs and in bronze objects such as neck collars -
- In pair, abandoned axes and other objects.
By adding two, you both reach these phenomena.
You do not have to choose, but create a balance between the two all the time.
A recurring rock carving motif is people who make volts.
It is believed that they show a ritual dance performed by women.
Most often you do volts over ships.
There are also bronze figures where we see these back volts.
Then we can see that women do the volts.
They have a special lace skirt that makes them easy to identify.
There is some kind of priestesses in a priesthood cult of some kind.
It can be about jumping between worlds.
It can be about overcoming fear.
It is a ritual act.
One thing that happens during the Bronze Age is that agriculture develops.
New cereals provide better harvests -
- What means that the landowners become richer.
This, in turn, means that they can bet their riches on long travel -
- And change copper and tin to make bronze.
These communities build their entire structure and logic on -
- To try to realize as long -distance trading as possible with the boats.
Boat trips south walk along the coasts and rivers in Europe.
The fast transport leaders of the time -
- Takes the crews to the trading venues on the continent.
We think it took 15-20 days to get to England.
There you could change both tin and copper.
To northern Spain it took maybe 30-35 days.
However, all this requires good weather conditions.
Investigations have shown that the copper in Scandinavian Bronze Age finds -
- Comes all the way from Cyprus and Spain.
18 bronze shields were excavated in the 1980s.
There is no counterpart throughout Europe.
Analyzes have shown that the copper in those shields comes from Spain.
It shows that we were then part of an important Atlantic trading system.
Many trips also go to different trading venues in Germany -
- Where you change copper and fabrics.
The sword has served as a kind of Bronze Age pass.
Someone comes with his sword, you know:
"You are part of the Brotherhood, you have the right to pass."
"You can get night shelters and food here."
It's a passport.
It may seem strange that you could talk to each other in near and far.
But in large parts of Northern Europe, a very similar language was spoken.
It is based on the Indo -European language that was one and the same -
- And spread across Europe in the migrations of stone and Bronze Age from the east.
Not only does the bronze make us Norwegians travel.
Wool, yarn and textiles are also an important part of the economy and trade.
In the Bronze Age, wool was valuable.
A simple garment can take five months to do.
There are text sources that show that raw, untreated wool costs ...
60 kg wool costs about as much as 30 kg copper.
In the trade in copper, tin and wool, Norwegians often have amber -
- But also beeswax, honey, dried meat, hides and fur.
But not only did they devote themselves to trading on the trips south.
On the trips you also capture slaves -
- As you either sell or take home as a labor force.
Much of the expeditions, which have been regarded as trade expeditions ...
Some are certainly pure frame slave.
The slaves have a huge significance, which has previously been underestimated.
The society we see in the Bronze Age is a hierarchical chief society.
It was a lot about controlling the import of bronze -
- And to be able to move people from the farms to the boats.
Make them a warrior on the boats.
This created a void in society, mainly on the farms.
Therefore, you have slaves who can manage the farm chores -
- At all different levels.
We would not have the Bronze Age unreasonable labor.
We do not know how long the Tierp woman and her husband live.
Nor what they die from.
She receives a funeral that arises the elite during the Bronze Age.
Over 3,000 years later, the archaeologists find her remains -
- And the gifts she brings with her in death.
The Tierp woman has been buried unburned-
- In an oak coffin that has since been laid in a pile.
Then you have been buried in their finest costume with their jewelry.
The Tierp woman has certainly belonged to the richest family.
An important woman in this area during the Bronze Age.
A few hundred years after her death, the chief of the chief has lost its position.
The land increase causes you to lose the sea contact.
Almost nothing from the later Bronze Age has been found in the Tierp district.
Now a powerful kingdom arises a few miles south of Tierp, in Håga.
The tracks from that kingdom are still there today.
Hågahögen is one of the most magnificent graves we have in Sweden.
The finds in the burial mound tells us about the lives of people and religion-
- But also about the enormous wealth the powerful in society has.
The grave was full of beautiful objects of both bronze and gold.
Hågahögen is the golden -rich grave from the Bronze Age in all of Scandinavia.
The person buried in Hågahögen must have had a very high status.
Some sort of chief or small king or so-
- With contacts across large parts of Europe.
We see that on the objects in the grave.
So this is the outermost elite, simply.
In Håga, you can see a sveavartic emerging in the 12th century BC.
It expands and dominates trade on the Baltic Sea for hundreds of years.
At the same time, you see that this is happening in other ways in other parts of Sweden.
Tanum may have been the center of a empire in western Sweden.
And Kivik seems to be the center of a larger empire in the south.
The empire with the center of Kivik has been powerful since the older Bronze Age.
Something we can see traces of today.
Kivik is the gate facing Europe and bronze trade.
Here, overlooking the Gulf of Hanö, there is a powerful tomb monument.
Here inside the burial chamber there is a pouring chest, full of rock carvings.
The carvings represent axes and ships ...
... four -legged animals, people and wind instruments.
The rock carvings in the Kiviksgraven are outstanding in its kind.
Actually without equivalent in the other rock carvings.
Interesting is the image of a two-wheeled combat or race car.
The oldest of its kind in northern Europe -
- Listed just a few centuries after the type of carriage was introduced.
The person who made the Kiviksgraven and carved these pictures ...
I think Kivikshövingen was very powerful.
This type of magnificent monument is signs of the power the leaders have.
These communities are most powerful 800 years before our era.
There are conflicts and warfare between these centers of power.
A constant struggle to expand.
Warfare, antagonism and violence between these different regions.
This man has become known as the Granhammarsman.
Sometime at this time he travels from Östra Skåne to Mälardalen.
A journey that will end with his death.
In 1953, after 2,700 years, the remains of his body are found on a field.
The site is Granhammar, a couple of miles northwest of Stockholm.
It is an exceptional find.
In addition to objects, intact skeletons from this time are unusual.
It's like a frozen moment.
Next to the skeleton, several implements have been preserved: a flint scraper ...
... a bronze chisel, a bronze plate, and several benzulas.
Everything indicates that the man used to repair different types of equipment.
With DNA and today's advanced analytics technology of skeleton and teeth -
- Can we now find out where and how the Granhammarsman lived his life.
The Granhammarsman is born in southern Sweden, north of Skåne -
- And grows up on a farm, perhaps in the Småland forests.
From the age of seven we can follow what the Granhammarsman ate.
As a boy he ate meat.
It is likely that he lived on a farm with livestock management.
We compare an early and a later tooth we can see that Granhammarsmann -
- Moved at least a few miles when he was ten years old.
Investigations of the skeleton show that he moved again as an adult.
Then he ended up in eastern Skåne, in the Kristianstads area.
That he moved often indicates that he was not well -ordered farmer -
- Out he was a second -hand figure, maybe a boy.
Wear in the right arm shows that he has been doing monotonous work.
And something exciting is that the teeth are worn out in a way that shows -
- That he may have twisted arch strings, chewed skins and other things.
Possibly he has been a leather craftsman -
- But I also think he has participated in battles.
When the Granhammarsman is around 50 years, he has reached Mälardalen.
For a long time, it was believed that the Bronze Age people lived quietly in peace.
But that picture does not seem to be true.
Instead, much indicates that the time was strongly characterized by violence.
In fact, we find traces in Scandinavia and the whole of Europe -
- As testifies to brutal violence, warfare and conflict.
In the middle of Bohuslän Brastad there is a unique rock carving.
Here we have one of the few examples in the Nordic countries from this time -
- At fight scenes, where you probably see a murder.
A warrior drives a spear in the trunk of another that holds a hood.
For the first time in Swedish history, we see the emergence of a war class.
We do not see that in previous phases.
We see this in rock carvings, graves and weapons.
The Granhammarsman becomes one of those affected by the brutal violence of the time.
The most startling with this skeleton -
- Is there are violent tracks, and not so little either.
He has several ax cuts on his left arm.
The last chop has cut off half the face.
He has been involved in an ax duel on life and death-
- And lost the battle.
We don't know what the Granhammarsman did so far from home -
- nor why he is killed.
But he dies at a time when life in the Nordic countries will soon change again.
The days of the Bronze Age are counted.
For now comes a new metal - the iron.
The iron is a little everywhere in nature - in lakes and marshes.
In watercourses like this you can find red soil, with iron in.
Because the iron is so common and easy to make -
- It competes out the trade that has been built around the bronze.
There is no longer reason to travel far to retrieve metal.
When the iron takes over, a new epoch begins - the Iron Age.
When you start to extract iron ore here and start using iron -
- Then the entire Bronze Age's social order breaks together.
You no longer become dependent on long -distance trading with copper and tin.
You can extract this yourself in the marshes.
It means that all this brilliance -
- With bronze and gold and international trade, disappears.
All the big and fine houses and trading venues also disappear - also disappear -
- But for the common man it may be a better society.
Because it will be a less hierarchical society, at least for a while.
For a few hundred years we have a more democratic society.
The iron means a technical revolution.
You get more efficient tools -
- Both for agriculture and cooking, and not least when it comes to weapons.
During the Iron Age, something big also happens down on the continent.
The Roman Empire is growing and becomes an empire.
During the Iron Age, we clearly see that Roman influence is growing.
We have always been traveling, but when the Roman Empire is established in Europe -
- Then the focus on travel becomes more focused on the Roman Empire.
The Roman Empire has been well known to virtually everyone in Scandinavia.
The Roman Empire is most powerful in the early 100's AD.
But it is at war with different people groups -
- And need strengthening of mercenaries from the Nordic countries as well.
In the early 400s, the Roman Empire is weakened by war-
- And new people groups that enter Europe from the east.
This is a time of upheaval - the migration period.
A way to make quick money and experience adventures for young men in the north -
- Is taking recruitment in the Roman army.
Probably the second and third sons are traveling.
The eldest son inherits the farm and the ground, but the others also need livelihoods.
Then you travel by boats along the coast and then take the rivers through Europe.
Many Norwegians came to the continent to serve in the Roman army.
In the Roman army, the Scandinavian warriors - learned
- To fight in a certain way and organize the armies in a specific way.
It took it with you back to Scandinavia -
- And used the same tactics in the internal war they had here.
It is a machogrej to make this trip, be warriors far away -
- Take with gold and valuables home, and to survive this trip.
It gives a high status once you come back.
One that seems very interested in status is this storman -
-which lives near little Jored in the 300s.
He has probably fought for the Romans and returned home.
In his grave you will find beautiful jewelry in gold -
- And a medallion with his Roman Portrait.
Roman gold coins are the role model, but made in Scandinavia.
At it you see the buried man depicted as the Roman emperor.
He has used the same sign of his power as the Roman emperor.
He probably wants to impress his surroundings with the medallion.
He adds details to make it look Roman.
But there is something that is not right.
Everything is not exactly like the Roman models.
Around your face you see something that looks like letters.
There are fake letters.
You have tried to imitate something you did not understand.
Thus, misunderstood Roman signs, because Latin has not been understood.
But there were those who understood the Roman alphabet.
They used it as inspiration for our first alphabet - the runes.
There is an alphabet from the 400s or 500s on the Kylve run stone.
One of the oldest runa alphabets that is preserved complete.
The runes are taken from the Roman written language -
- But they are adapted to Nordic contexts.
Among other things, the runes get their own names associated with Nordic gods.
The Roman Empire affects us very much up here -
- With objects, ideas and knowledge.
For example, you learn advanced operations by Roman field doctors.
It is knowledge that you bring home.
In Sweden, surgical instruments - have been found in various places - have been found
- As scalpels, probes and the like.
A tool has even been found to operate a star.
Something the Roman doctors can also be three -pan.
An operation that involves cutting, drilling or scraping holes in the main bowl -
- To relieve the pressure against the brain from an internal bleeding.
Trevaning is probably something that Northern residents in the Roman army came into contact with.
The operations were done completely without anesthetic.
We must imagine that they have been extremely painful and unpleasant.
Trevanation was also carried out in Sweden.
This skull belongs to a woman who died about the year 100–
- And was buried at the Smörkullen in Östergötland.
The hole here did not cause her death.
On the contrary, it was probably what saved her.
Maybe she had suffered from an internal bleeding in her head.
A serious condition leading to death unless the pressure is eased.
Someone tried to save her life, and succeeded.
This woman has survived a three -pan, and lived long afterwards.
If you look around the hole you can see that the bone tissue has grown.
This means that she has lived long after the procedure.
When conducting the excavation of the burial ground -
- If you find more people who have undergone the same intervention.
All of them seem to have lived for several years after the three -pan.
The everyday life of the Iron Age man is also affected by the Roman Empire.
For example, the Romans teach us the art of baking bread.
And many glass objects are imported from the Roman Empire -
- Together with other luxury items that provide status and prestige.
These are almost two thousand years old.
This time is also known as the Nordic Golden Age -
- Because of all the gold items found.
Jewelry made by the gold coins that the soldiers take home.
Perhaps the most beautiful examples of it are three gold neck collars.
The absolute masterpieces regarding goldsmith are the three gold neck collars.
One is found in Öland and two in Västergötland.
They show a golden age in terms of craftsmanship in the Nordic countries.
But at the end of the 400s, the West Roman Empire falls.
The North residents who have served in the Västromerska army are now getting rid of their jobs.
It will have consequences here at home in Scandinavia, not least in Öland.
The gold flow ends.
There are no more valuables to Öland.
Networks you have had in Europe collapses, you no longer travel.
This leads to problems on a completely populated island. There is no new land.
It will be a power vacuum where you need to build a new power structure.
Who is going to have power on the island?
This probably leads to a civil war, simply.
Who will be the strongest chief?
It is night in the late 400s when the conflict reaches its peak.
Behind the four meters high walls of Sandby Borg on eastern Öland-
- Leaves the village residents and sleeps.
It is believed that the chiefs had a party during the evening.
Probably several local tribal leaders have gathered to negotiate.
But now everyone is sleeping in Sandby Borg.
Now you are starting to understand what happened that night 1,600 years ago.
The excavations in Sandby Borg's ruin led to five jewelry hides -
—A which included gilded costume and glass beads -
- With origin in the Roman Mediterranean.
They also find a Roman gold coin from the mid-400s.
It strengthens the theory that several people here had worked in the Roman army.
But in addition to this, the archaeologists also made other, more macabre finds.
When the bodies arrived and we began to understand what it was -
- Then was my first feeling: "Exciting!"
And then: "What a terrible!"
A balance between archaeologically interesting and emotionally difficult.
These are real people, they have been treated terribly.
And you have that feeling with you all the time.
It was probably 200-300 who lived there, in terms of the size of the castle.
There are both injuries from swords and from blunt violence on the bodies.
There are not so many defense injuries.
It is more that you have been attacked.
They have not been prepared, but have tried to escape or surprised.
Surprise attacks we think it's all about.
Everything is over in a few hours.
Screams and horror changed in cold silence.
In houses after houses, the attackers have killed the inhabitants.
There are only the dead bodies.
Leaving all the dead remains is a way to humiliate them-
- And prevent them from moving on in the next life.
They do not get the rituals and the funeral they would normally get -
- So the dead will travel to the next page.
It is a humiliation that extends into death.
A mystery in Sandby Borg is that there are dead women.
Jewelry, looms, children have been found, so there should be women.
But so far, the skeleton has only been found after a single woman.
We think they may have gathered the women.
Maybe they have brought a couple of pieces, but not everyone who lived there.
Somewhere in the castle they lie, gathered together probably.
These seven precious costume buckles -
- I suggest that as many chief women were in the bail during the attack.
The archaeologists believe that the local chiefs were gathered there -
- And that enemies from another area were behind the massacre.
They struck in the middle of the night to knock out the overall resistance.
While life in other island castles continued as before-
- So Sandby Borg was transformed into a spooky place.
A place that the islanders avoided for generations.
What makes the place so special is that it is a frozen moment.
All the dead remain as they fell.
Everyone is in the middle of their everyday life -
- With furniture, food and what the houses have looked like.
We almost never see that archaeologically - usually houses are ejected -
- They have burned, you have moved.
Here everything remains.
In one of the houses, next to the fireplace, the skeleton lay of half a herring.
They may have sat and eaten just before this happened.
It is such an incredible snapshot that you have a hard time understanding it.
The massacre in Sandby Borg shows the chaos during the migration period.
Soon life in the Nordic countries will be thrown even more.
A disaster is on the way.
A disaster that will eradicate close to half of Sweden's population.
But from the ashes, a new era should arise.
Viking Age.
Farmers leave at sea-
–And is known in Europe and further away than that.
But over time, a new religion will take root here.
A religion that challenges the Vikings' way of life.
Texting: Karina Berg Johansson Swedish Media text for SVT