In tonight's section of Ifs, quiz about all culture in Sweden:
Legend from Degeberga, Petrina Solange.
Greek humor philosopher Thanos photographed.
The world's Swedishest Arab, Elaf Ali.
The roasting Syrian from Skåne, Filip Dikmen.
Pirate from the West Coast, Assia Dahir.
The pink panther from Colombia, Diego X Mami.
The prince from MFB, Hassan Makaveli.
Sweden's pride, Moroccan gold Loreen.
And the man, the myth, our host Ahmed Berhan!
Welcome to Season 2 of IFS, your favorite program's favorite program.
My name is 00 00 Ahmed Berhan, with a license to program.
These are our fantastic competitors.
Next to me we have Carola.
Next to none other than Niklas.
And rips orange: Christian.
The competition goes like this: You choose one in the panel that gives you an answer.
Then you decide whether their answer is true or false.
We start with you, Christian.
Doesn't he look like Kratos, though with anorexia?
It's just the arrow.
Good of War, though he forgot the muscles at home.
Great fun to have you here, Christian.
Who do you want to talk to?
Decision anxiety.
I'm in love with both Filip and Elaf.
- Filip has a little too much beard.
- The man, your beard is blatte!
You don't know how much beard Elaf has either.
-Elaf?
–Yes.
They only have fake marks there.
They do not have adidas, they have Adibas.
The truth is that the letter P is not in the Arabic alphabet.
So then they say B instead.
Police become Bolis, French fries.
When searching for porn they search for drill.
Harcore drill, lesbian drill ... so.
It could be true, but I don't believe it.
- You think she is lying to you?
-Yes.
Unfortunately, Christian.
It's true.
No point for you this time.
P is not found in the Arabic alphabet.
P can easily become B for Arabic speakers.
- Carola, who do you choose to talk to?
- I think I'm starting with Thanos.
- What happens, Ahmed?
–What happens, Thanos?
19 is the average age when Swedes move away from home.
In Monaco.
It is an over -representation on nobility and royalty.
They don't move.
They live in their males and castles.
So it's Monaco.
Hello, how hard!
I think it's false.
Why?
Okay that you want to live in a castle, but it gets boring.
-How do you know that?
- You want their own life.
A castle, not a second on the south.
- Maybe, but ... - you still think that Thanos is lying?
You do that right in. Congratulations, Carola.
You've received a point.
Royal or not.
The country where people live at home is Portugal.
- Niklas, who do you choose to talk to?
-I...
- I drive on Hassan.
-I love you.
Hassan?
- Camel Pung Bullets.
- Sant.
- Well!
- No, not camel pounding balls.
There are camel meatballs.
It's called a nice word in Arabic, Tiz Gamel.
I don't know if you know what Tiz is, but it means butt.
This is because the meat at the butt is very masquerade, like Waguy.
So it's meatballs.
Meatballs are.
- Yeah.
-True or false?
–Fi Gamel, is it Egypt's ...?
-No no!
Tiz!
/ Everyone says Tiz/ I believe in Hassan.
You believe in Hassan?
To camel meatballs ...
... As for some reason, Göt Camel is called, is the true answer?
You believe in Hassan.
Good that you are ashamed, because it is clear that it is false.
Unfortunately no points.
Koshari, the national law of Egypt, is a carbohydrate intensive plate:
Rice, macaroni, lentils, chickpeas, roasted onions and tomato sauce.
Christian, should we see if you manage to get a point?
--Assia.
-Hello!
Time for a video question.
An aheebak ya habiibi nakupnda mimi sana ...
The Somali woman went viral in 2021 with the song.
First Off, Fuck Yo 'Bitch and the Clique You Claim
Westside when we ride, come equipped with game
You Claim to Be A Player, But I Fucked Your Wife
We bust on bad boys, niggas fucked for life
There was new singing at Skansen.
I like it.
Hit Em Up is really the Wonder World black skulls.
She sings to all Somalis in exile to come back to her home country.
This is where those bastards need to be.
We Somalis are there!
I have no idea.
We say it's true.
You trust Assia, that exile somalis should come home?
It's false.
Unfortunately, there were no points now either.
She sings I love you in Somali, Arabic -
- Swahili and English.
How did it go?
An aheebak ya habiibi nakupnda mimi sana
Ogsoonow inan kujeclahay
I love you, my baby
- It's our national anthem.
- Carola?
Only you have received points.
- Do you get another one?
Who do you choose?
- Loreen.
Oh my God!
What were you thinking?
Turkmenistan's flag, darling.
You see the symbol.
It represents the release of the Turkmen-
- From none other than Djingis Khan.
Oh!
I have to look at Loreen and see if I can see ...
Look at me.
Walla, I speak the truth, Habibi.
- She is the Moroccan.
Do not forget.
- How does it feel, Carola?
It feels like you should.
I have to plug flags.
- I say it's false.
-Do you just like it's false?
You do that right in. Congratulations, Carola!
You've got one more point.
It is definitely not Turkmenistan's flag, but the Republic of Jämtland.
Jämtland?!
An association has been pushing Jämtland's independence for a long time.
A bit like Sweden's Kurds.
It's half fun.
Their current president is Eva Röse.
- The clip was from Storsjöyran.
- There I have played.
Congratulations to the second score.
- Niklas, who do you trust?
- No butts, I promise.
- I take Diego.
In Colombia on New Year before the twelve, pack a suitcase, La Maleta.
Then you walk around the neighborhood and think about where to travel.
It should be lucky.
It is our tradition.
Why do you look like you want to return to the camel issue?
What is the gut feeling?
- It is such a fall height here.
- Come again, come on, Niklas!
- Yng!
- Vamonos!
Let's go.
I believe in him.
You think it's true?
Congratulations!
You've received a point.
Bravo, Niklas!
It can happen.
La Maleta is a Colombian tradition.
If you wish to travel next year, fill the bag with important stuff -
–And goes around the neighborhood.
- You are heavy, Niklas.
Welcome into the match.
- Christian, now we drive.
- Then we drive Filip.
He cut his nose on the Zlatan statue.
No.
He has raised one of Sweden's largest rappers -
- which is called the prince of Rosengård, namely Timbuktu.
I have to take points now.
I don't have the faintest.
- No, I don't believe it.
-Not?
Congratulations, Christian.
You have also received a point.
Najs.
Dialy Mory Diabaté or "Dallas" has worked with young people in Rosengård for 40 years -
–And has been noticed for its great commitment.
- Can you bring home full pot?
-Hope.
- A panelist left to choose from.
- Something whispers: Petrina.
I'm not sure it's a good idea.
I take ... wait, who do I have left?
- It's one left.
- I take her, then.
I feel like the last kid at an orphanage.
"No, not she."
- Sorry!
I'll take her.
It will be fine.
- Petrina?
It is difficult to accommodate a stolen TV in the jeans.
Nah.
It is considered ugly to show the gender.
In trousers you see the contours.
You should not do that, hence a skirt.
- I think that is false.
- Secure?
So, I ... it's absolutely false.
It must be.
Absolutely false?
I love self-confidence.
But that is unfortunately true.
There will be no point, Carola.
Roma women should not wear pants because it is too revealing.
However, large velvet skirts are only carried by Finnish Roma.
They weigh 8-10 kilos.
Every Day is Leg Day.
If we look at the scoreboard, we notice that Carola has gone to the final.
You should bring some of the guys with you.
Niklas, all panelists are consumed -
- So your last panelist is randomly selected.
That is you, Diego.
No, Hassan!
Sorry.
I do not know...
The only time as immigrants is about to be randomly selected.
You would never see it at Arlanda.
"Take me. Me! Here!"
We will run a music issue.
Bi-L Kurmanji, by êbne Allah Ikhalli Efendine
Were Were Werre Ez Heyrana Bejna te me
The song we heard is in Kurdish, Turkish and Arabic.
That you should get beer.
It has become a large party song in Sweden.
You should pick up yogurt, water, onion.
But you must not forget the beer.
- Fan what Niklas got thirsty.
-Yes.
- Have you partyed for the song, Niklas?
- I have heard it ten thousand times.
I like it a lot, but have never understood the text.
I don't think that's right.
No.
You don't think the song is about picking up beer.
Unfortunately, Niklas.
No point.
Because that's actually true.
-Is it true?!
- It's about fetching water.
And beer.
The audience is allowed to jump in.
I will explain.
The song is Su Getir.
Artist Bahoz sings that you should pick up beer, water, yogurt and onions.
In Turkish, Kurmanji and Arabic.
A party hit in Sweden and in Norway.
- In chorus 28, the beer comes in.
- We play it from start to finish.
Unfortunately, Niklas, you got no points.
- Christian, you have no question left.
Now it becomes a rash issue between you.
Closest to wins.
-Were you born in Sweden?
-Yes.
It is not noticeable, I thought.
Najs.
You have written answers?
Keep it up, so everyone sees what you have guessed.
- Have you written as a percentage?
- They would answer as a percentage.
Niklas, you answered 20 percent.
- Christian?
–19.
-Oh oh oh.
- Jobbly.
The right answer, my ladies and gentlemen: 20 percent!
Congratulations, Niklas!
You nailed it.
- Christian, thank you.
The correct answer is 20 percent.
We have our finalists: Carola and Niklas!
Carola, you can start the final round.
But I explain what will happen.
First to five.
But when you answer the wrong, the point goes to the opponent.
- Carola, who do you choose to start with?
- I like Thanos.
I'll take him again.
- You are alone in liking Thanos.
- I have wife and children, you a slipper.
-Do you want it?
-No.
Check.
She will leave it tomorrow.
Do not remove it.
-Thanks so much.
-Thanos!
Kista Galleria.
Country.
- You take, right?
- Yes, Walla.
I get it.
The whole Lore is laughing: "I've been to Kista Galleria."
- "It's fun because it's true!"
- Sink, the name ...
- I die, that is.
- Per capita in the world.
Iran.
Many exiliaranies go back there to perform plastic surgery.
So ... yeah.
I say from my heart that it is / piper / false.
Why does your heart say it's / Piper / False?
Because...
I just don't think you focus on plastic in Iran.
-I do not know why.
I could be wrong.
--Wow!
Maybe in Sweden, if you are from Iran.
But not in Iran.
False.
You choose not to believe in Thanos.
Congratulations, you've got a point.
It's false.
Most plastic operations are done in South Korea.
Huh?
Not Turkey?!
You could believe Turkey, but South Koreans are more driven.
According to surveys, every third South Korean woman in her 20s has
- Made some form of plastic surgery.
Congratulations, Carola.
- Niklas, starting from the bottom.
Now you're here.
This is the peak.
- I drive Assia.
--Assia?
That Kanye has become cancelled.
No.
When you celebrate Sabbath it is a boy's circumcision.
The foreskin you take and bury at a discount ...
Or it may end up in a flower pot, but, yes ... in soil near the home.
After the funeral you have a ceremony.
Oy Vey, Niklas!
- I know that "it's a thing".
- What of it?
- Planting foreskin?
-It's where I start ...
--... Don't keep up.
- Stackarn.
Pung balls, tiz and now foreskin.
Do you have yours left?
Niklas is probably the only one in the room that has left his.
- Niklas?
Yeah.
Eh ...
- I think that's right.
- You think that's true?
Sabbath is a party to celebrate the circumcision?
The point goes to Carola.
Sorry, sorry, sorry, sorry.
The Sabbath is the holy rest day of the Jews.
Which is celebrated from Friday night, with Sabbath meal, until Saturday night.
Carola, before I go on my Sabbath, choose someone.
- I want to try Diego.
- Hey!
On a Chilean celebration, someone can pick up a handkerchief and suggest ...
It's a ritual in Chile where you fit around a handkerchief -
- As I do now, and sneeze ...
–Don't give me that shit.
- We are equally worthy, you understand.
Can't you just say that?
- Those down there too, we are equally worthy.
-I do not think so.
I think we are different.
Is Cueca a tradition where you share a handkerchief to show equality?
- Otherwise, it's too disgusting.
- I am not Chilean.
It sounds nice to share something, but not Sneese.
So I say ...
Oh!
False.
You say it is false because it sounds really good.
-Congratulations.
You got one more point.
-Yes!
It's false.
If someone offers you a cueca they want to make a pair dance.
Cueca is Chile's national dance where you wave a handkerchief.
- Niklas?
- Loreen.
Researchers investigated how Swedish students experience Finnish Swedish.
The content of the promil, Walla.
I'm just kidding.
There are Finnish Swedes and pure pimples.
And Finnish -Swedish, the mining -
- Let a little more intelligent, a little finer.
While the mining of Finns that have Swedish as a second language -
- Not as intelligent, boring and even ugly.
Yes ... eh.
I continue on the wrapped, rather bad path that I have chosen -
- To say true.
But I think that's true.
Congratulations, Niklas.
You've received a point.
According to a small study, Stockholmers valued Finnish Swede Higher -
- While the Falubs thought the opposite.
Like we care about Falubor!
- Carola?
- Haa ... Hassan.
Here we go.
It means "don't sell fishes".
- "Don't Sell Fisar"?
- You just got ass Content today.
-Yes.
This is also sexual!
- He is not through Freud's anal phase.
I can explain.
It's like an Albanian Jantelag.
In Sweden we say: "Keep on the carpet, brother. Don't sell."
- Can you sell fishes?
"Don't sell fades," I said!
- What then "don't sell"?
- I do it on my only fan.
There you have it.
Mos Shit Porde!
So.
I may regret it, but think it's false.
Thanks.
The point goes over to Niklas.
When you say "Mos Shit Porde", it's "Keep your bullshit".
Stay on the carpet, Carola.
The point is Niklas.
Mos Shit Porde!
- Niklas, you have received two points.
- How fuck did it go?
Let's go.
I drive elaf.
Well, in Hinduism it is important to embrace both darkness and light.
And Diwali, which occurs in the autumn -
- Shows about celebrating that the darkness has come, simply.
It sounds strange to celebrate the darkness.
–Darkness, Baby, Darkness.
-You Need to Celebrate It, Walla.
I don't want to celebrate the darkness, so I say it's not true.
That's why you say it's false.
It gives you a point.
Congratulations!
They celebrate the light.
Diwali is the celebration of light and lasts for five days.
They teeth fireworks, houses are decorated with lamps and you give presents.
It says 3–3.
- Are you going to take over the lead?
I choose Filip, of course.
Römosseskolan was closed by the School Inspectorate in 2022.
He had embezzled SEK 12 million of the school money.
It seems that he has among other things put it on sex purchases -
- "Adult hotel" in Thailand and an Islamist party in Somalia.
Possibly her relatives there.
It can certainly be true.
The world is dark, but ...
Not according to Niklas, apparently.
It's ... fake.
You think Filip lied to you?
The point just went over to Niklas.
The principal and moderate Waberi were convicted of embezzlement and accounting violations.
According to Media's review, the money should have been used for ...
... stuff in Thailand.
Niklas, who we now see on the scoreboard it says 4–3.
If you answer the next question correctly, you have won the whole thing.
- Dinner.
- You have a panelist to choose from.
- Why are you always last?
- In don't know.
- Petrina?
-Yes.
Burn it.
It's true.
There are different ways.
When a Qur'an is old and worn one should either bury it -
- Sink it in running water or, last resort, burn it.
It became a fucking misunderstanding with Paludan.
People thought he was a racist, but he had just read it.
Now I want to see what the gut feeling says.
I'm glad that is the last question.
I thought it sounded nice from the beginning.
It starts to get worn and you have to find a burial ground.
Then you should drown it and then burn it.
It traced out a bit there.
I don't think you can burn a Qur'an.
You say it's false?
Congratulations, Carola, you've got one more point.
Wait.
Huh?
I like your way of thinking, but that's true.
But do not burn it with garbage or together a racist Danish.
- Out in a clean place, become ashes ... - know trail.
We see that it is 4–4, which means it will be a matter of rash.
- We should write the year then?
-Exactly.
- tiz Gamel.
- Come again now, Niklas.
Carola and Niklas, show us your answers, are you please.
-Oh!
- damn!
-What did you write?
- Niklas says 1975.
Carola, you say 1976.
The correct answer to when the first Indian restaurant was opened in Sweden is:
1971 in Gothenburg!
- Niklas, congratulations!
You have won the entire program.
Carola, thank you for being competing.
Arrived.
You have got Jämtland's fine flag.
Place it around you.
–Yes.
Here you have your IFS diploma.
-Thanks!
Immediately after this, we will cut your foreskin.
Congratulations, Niklas.
Thanks for this week.
What happened?
Texting: Cristel Nyqvist Swedish Media Text for SVT
Oh, my God ...