In tonight's section of Ifs, quiz about all culture in Sweden:
Abracadabra!
He's back: Megic Mike.
Sweden's most fun Chinese, Evelyn Mok.
Albanian Swedish teacher Flakrim Fejzullahu.
The world's Swedishest Arab, Elaf Ali.
He puts the ride in Pride, Kenxo Slayz.
Gothenburg's best Somalier, Assia Dahir.
There is no semi-finished product in Hummus-Hustler Zeina Mourtada.
Jackson's Five's sixth member, Filip Dikmen.
Last but not least, program manager - guru, the gold boy with the dreadlock:
Ahmed Berhan!
You look at IFS that made the whole country dance Dabke and eat pipas.
My name is Ahmed Berhan and I am your host.
Here are our competitors:
She is from blue, but rips pink, no less than Therese!
She loves cooking and food traditions and rips green.
Lovisa!
Fire for fire, our firefighter today.
Orange Pulpet: Lucas!
We start the competition.
You choose a panelist and decide whether the panelist is lying or not.
We start with you, Lovisa.
You are plugging into a nurse in psychiatry.
Which of your future patients do you want to start with?
I feel that Zeina should speak the truth, otherwise so ...
I bought all her books.
-Zeina, welcome back.
-Thanks.
This Greek ... one had used his picture -
- And put it on a pack of Turkish yogurt.
Greeks and Turks are sensitive.
He was told and sued the company.
It feels like I've read this.
I think you speak the truth.
You trust Zeina?
Congratulations!
You've received your first point.
That's right.
The yogurt tour was not Turk, but Greek.
But he is the yogurt tour.
The man sued the dairy company of SEK 50 million in Athens District Court -
- And finally got two million.
He found out that a friend who lived in Sweden had traded -
–And suddenly: "It's stavros!"
Lucas, your turn to drive.
Before we take the question.
You work both as a firefighter and a photo model.
How much do you earn on Onlyfans?
It depends on whether we have the hose outside or inside.
-Bravo!
--Fire for fire.
It feels like he didn't attend Paradise Hotel.
He just: "Ifs!"
Awesome, Lucas.
Your turn to drive.
Who do you choose?
The debutant: Flakrim.
Kumla.
Just kidding.
It is the municipality of all classical place music:
It is actually Botkyrka that has the highest proportion.
I trust you.
You must not lie directly.
- You trust too much on Albaner.
- You are the first one I trust.
-Oh!
- So the last.
No problem.
But Lucas, do you know what?
You've received a point.
Congratulations!
True.
Botkyrka south of Stockholm has the highest proportion of foreign -born-
- With 43.3 percent.
Therese, you are from Kista.
You are used to being surrounded by black shells.
- What of the panelists are you chewing with?
- Filip.
I feel he can check away ...
Filip did a DNA test and found out he was a 23 % Nigerian.
He came back with Afro.
- You know I came here normally.
- What is it too abnormal with Afro?
We put it aside.
I came up with the attitude to fix myself nicely.
But when I heard Mike's Swedish I got a shock and my hair got up.
Your Swedish is worse this year than last year.
How fuck is it possible?!
It goes back every year.
Do you understand?
Filip?
My question to you:
The list does not want to come out in public.
BSBS, the blators that built Sweden, is a hip-hop collective from Skåne-
-Popular in the 90s.
Timbuktu was one of the members.
He went solo then.
Beyonced up in his bitches.
"Single Ladies, Single Ladies!"
Timbuktu?
No!
It's false.
She refuses to believe that Timbuktu hung with other black shells.
- "Not my Jason."
-Just.
- It's false, Filip.
Congratulations, Therese.
You have also received a point.
The blators who built Sweden are a TV4 documentary by Leif GW Persson-
- In labor immigration after the Second World War.
First round.
Everyone combed home one point.
Great!
- Lovisa, take it further.
–Evelyn.
Thanks.
–Evelyn?
-Yes.
Hello!
My sexual preference.
No, this is Bengali Marriage Fishes.
Wedding fish.
It is a Bengali tradition-
- Dressing up two fish like the bridal couple.
How to give them to the bridal couple.
You said you liked cooking and cooking traditions.
But this was a little premium.
I think that's true.
- You trust Evelyn?
-Yes.
You think the fishermen are part of a Bengali wedding tradition.
-Congratulations!
You've got one more point.
-Thanks.
It's true.
The fishermen symbolize luck, happiness and success.
Lucas, who are you trying to?
Evelyn was taken now, so Elaf.
I had my favorites.
- We were the second choice?
Thanks.
–As it should be.
ELAF?
Within cat policema.
- Customize her.
-Oh my God.
-Go!
Give The Fuck Off the Stage.
-Elaf, Elaf!
The correct answer is in Islam.
It is said that Prophet Muhammad had a cat.
Muslims like cats lick a lot, lick themselves pure -
- So they even have to hang out in the mosque.
It feels like a long shot, that, that is.
It doesn't feel like a good start to our relationship, that you lie to me.
He treats this as Paradise Hotel.
It's okay, it's okay.
-Stir the pot.
- I posted it.
- Lucas, you think Elaf is lying?
-Yes unfortunately.
-You are wrong.
–Wa?
Is it true?
What Elaf said is true.
The cat is considered ritually clean, welcomed in the home -
- And even in the mosque.
Who could believe that Muslims were cat people?
We all learn something.
Let's move on.
--Therese?
-Yes!
- Kenxo, do we drive?
In recent years, the American hose "Down Low" has found its way into the resort.
That's when you're in the wardrobe.
There is someone who is hiding, a little hide and seek, you are wanted -
- Have a low profile, you are down low.
Laugh, then.
No.
- Have you heard of the expression?
-No.
Admittedly, many may be hiding in both the closet and the police -
- But ... no, it's false.
You don't think anyone is wanted?
It's false.
You think Kenxo is lying.
You really are from the resort.
You are absolutely right.
Congratulations!
Another point to Therese.
But he still gave you a little hint.
"DL" is that you are in the wardrobe.
You are gay, but have not come out.
The whole of Södertälje, that is.
Been there, done that.
!
We have 2–2–1.
- Lovisa, should we see if you manage to get a full pot?
-Yes.
- What do you put your card on?
- Megic Mike I drive.
-Ooh!
Megic Mike, thanks for making TV history-
- As the first brother in SVT who has Durag on.
Heavy you are.
Mike!
He distributed genital herpes.
He wanted to cut -
–And got a recommendation from a Swedish music producer -
- Cutting at Salong Shadow Mikael in Rinkeby.
- Are you a UsherFans, Lovisa?
- I have never listened to him.
- you?!
--Wow!
Gasps in black skull.
- Do you never have ...?
-Don't you be here in the 21st century?
But I ... I don't know.
I'm a little too Swedish maybe.
Lovisa, what do you think?
Was Usher in Rinkeby/Tensta to fix a fade at Shadow Mikael?
–EVER ... no.
I think he is lying.
- You think he is lying?
Sometimes Ignorance is a bliss.
Congratulations, you've got one more point.
Usher had been at a conference and wanted to form his own perception -
-If the No Go zones Rinkeby and Tensta.
Lovisa managed because she did not know about Usher Fade or Shadow Mikael.
- And that Mike sat like this.
- She cheated, bre.
- We move on to Lucas.
--Assia.
A classic Roman coffee is ... Take a cinnamon bun, on the fallow sausage -
- On it you place tomato and then you put raw yellow onion over.
When you want home cooking and coffee at the same time.
I hadn't done that.
-You're lying.
-Okay.
Take two sides from a cookbook and just merge?
Unfortunately, Lucas.
No points for you, because it was true.
–Tu-you-you-you-you-is that true?
How?!
It's true.
Cinnamon bun, raw fallow sausage, tomato slab and raw onion -
- Is a Roman specialty and shows up in Zeina's next book.
He Lucas talks too low.
- You are a firefighter.
Raise your voice.
You talk unclearly, can you talk more clearly?
Megic Mike thinks it is the firefighters who scream, "It is burning! Help!"
Let's move on.
Lovisa has received three questions.
You have three points.
Lucas, you only got one point.
Unfortunately, you will not go to the next round.
Even better!
Oaah!
Therese, you still have a question left.
But, as you notice, all panelists are consumed.
Therefore, your last panelist will be randomly selected.
- Feel illuminated.
- Is the spotlight wanted?
Yasin village and Jaffar village are two Swedish rappers.
Both love the kids in Bullerbyn.
No, you joke aside ...
Megic, Yalla.
No, actually ... it's a common surname in Somalia.
Very common.
Like Svensson and things like that.
Stuck in Somalia.
I'm finished.
Yes, you ... well.
I'm sorry, I like you, but it's false.
-Do you think?
-Yes.
You don't think the village is a common name in Somalia?
You do that right in. Congratulations, Therese!
You got one more point.
False.
They have the village in the artist names because they come from Rinkeby, called the village.
They are also included in the collective village block.
Therese and Lovisa, you have moved on to the final round.
Congratulations!
Now it's time for the final round.
It's about coming first to five.
The difference is that if you answer the wrong, the point goes to the opponent.
- We start with you, Therese.
- Whoho!
Assia.
To mecca it is ...
When we Muslims see someone as Ken, we have to turn to Mecca directly.
Yes, I'm gay!
I notice that Assia wants to get rid of her job at P3.
Of course, it is ... In old hose you think "Mecca with the car".
But it has been given a new purpose.
In newer hose and out in the resort -
- You use it to say that someone does religious things, like praying.
For example: "Where is Ahmed?"
- "He's out and mecca."
It must be slang for something else.
I think it's false, Assia.
I'm getting curious.
What would it be like?
- Maybe something that you should not do.
- The man, she has lived!
Therese moved to Kista for a reason.
You know what?
Thanks to your experience, you have received a point!
Of course, it is Assia so false.
To mecca means to roll a goose.
- What is a goose?
What is a goose?
--Äzi.
You have not clarified that it is grass -related.
- You answered hose with hose.
- Welcome to Ifs, brother.
Filip is right.
It's about rolling a marijuana cigarette.
Public Service, Ladies and Gentlemen.
- Lovisa, your turn.
- What do you choose?
- Flake.
Flakrim, image question.
These are the Iranians who root your mom on subscriptions.
"It's just going into Bank ID ..."
No.
There are two well -known spy brothers.
They are known as Alan and Nami.
They spied on the Russian state and worked for the Swedish police and Säpo.
- Loova?
- I trust him.
- I think it's true.
- It's the spy brothers you read about?
Wrong.
The Iranians we are looking at are Alan Mamedi and Nami Zarringhalam.
The founders of the app TrueCaller.
They are on Sweden's list of new billionaires.
As a result, Therese has received one more point.
Congratulations!
Should we see if you bring home a third point?
- velyn, now we drive.
-Hello.
Okay.
Evelyn?
To protect himself from Paolo Roberto.
Metal Protection.
It's a cultural thing.
In order to protect their shy-
- You have a piece of metal there to protect yourself from evil spirits.
It is common in several cultures to have metal as protection against evil.
Is that how to do?
I recognize it with spoon, but don't remember why.
- Where do you put it?
Front or rear?
- Between, I think.
- It's a completely different program.
- Spare it to the after -talk.
- What do you know about Evelyn's explanation?
-It's true.
You put a spoon inside the panties to protect yourself from evil spirits.
It's not true.
It's false.
- Congratulations, Lovisa!
You got a point.
It was a British campaign-
- Auditated to young women at risk of being married abroad.
It gave the security check a reason to take them aside and talk.
- Loova, who do you choose?
- Filip.
Brother...
The plastic operated part.
The finest you can say in Persian is liver.
"You're my liver."
Why don't you know.
But it may be the only part that is genuine after all plastic surgery.
"You are my liver" is the finest you can say in Persian.
I trust him.
The world is weird, so I think ...
Why not?
There are such strange things.
I love your honesty, Lovisa.
Congratulations!
You've got one more point.
"You are my liver" is a compliment, an expression of love in Persian.
To a family member, a partner or friend.
If any other culture talks about it, then they are about to chal it.
As we see now, it says 2-2 between you.
It's tight.
It's najs.
-Oh!
"It's najs that it's tight."
- Watch you!
Cew it out!
- This is a family program!
- You were the one who said it.
There is a word in Arabic that is not in Swedish.
-/ Ululates/ –A'eeeb.
A'EEB.
- You are pressed!
- Can you translate A'Eeb?
-"Ashamed!"
- "Shame", but still not really.
I have a word for it, in Swedish.
-/ pronounces it soft/ Aejba.
- Man, in Swedish?
It's called Aejba.
--Therese, your turn to choose.
-Elaf with the lovely dialect.
Thanks so much!
Balkan moms say that Promaha is the main cause of death.
It is actually cross drag.
Balkan people are afraid of the air that pulls between two windows -
- And think it can make you really sick or kill you.
My first thought was when the sons moved away from home.
-The other one.
-Okay.
I think that's true.
- Do you have great fears for crosses?
-Yes.
Why?
Congratulations, Therese.
Another point.
It's true.
Promaha means cross draws.
Balkan moms want to avoid this at all costs.
They think it can make you seriously ill.
Lovisa, which of our panelists do you choose?
Zeina.
-/ Ululates/ - They have mucked the whole.
Zeina ... - Zeina lost so many sponsors recently.
She smokes Alhamdulillah Kush.
Ooaah!
Did it go well?
Is it safe?
-It went well.
-Are you okay?
-What happens?
-Yes I am fine.
I feel good!
I feel good.
The chair is not feeling well.
Zeina?
It's a slang word.
That's when you are away.
"He is Alasas. He has tagged with SAS."
-It's true!
Ala-sas.
-No.
No.
You respond with the entire chest.
You can't even whisper.
No, I think she is lying.
-In order to...?
–Sas, so ...?
No.
What else would it be?
"I am Alasas. I have tagged with SAS."
Think Zeina on a flight!
SAS ...
Random ... thus, random control every time.
Lovisa?
You say what Zeina said is false.
You choose not to believe her?
You did that right in.
You've got one more point.
Alasas corresponds to "as if" or "yeah, right".
You do not believe in what you hear, like you have traveled with SAS.
!
Right now it is 3–3.
--Therese, are you going to pick a four?
–Yes.
Kenxo.
If a Latin American invites you to a quinceañera ...
Quince is 15 in Spanish.
Quinceañera is when you have been married for 15 years.
It is when you gather the family at a big barbecue party.
It's like a wedding grill party.
- I think it's false.
- You think it's false?
Congratulations, you've got one more point.
Quinceañera is definitely not that you have been married for 15 years.
You celebrate the girl's 15th birthday, the transition between childhood and adulthood.
Lovisa, now it's your turn.
As you can see, it says 4–3.
This means that if you answer wrong, Therese has taken home the whole thing.
Megic Mike may be.
Listen, Lovisa!
If you cheat, I swear, it won't go well.
Brother, sit down so you don't break another chair.
Mikey Mike!
Your South Korean buddy will give you a move -in present ...
When you move into new, you get toilet paper.
If you have lots of friends, you get lots of toilet paper.
But if you don't have ... it will be difficult to dry the ass.
-What are you saying?
Do you believe in Mike?
-Yes I do.
-Why?
- Furray country maybe.
I guess.
The kindest prejudice I've heard.
It is a clean country.
Therefore, it is reasonable to provide toilet paper.
You got one more point.
In South Korea, Jipdeuri is called the move -in party.
The most common gifts are toilet paper and detergents.
It is not considered clean to use toilet paper.
You should wash with hose or ... but that is good.
The thought was good, but it's not ...
In Japan, they don't have a Shalatafa.
- It was South Korea.
-What the hell.
All Chinese.
-It is the same thing.
- I live in South Korea.
Everyone is Chinese!
In approve that message.
Right now it is 4–4, which means a rash issue.
It comes in the form of closest wins.
How tall is the Fittjamoskén minaret?
Reply in meters.
Are you done?
Let's see your answers.
Lovisa guesses at 4.7 meters.
Therese guesses at 17 meters.
The correct answer ...
32.5 meters.
- Therese, congratulations!
Come here.
You should get a price.
Roman coffee.
- Megic Mike wants?
-Of course, your IFS diploma.
Congratulations, Therese!
A huge applause to our competitors, winner Therese -
- Lovisa, Lucas ... an applause to our panel.
To those of you who have been in the audience and you at home.
Thanks.
See you again soon!
- Now we have coffee.
-It smells.
I feel too.
Good work.
Congratulations, Lovisa.
Texting: Cristel Nyqvist Swedish Media Text for SVT