-Look there!
-Good!
Very good!
It is important to be quick and catch them before the dog scratches them.
It was fine.
Many may have visited Gotland during the summer
But it's actually nice here in the fall.
In addition, it is high season for the small delicate Gotland truffle.
Here in Norrlanda, in the middle of Gotland, Luqaz runs a restaurant
In a small glass cabin.
Together we will cook a feast for some lovely islanders.
But first I will try to get out of the fence here ...
Right next to Luqaz restaurant is growing truffles.
Luqaz has put together a bunch that will help us look.
In addition to the landowners, it is with a real truffle expert.
- This was a nice glade.
-Really.
Here we have the oak with which the truffle grows together.
Here we will see if we can find a little.
In Gotland, several kinds of truffles grow.
But it is the one called Burgundy, or Gotland truffle
which you use for cooking.
Truffle has probably been on Gotland evenly but 20 years ago it became known.
The one who discovered it was no less than our truffle guide Christina.
The very first truffle I found before there were truffle dogs here
I did by crawling on all fours and feeling on the ground.
I felt that it was failing differently in one place
And I thought, "Could it be something here?"
Then I peeled away and saw the knotty, black surface.
The truffle is just below the moss under the oak where I am.
Then I get up the truffle and it weighs almost a quarter of a kilo.
Never ever afterwards have I found an equal truffle, despite dogs!
- Is she something going on?
- Search, Polly.
Wait, may I see?
Yes, what good!
Now let's see here.
Look, here it is!
Sometimes they can lie so superficially.
- Acient, Polly.
- Here is the first little truffle.
The truffle grows below the ground and to spread their spores
it uses the sense of smell of animals.
The strong scent attracts animals eating it
and then spreads with its stool.
To find the truffle, specially trained dogs are used.
Mainly Italian truffle dogs, but also Christina's spaniel
Has a well -developed truffle nose.
Good!
Very good!
It is important to be quick and catch them before the dog scratches them.
It was fine.
We are going to cook dinner on this.
What should we drive to?
How should we build this ...?
I think it's fun to combine the luxurious truffle
With raw materials that do not feel as luxurious - such as cabbage, onion, potatoes and eggs.
Quite cheap ingredients, but they fit very well with truffles.
Especially if you add the best friend of the truffle:
- fat of different kinds.
- fat in all forms.
Yes that's how it is.
The truffle is washed and we pull to the vegetable grower to botanize.
It feels luxurious, I think, to be able to harvest in November.
Really, it's super nice.
They are almost the sweetest now too.
- The little frostbone does ... - precise.
Should we see what we got with us?
Here was the lovely kale.
Nice leeks ...
This is fun - if you have never seen Brussels sprouts.
Yes, it grows so exciting.
It is hardly believed that it is for real.
Here we also have the world's largest beta.
It probably won't be so nice but we do a test
So we see if it is too woody or can be eaten.
It's fun with big vegetables.
It will be very green.
The beetroot is allowed to go into the oven at low temperature
and my plan is to make a potato dish
With butter -fried potatoes, hot cheese cream topped with a shock of deep -fried potatoes.
Luqaz works with different kinds of cabbage
And a pork that he boils in beer on the grill.
- This is so good.
-Yes.
I have been inspired by walking around the fields and seeing what is growing.
That's how I think, "What should I cook next?"
I am more inspired by farmers and producers than by other chefs.
The huge beetroot got better than we thought, so it goes with it.
But it's time to start posting, because the guests fall in.
We have used the truffle as a flavoring in different ways in the dishes.
But the most luxurious when having fresh truffles
is to tear or slice it directly over the food right by serving.
-What do you think?
Should we ... - we drive.
It looks great.
Here we have it: Truffle dinner.
In the little bowl you have a potato and onion serving
With hot cheese cream, planed truffle and crispy potatoes.
Then you have a small main course: grilled lace bowl, broccoli
slightly crispy kale and a beer -browned pork, a truffle cream
And so we have a big, nice beetroot that we found, which we have baked.
- We cut a thin disc at the bottom.
-Please enjoy!
- Fantastic.
--Wow!
-Very tasty.
- Was it?
There were so many wonderful textures in this little bowl as well.
The beta was damn lovely.
Do you know the taste of the Norrlandatruffeln?
Texting: SVT Language & amp;
Accessibility Swedish Television AB 2023