It is Tamejfan died here.
Not an animal left.
Check out, there will be someone.
It's Elin.
Is she mad that you pretended to be a medium?
Yes maybe.
It's best that I declare myself.
-Hi Elin.
- Hi, Leif!
Or the millionaire, the bear hunter, the medium ... what are you called today?
Call me Leif or Leffe.
It does not matter.
I want to apologize for yesterday.
It got a little crazy.
Do you mean when you tried to revive my grandmother?
- It was a little crazy.
-Yes.
I'm not a medium for real.
- This is my little brother Billy.
-I understood it.
Well, Leif's little brother!
Or the "demon", maybe?
Anyway ... Are you looking to come over for dinner tonight?
- So we pull a line over yesterday.
–Eh ...
Yes ... yes, absolutely.
It can be ... exciting.
How fun.
You are not a vegetarian like all Stockholmers?
No, I eat everything.
Bird, fish, beef, game ...
It is best I record.
- Bird, fish, beef ... - I am allergic to nuts only.
Good then I know!
Then you can come and have s ... come at six o'clock.
Fun!
I jog on.
Have it!
-How did it go?
- You have got a little date.
-Date?
What about me?
- You may be on a small corner.
We pull, it is completely dead.
I have to go shopping.
- It will be SEK 819.
-Yes...
- Do you want to test again?
- Fan, there may not be money.
We bought that leaf blower for 4,500.
Remove half then, Billy.
After all, we forgot to transfer money from Russian million ... the account.
And so I forgot my black American Express at home.
Test now, Leif.
It is still not allowed.
Damn, remove the cookies, potatoes and drink and that shit.
- It is well with the terminal.
- I don't think that's the problem.
- Do you want to keep these?
-No.
Not these either.
Then we try again then.
It still does not work.
This was the icing on the cake.
I don't even have meat for tacos.
May well do something of the vegetable.
What the hell was that?
- But, we will ... - Yes, the law has no need.
- But it's a fox!
- Yes, but the date must not be destroyed.
Pick it up.
Come now, it's in a hurry.
Hello!
Oh, how nice you are.
- Yes, okay ... Welcome in.
-Thanks.
It's rough!
Oh ... Hello.
- Yeah ... — was a saw.
It's like the worst luxury.
Thanks...
- What a nice thing you have.
-Yes thank you.
- Where is Leif?
-Eh ... - Leif?!
- She's here now.
-Here I am.
Hello!
Sorry.
Well!
Oh...
- thank you, Kypar'n.
- Kypar'n?
- Don't you join in and check out?
- No, it didn't.
–Leif said he wanted to be himself ... - with the disk!
I said I wanted to be myself with the counter.
We divide the chores.
I wash and he serves today.
Then we only had two chairs ...
- You aren't hungry?
- Well, I'm not going to have anything.
- So you can eat in peace.
-No.
Yes ... sorry.
The food is on the entrance.
And my gentleman may want something to drink from the beginning.
- Or now?
-Yes how nice!
I could imagine Chateauneuf-du-Pape.
Perhaps?
Leif we have ...
I think ... Chapnö tough dad is over.
- We drank it last week.
- Yes, it's over.
What is good is water, root wine, or red wine, and white wine.
- And tap water and beer, of course.
-I was joking!
Red wine gets shit.
- Yeah ... - I take a beer, as usual.
- Billy!
Bring it too.
-Thousand thanks.
Well.
Well ...
- Fun that you wanted to come.
- Yes, this you have ruled up well.
It's always fun when it comes to a nice ... new people to the village.
Then we want to invite a little.
-Sorry.
I'm a little tired.
-Yes...
So there, my vultures ... ladies and gentlemen.
- The food comes just right.
- Billy.
-Sorry.
-Thanks!
Thanks then, Kypar'n.
- bowl for Sörbäcken.
- For Sörbäcken.
And us ... everyone here.
How does it feel to have moved here to Sörbäcken?
I love Sörbäcken, so it's najs.
I haven't been able to do that much.
Or I took a run.
It's very beautiful.
- Do you train anything?
- I am doing different stuff.
- I have a black belt in martial arts.
-Tough guy!
- But for real.
Do you workout?
- Yes, I have a little ...
... karate business in Slaughterbo'n.
-Okay.
- I haven't got it started yet.
Right now I'm trying the most new blows at Billy.
Well ... I went on Thai boxing.
It was Askul.
But I got tired of being completely blown in the face, so I quit.
- I haven't been beaten yet.
-How nice.
Shit, what I'm hungry!
You remembered that with the nuts?
Billy!
Do you remember that with the nuts?
Sure damn!
"Beef".
- It is quiet!
I remember!
- What is on the menu?
- It's some fox meat ...
Someone ... beef mince ... Pleasant.
He has free reins in the kitchen, so I don't really know.
-OOOH ... –OOOH-Sch ...
-OOOH-Sch ... thank you, Kypar'n.
- It looks great!
It's a small tacos with Billy's own touch on beef.
Nämen, extra touch!
In the same!
What exciting, Billy.
-Have a nice meal.
-Thank you then.
- Bon appetite!
-Exciting!
Billy's special!
We'll see how it tastes.
I chop in.
Mm.
- It was a little salty.
- We like strong food, we.
Very exotic flavors and such.
You seem to be very close.
None of you have a girl?
Or guy?
There have been a lot of women who tried to get me on a case.
But I'm waiting for the right one.
-The right one?
- Yes, she should have ...
A little red, long hair.
Hit, kind of ...
-Nuts!
- Yes, and nice feet.
–Wa?
- What happens, Leif?
- You didn't stop the food in the food?
- It is clear I did.
She is a nut allergist!
What happens, Elin?
Say something!
- Stupid, you have given her nuts!
We have to make holes in the larynx!
Get a pen!
I've seen it on Discovery!
Calm down, you will be able to breathe soon.
- Not a pencil!
Calm down, Elin, take it easy!
What are you saying?
Amputate?
- We have to amputate!
—Ring an ambulance!
-Ambulance?
Damn!
You have killed her, Leif!
It is Öhmans from Sörbäcken.
Someone has got a fucking allergy shock.
It is Billy who got nuts Ina!
She got an allergic shock, but normally breathes now.
- But we keep her overnight.
-Thanks so much.
Hell!
Here I was meeting the woman in my life.
And then you poison her with nuts.
A nut allergy!
Good job, Billy!
Don't say beef then.
It is called cooking.
Mixed messages...
Pea iron, come now!
Do not waste more brain cells.
You disappeared like a wind tears fell from my cheek
Left there was nothing except your ring
Everything you left, was an emptiness so great and totally total
Swedish texture: Karin Karlsson Hutt (C) Sveriges Television AB 2017