Tjena, it's Tord.
I fax the numbers on Monday.
Then we say so.
Hello.
Hello, it's Gerhard.
I fax the numbers on Monday.
It is good.
Bye!
Well ... there were two ladies out shopping.
They arrived at the vegetable department, where there was a box of cabbage roots.
One woman takes up a cabbage root and says, "It looks like my husband's"
"Well! Is it so big?"
- "Big? No, but just as dirty."
The farmer and maid would go with the cow to the bull to get her covered.
On the way home, the farmer on the maid looked and said:
"Hörrudu, Anna, can't I do as the bull did?"
Anna started to blush and said:
"Sure you get it, it's your cow."
It's great fun with these burlesque, musty stories.
They are often a little peasant.
A master of this was my philosophy professor.
It was Christmas time and collection to Save the Children, and he said:
"Then I previously give the money to myself, because I am a solipsist."
According to Solipsism, everything is a product of its own consciousness.
Old cheese and the girl's little tastes good but smells bad!
- These women ... - Yes!
They make life worth living.
What is a woman really?
My friend, the question is as old as life itself.
- They are enigmatic creatures.
- How do you catch a woman?
- How do you tie a cloud?
- How do you hold lunar rays in your hand?
I remember the first time ... I was 14 and she was 27.
We were two lonely ships that met on the ocean expectations.
My hands went on exploration along her hills.
- Then she hit me on the jaw.
- These meetings!
I remember the first time a woman let me go all the way.
It was 1999.
We had been together for a long time.
We had dinner and went to the cinema.
Then we ended up in the same bed and she opened her flower to me.
- You understand what I mean?
-Yes.
- I mean her sheath.
-I get it.
I don't eat at home tonight.
The Korean is going tomorrow and we have to sort out everything tonight.
When would I have to meet another?
- Lena, calm down now!
- Oh, oh, oh!
No, it's the computer!
There is some screen saver ...
Ah, ah, ah!
I will be as soon as it is clear.
- So, what a small.
- Lena?
Lena?
Snap sound is heard
- River, you drugs.
-Oh sorry!
- Are you still playing ping pong?
- No, I injured my elbow.
–Ah, damn.
Did you get operated on?
- Well.
Check out here - steal operated.
I can't move my arm longer than here.
- When did you have sex last?
-Last night.
-How was it?
- Her eyes were like wells.
The breasts were like swallows and the care was like a marketplace in Cairo.
A myriad of different cultures, and scents from all over the world.
A constant commerce.
She offered me remi, a small autumn leave ... I answered no.
I do not understand?
Neither do I.
I got lost in the metaphors ... but we cuddled.
-Something else!
-Ouch!
How do you think that felt?
Don't you see that I have anxiety?
I am in a sensitive process.
I sit here and feel -
- And when you interrupt my private sphere, it feels like this ...
Do you write the wine on Thåström?
Hello!
It is fun that so many people are interested in flower binding.
My name is Markus.
Everyday I work as a librarian.
My interests are theater, film and socializing.
What can I tell you more?
Well, I suffer from Tourette's syndrome, a kind of verbal ticks.
Sometimes I scream the word "banjo" quite loudly, for no reason.
I wanted to tell you that already.
Okay, flower binding ... What can we say about the ancient art form?
Banjo!
It was not a real attack.
I just wanted to show how it sounds.
Flower binding ... banjo!
That was a real attack.
You will probably get used to it soon.
A flower arrangement can look in many ways ... banjo!
Lilies are nice to have as a foundation, as well as Akvileja and ...
False alarm.
I'm a little nervous today.
Crocus and begonia ... banjo!
You would see me in a bio -salon!
Carita!
I don't know who I am.
Who am I?
- But Per - Arne, you are Per - Arne.
- I'm?
I thought about when we met.
Then I was one Per -Arne.
- Isn't I another Per -Arne now?
- No, you are exactly the same as then.
-In some ways.
- In the center I got to see a jacket.
It was sporty and navy, and so it was impaired.
"My God, what a clip," I thought.
Then I thought, "Such a jacket, does it fit me now?"
"Can I have it now?"
So I didn't buy it.
- Now when I passed ... - so it was gone!
- How could you know?
- Now you, my beloved Per -Arne!
You should see what I bought for you.
Wasn't it this jacket?
No...
...it was not.
If Thåström had been Foreign Minister ...
... so Sweden had been in Copenhagen, or in Amsterdam.
- I am with a mature woman.
- This is classic!
She knows what she wants, purely sexual.
And everything she experienced!
Right traffic - the changeover, two world war ...
Then you have to say that she is ripe!
She knows how she wants it.
Yes.
She wants it carefully.
She has just got a new hip joint.
These women!
Ugly are you, but you don't scare me!
-Hello!
Elsa - Britta, I'm here.
-Come in!
-Hello!
- Lord Jesus, who are you?
-My name is Jan.
I am a substitute.
- You don't look Swedish.
- Yes, I'm Swedish.
- Do you own an old man?
I do not know.
Then we will see what to do.
You should start by making a sandwich, and then you do this:
Cut a thin slice of Skogaholms -Limpan and wide thick with Bregott.
Lingon jam, hot milk, ten drops of salmon ...
The stomach has not been doing for a long time.
Then you divide it into small pieces.
Thick slice, thin slice, film milk, the edges, then you mash it ...
... and put it in a teacup.
Have you understood?
Yes...
- Why do they send all new ones to me?
-I do not know.
As stupid as he looks.
In the gender in focus, we will talk about male sexuality.
What is it?
It used to be ugly to talk about this.
The man's desire was a bit taboo.
But now it is obvious that guys want as much as girls.
Yes.
Now it is totally okay for a guy to take the initiative for sex.
We feel more comfortable with our bodies.
A guy can take the initiative for sex without being called loose.
You can try!
But many guys don't get to know their body.
You feel it feels shameful.
You set up although you do not want to.
And fake erection, simply.
Many guys don't really know how to relate to their genitals.
One tip for you at home is to explore your genitals.
Feel free to help a mirror.
Then we have the eternal question: what should we call our genitals?
- What should we call it?
- It's a problem.
We asked that question on our website, and received an email from Jörgen, 28:
"Tjena, I call my genitals 'my little Pippi'."
Here we have one who calls it the "violin".
Bo, 52, calls his "Doris".
There are lots of suggestions.
Only the imagination sets the limit.
The subject arouses great interest.
Male sexuality is accepted more and more.
In Denmark there are porn videos too for men.
- We will see more of it!
-Exciting.
The gender in focus is over for tonight.
- Artist couple, Wenche Myhre ... —So there, Elsa - Britta.
Oh, my God, now all day is ruined!
- You wouldn't mash the sandwich!
- Yes, you said ...
Look here!
Have you ever seen a more stylish person?
A Svensson.
Many Svensson usually ask each other at after parties -
- What would play the lead role if their lives became a movie.
But everyone knows that a Svensson life comes out directly on video.
Here we sit and have a snack.
It is the heart of the entire business.
-Hello!
Paul is my name.
- Lotta.
- You have stood out with Tord all then?
- Yeah.
Paul you never know where you have.
You can count your fingers when you have shaken hand.
Tord is a fun dot.
We often laugh at him - behind his back.
- Then you have to be on guard.
- Yes, Paul is a slippery.
- You start working here?
- Yes, today.
We need to get talented people who can weigh up for those like Tord.
Don't take Paul seriously!
Nobody does that.
He is a bit of a house clown.
- What have you been working on before?
- With the mentally handicapped.
You will benefit greatly when working with Tord!
He is not mentally handicapped, but he is a little sluggish.
The thing with Paul is that he is stupid in the head.
I'll give you a log - in ...
She bargains
Oh sorry.
She bargains again ...
- Oh, forgive me!
-No problem.
...AND AGAIN
If you got to choose a characteristic of a guy ...
Humor, honesty or that he is a warm person ...
You can only choose one.
- Nothing is especially important.
-Why not?
For example.
honesty...
I don't know ... and I don't understand that with humor and warmth.
There is a thing that is very important.
- That he is ill -mared is very important.
-You are right.
It's crap.
- Are you remembered Peter?
- Yes, he was very ill.
So fucking ill!
How the hell could I let him go?
Thank you!
The next guy is doing this for the first time.
My ladies and gentlemen, a large applause for Torbjörn Sävlund.
Good evening!
Stand up - comic is warm to my heart.
A musty form of humor, with roots in the Jewish storytelling tradition -
- There is a figure called Badhan, Drev was pushing with the host couple.
An old gold grain from there is as follows:
"The landlord here is so stingy that he just lights the menora to Pesah."
Pesah is, as you know, a Jewish feast.
Another stack within standing up - comic is the dialectal humor.
One of my favorites is Gustaf Fröding.
I think of a piece from his collection of poems "Räggler and Paschaser".
Je Geng Tea Collect Broke on Töre, Tall and Oak
but string bart yes not nor yes fridd tea anna play
Gustav Fröding ... Thanks for me!
Hello!
Surely it is good to fuck?
- Carita, we have to talk.
- There's nothing to talk about.
- Well ... - no.
“Purple Rain” with Prince
Per - Arne, I love you!
- It's exactly what I mean!
- Frida!
Kristina ...
- Can you mimic a seagull?
- a seagull?
- Yes, I can.
- Follow with me for a little while.
I can only pee when I hear the sea.
SVT Program texting: Anna Borgström