Now we are at Stora Amundön, a nature reserve that we have some surveillance on -
- To protect this important eel grass.
A few years ago I read in the Gothenburg Post about the Port of Gothenburg and the Swedish Maritime Administration wants-
- deepen and dredge in Gothenburg harbor.
They wanted to dump toxic mud masses in the archipelago outside Vinga.
I went together with others from the locals out on the islands.
We wrote together a name gathering and I wrote a debate article about this.
I sent it to the Land and Environmental Court.
And in the end, they got a no no on these poisonous mud masses not being allowed to end up in the sea -
- Without it, it must be deposited on land and be taken care of.
It looks pretty clear and nice in the water.
We have a nice seaweed.
And that the burns have come back - and they look pretty thick and saturated and satisfied.
I think we should dive a little neighbor.
We'll see what it really looks like down there.
Here we have then ... Such a nice seaweed that has also become overgrowed by these fine -tough algae.
This fluff.
As you can see, it is completely covered.
When we get too much nutrition from, for example, wastewater flooded when it is a rainfall -
- So it grows very quickly.
It can cover this nice pliers we have here.
And the sun can't penetrate.
It does not get the sunlight that this pliers needs to grow and do its important work such as catching COPD.
Below me here, the pliers are covered by this.
It looks like a big fluffy rug.
And so we don't want it.
We want it to look ... like this!
I probably wanted people around - in the public - in the public -
- Would be noticed in the important environments that are underwater as well.
That they are affected by what we do.
How we run a boat, how we build jetties.
For people to participate and protect this close to the underwater nature, which is also very important.
It's not just big whales and sharks that are important -
- Without we also need the pliers, jellyfish and eel grass to have a healthy marine environment.