One of the key words we chose to highlight in this pod project - and also throughout the election -
- Is accountability.
Review politics so we can say: "But you said like this in this pod section. Why wasn't it?"
Or why have you changed or what it is now?
Hi Janet Ågren!
Hello Anders...!
Hi Lena ...!
When we started thinking about the election - sometime in 2019 -
- Then we thought about what we can contribute.
How can we develop local democracy?
Then we saw that a problem that local media has is to ask question three, four and five when interviewing about environmental and climate issues.
They rarely know the follow -up questions.
Then we felt that there a pod can fit well and ask follow -up questions.
Because we feel that you can get away but quite a lot of ignorance.
In many issues, but also climate and environmental issues.
So we think this is both a way to show citizens what the politicians are actually answering -
- But also to form the politicians.
Because they have to read on and reflect on these issues.
But to my great shock, we are approaching 400 listeners to these pod sections.
I don't know what local political madmen are.
But they listen.
On this top of the island you want to build quite a lot of housing.
It has many advantages, but at the same time it means cutting down quite a lot of urban forest.
And limits biodiversity.
The expansion has been paused because you have seen white -backed woodpecker there, but you want to get them to move from there.
We talk about such urban building issues in the pod.
And quite so much also in the Nature Conservation Association Umeå.
I hope and wish for circles that you do not release politics.
To actually influence politics locally.
Because it is the politicians who make the decisions that affect the climate and the environment.
And they are the ones who have the resources to actually make any difference.
If they sharpen.
So yes, we will continue.
And the next step is that we will try to get interviews a year after the election.
Maybe with those who lead the municipality.
And ask: What have you done?
How do you look at your work?
Will you reach the climate and sustainability goals after that work?