Hi, my name is Oskar Tagesson.
Is ideally involved in the Swedish Society for Nature Conservation in Gothenburg in an interest group called the City Planning Group.
Today we have gone to Lindholmen in Gothenburg, which is located just north of the central town, by the river.
And today we were thinking of going around here and checking out a bit of exciting examples of sustainable urban development.
In the city planning group in Gothenburg, a large part of the work is about writing opinions on various detailed plans -
- But it can also be infrastructure projects or various strategy documents that the city develops.
It is a large part of our work - to write these opinions on consultation and during review and participate and think and think.
And pay attention to the municipality and citizens within the municipality -
- Seeing how this building plan affects the environment and the climate goals, for example in Gothenburg.
Lindholmen is an area that has been operations and industries before.
So where it has been a gap - where there may have been parking areas or arrangements - you have managed to densify with new buildings.
We see that with several houses here.
That you have received residential buildings on parking areas.
And it is a very good way to build.
You do not use new natural land, but you use the areas already in the city.
It is also an effective way to build in existing areas.
Then there is already the infrastructure - roads, bike lanes, sidewalks, road and water, electricity and all such.
My dream and vision for the organization and the city planning group is that we will continue on that track -
- That we are involved and influence and have great credibility at the municipality.
But also be able to get even further there -
- And really become a voice that politicians and officials listen to and act based on it.
Here we have existing houses that are not used today maybe.
To a certain extent - some are still used.
We have huge surfaces, asphalt areas that have been parking spaces or arrangements.
And it is land that is already the claims in a city.
So instead of building a residential building a little further out -
- Where you may need to cut down a forest or where you need to remove agricultural land or pastures -
- So you can build here instead where the ground is already used in a way.
So it is in the basic principle one of the sustainable stuff.
We at the Nature Conservation Association in Gothenburg want to see a green and sustainable city where we live in harmony with nature.
Where you are close to green areas, where you are close to school, for service, for work.
Where it is easy to live sustainably - you can walk, you can cycle to the nearest place you are going.
null