I run a project where more people should get out into the forest and learn more about species, biodiversity -
- And what a real forest looks like.
I drive a lot of the joy of the forest, but can also feel very stressed and a great sadness that -
- Forests with hearing natural values are harvested at such a rapid pace.
Only now while we stand here, forests are harvested with high natural values, which have never been harvested before.
Where the authorities do not have resources at all to follow up on each harvesting case or to inventory.
So the risk if there are no non -profit forces that are committed to the forest is -
- Loss of biodiversity, loss of natural forests, loss of forests with high natural values.
Here we see that it is a spill crow that has been.
Typically like this at the base of a spruce.
It is a red listed species.
With this project, to get people's formation around forest -
- And be out with other people in the forest who are committed and want to learn more.
It gives an incredible amount of energy and joy.
So for me it has become a way to make my commitment more sustainable.
I have several examples here in Västerbotten where it is thanks to the commitment of individuals -
- That many forest areas remain.
That they were excluded from harvesting and maybe even today is a reserve.
My dream is well ..
... another forestry.
Where we do not have this calving use, but where all forests with high natural values receive long -term protection.
And that we use the forest in a different way than we do today.
It is a possible dream.
Not an unreasonable utopia.