Joe and Sonia, thank you so much for interviewing you.
Would you be able to tell you about the day when I guess your lives changed forever?
That morning was a fantastic beautiful brilliant day.
The only reason I remember it was that September 10 had lousy weather.
September 11 is his birthday, so I woke up and thought this will be perfect.
I went to Manhattan to arrange for a little surprise to him-
And they started evacuating the building I was in.
They did not tell why.
When I got out he called and said, "Listen carefully to me-
-We are under attack, this is a war.
Take the next bus, stay away from the train-
-And promise me that you don't stop. ”
But it was broken and at the same time I saw fighter aircraft.
Because I was an emergency medical technician in New York-
-So I thought this was not an exercise, because we have never practiced fighter aircraft.
I wondered where my husband called me from, because he knew too much information.
But I had to stay focused and when I got home my daughter sat on the floor.
She was very surprised to see me because she saw everything that happened on TV.
She thought dad was dead because she knew he was there-
-And she thought when I didn't get home that I went there too.
But she did not understand that telephone communication did not work, so none of us could call her.
When I held her, she said:
"Dad hugged me harder and he kissed me a little more, why?".
I didn't know what to say, but the phone rang which was very worrying-
-For that telephone network had been turned off.
So when we picked up the phone it was my husband and now he sounded different.
Now he says: "Everything is gone, it's gone".
"I can't see my feet. I can't see anything, it's gone."
I didn't connect what he meant.
He constantly said it was dark, but it was still daylight out.
But he said he would call me at 10am and that he would be near towers 7.
So we hung up and my friend from Tennessee called me.
I said, "No, don't talk anymore".
"Here's the phone number I want you to call so you can tell the family that we are okay. Joe is near tower 7".
She became quiet and I asked why she was.
Then she told me that Torn 7 had just collapsed.
I don't remember having put on, I don't remember anything.
I just remembered that my daughter said it was evil.
"That we could talk to dad and that God then removes him".
For some reason I became very logical and grabbed her and said:
"You have to understand that there are thousands of people who will never get the last call. We got it."
"Dad said he would call us at 10am and we will wait until 10 o'clock".
But Dad never called, so in the morning we thought he was dead.
Oh my God!
"We have these pictures that no one can ever forget."
The World Trade Center in New York is burning.
A few minutes before three this afternoon, two planes drove into the two scratches in the middle of central New York.
I was there before the second tower raged.
It was crazy, people ran.
We led them to Brooklyn Bridge.
People came out with dust everywhere and I had to make a call from a satellite phone.
I could call her and explained to her what happened-
-And at the same time I continued to do my job and I forgot what I said.
I forgot I would call her at 10am.
When I got home I was covered with dust.
I had fallen in the brilliance and hurt myself.
But if I had gone to the hospital, you must not go back.
You may not participate.
So I kept it quiet about it.
I told her because she was an emergency care.
I said "Sew me please".
I cried and she saw it.
Then I just said "you need to sew this so I can go back".
Later I find out that two of my friends had died in the second tower.
They were police officers.
It was difficult to accept that this was the largest crime scene we ever during my lifetime.
I had been a police officer for almost 30 years.
He didn't talk about four days when he got home.
He would just take a shower and sat in the living room.
He looked at the clock until it was time to go back.
We couldn't understand it, but what we needed as a family was that Dad hugged us.
To tell us it was okay and he didn't.
The fourth day when he got home he had a note that he looked at-
-And I took it and could read names I recognized.
I asked what it was and he replied that they were gone.
I said "removed from service?." No, they are gone ".
They were killed and then he said, "I don't understand how they died and I lived".
I did not know what to say to him because patients I tried to help have sometimes died.
When it has died, I have always wondered what I did wrong.
I have never thought that they might have been too sick, so I understood what he felt.
But despite that, we became a broken family, we just couldn't talk about September 11.
It was too difficult and we could not accept that this happened in our own country, in our city.
We just couldn't accept it and we lived for about seven years.
The emotions remain, you feel it.
She has the dreams, I have the dreams.
No, they are not dreams.
They are nightmares.
In the middle of the night I see her get up.
She will help a firefighter among the trash.
You know, something like that and it's hard.
We are fighting!
We are fighting against and we continue.
How long did it take until you went back to Ground Zero?
So after the attacks when you worked there.
About 10 years.
It was, about ten years.
How did it feel to be there after ten years?
First I could see what they did about the construction of the place.
But I could feel there with the dust clouds and people who cried and screamed.
That's all.
Wherever I went, I knew what was there before.
So it's a reminder.
With the trauma you have?
It is difficult.
Advice from the medical part of the World Trade Center is offered.
So they give us help.
They give us an understanding of what everyone else goes through.
I'm not alone, others experience the same thing I know.
This disappointment, I don't call it hatred.
The disappointment at those who came and did this.
I wasn't the only one who thought that way.
You also have diseases because of this, right?
We didn't know we were sick.
We thought everything that happened had to do with working too hard or getting older.
We both have stomach problems that, due to the acid, actually come up.
It will eventually cause suffrageal cancer, there is no way out of that.
He has more problems than I do.
We both have problems with our breathing.
He sleeps with a machine.
He takes medication every morning.
He has around 20 bottles of pills that he stopped taking for a while when it was so depressing.
So I bought a cabinet cabinet and put it in the bathroom and said:
"You don't have to see the pills. Just get up in the morning and take them so you don't have to see them."
Then ended with me doing the same.
It is difficult for us to accept that we are sick.
No, we do not want to accept it but every time the doctor gives us a new diagnosis we know how it will end.
We know how it will end, we have lost friends.
We tell each other that until that day comes, until the doctor says there is nothing else you can do-
-So we live, because we have to.
But losing friends is the hardest and we have lost more friends-
-Af after 9/11 due to 9/11 than we did 9/11 due to illnesses.
Due to illnesses?
Due to illnesses and they are horrible diseases.
People continue to die too, right?
Yes.
We have had over 180 cancers and Congress only wants to accept 56 of these.
So I mean, there are people who die and do not get medical care because the congress said no.
It does not consider it to be an acceptable illness.
So how many more people have to die before the congress realize that we die?
We die, I don't know where we will be in ten years.
I don't know if you will come back in ten years and interview us, we may be gone.
It is a tough pill to swallow because we will soon have a grandchild.
Tomorrow, right?
Tomorrow we have a granddaughter in Texas.
It is not fair to them that they lose their grandparents.
But it is also important to us that they are told that they lost their grandparents because of something we did.
We want them to have that inheritance men-
-But also understand that they need to do good things in this world as well.
That is the assignment for us.
We must continue to tell the world to keep doing good things.
You will go through a tragedy in your life and it will change you.
You have to let that change be positive.
You can't let this change give you hatred, because that's the only option.
Anger and hatred, I don't want to live that way.
Today as you say when you hear about terrorist attacks or shootings and similar things happening.
Are you still afraid when you hear something?
Because of that day ..
New York City is a fantastic city where you can go anywhere by taking the train, so I've always traveled.
Some fantastic female volunteers here found out that I couldn't take the train anymore.
They took me on a train, I panicked and was very upset but they talked to me in the meantime.
However, I have not been on a train since.
Because I did it with them and there was some comfort.
I thought I couldn't do it.
What did they tell me well?
You can do it, you did it with us.
So now you don't have to worry about ever doing it again, don't worry about it!
It is a society where you are in a club that you did not want to be a member of.
We are undoubtedly involuntary members of this September 11 club.
But had it not been for the tribute center I would not have met the people I did.
These are the ones who helped me to heal and it was they who helped him heal.
We have become a family and it is thanks to the tribute center.
Why would we like to tell our story?
Surely no one wants to hear.
But people continue to come and as long as they continue to do so, we are willing to talk.
Simply because they stole the votes for almost 3000 people but they did not stole ours.
That's how we fight that terrorism, we're still talking.
If you include all people from Pentagon.
Oh, yes!
Pentagon, Shanksville.
We have met them, we have gone to their memory moments.
We don't like the reason for how we met them, but we are very proud to have them in our life-
-for it had not been for what we all went through, we would not have met the most wonderful people.
We have traveled all the way to Gander in Newfoundland just to say thanks to the city.
A city in Canada that received 38 aircraft with over 7,000 people that day.
Their population knew exactly what they would do and I've always said-
-That they showed the best side of humanity when we saw the worst.
It is the kindness of so many strangers after 9/11.
In our own city I could not walk a block without someone offering me a hamburger or a sandwich-
-or a bottle of water and so it was!
These are those days, all year after 9/11 that we hold up at-
-For we saw kindness and humanity when it was best.
After these 24 hours where we struggled to fight the hatred and get people out.
We tried to help people out if there were any survivors left.
We live with it, could anyone have done something to save these people?
18 years later we know that people had to die because of exactly where the aircraft drove in.
But so many of us wonder what we may have done differently.
It's hard not to, but when we hear from a knife cut or a shooting.
To Ecampel the latest shootings in Pearl Harbor, the one in the grocery store and in Florida.
We thought "wait, no?".
This happened three four days in a row and we just sat down.
We didn't go anywhere.
We sat down and tried to breathe and tried to go through it.
We talk on the phone with our friends who ask if we are okay which we are not.
How do we solve this?
Then he gets quiet and I don't want to talk.
Then after four or five days I say: "No, we can't continue like this".
We have to come back, we have to come back.
Every terrorist attack, shooting and knife-cutting is a reason for us to continue to fight-
-And make our community stronger, but it's tough.
The first few days we relived 9/11 and we have to find a way to get through it.
We are not the only ones, there are thousands in the same situation.
In addition to all this, seven people who worked after the attacks of 9/11-related diseases died.
When all these things were going on, we would lose people because of the terrorist attack.
Because of the poisons they breathed in.
So now we see all horrible things that happen in the other side of town and then our friends die.
It was a tough two weeks for us.
But, but we're here, that's the only way we can think of.
We are here, we survived.
Many have used the terrorist attack to split human
-and spreading hatred for political reasons.
What do you think about it?
Politics has no one to do with September 11.
I do not care.
That day it didn't matter what your religion was.
It didn't matter what your faith was.
It didn't matter what skin color you had.
That day was all a hero, they saved someone else and they didn't say ::
"Are you Catholic? Are you Jewish? Are you a Protestant?"
No, that day we were all just humans and that's how it should continue.
When it comes to politics.
Politicians who want to help us can come.
If they will not help us then do not criticize us, do not talk to us about it.
Some come to us to ask about conspiracy theories.
We look at them and say I'm not a conspiracy theory.
It happened!
I'm here!
I'm here to tell you it happened and I was there.
He can tell because he saw it.
What conspiracy theories?
Oh, the government did.
If our government did, I don't want to hear.
No, I'm worried about the affected families and that's what the world needs to care about.
Conspiracy theories belong where they belong, the one who started it, keep it.
We say to children:
"Want to learn more? Get where the stories are. Lift your head off the computer and stop thinking:
"They said this and they said the other".
Go there where the stories are.
Go to the people who lived and experienced it.
Go to the truth!
Conspiracy theories?
We live it!
This is not a theory, it is not a conspiracy.
What was a conspiracy was that 19 men believed in a man's hatred.
They came here and thought it was honorable to kill themselves.
They believed in the theory from the hated man, we don't even like to say his name.
It was a conspiracy, he told them to hate us and they decided they would kill us.
Do you want to talk about a conspiracy?
It was a conspiracy!
Anyone who continues to shoot people because they are Jews or because they are Mexicans.
Those who continue to treat them poorly because someone told them that they are criminals, it is a conspiracy theory!
Read on.
Attention.
Make your own research.
Educate yourself!
Don't believe what someone says just to tell us to the children.
Common sense.
If you want to know the truth, go where the truth is.
I don't believe in anything that someone tells me just because they told me it.
I want to investigate and think for myself!
The 18 men who did this did not think through it themselves.
They believed in what a man said to them:
"We have to kill Americans, we have to hurt them"
"Let's influence their finances, let's influence their military, let's influence their government" and that's what they did-
-and the murdered people because of this.
I have no time for conspiracy theories, not at all!
No, it's not on the map!
This is also a reason why I want to make this video so your votes are heard.
Politics has nothing to do with it, it is a human issue.
It is the human factor.
So I guess this is your message or why do you want to do this interview?
I hope that children will see this and understand that you start to start thinking yourself early.
If someone tells you to bully someone and you do it-
-trot that the person has not done anything to you.
Just because someone tells you to do it.
The terrorists thought in the same way.
"Oh, this man told us what Americans did, that and the other-
-So we'll believe it. "
Think for yourself, be your own person.
My most important message to children is:
“You are our future so you need to find a way to make society stronger-
-So if hate comes there it is already strong
Your society will fight against it and then everyone knows: "See what they were doing".
That's what I brought with me after September 12 when we heard about what they were doing in Gander, Newfoundland.
They were as scared as we, they accepted 38 aircraft.
What if a terrorist was aboard one of these?
They opened their doors.
No matter how nice we were here in New York, I would never open my door to anyone and say to them:
"Here, take a shower. I'll be back in a while"
You just don't do it here, but so did people in Gander.
They did it.
So they showed us that it can be done.
Friendliness and humanity.
That's it, humanity!
For me, it's always about our young people.
Learn, hear the stories of those who were there who tell us how it happened and why.
They don't say you should hate anyone.
They say you should be your very best, be the change you want to see in this world.
It is my message whether you are young or old.
There are some people who still carry feelings of hatred and we understand them.
But we try to meet them and say:
"When you wear anger, just let them win. Do you want them to win?"
Please be the best thing you can be.
Be as good a person as possible and if we can get this message we will.
That is why we are here, we are all people, we are all the same.
But we have differences that are what makes us unique.
When I hear from someone who tells me:
"Oh, this is how we celebrate it in our country".
"It is fantastic!
We care and learn more about it.
"Wow, it's amazing! We might take it after that!"
Now that we are grandparents, we want them to bring this with them.
It is the best way to teach your children by learning about other people.
You are never too old to learn, never too old to learn.
It is you!
I want to thank you for this interview.
I want to thank you so much for this.
You are our voice.
That's it, you're our voice.
We are the voice for those living in this and you are our voice to spread the message.
I am very grateful to meet you, it has been very interesting to listen to your stories.
I know it's very tough and hard-
-And I know you were also worried about doing this interview.
Yes.
You really send a message that I hope those who see this take care of.
Thanks!
Defend the right for humanity!
All cultures.
Thanks so much, thank you!
Thank you for coming!
Now let's help you put everything back.
Does it feel good?
Yes!
Good!