Going to school can be demanding.
You are expected to concentrate on lessons, remember homework and samples.
At the same time as you should relate to classmates and teachers.
Is the head at the same time full of hard thoughts and emotion-
-In it difficult to focus on what your teachers say.
Feeling worse in periods and feeling that everything is wrong is perfectly normal.
But if what feels hard takes over too much or holding in
-An longer you may need support in sorting out what weighs one.
Many people feel bad in periods.
What I have noticed in recent years-
-Is that many students feel even worse about staying at home.
Not to go to school.
Sometimes it is better to be in school.
Be a little passive and leave it.
You do not always have to deliver and perform at a high level.
But sometimes it goes a long way to just come to school-
-and join the community.
I think that I have seen many students who still feel good about.
There are no requirements on you how you have to be social-
-or that you have to come up with a lot of energies.
Sometimes but sad, sometimes you are a little angry, sometimes you are happy-
-Int is you angry ... all emotions are totally okay to feel.
Come to school as you are.
I think that when the pondering becomes so tangible for one-
-That it takes over a little too much, so you don't get energy-
— maybe do other activities, or that you get a little powerless-
-Then I think it's a sign that it's time to go and talk to someone.
But again, I would really like to say: come and talk to adults.
About big and small.
One should probably never be afraid to put words into how to feel-
-And how to do it.
Is it that ...
... that you need help.
If one is a little afraid to put word-
-and start processes, so maybe it is still a sign on-
-That you need to talk to an adult.
Then you may need support in moving on.
An important thing to know if one comes to a curator-
-This is that we have a professional ethical duty of confidentiality.
That means what you tell me it will stay with me.
Unless you are in any kind of danger.
Then I have to take it further.
Maybe to parents or other instances that you need help from.
Then it does not always have to be so that you end up in a large process-
-As because you come to a school curator and talk about how you feel.
I meet many students where we may have three to four calls-
-And maybe we have some follow -up a little later.
Some quick tips for those who might not be on top right now-
-This is that - number one: I think it's pretty normal.
You feel bad for periods.
You will feel better!
Number two: Exercise.
Try anyway.
All these things like exercise, diet, sleep - start there!
Because it will affect how the brain works as well.
And of course: Take the help of adults around and their peers.
Are you worried about yourself or for any other-
-Is it important to put words into it.
A first step toward feeling better-
-As to talk about how to do it.
You can always contact an adult at your school-
-But there are also many organizations that you can turn to.
Texting: Fredrik Nygren Iyuno Media Group for UR