Sometimes your math calculation does not match the fact.
It is good.
Too as important as being able to count right-
-Is to have good strategies to understand what went wrong.
Being able to troubleshoot.
Have you understood the task?
Read it again so you know you haven't missed anything.
Think about whether you have chosen the right method to solve the task.
There may be another way.
Check that you have not made any calculation error or written the wrong character.
It may be some brackets or some minus signs that you have missed.
You still can't find the error?
In that case, you should do this:
Write down and calculate the task again on a new page.
If you get the same result twice, the risk is small that it is a careless error.
But if you get different results you can start comparing your calculations-
-And think about what has gone wrong.
Texting: Camilla Dunér www.btistudios.com