To start a new academic year and new semester
May feel like a new start.
And just like at a new year set many new goals
And want to change or improve on the new academic year.
But as common as it is to set goals
Is it to lose interest after a while.
It is difficult to keep the energy and the will you felt from the promise.
But there are things you can do to make it easier for yourself.
To improve and reach further requires effort and will.
So think about what exactly you would like to improve.
It might be about getting into the right high school line
Or just prove to yourself that you can if you are striving.
Keep in mind that everyone who is good at something has spent a lot of time.
Whether it's about counting math,
Write well or run fast.
In order to cope with the entire semester,
Start by writing up your goals
And think about why you want to achieve the goals.
Motivation works like with almost everything else.
It must be maintained.
To achieve your goals you need to maintain your motivation!
So write down what you want to achieve and what is important to you.
When you may have lost later during the semester
a bit of your will and your motivation
Go back and look at what you wrote!
Try to write down why you want to reach your goal
and what is important to you as accurately as possible
so that you can get into the same feeling
When you read it at a later date.
Because you will spend a lot of time at school
With your classmates and with your teachers.
Put extra energy into helping to create a nice climate.
Even though you and your classmates may be different.
Make sure to respond to everyone in a nice way.
It will be much nicer for you and your class
If everyone exerts a little extra
to include and show appreciation for each other.
It becomes much easier to keep the energy during the semester
If you have a good atmosphere in the classroom.
So do what you can to maintain a nice atmosphere!
And remember,
No matter how easy or difficult you have for school, you can reach your goals.
To reach where one wants to be much more about
motivation, will and endurance
than what talents you were born with.