Here are some tips on memory techniques-
-What makes it easier to remember what you have learned.
A good method is the ten -minute rule.
The key to remembering better is repetition.
Because without repetition, what we learned disappears fairly quickly.
And keep in mind that you have to repeat before you start to forget.
The first rehearsal event should thus come quickly-
- After the learning - already after ten minutes.
Otherwise, you will forget pretty quickly.
The next rehearsal will take place after a day and then after a week.
If you want to remember all your life you have to repeat again-
-After a month and then after six months.
A good method when repeating is to interrogate yourself with flashcards.
Thus patches where you write the gloss, the name-
-or the concept that you should learn on one side-
-And the answer to the other.
So if you eg
shall plug in Englishaglosor-
-Es you write the English word on one side-
-And what it's called in Swedish on the other.
Flashcard is also easy to bring-
-So take the opportunity to interrogate yourself on the break or on the bus.
Another effective method for remembering is to use association.
Then you connect new knowledge with something that you associate them with.
It will make it easier to remember.
For example, if you
Should teach you new gloss - what do you think the word sounds like?
What makes you think about?
Feel free to create images in the head of what you think.
You can also find your own frames that link the associations.
The snapper they are, the better, because then you remember them easier.
You can also use a so -called
Memorial walk, or the loci method.
It is about the fact that you think you are placing out the fact-
-When you need to learn in different places that you know well.
As your home or maybe along the way to school.
Then you connect what you should learn with the different places-
-And creates an association.
When you then sit on the test, you can walk the walk in the head-
-And pick up the fact that is linked to the different places.
It is important that you follow the walk in the same order-
-As you placed the fact.
One last trick for not forgetting on the test-
-As to use a permitted cheat.
So - when you sat down on the test - ask for a scrap paper-
-and write down all the facts, all words, concepts or formulas-
-When you think you should forget.
Then you can release it-
-And does not have to sit with unnecessary stress during the test.
Instead, you can use your energy to answer the questions.