A short story is a short story-
-Unlike a novel, which is longer and has a lower pace.
In a short story, the main character is often introduced early.
There are no direct rules for how long a short story may be.
Tips when writing a short story:
Have a red thread through the story.
Stick to the action.
Plan: What are the characters?
What will happen?
Where is it?
How will it end?
Do you have a message or a sense of morality that you want to reach out with?
Introduce the characters and any conflict early.
Think out good details.
You can use popular cultural references.
If, for example, the character listens to music, mention the song or artist.
It can arouse associations.