Are you behind with school assignments?
Has teachers started to remind you of submissions you haven't even started?
Hörni, Reading Log Two should be finished until Tuesday, so ...
-Isn't that next Tuesday?
-No, it was now on Tuesday.
Maybe the plan was to plug in yesterday, but instead you hung with a friend.
It is easy to close your eyes and postpone the tasks to be done.
But it just gets more difficult the longer you wait.
Here are tips on how to catch up if you ended up with the information.
Overall picture.
Start by thinking about everything you need to do.
Write down all the information so that it becomes clear to you.
The English we have this week, well?
Write when the information is to be Klara-
-And think about how long you need to spend on each task.
-Sweden was still pretty much.
-It will take five days.
When you are done with a task, check it.
It is motivating to see that you get things done.
Hold on.
Is the list of things to be made long-
-Attempts to visualize how it will feel when you have done everything.
Maybe you have an intense period right now-
-But try to see it in a larger perspective.
And even though it feels far away now, you will do it.
Prioritize.
A good way to get started is to structure up-
-What is most urgent and what can wait.
What is important is the chemistry test.
We have that next week on Friday.
Yes, and the language selection test and the Reading log in English.
Although everything feels urgent, prioritize anyway.
Decide what to do first - you can't do everything at the same time.
Talk to your teachers if you get stuck with a task.
Aim to get all the information in time.
But if you feel it is impossible, talk to your teacher.
-We don't understand what to do.
-And we won't have time.
Maybe you can get guidance and help with how to get started.
Start by describing core line ...