If you have been involved in the lessons, you should know the basic knowledge.
In English and Swedish it is not so much about fact-
-Or about the ability to talk and reason.
The national test is counted as a large part of the grade, but not everything.
If you have shown what you can on other tests and lessons, you have it in mind.
The teachers think about the whole.
The test is a way to raise your grades.
Since you are more in the group, you can both lead the conversation, listen and participate.
Listen actively during each call.
National is not a competition.
If the group succeeds, then you succeed.
Help each other and make sure everyone gets to talk, so it will be a better conversation.
The national test is not for putting you there.
Most often, the teacher has adapted the group so that you get good dynamics.
Much of the oral national are things you already can-
-for example.
To talk, listen and answer questions.
Under National you should do just that - just with a little more commitment.
Before English, plug in synonyms!
You get a larger vocabulary and can use more advanced formulations.
Practice discussions with people in your vicinity.
Listen and ask questions.
The stress before the test may feel hard, but it can help us!
In case of short-term stress, adrenaline is excreted, making us alert-
-And it makes us think and reason faster.
Visualize that the test is going well.
It becomes like a mental preparation.
And give yourself good conditions by settling in time.
And don't forget to have breakfast.
You can do this.
Good luck!
Texting: Moa Eneroth www.btistudios.com