Reasoning is done in many subjects and has the use of your entire life.
You often make different decisions and have to reason about advantages and disadvantages.
Reasoning means developing thoughts and opinions.
You can say something: Meat is bad for the environment.
But why?
What do you base the claim on?
A reasoning should explain and deepen a thought or opinion.
The teacher tells us what you can develop by starting from the knowledge requirements.
They describe the different levels you can show knowledge.
The knowledge requirements define what rating you receive.
According to the knowledge requirements, a reasoning can be simple, developed-
-and well developed.
Superbly, right?
No, an example is needed.
This is how a book tip can be a well -developed reasoning.
Why should you read the book?
Wait.
Here are thoughts to develop.
Explain what you mean.
Why do you think like you do?
Give examples.
It raises the quality of your reasoning.
The book is thus exciting.
Why do you think that?
What does it lead to?
Just!
You developed the reasoning-
-When of telling us what was exciting with examples.
The book is about courage.
Problematize by using different perspectives.
"On the one hand" lets you show how you see things in different ways.
Why is it important not to judge others?
What could it lead to?
Does the book have any message?
In what way would it be better?
There you got thoughts that the book aroused.
You also generalized by showing what others can learn from the book.
When developing a reasoning, you should stick to one thought at a time.
Then develop what you want to say by asking why, how, when and what.
It becomes even clearer if you give examples.
Use binding words to tie together and get a good flow in the reasoning.
You do not just do any reason in school.
You make others understand what you mean and develop your own thoughts and ideas.
You will benefit from this in several subjects and in your spare time.
Texting: Elisabeth Enström