In our time, high demands are placed on technical knowledge.
Technical improvements solve many problems.
In the technology subject you should develop your own technical ideas and solutions.
Developing technical solutions requires both creativity and problem solving.
An architect, for example, must first identify and examine the needs-
-And try ideas for solutions with sketches and models.
For example.
the building may be climate smart and functional.
But it should look good and be economical.
When there is a proposal, a drawing is designed, and the house can be built.
The technology development work in the school is similar to the architect's work.
To assess the quality of your work and tell you what you can develop-
-Your teacher always starts from the knowledge requirements.
The requirements for technology in grade nine stand:
To systematically try and re-examine ideas act om-
-Developing and adapting solutions to different requirements.
Here comes an example:
Here is a picture of what the area looks like.
Okay, Attefallshus we have talked about.
It may be a maximum of 25 square meters.
The neighbor's house is quite close, so I put in the middle of the other side.
According to the Swedish National Board of Housing, Building and Planning's site, Attefallshus must be 4.5 m from the site boundary.
There the house ends up well.
How loud should it be?
It may be a maximum of 4 m between ground and roof.
Then it will be tough with two floors-
-But I build a sleeping loft and get more floors to put furniture on.
Good!
With the help of the plot map and the Swedish Housing Agency's website-
-You examined the conditions for the assignment.
You also weighed the need for space in the form of an extra sleeping loft.
The last lesson we looked at hold and stable constructions.
How do you choose in this case?
I use the roof chairs to create the sleeping loft.
Yes, they make it stable.
Do you have any ideas about the foundation?
I cast a concrete slab.
In it there should be a grid of reinforcing iron.
Then I get better tensile strength in the concrete.
Good foundation.
And the concepts of concrete slab, reinforcing iron and tensile strength-
-Shi that you use a technical vocabulary.
Maybe there are more adjustments that make the house energy efficient?
You should minimize heat loss and maximize gains.
For example.
Should the house not be built in shade.
Do you have to rethink something then?
Yes.
I have to move the house a bit from the spruce forest that shadows.
-Anything else?
-Yes, choose the appropriate insulation in the walls.
By lifting in energy-efficient solutions you got new ideas-
-When you show the sketch.
Some work remains before you can do drawings.
For example.
Must all dimensions match and be scaled.
But now we leave the example.
Technology development work in the school can be divided into different phases.
In the example, the need was first clarified: to build an Attefallshus.
The need was then examined on the basis of different requirements-
-for example.
Building rules, strength and energy efficiency.
The proposal was tested and re -examined.
New ideas meant that the student had to investigate new things.
Then the ideas were developed into a good proposal for a solution.
In the example, the student talked with a teacher-
-But most often the work must be documented, so save your sketches.
Sometimes a physical or digital model is needed to see that the proposal works.
The written documentation required
-To see the teacher what choices and changes you have made.
So remember to motivate your choices.
Technology development work is reflective work-
-Where you value and develop your proposal for a solution.
It is an innovative work that you will benefit from in several subjects.
Texting: Sofia Sundqvist