You know the feeling when to do a test.
You get the test, watch and you take nothing.
Absolutely not a word.
If you have not plugged, you may blame yourself.
If you have plugged and yet do not take you can test different strategies-
-To get out of that feeling of brain drop.
When it feels impossible to focus, you can test a relaxation exercise.
Close.
Pull up and drop your shoulders.
Place your hand on your stomach and take some deep breaths.
Massage your fingers.
Stir gently on the head and massage the shoulders.
It makes you relax and reduce the stress.
You get the bloodstream running, oxygenate the brain and get your thoughts.
Now look at the questions again.
Is it still completely still in the brain?
Okay, then ignore the questions for a while.
Write down everything you know about the subject on a scrap paper.
You brainstorms then and do not lock the idea of the question but think freely.
It is good to draw images to use another part of the brain.
Go back to the scrap paper when the stress has released-
-And it is easier to come up with the answers.
Do not force words that you do not come up with.
Write something else for so long.
It may be in response until further notice and you continue with the test.
As you read your answers again, the word can suddenly appear in the brain.
Keep in mind that you can take help from your teacher.
Ask questions.
Don't just say: "I don't understand."
Be more specific.
"What does this word mean?"
"What is in demand?"
The teacher may be able to develop the question so that you come up with the answer.
If you get stressed by sound around you try to shut them out.
There may be hearing covers in the classroom.
Or bring your own earplugs.
Some tips for getting out of the feeling of brain drop:
Do a relaxation exercise to reduce stress and think better.
Write down everything you can think of on a scrap paper instead of getting stuck.
Draw a picture of what is in demand.
If you get stuck on one question, write another word for so long.
Ask your teacher or ask to have the question read loudly.
Remove sounds that stress you.
Use hearing aids or earplugs.