Everyone is postponing things.
Sometimes we need it.
When we postpone something even though we know it gets negative consequences-
-Then we procrastinate.
It might be that you postpone to plug because you don't cope-
-Fast you have less time tomorrow-
-and won't be able to plug so much.
We let short-term benefits control-
-Sagare than thinking in the long term and seeing the benefits of grabbing things.
Identify your designs and excuses.
I'm too tired right now.
I read the text when I'm in the right mood.
I still work better under pressure.
I'm just gonna...
Overlook.
One reason we postpone something is because it feels too big.
Divide what you should do into different parts.
If you are going to count math, start with a page in the math book-
-or maybe a dozen.
Plan and create structure.
Plan in when you are going to plug, but even when you are free.
Rather plan shorter plug passes and allow yourself to take breaks.
If you plan in too much, the discomfort may increase-
-Then you might continue to postpone it.
Learn to live with the discomfort.
It's not always fun to plug.
We are good at finding on excuses-
-But you can plug when you are not motivated or when it is hard.
Five minutes.
If you notice that you are postponing a task, give it five minutes.
Maybe it loosens it and you can complete it.
Otherwise, spend five minutes again later.
To be satisfied.
Sometimes it is enough with "good enough".
Too high demands can lead to us not taking hold of homework.
Everything doesn't always have to be perfect.
Sometimes it is good to lower the bar.
Plug with a friend.
If you have determined time with some-
-Is the probability greater that you plug-
-and don't postpone it.
Reward you.
There can be small rewards.
You can reward yourself by seeing the latest episode of a Series-
-When you have clearly written the first pages of the task.
Sometimes we have to postpone things, but try to withstand short-term advantage-
-and try to think long term.
What do I win the most?