One way to take on what you read about is to ask questions to the text.
null
Questions such as "When?", "" How? "," Where? "," Who? "And" Why? "
"When was the Renaissance?"
"How often is it election to the EU?"
null
Or: "Why is sleep so important?"
Imagine you want to know more about what you read.
null
Be curious about how it continues and what you will learn later.
When you ask questions to the text, use the knowledge you have.
null
That there is a period of time called the Renaissance.
That it is chosen for the EU.
null
That you have to sleep.
When you ask questions, the brain works and what you read is easier.
null
Texting: C. Dyfverman Sverrenius www.btistudios.com