See how the hare hunts, guess and run  all directions without getting anywhere.
But what do we have here?
Turtle!
methodical, smart, factual.  one step at a time.
It was different that!
It is a bit similar to mathematics.
math can be difficult,  sometimes it may feel impossible.
then one should not increase the pace.
Take it easy instead.  one step at a time.
It's no competition.
Do not do like the hare running, hunters,  and hope it will be right.
Think a little more like the turtle.  objectively to weigh.
It is not going fast,  there no speed competition.
In the end it is still the turtle  gets the correct result.
There are many strategies  take in math.
one of them, perhaps the most important,  to take it easy.
Take a deep breath, look at the result.  the reasonable?
It is an equation you calculated, replace x  your answer and count again.
Then you know if you've done right or not.  is pretty smart.
So, take it easy with the mat.  one step at a time.
Was a turtle.