But God, of course, they sit there now that I couldn't fix myself.
Oh my God.
-Come again, I can.
I don't need makeup to be good looking.
Natural Beauty.
Okay, this is going well.
Smile too.
No, not so much.
I want to seem a little difficult too.
Why is she going like that there
Oh.
-She think she's so damn good looking.
... so damn good looking, so damn good ...
Come on, just go as usual.
How was it you did now
It wasn't that dangerous.
"You worked that runway."
God, no now I come too late ... Then everyone sees that I am unchanged!
Hi, Freja!
-Heh, Stina.
I'm in a hurry.
You look a little tired, what is the situation?
-Good, but ...
You had a time with me on Monday.
We can talk now instead.
I must go.
Now nothing can distract me.
God...
He is so good looking.
And he comes to me.
Will he say some hell, I'm unfixed!
He must not see me like this.
But how can someone be so perfect
So damn nice hair.
Why doesn't the Finn disappear
What is it wrong with the eyebrow
Shit, he looks at me ... or maybe not.
You are the nicest Gärin in town.
-In the city?
Not in the world?
No, you don't understand, me ... -nähä, so I'm stupid in my head?
No ... -Yeah, what good!
Thanks, Schyst!
Jasmine, don't go, we can talk.
Hey.
-Hello.
I'm so ugly today.
Damn, what I am ashamed.
What I am ashamed.
The lesson too ... no idea to go in now, everyone will see me.