Most of us detect and have difficulty dealing with stress.
Why is it like that?
How does it affect the body?
What is stress?
Stress is a natural reaction found in all animals and humans.
It is the body's way of preparing for a challenge.
For example, you should compete or lecture.
During challenges, the body's functions are tightened.
It may be good to know that stress is not dangerous.
The short -term stress is good.
The problem is when the stress becomes prolonged without the body going down in turns.
One should distinguish between short and long-term stress.
Short -term stress raises the immune system.
You don't have time to be sick.
In case of prolonged stress, the immune system is broken down.
In prolonged stress, the stress hormone cortisol is excreted in the brain.
We get too much of it.
It can adversely affect the brain.
In an information society, it is not clear when a threat is over.
Brown bear is dangerous, I run, but then the danger is over.
Now that we live more in our heads, we can start stress by thinking.
"God, think what embarrassing I wrote yesterday."
"The test I will never fix."
This thinking gives the same physical response as a brown bear.
It is a challenge how to rest and go down in turn-
-and not stress by thinking.
Not to start the stress response by thinking.
Short -term stress is not dangerous.
But during prolonged stress-
-Sjunker the immune system and the content of cortisol are increasing.
Therefore, it is important to let the body go down in turns so you can recover.