A factual text is full of information, and it may feel difficult-
-To know how to take in everything in the text.
But there are strategies that can help you.
And which also makes the book feel more interesting.
A first step is to decode the book: to create a perception-
-If the content of the text before you start reading.
Here's how you do: Look at the cover.
What does it say?
Read the text on the back of the book.
Check the table of contents.
What does the book seem to be about?
Browse the book.
Check out pictures and fact boxes.
Read the captions.
Look out for summaries and words in bold or italicized style.
When you decode the book, you give yourself an understanding of the subject.
You start to get into what you should learn is about.
When it comes time to read the text at real-
-Do you already check the content.
And it facilitates your learning.
You can also obtain understanding by reading magazines, see movies-
-Youtube clips and search the web on the subject.
When the new one meets what you already know to-
-Ir your knowledge both deeper and larger.
Texting: Camilla Dunér www.btistudios.com