To reason you do in several school subjects and in many other contexts.
As you reason you develop your thoughts and opinions.
The teacher tells us what you can develop by starting from the knowledge requirements.
The social science states that the pupil should bring nuanced reasoning-
-and describe complex relationships.
So how different things are interconnected.
It can be a little tricky.
An example of how to nuance a reasoning and explain the relationship.
The subject is opinion formation.
They use relevant concept-
-And addresses factors that affect the possibility of reaching out.
They give concrete examples that they also problematize.
Complex relationships are formed when they reason about how everything is interconnected.
Here we must find out which factors are important for influence.
It is easy to start a group in social media.
But how do you get an effect?
It is about power.
It matters who you are and who you know.
Interesting.
They use relevant concepts and have mentioned two factors-
-which is important for the opportunity to influence.
In this case, status and network.
Can they develop using examples?
Yes, status plays a role.
If a celebrity I like takes a stand for something, I will be affected.
Surely others too.
Many people follow their updates.
Many followers give power.
On the one hand, celebrities immediately get many followers.
On the other hand, social media has evened out the opportunities to influence.
With the right timing, anyone can create opinion.
The reasoning is nuanced.
Students problematize examples of opportunities to reach out-
-And uses the expressions "on the one hand" and "on the other".
If you develop your thoughts in several stages, reasoning chains are formed.
And so complex relationships, how different arguments and examples are interconnected.
How does the students show it?
We change perspectives.
If two ordinary people want to drive the same question-
-What improve school food, is there a difference in who we listen to?
For example, it is about how to say something.
Do you have the habit inside?
Or which words you choose.
The person's socio -economic background plays a role.
It affects how you express itself.
You can be more or less credible.
The background is not decisive whether they were herself affected or witnessed.
But how others interpret what you say also depends on gender and appearance.
The story becomes different depending on the storyteller.
The background can be decisive for who they know.
Even if you are not a celebrity, you can feel influential people.
Yes.
You have to reach someone with the power to influence.
You have to be strategic, choose the right channels.
Yes!
Complex relationships are formed when explaining how factors are connected.
Then you can describe similarities and differences in several stages.
Students are in complex relationships depending on socioeconomic background-
-When they link to other factors such as credibility, gender and appearance.
They also address networks and strategy.
We leave the example of opinion formation and look at the knowledge requirement.
In all subjects one must know relevant concepts.
Find out important concepts before you start.
Find different factors that affect what you reason about.
Explain how these affect each other.
Give real examples.
Show that you know what you are talking about.
There are different ways to look at most.
Which perspective have you chosen?
Finally: How are your different arguments related?
Describe the relationship by pointing out similarities and differences.
Then you show more or less complex relationships.
Being able to explain how things are connected, you often benefit.
Both in several school subjects and in other situations outside the school.
Texting: Elisabeth Enström