We are fed every day with new information and new impressions,
And much of that we don't have to remember.
For example, it is not important to remember exactly
What all the people on the bus looked like.
But many things want and we need to remember!
With different memory strategies we can remember better.
One such strategy is the Loci method.
Also called memory palace.
Loci is Latin for places.
The strategy is based on converting what you want to remember
to pictures and imagine these placed
Somewhere in an environment you know well.
Starting from a place.
For example, your home.
The best thing is if the place is divided into several parts
For example, different rooms.
The more defined places are apart, the easier it will be.
Go for a walk through your palace
And place what you need to remember!
For example, if you have to remember different types of vertebrates
can you imagine a snake to rush out
Under that old office standing out in the hall
Imagine what it looks like,
How the mountain feels.
When you then move on into the kitchen
Do you see that the kitchen doors have become bird cages.
When you open the cabinet, a pigeon flashes.
Visualize how it sounds, feels or smells.
The more in -depth you imagine things,
The easier they will be to remember.
When you then sit on a sample
Can you go through your "palace" mentally.
Stop in the different places and pick up the fact that is connected to the site.
It is important that you follow a definite route,
both when placing out the items,
And when to remember them later.
It is with the help of our senses
sight, taste, hearing, feeling and smell
We perceive information.
So when you are going to learn something new,
Try to use as many senses as possible.
Then it becomes easier to remember!
Had you just said crawfish in the hall
And birds in the kitchen would not have become as strong.
Make the pictures in your palace as vivid as you can!
How or where you place the knowledge
does not have to be logical or useful for someone else.
The method works better
The strange and more personal information you connect to the item or place is.
The reason why weird images work better
is because the memory is more susceptible to what is deviant.
The brain records easier things that are strange than completely normal.
The more you use the loci method
The better you will be at creating your memory palaces!
It may feel unusual at first,
But over time you will get the strategy