To do several things at the same time to try to be more efficient-
-Can of course sound like a good idea.
But there is a risk that it instead makes a less effective.
Because the brain's working memory is limited in how much it can handle
-can too many things to focus on, and things that are disturbed-
-Glag that you lose focus.
Because it is not true that you focus on several things at the same time-
-Outan you share and shift your focus-
-And for each replacement, your concentration is broken.
Then it may take time before you find back again-
-and for the brain to change.
Time that you could have utilized better.
On lessons it may mean you miss important information-
-Fear harder to learn, will have less-
-And may be allowed to bring more information home.
At home it can cause homework or other tasks to take longer-time-
-An what was really needed.
So not so effective.
So the best thing is to do one thing at the time-
-And reduce the number of times you are disturbed or switching between tasks.
Therefore, try to reduce the risk of being distracted.
Find a place that fits well for you-
-Funder on what distracts and what makes you better focused.
Often a quiet place can work well.
To plan what you are going to do and when reduces the risk that you change-
-Between different tasks.
Divide large tasks into smaller parts.
Then the chance that you can keep up increases.
Plan special time for tasks that require a lot of concentration.
Then it is extra careful not to be distracted.
If there is something special that you go and think about-
-Can you try to decide a time for when you have to think about it.
Put off your mobile and turn off notes-
-And tell friends and family that you are busy.
By focusing on one thing at a time and relieving the working memory-
-Can you increase your focus and concentration.
This in turn can make you more efficient-
-Both in terms of learning and time.