When I remember math concepts, I use a memory strategy.
I make a story about the word to remember.
It works in all subjects but I have chosen to use it within the mat.
First I think about the word.
Then I wonder: What does it really mean?
And what does it sound like?
But I have to do one thing first.
Namely to close your eyes.
Pythagora's kit.
Pytha, python ...
Yes, python!
Pythagora's kit is python.
Is that snake long or maybe it is short?
How should I find out?
Pythagoras well calculates how long a page is.
So a side of what?
Pythagora's kit fits well ... SATS ... cat.
Yes!
A cat's face I think about.
A cat looks like a triangle, a threesome.
By thinking of a python and a cat's face-
-I remember what Pythagora's kit is for something.
Cylinder ... bicycle wheels.
Rotating wheels.
Hamster wheels.
Yes, but it's around.
Cylinder, it sounds like my bindings.
What do I do of my used bindings?
I usually put them in a toilet paper roll.
And it is shaped like a cylinder.
Then I don't forget it.
Yes, but then I have my bindings in a cylinder.
Now I never forget what a cylinder is.
Isn't there such a road cone?
Cow, phone, con- Ny ...
Conny, that's my guinea pig.
And he loves cancerous disc.
Then you have party hats on.
And it's cone shaped!
It's my guinea pig.
Yes, then I just think of Conny when I remember a cone.
So I do to remember the different concepts.
Everyone can make their own stories.
There is no right and wrong.
By associating words and building a story, it becomes easier to remember.
Images are usually easier to remember than names.
So try yourself.
The crazier the better.
Texting: Camilla Dunér www.btistudios.com