Hello
Hello there
Welcome to this channel
Life on and off the stage
Today it will be a little different movie because I prepared namely
A movie that you will see later
If of course you want
Dealing with car care
And
I think I a movie that I think would fit ..
... ER who are interested in caring for your car and
It is quite large investment you make mainly if you buy a camper
A regular car too
So they are preparing
Today
But the movie you will see today is based on
I have received some requests
About wanting to see some backstage
Yes you who have been on the channel
You know that I
Not only deal with motorhomes like a hobby but I
Then also on stage and works as an actor producer
And
Director sometimes too
And I have played murder mystery throughout the fall and we will continue in the spring
I got one on instagram because it was i got a little message about
Wouldn't we be able to see a little neighbor what it looks like in castles
On Kalmar
A little backstage above do before the show
What looks like and so on and
I did like this that I
I took my camera and then I told the ensemble that we would make a little movie about this
And they took on the task with bravur
This camera it it brought around between the ensemble members
I don't really know as much as has been filmed but they have
I have filmed a great deal and
This is completely unedited
And
Just assembled from the outside
What is filmed out of the ensemble
So
We may well apologize if the sound is as it is
I try to boost it as much as I can but
But here is Iallafa ll is a movie about
Themselves
The murder mystery at Kalmar Castle
Death takes command
come along
So like this
Yes
Preparing into the last
What you will see now is then unedited
Cut from Kalmar Castle where we play Mogården
And do you think this is exciting and interesting then we play
Again now until spring 15 January 2022
Where are the eight performance
Can recommend it
Is a good Christmas present if it is now that you
Have a little idea to dry what to give to someone who has everything
So it is then would it work great with
Murder of Kalmar Castle
And besides, it is a 3 course
Dinner, too
Not to forget
Good food is a really really good food
That's how it is
Perfect is it
But now I will take and prepare
Former
That you are thrown right
Into from the lodge at Kalmar Castle and sees this material is on I say
Look and
Have much
You need Peter you need to do anything know you can
Stretch out the legs here take it easy
Fix it
Lets see
Now Vu has chased out all the ghosts out this room
Time for a little to drink
In other words
I think you should look like this all the time
Exactly, really my new hairstyle
Agree with
Now I will take them out now I will have to attract my little pile
We may hope that the next murder mystery that you may have these left
Yes
How are you going for you then
It's fine
We run some maud style here.
Really fancy I have to say
Nice looking
If you look at, you look at.
Here you stand and are looking
Seeking for the meaning of life
Far down in a box
What is it I have Joesfine, is that the one I have, huh?
I think so
Peter then we rig the lights here huh
Is it good with the chairs over there
Yeah that looks good
What is going there is the tray and the other glasses
Yeah just that yes
Check this out
This should be in the gray hall
Yeah, it should stand on the cabinet
Where
It's damn dangerous ......
Where should it stand somewhere
Uhhh ...
I can accompany you so I will show you
So
Perfect
Cannon
We go on into the gray hall, precisely the one it will stand up there
But you who are tall and stately
There is no inner gauge in the cabinet
Okay
Take off your shoes
So
Pope
Have i tell you a story about P Ovel
Povel Ramel
Lotta Rammel, I've been to a party there ....
VA
Do you have some apple juice
No
Is it up in the Kuretornet
What happened to Povel Ramel.
Well, there was a friend who knew her, I didn't know her ....
And when we got in there, a man suddenly came into a ...
Morning Rock .... It's Povel Ramel
He must have been the Thomas Di Living time
Hello Hi, then he just goes on .....
Is it good
Yes, it works well there.
Yes, it was Povel Ramel .....
We will see what happens in here then.
(Waffle)
Are it you who spinn my socks
Socks
Chairs ... the socks are left .....
What is happening here now
Here are lots of secrets the secret shrine ... Well it wasn't .... it was a bomb attack ...
(Ticking sound)
The voltage increases
Someone can help me move the cords ...
I fill this with something drinkable
I keep up
Now let's see here ...
What playground we got today ...
Huge
Hubertus is not a man who takes a lot of space on this earth
No, a very modest character
Nice and kind
Something like that, then they'll be backwards
Tongue as lead
It is noticeable that Daniel is used to hard body work
So it is in the arm ... it might not know about ...
No
Do you have anything else
Type of body work
Yes it is the more sweaty bodies
Candis sugar is in place.
Apple juice we have to fill in
The books are in place.
and Götes is in place, that's the most important thing
Who is this goth
The suffering of young Werther ....
Can't you read something
I can give you today's word ...
Today's word eating from Götes.
It is nothing.
As much as it is in Eugenia's head.
So wicked is hubertus
Yes so it is not every day you are at Kalmar Castle
RUT HALL
VA
Who would lie here tonight
Carlosvald
Yeah yes but that's good
Yes yes the time is ... we have 55 minutes on us
Now on film
Yes, I am.
I wondered what you walked around with.
Have fun.
You are welcome
I do not know
The lodge
Yes
Fantastic
(Laugh)
He tries to look at my conversations.
This is the secret deal
Yes Yes
Do you follow me yes I do
Oh, the clothes have come in too
You're lying to me
No, would never do
I am a very early gentleman, you should remember.
(Shot)
A shot, who was the one who shot
What is that sound.
It sounds like a clock.
Mushroom salad.
You get to taste
I feel that you can feel very strange.
So it is similar to what the Aztecs call Teonanacatl.
Oh, so you can mushrooms
No, I know nothing.
Neither do I.
It is similar to my father brought with her from his travels in South America.
Albert's death, what does Gür think about it
Albert's death, what do gur think about it
Albert's mouth will remain closed for all time, and that is good.
Hm, wonder what that is too button
Ha, it's ticking.
How fun.
A bomb.
Think about the father of it.
Why did Albert Maud give a bomb
He didn't.
I found it in his military trunk when he came morning.
He always brought presents with me, so I peeked in his bag ....
Found this one and knew it must be to me
You are not kind.
These tablets make me weak and insane and forgetful.
I forget everything after taking them.
Hubertus no, so yes my friend.
You just think so.
Give me the gun.
I don't think you know how to handle a gun.
Suddenly I hear a huge bang, and reflexively I get up ...
Bertil's death.
Yes.
But how did Albert get on you
I turned around, and behind me was Albert.
Revealed
But, this was two years ago.
How can Daniel still remain in the military
Albert came walking from Bertil's direction ....
and in his hand he held
The rise.
The bombing staircase.
He replaced it
Yes, and I stood with my pants down, and Albert glowed like a mood.
You will be arched, what the only thing he got out.
And I guess you said the same thing back.
Five
Five what is Hubertus talking about?
But it was well five children
Give me some must ....
Now I have to think clearly ... five ...
Well, the brother of love
Five
Uhhhh ... you have to help me count here now
First came Eugenia.
A day of sorrow
I think it is she who killed Albert.
Why
Sorry, i mean, i hope she who killed albert
no no
Not any of the four children are guilty.
Five
A gun give me it!
What is this doing
Do not know.
I haven't seen it before
It smells of gunpowder.
It does not at all it is not mine.
I've never seen it before.
Why is there a recently fired gun in your bag
I don't know ... it must have ...
You murdered Albert.
You shot him.
Why would I have killed Albert
Albert was shot.
How should you explain it to the county governor
Well, eugenia .....
Why do you have ...
Uh, wait now.
Sit down.
Yes, my mother always said that women are cunning than skator.
Skator
Empty your bag on contents, scary, unpleasant skates.
Freja, stop.
See, how easily the county governor got your balance.
You must be prepared, if you are now as innocent as you say.
Running around with the murder weapon requires you to think before you answer.
So, come so we have interrogation with the county governor.
You don't have your tablets, then Wednesday morning.
It's dangerous for you, Hubertus.
You can die from heart attack
But, I get so lethargic in the head of them.
No, no, you will not be lethargic.
You become sharply thought like a herring.
Herring.
Herring is one of the most common fish varieties.
It lives on both sides of the Atlantic ....
Empty your bag on contents, aircraft.
You think you can fly, but you are just a stupid ostrich trying to hide what you have.
Then we are done how does it feel Madde
Well then, it feels a bit sad
It is the last for the fall
But we got back
Yeah right when when we'll be back
I can't date but it's January
Fifteenth
Fifteenth January
Then we are back.
But now we'll pick down everything
It will be Christmas market at the castle and it will be Christmas table
What will it be for this castle now
We will bubble down as we called
You may keep up with simply
Wow
Feels good
Yes, what is this ....
Yes, you pick down the lights yes, so good
But the barn walls
Good you are
I have learned all terms
God what it was removed here then
There stands some disk to be washed
I'll leave
Stuff
Now we come to the secret area that visitors are not allowed to come to when you are at the castle
It is ... what is it called the cure tower ...
Base
No it's not base
The tower, the tower is this
It is the tower that one can see
The flag it will with home ...
Yes it works
What should I place these lights
We don't use it
Does someone use it
Well, it's Gurs Rucksack
But should everything be here or there
Here
No, there does not have to scoop it up
Yes yes but is it the box to the lights
Yes use it
Hello
Did you get with your Åsa up too or
I haven't seen Åsa
I take home my jug and the two mugs
Hello
We are visible and heard
And when do we appear yes we can see the eighth
Then we'll scratch
But when do we have performance
The 15th
January 15
Great
(Waffle)
Hello
What did you do now
What is not visible is not there
(Laugh)
Away
What is the pill to put in
Pill pills
Well
What did you say Madde
Ghosts
Is it ghosts here
You feel like that
Do you feel it is ghosts here
No
Should it be left or
Although Eugenia looks like a ghost
I do not think so
Gur shall talk too much
Here then, we should try to get down all our stuff now before we should ....
.... have some break
Whose is it that Pippi's Rucksack
It's Gur's jacket.
It's a little candy sugar.
We can shut it down.
Hello
What do you come up with for something exciting
A table
Chair
Yes there look.
Can the sir sit down
No clue
This is the Kuretornet
I have never been up here now and it might be ....
Lucky we are not up there and play
Then maybe you can happen to a murder for real
What do I know
Are you tired
Yes a little
We are in the process of packing our stuff together
It's not so much stuff here
We are ready for the fall.
But we will come to spring, or how
Jajemen
January.
January 15
Yes now everything is removed.
Has everyone picked up everything now
Yes
How nice
It's just the last now that is out and then so ....
I am just going to pick up myself
Yes good luck jenny
We....
Well
Yes then we take and take some Christmas holidays from the murder mystery in Kalmar Castle
We'll be back on it
January 15
So go in and book at Summer Theater.nu
Death takes command
Welcome