The synthesis test goes as follows: In a test room you can sit on a chair.
You will see a painting, then you should hold for your left eye-
- And read a row from left to right.
When done, you have to change your hand and eye-
- And hold for your right eye and read the same row from the right.
When you are done, you can read a line with both eyes.
If you have lenses or glasses, you bring them so we can use them during the synthesis test.
If you use night lenses, you may not have them a week before trial.
If you have impaired vision, bring a current prescription from the optician.
In the color release test, we check your color vision.
You will see numbers with clearly different color.
One, two or no numbers.
You have three seconds per painting.
During the hearing test you can sit in a soundproof hearing cage.
During the hearing test you have a pair of hearing aids on you, the red should be on the right ear.
In the test you will hear both bright high tones and low dull tones.
You press the button immediately when you hear a ton.
We check one ear at a time and the test starts on your right ear.