Negotiating your salary can feel both uncomfortable and
hard probably because you've never been taught how
one should actually prepare and conduct a negotiation
in a good way.
But it stops now.
In this video you will receive three concrete rhetoric tips to succeed in your payroll negotiations
For you who are new here on the channel
This is how my name Pontus F. Christoffersen I run
rhetoric consultant.com where I train the company to become
skilled communicators and increase their profitability through
Their presentations, meetings and negotiations.
Before we start: Do you have any specific arguments or
objections you usually hear and want me to give a good answer to
Write in the comments and I promise to come back.
Okay tip number one to negotiate your salary.
Avoid arguing from emotion and what you think you deserve.
Develop rational reasons why you
deserves the increase now they pray, how are you more valuable to
company now than a year ago how will you be more
Valuable for the company in the coming year
What have you done that was above expectation or that went beyond expectation
Your boss usually has an opportunity to keep track of
everything that everyone does, which means you need
become good at telling you everything you do so that your
The manager knows about it.
Tip number 2 to negotiate your salary.
We all almost make the mistake of going into a conflict
when we negotiate.
But instead of going in like a bulldozer and tell
that you should have an increase and it should be this large lay
Instead, it is like you want to grow with the company.
You want to become more valuable and for it to be
Motivating it needs to be fair in both directions.
You generate more value for them and they pay you more for
that you are more valuable.
So shape it as you have a
Discussion about the future.
Where you together try to find the best solution for
to develop together.
Tip 3 to negotiate your salary
And this is the most important strategy that you bring with you.
The absolute best thing you can do to raise your salary.
It is to discuss in advance how you can get where you want
be and set goals with your boss.
You can end the hearing you are going to in soon with that
Say something in the style of to get my salary to 32,000 next year.
What do I need to do until its
Set clear things that you are going to implement, because it will be very difficult for your
boss when you follow up on this a year later in the next
wage negotiation and you have done everything you will
Agree to not give you the salary that you asked for.
It is much smarter to work proactively in this way
than to try to argue your salary during a negotiation.
Okay that was all for this video if you want to learn
Negotiation technology so you should watch this video as well.
See you in it.