A medical abortion means that the abortion is done with medicines.
It is important that you are sure of your decision because the first tablet can make
The fact that you start bleeding and in some cases can cause you to get miscarriage.
First you have to come to a reception where you are examined and receive advice.
Then you get a tablet that starts the abortion.
You swallow the tablet with water and then you have to go home.
You can get a little bleeding after you take the tablet.
The next round of tablets you can take home or at the reception.
You and the healthcare staff agree on this at your first visit.
Insert the tablets into the vagina.
You need to lie still for at least 15 minutes after you have brought up the tablets.
You can feel bad and get a fever and chill, it is common and nothing is dangerous.
You start bleeding two to four hours after taking the tablets,
But sometimes it can take longer.
Take the last tablets after three hours.
You take the tablets whether you have started to bleed or not.
Insert the tablets into the vagina.
The tablets give you contractions in the uterus.
It feels like heavy men's cramps but how evil it varies,
And it can also vary how much you bleed, depending on how long you have been pregnant.
The longer you have been pregnant, the more you bleed.
You should have received painkillers from the reception that you can take if you need.
If you have not started bleeding after two days, contact the reception.
After the abortion it is common to bleed for one to two weeks
But how long and how much you bleed varies.
If you are early in pregnancy, you will bring a pregnancy test home.
The pregnancy test you do three to four weeks after the abortion.
You do the test to make sure you are not pregnant anymore.
It is important that you start with contraceptives immediately after the abortion, if you are going to have sex.