- Welcome to shrimp frozen.
-Last episode!
It feels sad.
- How does it feel to you?
-Good!
I've been here every week.
It has been really nice.
I also appreciate that there has been free admission.
Free is good!
A little thing just ...
I have traveled taxi back and forth for a pretty small sum ...
- How do we solve that bit?
-What do you mean?
Travel allowance, etc.
I have receipts, so there should be no ...
We cannot pay people's travels here.
But it will be very expensive, this!
Have you had a good week?
Yes.
I have had visits from relatives from Germany.
Have you done any fun this week?
Last Tuesday I shaved off my pubic hair.
I am really pleased.
Everyone says I look 20 years younger.
- You have always been a little vain.
-You also.
Yesterday I would buy a t -shirt.
-Can I help you?
- There are only three t -shirts here.
Sure, but what a quality!
Feel the material. This is not a dozen.
- It's too small, huh?
- It's stretchable.
- I don't get over my shoulders.
- Can't the first time, but ...
This is an Italian product that stretches 35-40 % after washing.
If it does not work, you can lose weight into the garment.
This one fits perfectly!
- I should look at another deal ... - no, no!
Nilsson, a customer needs help finding pants in the right size.
- I am looking for a t -shirt.
- interested in a pair of stylish pants?
No.
If you do not have a t -shirt in my size, I go somewhere else.
We have lots of t -shirts.
Here!
- They are too small.
- It's a stretch material.
I have heard that once before.
We have more T -shirts at the warehouse.
I pick them up.
I'll be right back.
- I found one that fits.
- This is your t -shirt!
- No, it was behind some boxes.
- You have taken off your sweater!
- Yes, it was a little warm ... - it's a coffee splendor there.
It is Italian design.
It represents a coffee splendor, but it is really the T -shirt's "logo".
-Lacoste has a crocodile ... - it's a little wet too.
Half price?
- Nilsson!
Pile into the warehouse and see if there are more t -shirts behind any box.
Nilsson goes in and looks if there are more T -shirts behind any box.
- I found it here in the warehouse!
- This is your t -shirt!
- Well!
I have hung it off.
- And no pants either ...!
- I took off my p.g.a.
the heat.
- It's so hot in the warehouse.
- We ignore this.
Bye.
- interested in Italian underwear?
What strange deal?
It was like a sketch.
So you filmed your clothing purchase?
The salesmen were similar to the actors from Änglagård and the hunters.
You stand with both feet firmly on earth, David.
Oh really?
Thanks.
You do not change when you become known but it does people around one.
I feel a huge pressure to always be extra nice.
You say yes to stuff that you don't really want to do.
My mom called and asked if I wanted to be plot on Christmas Eve.
I said, "Mom, you have to ask my manager."
“What kind of gage?” I ask.
"0 SEK," she said.
I said, "Mom, I have my own TV program."
"I don't let go of a fish for under ten sheets".
You must not let people drive with you.
To perform free you only do where there are important people in the audience.
Exactly!
I said: "Mom, who do I have in the audience? It's Grandpa" -
- "And Uncle Åke who has not had a job since the shipyard crisis - 79!"
But you are kind, so I said, "Okay, you are my parents."
"Five sheets. For that money I am plot" -
- "And hand out the Christmas presents."
"In addition, you get access to me at Christmas dinner."
People use one all the time.
My acid wanted me to become a godfather to her son.
I didn't want to be nonchalant-
- So I sent my assistant to baptism.
You are too kind.
The acid didn't even send me a thank you card.
Hello, everyone!
Have you thought about this with Göran Persson?
Is Ingvar Carlsson not like a shoe with glasses?
When I appear I usually say:
"Let the politicians put on you, but never let them sit on you."
And when you have been out and supit and are back then after ...
Then you are always so thirsty.
Why?
You have been drinking all evening!
Now I'm going to make an extra number.
I'll mimic an animal.
Which animal in the jungle am I now?
-Hello.
Two to the "sixth mind".
- It's an exciting movie.
Bruce Willis plays child psychologist.
He should help a little boy who can see ghosts and kill people.
But it turns out that Bruce Willis is one of the dead people.
Be so good - two tickets.
Hello.
A ticket to the "sixth mind".
Bruce Willis is one of the dead people.
- Next!
Even the one who has their garden on the balcony -
- Can enjoy the summer's lovely, home -grown vegetables:
Tomatoes, radishes to crunch and salad leaves to pinch.
I myself am fond of tomatoes.
They are easily grown.
You can have them on both terrace and balcony.
As the fruits grow, they are tied up.
When buying tomatoes to be planted -
- So you should take a variety that is for outdoor drive.
There are many different varieties -
- Everything from small cocktail tomatoes to large stifling tomatoes.
The unusual varieties are not cheap.
Buying tomatoes is like buying whores - tastes it, so it costs!
It was great.
It was just the last thing that sounded a bit strange.
Did I stumble on the words, or ...?
No.
But what you said about tomatoes and prostitutes ...
I wanted it to be a humorous grumble on it all.
The problem is that whores are such a strong word.
Maybe I should say Luder instead?
Tjack - Luder?
Spray -Luder?
- It's best to ignore it.
- Can we fix it in the editing?
Welcome, actor Josef Berens.
Welcome!
This is what you look like in your parade role - Bobo Chicken.
I have designed Bobo for eight seasons.
I'm starting to feel close to him now.
You are mascot at the fast -food restaurant Mr Chicken.
- And that's when you dance?
-Yes.
The dance is an important tool.
I carry a toolbox with different things in, e.g.
dance.
Pantomim is another.
"Chicken goes into wall".
The floor mop is also an important tool for you.
As a player, you can't shut out any of what is happening in the room.
Presence must always be total.
If anyone spills anything, do you have to dry it up?
You can see me at Hotel Malmen in Stockholm -
- When I have a beer at the bar.
Fired?
No, I resigned.
The advertising industry was too superficial.
"Father to hell," I didn't say, but ...
I want to work with real people.
I am a warehouse worker.
- Nice workmates?
- Cannon guys!
But they super much.
The staff party last week was ... oh, oh, oh!
It was completely senseless!
We are group -conscious guys.
No prestige!
But that's the case with authorities.
Someone has not settled with the dad, so the manager may take that geese ...
Fuck you, Olsson!
I'm gonna kill you!
- Get your hands off me!
They bend properly. It is even someone who derails when partying.
It's sad.
Calm down now, for the hell!
Olsson!
I'm Gonna Kill You, Olsson!
Fuck you, Olsson!
Well, it's my working pole.
I think we have the right fun anyway at the parties.
Their stuff is not my problem.
I have to move on.
I'm going on a job interview.
See ya!
For the last time we welcome our optimist consultant Henrik Elmér!
Here I am!
The minute of revenge has arrived!
This is my f.d.
Girlfriend Gunilla and her new guy Jörgen.
Look, what a strange nose Jörgen has!
It is the same as Gunillas.
Nöff!
We have practiced this song all night!
It was the way she took butter on the bread that made me understand
that it was meant by fate that it would be we two
She not only spread to her butter as others do - o no
She took my hand in her and then she brows her butter on me
It couldn't be misunderstood - sandwich!
I lit up and wanted to dance maybe it was stupid
However, I chose to chance for I imagined 'nothing scary
Then lighten 'something more - a knife!
She cuts' up me raw - o no
And soon there was as a result of her crime - two me!
I might have misunderstood for good!
Soon I was lying there in her forehead, cut and in butter
I thought the feelings were true, but now I feel tender
And the last jump is extinguished iity she invited a new one - o no!
She is in love with another man and on their menu stands me!
I saw how she took butter on the bread without understanding
How it would go!
Do you think Henrik is the best optimist consultant we could get?
No.
It may not have been so successful.
You might say that it has been unsuccessful.
That's how I feel.
What have we learned from this?
I have learned that the next time you say you have met a nice guy -
–Am I see it as a warning bell
Next time, before we give a severely disturbed people a forum in national television -
- So we look with each other.
Good!
Do you remember when his offered kissogram.
Do you remember what I said?
"Kiss me in the ass!"
Fuck!
Do you remember when Börje invited us to a porn show in Vaasa?
And Raimo, Tokfinnen, said: Satan, what here smells of fish!
What a crazy guy, huh!
Old men, we've done a damn good job.
That's why I have a surprise!
I've taken a comedian from TV - stand -up -guy David!
Hello!
This with a sauna ... Why is it so damn hot in the sauna?
What if it was cold in the sauna?
"It's ice on the floor! We freeze to death! Oh, how cold it is!"
The most common question we get is: When does tap water become unfit to drink?
We take SVT's public service assignment seriously.
That is why we intend to try water.
This water is from the kitchen here.
It is a clear and healthy water.
I'll try it.
Ordinary Swedish tap water.
We have access to good water in our homes.
This water has been standing for a week.
It's not as clear.
The taste is fat, but you can still drink.
So - we have good water in Sweden.
Thanks!
We move on in the program.
This glass of water I found in my apartment six months ago -
- When I moved in.
- It's at least six months old?
-Yes.
It's yellow and smells awful.
We'll try this water.
Oh, fuck!
It's a very disgusting water!
-Can I taste?
- It is very disgusting!
This is bad!
Very bad water!
Avoid drinking water that is six months old.
Hope you are happy with the answer.
It is your license money that finances ...
FART!
... our program operations.
Excuse...
SVT should be people -forming.
Certainly it should be invested in entertainment -
- But there should be entertainment where the brain is included, and not just trams.
It is even more important in today's TV selection.
We must give room for reflection and depth.
We must have a high lowest level.
There is talk of a crisis in Swedish television drama, and I agree.
As a young playwright, you have a responsibility to pass on the relay -stick -
- As you got from Bergman, Molin and others.
It's probably about letting through some incomplete script ...
And young people who are not mature to do TV can still do it.
It may not be so successful.
Maybe we should ...
- You don't feel good, Johan?
-No.
Here I have a water ...
... which comes from my grandfather's floor - well.
It is at least two years old.
This is a very bad water!
Okay - then we drive!
Why are we doing this?
Oh, God!
It is expensive to do TV.
This water test, which has been going on for two minutes -
- Costs almost SEK 40,000.
Many people say that for that money we can get a number of hip joint operations.
But quality must cost money.
- How are you, Johan?
-Very bad.
It must be the water.
Before we finish shrimp, so ...
Here I have a kebab.
I found it in a rock pocket.
It has been there since New Year's Eve –94.
We will try if it can eat.
Thank you and goodbye!
A peculiar species in Swedish folk art is the wall and roof painting.
Pouring painting, as it is incorrectly called -
- Had their flowering period in the late 18th century and the early 1800s.
The motifs were adorned with imaginatively designed flower decorations.
These flowers are typical elements of the valley paintings.
You can still see them here and there.
These beautifully stylized flowers -
- Red and sweet as teenage pussy ...
- Break!
-What is the matter now?