-Hello!
-Thanks so much!
Welcome to shrimp frozen!
- You seem to be in a good mood.
- Yes, I've met a girl.
I'm really in love!
She is fun, intelligent and looks good.
- I have a photo of her here.
-Very cute!
A real tingle!
- Swalling hair.
- Yes, and nice eyes.
-Full lips.
- As a photo model.
You are happy.
So am I.
I have been with Magdalena for a year.
I really love her.
- I've never met her.
-No...
I have a photo of her too.
- Sure she is cute?
- mm.
Yes.
-Do you think so?
-Do not you think so?
No ... No, I can't say that.
- She is an ordinary sweet girl.
- No, now you are deceiving yourself.
- She is below average.
- What a great you are!
I just say what I think.
- She is kind, intelligent ... --... but not attractive.
This is an automatic photo, but I have one from Greece this summer.
- At the beach in bikini ... –Ah, five!
Oh, she really stinks!
Take it.
- It's my girlfriend!
- I feel bad now.
- Connect, that's my girl!
- Mot her down in the swamp again.
Check out, here she is five years!
Very cute little girl with braids.
FUL -Alarm!
I see an ugly man, ugly man ...
Can you stop!
That's my girl!
HA!
Can you leave?
Either she does an operation or you kick her out on the street.
-What are you doing?
- Have you not seen Ricki Lake?
I'll talk to her.
Can I borrow your phone?
Thanks!
We will become more culturally oriented.
We will help you navigate in cultural Sweden and give you good book tips.
I don't like to read for my dog was overrun by the book bus.
But I like "from monkey to human".
It is available at the library.
What a lucky thing you live now!
The first people had to learn everything from the beginning.
What can be eaten and which animals are dangerous.
Imagine the first pregnancy - your stomach begins to grow.
"What the hell have I eaten?"
And suddenly a new person comes out!
You have to be smart: "Sure, I cuddled nine months ago!"
They must have thought about all other reasons: "Have I bathed for too long?"
They had no language.
How do you think if you don't have a language?
We can't think of how it is but a language, because we think about the language.
Imagine if you see a stone and you can't think "stone".
You can't think "gray" or "hard", but just "uh".
Darwin believed that people started as monkeys and then advanced.
Neanderthal became Cromagnon etc.
But the types overlapped each other.
There was a time when Neanderthal and Cromagnon lived at the same time.
Imagine a group of Neanderthal!
One beautiful day comes a new kind of man: "Hello. Erik - Cromagnon."
We have moved into the cave here.
We enjoy it!
We will paint and refresh a little.
Yes.
We have summer cave down in Österlen ... where we enjoy it very well.
I invented the wheel yesterday.
Very happy!
Okay ... I'm not going to get long.
Do you have a fire?
I was just joking!
My book tip: "From monkey to human".
The late summer's most beautiful flower splendor is probably Dahlian.
The dahlias are diverse -
- And lights up the garden until the cold arrives.
The dahlias cannot tolerate very well.
The tubers must be taken out of the soil and enter the heat during the winter.
Many who have dahlias leave the tubers left for too long on the autumn edge -
- And then the cold comes and fucks them in the ass.
When the temperature drops, it's time to pick up the tubers from the soil.
Feel free to let some soil come along and polish it when it has dried.
Bring about 10 cm of the stem as well.
Then you bed down the tubers in sand or peat -
- And they should be cool and dark until you plant them again.
More difficult than that is not!
- We buy it, huh?
- I don't like that expression.
-Oh really?
"Harder than that is not"?
- No, the other - with the ass.
Well?
Does it feel wrong, do you think?
It doesn't fit.
Can you reformulate yourself?
- I could say "going bad".
- Yes, it's much better!
Okay.
Let's go with that!
There are many psychopaths.
One of them is the small lander Göran body.
He has tried to ski over the North Pole eg.
This book is about when cycling from Småland to Nepal -
- Claimed up for Mount Everest and cycled home again.
That guy has too much free time!
How did Göran reason when he walked around the Småland mill?
"I don't think stay in Småland! A stone fuck got stuck in the plow."
He goes to the bike and his old neighbor - Kristina, 85 years - passes by:
"Are you going out and cycling, Göran?"
- "Yes, I was going to cycle to Nepal."
"Are you going to the store, did you say?"
- "No, I'm going to Nepal."
"Do you think cycling all the way to Nepal?"
"Shut up, sheepary! I'm going to Nepal."
He starts cycling out on the main road towards Växjö.
After 400 meters, the chain jumps off.
"No! I'm going to Nepal!"
The first night at Stadshotellet in Vetlanda.
He hears the aircraft.
"I'm going to Nepal. Satan!"
Göran Body is a hired lecturer.
He goes around and talks efficiency for SEK 50,000 in half an hour.
Volvo's management team thinks: "We will have a conference on efficiency."
"Göran body is very effective."
He can cycle to Bromma then!
The reason he is allowed to go around is that he was first.
He thought, "I'll climb Mount Everest!"
Everyone said, "People have done before."
Göran said, "I do it without oxygen."
"Many have done so too."
- "Yes, but I'll cycle there."
There is no stopping it.
His wife and dog will do it too!
He could take the bike to the Kaknästornet -
- Take on an oxygen mask and take the elevator up.
Nobody has done before!
My book tip: Don't read this book!
What fun we could go out in the end!
They have the best carpaccio in town here.
We want carpaccio for starters.
The lady wants chicken tutte and I take Duck myself.
Have you taken part in the wine list?
We take a Chateau Margot –87.
- It makes pirouettes on the gum seal.
Unfortunately, it is over.
But I can...
You have ruined everything!
Everyone knows the owl is wise, the donkey is stupid, the fox is cunning -
- And the ox has poor local mind.
Since childhood, we have been indoctrinated with these prejudices.
Shrimp frozen has tested if they are true.
I wanted to test if the owl is wise so I handed out an IQ test -
- A high school class in Nacka and a group of owls.
What was the result?
First, the high school in Nacka has an IQ below average.
–And the owls?
- They don't seem to understand the questions.
They just flew around with the holes.
They may have emotional intelligence - EQ.
It has become important.
No, they flapped around and soiled with feathers and feces.
Not like the wisest animals of the forest.
I tested the prejudice "proud as a rooster".
I went to a chicken farm and tried to hurt the rooster's pride.
I said I earned better than him and that his hen was a bitch.
Then I started a dirt -throwing campaign.
I walked around among the chickens and spread rumors.
I put up flyers in the chicken farm - this one, e.g.
"The tip's trust at the bottom."
I continued with this one.
I finished with this one.
But I did not disrupt the pride of the rooster.
Then the prejudice is true in this case?
Well ... I went to a cowhage and drove the same gloven word against the steak.
They were also untouched.
So the rooster is no proud than any other animal.
Who has said that the animals are human?
The fables - these devil's glare!
I agree with.
Most of the fables is pure lie.
A fable is about a running competition where the turtle wins over the hare.
It's unrealistic!
A hare is faster than a turtle.
And when has a hare arranged a running competition?
He can't talk.
You should fix sponsors, among other things.
The fables are just written to make money.
Commercial shit!
The fables are harmful to children.
We have an affected person on a link from Gothenburg - Ulf!
- You are located at Sahlgrenska Hospital?
- Yes, I've been here for two weeks now.
How did it go this crazy?
I went with the kids to Borås Zoo.
Nice to come home.
Otherwise you have to go home with the aunt and she is not related to Einstein ...
What happened this day?
We went to the lion.
I thought it might be fun for the kids.
The lion male had a tag in the paw.
I thought that if I remove it I will be the friend of the lion.
- So I pulled out the tag.
- Did the lion grateful?
He gave me such a fucking bang.
I flew into the fence.
The lion was on me and the kids cried.
He hurt me significantly - a pair of ribs smoke.
That's the thank you!
- How could it go so badly?
- You can't trust the fables.
You get pissed off!
I thought I would be friends with the lion.
I don't mind lions.
They come here from the jungle in Africa.
They must adhere to our customs!
Simba is allowed to lie down and eat beef fillet.
There must be limits!
We are at an inevitable point.
We have tried to cancel the contract but are forced to have our lifestyle consultant.
We would like to point out that the views that Henrik is in front are entirely his own.
They do not represent Sweden's television's view.
Once again: Henrik Elmér!
Welcome to "Meet Life with Henrik"!
The course that can change your life.
You have to be the blacksmith of your own.
My girlfriend Gunilla ended up with me.
But I don't dig myself in bitterness - it's no one helped.
Instead, I stand on TV and tell the whole country about the pig Gunilla.
What a stupid her new guy is!
Better than being bitter at home.
Learn this!
If you are open, you can always find something positive in a situation.
This summer I fought with a friend and his family.
I have a hard time for that family.
To top it all, I was involved in their snuff life.
I woke up at night because their dwarf rabbit put on my nose.
You would have seen their little son in the morning: "Where is my rabbit?"
In the end, I had to say as it was: "He is with me now."
Then I was with the rabbit.
But I got tired because he wanted sex evenly.
I tried to meander, "No, I have a sore nose."
The point is that I affirmed what happened.
You can read about that in the booklet.
Unfortunately, the booklets are not finished yet on the damn cock -printing!
There is a plot on my course.
Gunilla's lawyer told me-
- That if I didn't stop talking about Gunilla on TV, they would sue SVT.
I have come across Gunilla.
But she is such a good example of how to move on.
Do you know what to do?
I know!
Don't miss next time, because then Gunilla comes here!
- Do you hear it, Gunilla!
You should sit here at my feet and beg for grace!
- Do not miss it!
Tickets!
Tickets for sale!
Come and Buy Your Tickets Here!
- DO YOU WANT TO SEE THE VASA -Ship?
–Yes.
It's a Beautiful Ship.
You Buy Your Tickets Here.
They Cost 150 Crowns.
That's a bit expensive, isn't it?
Everything is.
You can't live in this bloody country.
But It's Worth It - It's A Beautiful Ship.
300 Crowns for the Two of You.
They have the Tickets inside and they only cost 50 Crowns.
Ah, what the hell!
In Took a Robber.
It was a chancing.
IF IT GOES, IT GOES.
We're all people!
You know me.
Have fun!
Enjoy the Ship.
- Tickets!
- We will meet an interesting artist.
- We welcome Bengt Johansson!
Welcome!
You experiment with new techniques?
Yes, since I went out Konstfack I have experimented with different techniques.
From the beginning it was the most mosaic and textiles and such things -
- But now I am most interested in sculpture.
Especially in living materials.
So now I mostly deal with meat crafts.
We visited Bengt's studio this week and we will have a look at it.
- You work with many different materials.
- It depends on what you want to express.
Sometimes it takes heavier materials such as ox or pork -
- And sometimes I play completely freely with calf jam or minced youngsters.
You want to exhibit your art like at Millesgården?
It would be wonderful!
- In a park?
- Well.
Can't there arise if you exhibit meat art in public?
Well, dogs can be a little well interested in one's art.
It can also be smell and flies - though it usually goes pretty well.
Last year I made a large statue for the municipality in mixed mince.
- It stands in front of the town hall now.
- Yes, we have pictures of it.
-Hey!
- Well, Hello!
-Hello!
- The situation?
Yes, a little elaborate and stressed ... but that's good with me.
How about you?
It is good!
I was at Lasses and Alexandra's wedding.
-How was it?
- It was successful.
A little stiff in the beginning, just ...
Oh, the but in black!
Are you going to have?
Well - then I drink!
Otherwise as nice!
And after the ceremony, everyone set up for wedding photos.
Moonbase Alfa!
HEY!
I'm at a wedding.
The mitt got it.
Come here, for the hell!
Then it was offered champagne.
Many happy bowls were brought out for the bridal couple.
I was a little tired then ... I have pretty much to do, as I said -
- So I broke up a little earlier.
Next Saturday, Anders and Sofia are getting married.
It's nice to even develop!
Do you feel more culturally enriched?
Yes, I'm going to write on my book now.
-What is it called?
-The emigrants.
It is based on a book by Vilhelm Moberg.
I have borrowed the action, the characters and all the words of him.
But I write mine with lysyl.
I am also very creative.
I wrote two poems before the program.
- Do you have them with you?
-Yes!
-Impressive!
-Thanks for tonight!
I ... thought about reading a little out of my book.
I have written it myself.
I wrote it when I sat on the kitchen.
I sat on Kumla for four years.
"I'm not your bitch, Willy," it's called.
Chapter four.
Kumla, February 29, 1971.
I was tired that morning.
It was cold as Satan.
I would sneak up ... I wasn't drunk - I was sober!
I went up to the shower room and it was cold.
I stood there and ...
I saw that the soap slipped down on the floor.
I thought I could pick up the soap.
Then I see a big shadow behind me.
It was Willy, that bastard.
He said "Now you are mine, Gert! Now you should taste the salty!"
I screamed, "I'm not your bitch!"
SVT Program Setting: Britta Landén Bergman