-Thanks!
-Thanks.
Welcome to shrimp frozen.
We have two exciting competitions -
- And so comes our lifestyle consultant Henrik Elmér!
Last time, a long -awaited guest comes here - Robert Gustafsson!
- You look a little worn out, Johan.
- Yes, I sleep poorly at night.
It's a bad now.
My girlfriend left me - four years ago.
I sat at the computer all night and had cyber sex with a dyslexic.
It was frustrating.
"What the hell writes man?"
Finally, I fake my orgasm.
I wrote: "Oh, the ground shits ..."
My dad got a computer a while ago and it's hopeless!
He browses all day - and double - click on the lamp buttons at home!
He empties his mailbox all the time and puts bookmarks in the Mushroom Forest.
Dad asks: "Are you sure you will throw the garbage? Yes, no, cancel?"
There are disadvantages, but I need to meet people.
- You were out this weekend?
- Yes, but Jimmy was with ...
Hello guys.
What evening we had yesterday!
Huh?
No, I agree ... What are we doing?
Every night the same thing.
Any evening ...
So full - why do we get it?
When did we go out and have a beer last?
It has never happened!
I take two and ...
Sorry!
The gay, come back!
Kick me in the ass.
Oh, those girls!
They were as boring, like three of my hurts, and just stood on the floor.
Although the blonde seemed to like me.
What 'fuck are you doing?
It was just love.
Are you dad's little dry ball?
After one such trip you think:
Someone should get up and say: Now we go home!
- But did we go home?
!
We go to Slopys!
Yes!
Slopys!
Were we forced to choose the worst place in the whole city?
You were almost killed by the guard.
I'll solve it for you.
The girl, the girl, the girl, the girl and five of us.
The gays remain.
- What 'ere?
I'm trying to solve this.
What the hell!
Damn, what a fun evening!
We have to do that again.
It annoys me that people say: You look much shorter in reality.
People look further on television.
-How tall are you?
–1.64.
I'm 1.58.
In television you have nothing to compare with -
- But if the person stands next to something you recognize, it will be fair.
If you stand at a matchbox ...
It becomes more fair.
I saw Jan Guillou down in Malmö.
He is much shorter than you think, and wider.
He had red hair and spoke Danish.
And TV puts on a few pounds.
Peter Harryson is probably not so thick ...
No, it would be sick.
We have received a postcard on trucks set outside a barbecue kiosk -
- From an au pair in Germany.
Klingelingeling, hier came there eier - man ...
-Who was it?
–The eier - man.
He comes here every time you say that word.
I can't say the word now because then he dances in again.
Is the word truck?
Barbecue kiosk?
Lotta?
- It is the country ... - Germany?
Klingelingeling, hier came there eier - mann
He is funny!
Why is he coming?
There was something about it in the rental contract.
Take the postcard now!
It is from Lotta, who is au pair in Bern, who is in ...
Bern is not located in Germany!
Klingelingeling ...
Lotta writes: "There is so much crazy stuff in shrimp frozen."
"Where do you get everything from?"
We buy most fun.
Yes, e.g.
Many Polish jokes.
Cigarettes, vodka!
Buy!
Good prices!
- Hi, do you have any jokes?
- Yes, many fun!
The joke!
Many fun jokes.
Everyone laughs!
Party with the ferret Göran ... it feels stolen.
No, it's not stolen!
- Do you have a thunderstorm?
- No, but zipper!
Okay, we say: The joke - and two loafs the cigarettes on the purchase.
- But we don't smoke.
- All smoke!
We say: The joke, a loaf of cigarettes - and salami!
Good!
- Two tomatoes that go over a road ... - But the sausage is delicious.
No stupid sausage.
- 500 bucks for salami, cigarettes and jokes!
The cigarettes, vodka, buy good gift!
Do you have any jokes?
Now we intend to announce a competition -
- And want you to send in your jokes so we perform the most fun contribution.
The ten most fun jokes are rewarded with a bumper sticking.
The most fun joke wins a piece of the Berlin Wall.
But how can viewers be sure it is a piece of genuine Berlin wall?
It comes with Bengt Fahlström's authenticity guarantee.
Bengt Fahlström from Barnjournalen -
- Points on the stone and says: It's genuine!
Send your jokes to us and we will assess the comic quality.
I have a solid background as stand -up comedian -
- And has become a perfectionist when it comes to humor.
I can create magic on a stage.
Thank you.
- Then it's time for the next program point.
We're going to change pace.
It's time for the stand -up comedian David.
Fun to see so many people here!
Why do you have socks, really?
Is it like caps for the feet, right?
The timing is the most important thing.
Without it, the whole comic can be ruined.
The difference between hit and miss is delicate.
On an airplane everything is so small!
On the tray you should put these little bottles.
I'm just saying: Stick!
The comedian must see things in everyday life that people have not succeeded in formulating.
Why do all Chinese have oblique eyes?
Are they so yellow that they get dazzled?
- "I have to pee!"
It is not the comedian who will shout when the emperor is naked.
We must criticize the men of power!
But the most important thing is to entertain, to be fun.
There is no better reward than seeing joy in the eyes of the audience.
I may have brightened up their meaningless life.
Last week we asked you to submit your own home video movies.
We have received many dull films and selected four finalists.
Oh, a mouse!
Where are you going?
Well, a bat!
Now I got hold of you!
No, he smeared!
What a disaster!
Now I have you!
A little wire flavor ...
Where are you going?
Stay!
-Do you want to play?
- No, go from here!
You seem to be a strange lazy undulating!
I go up for a while and check.
No, here was nothing.
-I can not take it.
- No, stick then.
- Sen to work as usual ... Oh!
- Should you drive or stand still?
- I drive by.
I'm in a hurry.
- Night's car - turn!
I don't know if I'm going to front or back.
Oh, a bus!
- Here you can't sit.
Circulate.
- We are just waiting for the bus.
You ruin my nice hairstyle!
Oh, leave!
Stop!
We will select a winner of these four.
The winner we send away to an industrial area outside Bucharest-
- To participate in one of Europe's largest asbestos remediation projects.
The winner is accommodated at Vladislav and Alina.
The winner is allowed to work in rubber factory -
- And maybe taste Vladislav's famous salt sausage.
It's exciting.
Who can win?
Who is the winner of the weekend trip?
Winners are "strange undulates" of Ulf Buller!
Thank you!
Wonderfully!
-Congratulations!
How does it feel?
- I could hardly believe it!
I didn't understand what I had, but "the government" said:
"Submit this to TV."
It was just to obey.
And between us:
I sent the video to the Zick Zack program already a couple of years ago!
But the one waiting for something good ...
If you need a new washing machine or other appliances then come to me!
Uffes cash in Höör!
Absolutely crazy prices!
Thank you.
I'm happy, because this is showing -
- That with hard work, anyone who is prepared to fight can be something!
You should not think that you can come here and only receive contributions after grants!
Look at America!
The Indians did not stop immigration in time.
Now they live in celibacy!
You get bus tickets to Romania.
Nice trip!
Jörgen is a genius in web construction.
- We have known each other for a long time.
- Sustain to get hold of good people?
You have to have the right "Employ image".
Ulla holds us right.
Here is Göran.
- We might be able to talk about finances.
- You got to see you about?
- Yes, then.
Then maybe we can talk some prices.
Have a seat.
We cannot go below SEK 400 per unit excluding VAT and shipping -
–And a fee of SEK 1,200 per hour.
That price does not pass our budget.
-Hello.
- "The Crying Game."
Have you seen it?
- Customer number?
–4511, I think.
Then it will be SEK 45.
A five -crown back and then the movie.
I think you will be surprised that the good looking black girl is a guy.
Welcome back!
Soon Robert Gustafsson will come, but before that ...
- Don't the egg man come back?
-No.
Just if you say the word ...
We welcome our lifestyle consultant Henrik Elmér!
Thanks and welcome to the course "Meet Life with Henrik".
Today we will talk about an increasingly common problem: loneliness.
But many want to pull away from the human community.
They do not want to receive hands that are stretched.
Do you have good cohesion on your page in the telephone directory?
I'm standing on the most boring page!
I sometimes call everyone on the page and want to have a party or go to theater -
- But everyone ignores it.
I call when they turn years and on the telephone directory day that I introduced.
Last time when I turned years, I was awakened by some on my side.
They brought me a gift - a telephone directory with their own page.
Then I got angry, called everyone again and said we had to talk.
I cannot take responsibility alone for our cohesion.
No one of course had time to meet.
Someone would go abroad and someone would go out with people on another side.
A guy had a secret number.
And we who were almost besties!
It annoys me that people change to secret numbers all the time.
My f.d.
Girlfriend Gunilla has switched to secret number.
Why?
I don't like that!
What do you think?
I can explain why, but then I need some person.
I take the very beautiful woman here.
If you would like to change from ... what kind of phone number do you have now?
Or I can troll a little!
Do you want to see?
I have a little trick ...
You will probably be surprised if I already have your number.
I'm alone in this in the world.
Do you recognize this?
Not yours?
No.
Some time I will encounter a girl who has this number!
The course is about positive thinking and next time you will know more!
What are you doing?
What 'fuck are you doing?
- You took my money!
I saw it!
- No, that's my money.
The vending machine is behind.
Next time will your money come.
Can I get my money here!
Go to the bank and ask.
Stop it now!
That's my money!
- Do you want to call the police?
- No, I took a robber.
I was just a chance.
If so, it goes.
You don't take it badly, right?
Yes Yes...
I can't cope with Stefan.
It gets too much.
- He is worse than the kids in kindergarten.
- I don't take it up with him.
He might be disturbed in childhood.
Missing a father figure, maybe.
Broken toys, maybe.
Hi, Stefan.
Kerstin and I have talked about one thing.
We think you do a good job here and everyone likes you and so ...
But you have to wash better in the kitchenette.
People get annoyed.
You know how annoying it is when there is no pure stuff.
Now to what everyone has been waiting for!
He has an incredibly "tight" schedule, but here is Robert Gustafsson!
You work as a tiler and have your own company outside Sundbyberg.
Yes, Robert's building.
You worked on the tile expert in Nacka but then started your own.
You put tiles in wet spaces and it is not spectacular -
- But you have also put tiles in different storage areas.
- But that's not why you're here.
- Joo.
Robert, you are out working a lot and meet new people every day.
There are certainly a lot of pleasures on a regular working day.
No.
- No especially you want to tell us about?
-No.
You have no Eskimå -Diso in your pants?
Huh?
Maybe they just stoves plates this time.
Robert, a little bird whispered in my ear -
- A couple of years ago you tiled a whole kitchen with Danish tiles.
Danish?
I would never do that.
- Maybe something you dream about?
-No.
You are mostly out and parties with your ferret Göran.
Huh?
Robert, once you were in a townhouse in Upplands Väsby and tiled a kitchen.
- Then something happened crazy.
-Yes.
- You stood on a ladder.
- Something happened crazy.
-Yes.
The steps stood against the door, the wife opened the door -
- The steps overturned and you crashed straight straight down the floor.
Tell us about this!
I was in Upplands Väsby and worked.
The wife came home and opened the door that I had set the steps towards.
I fell straight on the kitchen floor.
Robert, I have a bottle of chlorine here.
You can do whatever you want with it.
You may want to taste a little, it will be a fun thing.
Chlorine?
He's talking to hes voice
Thanks, Robert Gustafsson!
We have learned a lot this evening -
-for example.
Drinking alcohol in moderation, and not saying a special word.
Germany.
Klingelingeling, hier came there eier - mann
SVT Program Sewing: Birgitta Sunnerdal
- We have bought a fifth with a balcony.
- I live in a second with a good position.
But I have no balcony ... and the kids?
Josefin goes in second and Isaac in kindergarten ...