Västerhavsveckan is an initiative from the entire west coast
Where the purpose is to emphasize wildlife underwater and explore environmental awareness.
The North Sea Week was started in 2008.
It is a theme week for the marine environment that Västra Götaland's environmental committee initiated.
We want to raise sea awareness with our visitors.
The sea means a lot to us.
Without the sea we have no life on land either.
We in the environmental owners took the opportunity to document and experience the week.
My name is Fredrik Gröndal and I am a teacher and researcher at the Royal Institute of Technology in Stockholm.
I am also a station manager for Kristineberg's marine research station.
The boat we have been out now is one of our research vessels.
We have two.
Then we have a larger ship called Skagerak and which comes here after the summer.
We only go in special places to save the bottom, so we are very careful when we work.
What I am doing very much is jellyfish.
When I started working with marine biology and doctorate, it was ear jellyfish and fire jellyfish.
I was the best in it, then.
After exploring Oskar von Sydow and getting to meet Fredrik Gröndal
We went on to an eelgrass bed in an area called Bökavik.
Me, Christian and Stefan put on swimming feet and snorkels to dive.
To see the beautiful eel grass beds wander around on the bottom of the sea,
All sorts of herring and jellyfish were absolutely amazing
There is so much more below the surface than we think.
We still have the same problems that we had in 2008, for example, how do we get new food from the sea with algae.
We are still talking about plastic and debris in the sea, acidification, eutrophication and overfishing.
Some things have been better over the years.
But, even though we are aware of the problems, a lot is getting worse.
We have to work a lot more for our sea.
More and more people use the sea.
We need the sea for food.
There are more and more recreation boats for recreation.
Fishing.
Everything, everything needs much more space.
We have to get a balance so that we in a sustainable way use the sea and not destroy it more than what we have done.
About the middle of the week, two of the environmental owners Bosse visited a Hönöbo with a heart for seal safaris in Gothenburg's northern archipelago.
Now we will take you out on a guided tour.
It is Harald, my granddaughter, and it is the third season he runs so he is experienced on this.
I am completely calm and can consider myself telling where we are somewhere.
In 2008 we were about 30 players.
This year we are over 100 players.
We have expanded with Halland, Skåne and Denmark.
We are more and more who want to join and that is proof that the issues are becoming more and more important.
The important thing is to understand what is down there in the sea because we do not see it and we have far too little knowledge about it.
Seeing children playing with junk may seem something unusual.
Fantastic children, young people, adults and together we create instruments.
We have no special rules for it.
So there are only ideas and it is so exciting.
Imagine that a plastic can can be turned into a ukulele and a yogurt can becomes a drum.
Together with the artist group Sepandarmaz, children create musical instruments with junk from the sea.
We can become a dialogue between children across cultural boundaries.
I am passionate about the sea and feel that we have a long way to hike and we have to change our own behavior.
I see our over -consumption that leaves traces both here but also in Africa and other poorer countries
Which happens very badly because we consume too much in the Western world.
It's something that drives me pretty much.
Then of course I want a beautiful sea that I can enjoy, swim in,
Snorkel and discover that there is this huge life under the sea.
Then I get to learn something new every year and that is what is so fun about working in such a project.
Because I also learn all the time and the curiosity you have and develops never end.
I think that is wonderful.
The island of Måseskär is located at the far end of the sea band outside Orust.
The trip goes via Kärringön where we change a boat.
I have a chat with Tomas Liebig, a dedicated biologist who is happy to share his knowledge.
Actually, we should call the island of TrueSkär because here is more trout than seagulls.
The trotting we have in the largest number is herring.
This year, 200 pairs of herring are hedged here.
It has been good for them.
There are a lot of kids that may be heard in the background, the small ones feed by their parents.
There is a lot going on on Måseskär under the flag of the North Sea week.
And here you use rainwater.
Guidance on life as a lighthouse keeper, a lecture on the mythical storm vault,
But we listen to Tomas.
What is very special about Måseskär is that outside the island there are two sea currents that shock on each other.
It gets a stir in the water.
It is released a lot of nutrition.
We get plenty of plant and zooplankton.
Plenty of small fish thus tobis, small herring and then larger fish.
During the 30 years that Tomas regularly certainly on the island, he has seen how bird life has become different.
There is a lot that has changed.
It is sparse and sparse between proper ice winter.
A huge change is that we get more bird species that winter in the area.
Birds that moved south before the millennium shift, we find here all year.
It is dax to get to the mainland again, but we will be back
Maybe this spring when the herring box and the other migratory birds return to Måseskär.
We are Fridays for Future.
We are co -organizer for the North Sea week.
Now we have a demonstration for the sea where we will cycle around Gothenburg.
Do you know why we should cycle at the demonstration
Because we want to say that we should take care of the sea.
What does it say on your flags
We hope to awaken a consciousness in the public.
We hope that the media will understand how important it is with the sea.
We hope that politicians will understand.
We simply want attention.
And we should have fun and support each other so there is not so much anxiety and lonely.
The sea is required to save the climate and the climate must be saved to save the sea.
So it's all about stopping eutrophication, sustainable food from the sea, quitting with large -scale fishing.
In the North Sea also lives a small algae called meat leaf.
It is red and it tastes fried egg.
The meat leaf hall requires us to protect the sea.
Our second requirement is about sustainable food from the sea.
First, fish sustainable.
We need to get rid of bottom line and other destructive methods that are actually subsidized today.
Instead, we want the state, the municipality and the region to support small -scale fishing.
And also test on new food varieties.
Humanity stands and falls with the sea.
It's so simple.
Fish sustainable should be obvious
Although I myself live on an island, I must say to experience the west coast like this and see all the amazing nature
Is still as extraordinary as the first time I saw a sunset here.
After coming home from the North Sea week, we must summarize it with a single big plus.
Being able to join and create a future for the sea and interest in its nature is absolutely wonderful.