In February 2019, the Alpina World Cup is decided in Åre.
A village that for the third time is hosting when the world
Best skiers should make up in honor and medals.
Follow behind the scenes when Sweden's alpine national team
Prepares for a World Cup at home.
Follow along on the way home.
I have made a very good autumn, trained hard and
I take steps all the time and I think that -
It comes more and more, and then it is very upside down -
But that the speed is there and ...
I just need to rub on and there will be more and more
All the time so I think, yes.
You often talk about routine.
Can you feel now, from last year, that when you come
back to some places, that you have been there once and -
You recognize the hill and how much does it affect?
Super very much.
I wish I was one of those just as:
"Lala, now we drive, new hill, doesn't matter."
But a lot of difference.
Just to get to Garmisch now and have run the downhill
Great, I already know before the first inspection was -
I will, what is needed and what it takes as well as and -
I know so much before step one.
Instead of starting on step zero and then trotting up.
So, huge difference.
When I get to new slopes, you immediately see that
I am behind and then you do not match the best -
In the world there is a big difference.
It feels extremely nice to come to a place you have been.
A lot of experience is required.
Partly because you have to learn the slopes in a different way.
There are such high speeds and there is a lot that happens
And a lot of risks.
I think the mental part of a speed competition partly to learn -
everything but also to dare to throw out, it takes a while -
Before you get over the bit that you have to look down.
Without then, you can focus on skiing and searching for speed.
I have come many times the first time to the hill and
Don't know where I'm going anywhere.
Even though you have two throughout and two races, it is
Still difficult the last day you get down.
It takes a while because one has
Four rides in the same hill in one year, then you should -
come back next year again.
So it takes a while before you learn.
Welcome.
No, no cleaning.
We rush to Lisa.
Welcome to us by the way.
I have cleaned.
Who lives here then
When Lisa has her own room, then it's okay.
If you share room with her, then you have
One fifth of the room she has the rest about this.
The sickest is when she packs, no one is so quick to pack.
She just pushes everything down, nothing is weight, everything is just:
Then she jumps on the bag, pulls it again, so she is before everyone.
Should we greet Lin
Here we have someone who is related to Matts Olsson I think.
Hello.
Hey.
Do we disturb?
- No.
Here you can see, check out there.
Yes, even the inner shoes.
It should be neat and nice.
It's not even very nice.
I get some anxiety from that actually.
It's you and Matts Olsson.
Yes, so Matts, I understand you.
Do you also fold the dirt wash
Exercise shoes wrapped.
Dirt wash - weight.
Yes, I actually do.
Otherwise it won't go down, I don't understand how Lisa
Corner leaves can do it.
We also have Ida here.
Ida
Haven't moved out of the spot since she came home.
I'm a little tired so I lay down.
Should we tell you a little about Lisa's porridge maybe
Yes we can do that.
Now we all do together so she doesn't have much to
Choose.
If she does herself, then she does ..
If you were to say the recipe for porridge, it's 5050 -
Water, oatmeal?
And Lisa thus has 9010.
Oatmeal is 90 then.
And then it's a little splash of water.
And then it gets to go together.
Porridge at La Lisa.
How does it work
It is easy.
There is a lot of oatmeal, a lot of salt and some water.
Sticky
It should be sticky, yes.
Good as well.
It is very ...
Hard, sticky, heavy.
Extremely disgusting.
Salt.
It should taste salt as well.
Then you just pour.
It is terrible.
It's like.
She boils it twice as long as an ordinary person.
After all, it becomes like wallpaper paste.
Hard.
Hard and tough and ...
I don't understand how she can swallow it.
It's impressive indeed.
Now it's finished.
Now it's just going to ...
Together, like.
You have nothing on
Yes, the track.
The track is on.
If you put on a little track here then it is ready to run.
A little more salt, I could have.
Sure my hope was better now
Yes it was.
Now you were central to the stuff, then the skis follow the ground.
Now you have been selected for the World Cup.
How did you think then
It feels too good to be true.
It's great fun and I
Feel that I am here to create experience.
If I manage to ride the skiing I know I can go
Then I will be really happy but I have not set up -
Some results.
Should I give some tips ...
so is it to take advantage of
Partly that it is home and ...
I will not say enjoy because I hated when people said
Enjoy me, that I would be at the competition and enjoy but -
Feel the strength of being at home.
When I was on the start and everyone roared "Åre" it felt
So damn powerful.
And something that built me even more.
For all who come here then, the audience
What do they have to expect
Spectacular competitions.
Funny nightlife, maybe you shouldn't talk so much about
For the sake of the athletes but for the sake of the audience, I think that -
It will be a real folk party.
Where one should take advantage of the skiing as you
Will get to see but also all around as -
The village and Åre offer.
I think it will be powerful.
It goes up for one to finally happen.
It just feels fucking fun and as i said then so
I bet on top 10, but expectations are just that -
It will be great fun to race and out and gas.
I am very charged.
Pirry, but look forward to going very much.
I'm charged.
It will be great fun.