Then we are back with ten unnecessary
Facts that you may not know about.
I was going to start directly with a small question.
What do you think first came the postit note or calculator?
Do you think a bundle of paper with a faint glue
As you can make small notes on Come first?
Or do you think an electronic calculator who can math
came first?
It was actually the calculator.
Believe it or not.
The first portable calculator was invented in 1967
by Texas Instruments
and could perform basic mathematical calculations as
Addition, subtraction, multiplication and division.
Post-it note came to the market in 1980.
But the glue itself used to hold together
The pieces of paper were actually invented in 1968 by Spencer Silver,
a scientist at 3M, and was invented by a mistake by him
tried to create a super strong glue,
But instead ended with a weak pressure sensitive glue.
Snails
Teeth
Have you ever seen a snail smile at you?
Snails actually have thousands of small teeth lying on a band inside your mouth.
This band is called Radula and the teeth
used to scrape or cut food.
They are microscopically small so not so
Strange that you don't notice when a snail smiles at you.
If now snails can smile at all,
What would a snail with human teeth look like?
Okay, we're moving on.
The smell of the moon.
Astronauts who visited the moon reported afterwards
that the moon's dust has a very distinct smell,
Similar burnt powder or wet ash.
According to Thai law it is
illegal to harm, destroy or show a lack of respect for banknotes or
Coins containing depictions of the king or other members of the royal family.
This includes actions such as pedaling or tearing down banknotes.
It is a crime to insult, threaten or slander the king, queen, successor or regent.
The punishment for these crimes can be very serious, including long prison sentences.
Koalor's sleep
Koalor is among the mammals that sleep the longest.
They can sleep up to 18 to 22 hours a day.
And if you didn't know it, a day has only 24 hours.
Their long sleep is an adaptation to their diet
which consists mostly of eucalyptus leaves.
They contain very little nutrition but have a high fiber
slippery and requires a lot of energy to digest.
Giraffes are among the mammals that sleep least.
In the wild, giraffes sleep only about 30 minutes per day.
This short sleeping time is often distributed in small
Taps that last for a few minutes at a time.
Because giraffes need to be alert to avoid predators' attacks.
Newborn calves sleep more, but are also protected by other giraffes that watch over them.
Giraffes can sleep both standing and lying down, but adult giraffes
often prefer to sleep standing to be able to quickly escape from predators.
In captivity you might be allowed to sleep longer
up to 6 hours per day on average.
Mercury is the only metallic element that is
Liquid at room temperature, making it unique among metals.
This is because of its very low melting point
at -38.83 degrees Celsius.
Most other metals have the melting point that is much higher,
such as steel that melts at 1400 to 1500
degrees Celsius
The chlorine smell in swimming pools.
The distinct chlorine smell that one often feels
In swimming pools is not just from the chlorine itself.
It is actually the result of chlorine reacting with urine,
Sweat and dirt from those who bathe there.
This means that a strong claw smell can mean that a high level
of these pollutants.
Have you ever looked down on
Your keyboard and wondered why the letters are placed as they are?
This layout, called qwerty after the first six letters
in the top row, was created during the 1870s by Christopher Sholes
the inventor of the typewriter.
The reason why the keys seem to be holes about noise and not in alphabetical order
Depends on the typewriter as mechanics.
When you wrote on a typewriter in the past and pushed down a
The key went a metal arm out with a letter that hit the paper.
To reduce the risk of these arms stuck in each other,
especially in case of quick writing, so separated
Shole's commonly occurring letter pairs.
And this led to the layout we use today.
The longest place names in the world
Available in New Zealand and is a Maori term for a hill in the Hawke's Bay region.
The name is often shortened to Taumata for the sake of simplicity,
But this is how the correct pronunciation sounds
for almost an hour.
Thank you for being for food is to look at how
You get lookup and here to find this house.
But there are other places with very long names.
There is a village in Vienna that has one of the longest names in Europe.
It's called to become the ice princess.
Do you have any Swedish speech ref
that is in English and
It does not sell Google.
If we find ... you will not get it for me and no.
Equally tagged I'm, but I'm pretty angry
Is pretty mad.
Often shortened to Lake Webster
It is the name of a lake and is said to mean you fish on your side.
I fish on my side and no fish in the middle.
The world's first SMS that incidentally stands for short
Message Service was sent on December 3.
1992 by Neil Papworth
A test engineer in the UK.
The message was sent from Neil's computer to a manager at Vodafone,
Richard Jarvis, and obeyed Merry Christmas.
This historic SMS marked the beginning of
a new era in digital communication and although less sms is sent today
Due to all apps used, such as WhatsApp, Snapchat and Messenger and so on,
So it will still be sent about 23 \ hillion
SMS every day around the world.
There were ten unnecessary facts.
Part two Don't forget to subscribe to this channel.
Feel free to put a thumbs up on the channel if you liked the video.
And as always thanks for looking!