What is bigfoot?
We will find out today.
For several years, people around the world have been fascinated by the legend of Bigfoot.
Several people have talked about their meetings with the hairy beast.
A large and hairy alar -like creature that goes on two legs.
But even though there is no definitive evidence of Bigfoot's existence, new reports on possible meetings with Bigfoot continue to emerge even today.
Today we will dive into the legend of Bigfoot to go through the most famous ...
And perhaps most convincingly so -called "evidence" and hopefully get an answer to the question that everyone is asking.
Is Bigfoot for real?
In this video we will go through the following things:
What is bigfoot for something?
How did Bigfoot began to spread?
What is the evidence?
And finally.. Is Bigfoot for real or is everything a scam?
What is bigfoot?
Bigfoot is a large alar -like creature that is said to be in the forests in North America.
It goes on two legs, which we humans do and have a dark coat.
The body should be very muscular and broad -axled.
The length of Bigfoot is somewhere between 2-3 meters.
Bigfoot leaves large human -like footprints behind.
Hence the name..bigfoot
Those who are said to have seen Bigfoot say that the face has character traits similar to a person's but that it also resembles a gorillas.
Bigfoot should also have a very unpleasant and peculiar smell.
A stench that feels at a very long distance.
Bigfoot is what is called a cryptozoolological creature.
It is a collective name for a number of different animal species that have not been proven by science.
Examples of these are Storsjöodjuret, Loch Ness beast, Chupacabra, Yeti [Snowman] and others.
The most common theory that flourishes about bigfoot is that it is a kind of undetected species of a primate.
An alar -like creature, but still more intelligent and developed than any other primate that we know.
How did Bigfoot began to spread?
The legend of Bigfoot is not as old as you might think.
It all started on August 20, 1958, when a forest worker named Jerry Crew outside the community of Willow Creek in Northern California, USA was a strange discovery.
When he came to work that day he saw unnaturally large footsteps in the ground.
The footprints were discovered at a river called Bluff Creek.
After that, more people in the workplace began to tell us that they had also seen similar footsteps and that they had been involved in inexplicable events in the workplace.
Among other things, an oil barrel that should have weighed over 200 kg had disappeared for a day without any explanation.
Some of the workers also told me that they felt observed sometimes when they worked late in the evenings ...
The casts were made of the footprints and they turned out that the footprints were about 40 cm long.
Hence the natural name of the creature that made these footsteps ... Bigfoot.
It didn't take long before the history of a large and hairy best that left large footsteps began to spread in the United States, first from mouth to mouth and then from newspaper to newspaper.
In October, 1958, the footprints were on the first page of the local news magazine.
Soon, the rumor of Bigfoot had spread throughout the country.
What is the evidence?
What evidence do we have for Bigfoot's existence?
What we talked about was exactly the footprints at the River Bluff Creek.
However, these are not the only footprints.
There are ... 100's of different pictures of different footsteps that people think they belong to Bigfoot or Snökannen.
Is it proof that Bigfoot exists or is it just footprints from eg.
a bear?
We will come to it a little later.
At the beginning of July 2008, two hunters from Georgia in the United States emerged, Rick Dyer and Matthew Whitton.
They claimed that they had found a dead bigfoot in the forests of northern Georgia.
The news quickly spread to several major American news channels BBC, CNN, ABC News and Fox News, among other things.
In fact, the hunters had even been supported by a researcher that it could very well be Bigfoot.
But was it real?
We go through it in a little while.
First, we have to look at other so -called evidence.
There are actually several occasions where people have managed to get Bigfoot on film.
I thought we were looking at 4 of them.
The first film shows "Bigfoot" which goes among the bushes and then it picks up its child in its arms and goes out of the picture.
Some claim that this is a clear proof that Bigfoot actually exists while others say
That it is simply just a man with a gorilla costume.
The second movie is from 2011 when a family is up among the mountains, unfortunately it is unknown where they were.
They let the son practice sniper and a helicopter floats above them while this happens.
When the young boy on the movie shoots a shot, you can see something moving on the right of the movie.
Let's look.
Did you see?
We look again.
What is running over there among the bushes?
It moves very humanly but unfortunately it is too far away to say exactly what it is.
Was it scared of the shot?
Who knows.
The family was obviously wondering why the helicopter was there, but now they believe it chased Bigfoot.
Third film, filmed by an unknown person on December 29, 2009 in Carbondale Pennsylvania.
The person in the video walks around the woods on the back of their house after hearing noise out there.
At 41 seconds into the video, Bigfoot shows up among the trees.
What differs from the other films is that Bigfoot is white.
A so -called Albino Bigfoot.
The fourth movie, the movie that is perhaps best known.
It was filmed by Roger Patterson in 1967 when he was to film a documentary about Bigfoot on the River Bluff Creek.
Let's look.
In the film, we clearly see an alar -like creature that goes on two legs as a human being.
The creature also turns to the camera at one time.
The film is still used today as evidence of Bigfoot's existence of the Bigfoot fantasies while others again just think it is a man in a gorilla costume.
What all movies have in common is that they are filmed at a distance and that Bigfoot is blurred and difficult to see.
So either ... it is simply a coincidence that it just happened to be so when you were filming ..
Or ... so maybe bigfoot is blurred.
Joking aside.
These 4 films are only a fraction of a certainly 1000's of different pictures and films that people have taken on "Bigfoot".
But no picture or film has become a definitive evidence of Bigfoot's existence.
And then we come the last question ... Is Bigfoot for real or is everything a scam?
Here we have to rewind a little to the footprints found on the river Bluff Creek by forest worker Jerry Crew 1958.
In 2002, however, the truth emerged.
It turned out that the father of a forest workers had secretly made the footprints with their own homemade footprints of wood
As he simply just entered his own feet like a pair of big flip-flops and then he trampled around the clay around the river Bluff Creek.
You know the hunters Rick Dyer and Matthew Whitton who found a dead bigfoot that they had placed in a freezer box?
It was revealed that Bigfoot: One that lay in the freezer was in fact a masquerade costume from an American website named The Horror Dome.
And that "researcher" who supported their claim?
Yes, the "researcher" was, in fact, brother of one of the hunters.
Real researchers had been involved when their bigfoot thawed and it was quickly discovered that the head was hollow and their feet were made of rubber.
Then we have the movies.
The difficult thing about proving or disproving Bigfoot's existence is that it is so incredibly easy to fake.
Place a man in a gorilla costume in the forest, stand far away with a camera and voila!
Bigfoot.
Hence the first 3 films I showed difficult to give any explanation for.
But the fourth movie, the first movie ever that came out on Bigfoot there is actually an explanation for.
In 1998, a man at Man Bob Heironimus emerged and said "I am the bigfoot".
Okay, he didn't say exactly that, but he told me he had been a friend of Roger Patterson and got paid by him to put on a gorilla costume and walk around in front of the camera.
Another person was called Philip Morris in 2002, who told me that he ran a company like the 60s that produced different kinds of costumes and other props for magic numbers.
He remembers that he sold a gorilla costume to a person in 1967 via mail order.
The buyer must have stood as R. Patterson.
And now that all these different evidence has proven to be a scam, it was perhaps thought that the legend of Bigfoot would die out.
But that did not happen.
The news The various bluffs were ignored by the Bigfoot enthusiasts and the interest in Bigfoot has instead become even greater.
Today, there are clubs and organizations in the United States whose sole purpose is to search for bigfoot.
A little strange how we humans work sometimes ..
Although the name Bigfoot became known in 1958 in the United States, legends on various large human -like creatures have been around for centuries in the rest of the world.
For example, Yeti, also called the snowman who is said to live up in the Himalayan Mountains.
We have the Russian creature Menk, which is Russia's version of a Yeti you can say.
Mongolia is said to have a creature called Almas.
Vietnam has Nguoi Rung.
Indonesia has EBU Gogo.
China has Yeren.
And so on and so on ...
So I guess it doesn't really matter if it's really or if everything is a scam.
The legend of Bigfoot will live on anyway.
What do you think?
Feel free to share in the comments field.
Don't forget to subscribe to this channel.
And as always…
Thanks for watching!