Thanks, Mrs. President No, here is not blamed anything.
But it is very important to compare.
Then we will compare in the defense area.
What did it look like then, during the bourgeois government
What does it look like now makes that comparison!
Make comparison with investments in the judiciary
Make comparisons in terms of laws, where we tighten 50 laws and before 20 new crime classifications
There was nothing in the office drawers when we took office from the bourgeois government.
That comparison must be made.
I am proud of the fact that Sweden has one of Europe's strongest economies
And that we could take on the pandemic in a way that few countries could do because we have such a strong economy.
I am still equally obsessed with fighting crime, and we see that results can be achieved in, for example, Malmö.
But we have to do much, much more.
Then we have to have more police officers, and that is what this government makes sure it is.