Welcome to Trosa and to history in Sörmland.
I think many people think about this with summer and vacation when thinking about panties.
Precisely the holiday and summer life has shaped this society in many ways and do so even today.
It began in the 19th century, in the middle of the 19th century, Trosa was a fishing community with approximately 500 inhabitants
The streaming fishing in particular was important at this time.
Somewhere in the second half of the 1800s it began
Going worse with the fishing industry, the flock fishing was not as reliable.
At the same time, bathers, especially from Stockholm, began to discover Trosa as a seaside resort where one could live
live a healthy bathing life.
It became a more common and more common pleasure for the rich during the second half of
19th century.
Then people here in Trosa discovered that here there was a new income that could replace
Streaming.
They started renting out houses to the bathers for they had special performances
About how to live in such an archipelago.
They also began to build new to meet the wishes
Painted with light linseed oil colors, it would be carpentry joy, that's what you wanted.
So they began to reshape the river and the area around the river and created walking paths so they could
Klan here and have a good time.
You took tourism so seriously and invested so much on this so you even had some kind
Tourist office, a bathing chambers here from the late 1800s and about 50 years ahead.
This with summer, summer pleasure and holidays were something for the rich initially but
From 1938 you can say that Sweden became a holidaying people if one is to express themselves.
Then we got statutory with two weeks' vacation and still today we take this with holidays on big
Serious, many of us anyway.
Sweden is one of the countries in the world that has the most summer houses and
Leisure boats if you look at the proportion of the population.
Many who come here from other countries and settle
themselves here say they feel first as the Swedes when they have acquired a summer house,
Then you have something to talk about on the coffee break.
Do you want to experience a real summer bead but also take part in an interesting and exciting
History about this with holiday life and bathing so come here to Trosa.
Welcome