Is it that you have saved SEK 10,000 together?
You may be thinking about: What should you do with the money?
You can't have them in a bank account at your regular bank!
What do they give?
Type 0 in interest.
Then this video is perfect for you!
I intend to show you how I think, if I had invested SEK 10,000 just today.
If you do not know who I am, my name is Marcus Lindblad and I run Sparecash.
Sparecash.se I have started, as well as this Youtube channel,
With the goal of learning you who are beginners how to invest in shares, funds and much more.
But keep in mind that investment comes with a very high risk.
This means that when you invest your money you can lose parts of, or whole, your capital.
So be careful when investing your money.
- subtitles of talk - - www.prata.ltd -
The absolute first I had done with these SEK 10,000
is that I had divided them into four smaller pieces.
The first one will then be SEK 2,500.
What do I do with them?
Well, the first thing I had chosen is a global fund.
With a global fund you get a very wide spread all over the world
And the absolute largest companies in the world.
If you look at global funds today you get exposure to, among other things:
Apple, Google, Microsoft and Large, American, Stable Companies
Which has made a lot of money and will do so for many years to come.
If the world economy goes well, the funds will also go up and your money will grow.
But which global fund should you choose then, maybe you are thinking about.
Well, I had chosen Länsförsäkringar Global Index -close or Avanza Global.
Two perfect global funds.
There is not much difference between these two so it does not matter which one you actually choose.
So, now we have invested SEK 2,500 in a fund, and now I want us to take the step and actually buy a share.
So we thump SEK 2,500 in Investor.
Boom!
Investor is an investment company, which means that they in turn own other companies.
These companies are stable, safe, Swedish companies that do well with profits and also distribute the profits,
Which means that we as a shareholder get some pure cash into the account by owning these shares.
Investor is a perfect beginner's share that has also beaten the stock exchange, historically.
But what do you get if you buy Investor?
Yes: Atlas Copco, ABB, EQT and many others.
The third investment.
2,500 SEK we will now add.
There I want to strike a blow for a fund robot.
A fund robot is managing the investments for you.
Do you need a fund robot?
No.
You absolutely do not need to invest in a fund robot if you do not want to.
But I think it's nice to have a fund robot.
A bit like a airbag.
If one's self has some trouble dealing with the emotions
And may not know what to invest in, so a fund robot is perfect for you who are a beginner.
With a fund robot you usually get a very wide spread
Among a variety of funds and ETFs at a reasonably low fee.
If you do not want to choose a fund robot, you can instead double the sum that you put in a global fund.
It is just as good with a global fund as with a fund robot.
If you are eager to invest in a fund robot then I have made a comparison between Lysa and Opti
which are two of the larger fund robots in Sweden, which you probably know.
My favorite is shine.
Lysa is the cheapest fund robot and the fee is very important to look at if you compare different fund robots.
My strategy, when I invest in a fund robot, is to always have 100% shares.
It is true that when you choose a fund robot you have to answer a few different questions.
These questions will give you a suggestion for various investments that you will choose.
The fund robot will thus give you a proposal for distribution between shares and interest rates in your investments.
My philosophy as an investor is to always have 100% shares among my investments.
Because the interest rate is quite low now, around the world but also in Sweden,
So you don't get that much for the money when you invest in interest rates.
Therefore, I prefer shares instead, in the long run, if you are a long -term investor.
If you want a little more stability and that your money doesn't turn so much ...
If you were to invest in shares then it goes like this
But if you invest in a mixture of shares and interest rates, you will receive a more stable return.
So for those who may need the money within a slightly shorter time,
If you need them within 3-5 years,
Maybe it's a good idea to have some interest rates in your portfolio.
But I'm not an advocate of it.
If you want to read more about fund robots, I have a comparison on SpareCash that you can check out there.
The fourth and final investment.
We have SEK 2,500.
Here I want to fit over the ball to you.
I want you to read on.
Think about what you are interested in investing in.
Is it that you want to choose a share or a special fund?
Think!
In any case, I had chosen another fund.
I usually advise beginners to aim to have 80% funds and 20% shares.
In my case, I choose a fund that I believe in.
Then I choose a small company fund.
But you can choose some other type of fund.
For example, an Asia Fund, a emerging market fund,
Or a particular country you think will go well in the long run.
Or another fund, such as technology, sustainable energy or similar.
Think about what you believe in, which you like to follow and read about.
I choose a small company fund because small companies have actually gone very well over time.
Small companies have tended to go better than the stock exchange in the long run.
Because if you find these little companies at an early stage
So you have to participate in a very nice trip in the long run,
If they are increasing, make more money and grow in the long run.
Then you can make a really nice trip.
But, as I said, I want to fit the ball to you.
Think about what you wanted to have in your portfolio.
When investing in shares and funds,
Then make sure you do it in an ISK account or in a capital insurance.
It gives you a low treasure and you don't have to declare your business.
If you have them in a stock and fund account then you will instead pay 30% tax on your profit
And you will need to report your business to the Swedish Tax Agency in your next declaration.
And it can be a bit boring!
Do you have any thoughts about these investments I have talked about,
Write a comment a comment.
And if you liked these tips, please press your thumb up.
Then, as always, I have a lot of guides on sparecash.se, so check out there.
If you have any more questions and may want to get to know others who are interested in investing their money,
So you can really join our Facebook group
Or in our Discord server, which is open to everyone.
If you are even more tagged and curious about how I do with my investments,
When I buy and sell something, you really have to become a member on the channel.
Thanks so much to you who are already members of the channel!
If so, we will see you in the next video.
Ciao!