In today's video so we'll go through
The funds that I think are best to invest in
This does not mean that
These are the best funds
Without it are the ones I consider
Are interesting to start saving in case you are a beginner and may want to start saving in funds this year
If you do not know who I am, my name is Marcus Lindblad.
And it's me who runs Sparecash!
On sparecash and you will learn
Save in shares, funds, and much more.
The funds that we go through in this video you should see as
Inspiration and tips
But not as advice without
you must always read on
And wondering if this is right for you
Never invest more money than you can afford to lose
Because if you are a beginner and want to start saving in funds
For an extended period of time for example three to five years ahead
Then these are these funds you should invest in.
Some key features that I look for when I look at this fund
It is that the fund should have:
Performed well in the past
That it has a low fee
And that it is a equity fund.
It is the three important pieces that
You should look at if you look at different funds.
And when we talk about funds with a low fee
Then I look at funds below 1 % in fee.
(The discussion about fees) It is a completely different video that we can take another time.
Now we jump into the first fund!
The first fund I think is good to have in a long -term savings
It is
Spiltan equity fund investment company
Spiltan Aktiefond investment company is a
Investment company fund
The fund is investing in
Other investment companies
And for the most part, it contains:
Investor
But also other investment companies such as:
Industrivärden, Kinnevik
And many others.
And this at a low fee of only 0.2%
And yes, you can definitely buy these investment companies yourself!
But in case you are not ready to
Start buying shares
Then buy this fund.
I have this fund as a base in my long -term portfolio.
Because it is easy to save only each month in the fund
To this low fee
Fund number 2 which I find interesting it is Avanza Zero.
Avanza Zero is a free fund
Which invests in Sweden's 30 most traded shares.
And then you get a pretty
Nice mix of
Big
Swedish stable companies traded over the stock exchange
The good thing about this fund is completely free.
So you will get a stable return over time and it doesn't cost you a single penny.
The third fund that I find interesting in long -term savings is:
Avanza Global
Avanza Global is a global fund
This means the fund is investing in shares all over the world
So then you get exposure to the absolute largest companies in the world.
And this to a very low fee
And these three types of the funds - they are enough!
(short and good)
In a long -term fund portfolio.
My own little tactics when one
Saves in funds: three funds are enough
You need a Swedish fund
An investment company fund
And a global fund
And then you can season with
Small companies
Technique
Or somebody else
For example, developing countries or whatever.
But it is enough with these wide funds that have a low fee
And that invests in 100% shares.
This type of funds is enough for your savings if you are long -term.
They fit perfectly if you are a beginner and just want something to save in each month.
Of course there are options
To Avanza Zero
Spiltan investment company
Avanza Global
There are a lot of good options
And I've listed them in my article:
Best funds at sparecash.se
So check out that article and I put a link below in the description
And the comment field
So go in there
Because there you can see more different funds.
There are many good funds out there!
But the most important thing you have to think about.
It is to save every month!
Instead of trying to look for
which fund is the best
Instead try to sell out
Those funds that are bad
It doesn't matter if you go one or two percent up or down
Up or down
Or so
Without looking for them instead
Good funds
Save in them all the time
Do not try to change and so if you do not
manage to spend time on it
Without finding any good funds
Save in them every month
And do it
for several years
That's what will make you
Really rich over time.
Thank you so much for watching this video, and is it that you like such types of tips?
So please give me a thumbs up on this video
If so, we will see you in the next video!
Ciao