Yes but hey or is it good with you or
Today we will talk about shares or funds what should you choose
And how should you think when choosing between shares and funds
Is it that before you watch this video it can go well to
Make a cup of coffee and since we are more than a thousand subscribers now we will celebrate with a small bun
I haven't paid for so #sparadkrona
Before I have eaten my bun, I will also present the winners and the winners that I pulled is
Filip Rydin
Emil Hanna upstream Siberia's soup kitchen
Åsa Lundgren Hurry nurse Karam Julia and Ardalan
Congratulations You have won each share book You can contact me on Instagram or Facebook
With your address so I send out the books to you
In today's video so we'll talk about
Shares or funds, ie
What should you choose
When you save
Should you buy
Shares or should you save in a fund?
And yes the biggest difference between stocks and funds
When you buy shares you own indirectly
Part of a business
And if you buy a fund instead
Yes but it is so that you get some of
A bunch of different shares
Up to 20-50 different companies you might get if you invest in a fund
But if you buy a share then it's just the company you invest in
If we think about that particular claim
So maybe you understand that
There is a little higher risk that
Invest in shares
than it is to invest in funds
When you invest and save your money
so do you have to think about how much risk you are willing to take
By investing in shares so take very high risk
And when you invest in equity funds, there is also a high risk but not as high as if you had only bought 1 share
So if that company goes bad (in which you bought shares)
so does your entire investment go to the beep turn
But if you buy a fund instead
Then you spread out the risk
Among different companies
At least 16 shares you get if you buy a fund
I usually say that
Stock suits you who are looking to take some more risk that may want to
it should go up and down a little faster
Also you want to spend some time analyzing different companies and seeing who goes well and
You may be thinking that "this company will go well"
You like to speculate and you want to spend some extra time on your investments
You may find it fun to invest in stocks
You may find it fun to follow different companies
And like the economy and everything in general
Yes but then maybe shares are something for you!
The hook of buying a fund instead of shares
You don't have as much chance to make as much money
If you then buy a fund instead of shares
But a fund is perfect for those who can't think of spreading the risk without
Want someone else to take care of it for you instead
If you want to invest shares
Yes but then maybe it is because you wanted a little higher return
For example, I buy shares because I think it is fun.
Not because I think I am a professional or that I am good at analyzing different companies but it is a bit like a hobby for me
I think it's pretty fun to follow different companies, how it goes for them
And yes, then my grows
Bargains also over time if it is so that the company is going well
If I find something that I think will go well.
It's all about speculation simply!
Instead when you buy a fund
How do you leave that responsibility
To the managers who manage the fund
Because you think they are better at finding good shares than you are.
If you choose shares - then you will receive the following benefits
You have the chance to make more money than funds
It does not cost any annual fees or current fees when owning shares
3. You decide entirely which shares you want to invest in
When you buy funds so maybe it's a bit difficult to think about
What shares are what actually exist in this fund?
Because it's not something you can control
So if you wish to invest morally or ethically or environmentally friendly or other
Then you can't choose it in a fund
There are various funds that have such classifications
But
It is actually the fund manager who chooses what should be in the fund and not you
But when you buy shares then you can control this yourself!
Disadvantages of shares
Yes but that is that you have a higher risk than funds
Also swinging pretty much upside down
So it is that you are not.
comfortable with
It might go down 10 % in a day
Yes but then maybe you should have a fund instead.
When you buy a fund then it is so that you hand over the responsibility to the fund manager.
To control and set and decide which shares should be in this fund.
Funds may be for those who want to spend a little less time on your savings
And just have an automatic savings where someone else takes care of you
You may not have the desire to sit and pick out different shares
And then maybe funds fit better just for you
A typical stock investor
Yes it sits on needles most often and often check how the savings go every day
Myself, I am one that invests in shares
But I think it's fun!
I enjoy following the stock exchange and keeping track of how the investments go up and down
I have no problem if it goes down pretty much in one day.
I think it's pretty fun to follow how my shares go
But one absolutely does not have to choose either or
Without you can have both shares and funds in your savings.
I myself have both
I have about 80 % shares and I have 20 % equity funds
It is no fixed rule with 80/20 principle
I just think it's nice to keep it in about
If it is so that my shares go bad, hopefully my funds will be better.
The vast majority they probably make more money
on investing only in funds than shares
It is very rare as one sees that
Persons hit index (stock exchange)
You have to be good at selecting good shares
If you want to be able to beat index
It is required quite a lot at least over the long term
In the short term on some year
So yes but then maybe it is so that you beat index, but in the long term it is very rare you do
The vast majority actually earn best at choosing a free fund
Thus an index fund with very low fee
They show over the term that they give quite well
But if you are such as
Do you like to keep on and pill and invest yourself and find different shares and companies
Yes but then maybe it is so
You should invest in shares with
One absolutely does not have to choose
Without it, it is good to actually invest in both shares and funds.
Whether you are new to investing and you have neither or invested in shares nor funds.
Yes but then I think you should start with a fund anyway
Funds don't turn as much as stocks do
And it's pretty easy to get started and
Just put a hundred dollars into a fund without costing any fee.
Thus, there is no purchase fee and no sales fee on funds.
On shares, however, you have to pay a fixed fee a purchase fee and a sales fee
called brokerage while on funds so it is a running fee
an annual management fee deducted on your investments
But there are free funds out there that you can use from that you can start with if you are a beginner and want to start saving
But then maybe it fits well with a free fund
To sum it all up
Choose what you think is most comfortable to invest in
If you like slightly higher risks but then maybe you should invest in shares
But if it is so that you want to spend as little time as possible
Then maybe it fits better with investing in funds.
If you want to have as low fees as
Choose some free index funds
If you want a little better control and
Want to invest in funds such as
swinging a lot and has a higher risk and higher chance of making money
Check out active equity funds then instead
It might be a better suits you
And then when you have learned
Yes but then maybe you can go in and test and buy some shares
It's all up to you - feel for yourself
But dare to invest - that's the main factor!
Dare to open a savings and just start investing for
With time you learn more.
I hope you have got some more meat on your legs and regarding the issue of shares or funds.
Thank you so much for looking, you give me a thumbs up and I understand that you like this video and then I hope to see you in the next video!
Ciao!