You have probably heard that you should not lay all the eggs in the same basket.
In this video we will go through how to diversify its portfolio.
Now it is the same basket, but it is still important to have several assets in their basket.
Got reconciliation at a Snickers.
Allright, then we drive then.
In this video we will go through five good tips that I wish I got when I started investing.
I have seen a horribly many beginners who totally do away with them when investing.
So we will go through diversifications in this video.
It is important to spread your risk so that you do not lose money on the stock exchange.
For example, you invest all money in a company or that you may be all in cryptocurrencies or something else.
It can have horrific consequences for your portfolio and your money.
Believe me, I've learned the hard way.
So what does it mean that you diversify your portfolio?
Well, it simply means that you protect yourself against your own stupidity simply among your investments.
Do you have all your money in a business?
Yes, then it is true that if the company concentrates (go bankrupt) then you will lose all your money.
So for example, the seat belt, we do not have it for us to crash, but it is if we collide.
You do not know if it will go to hell.
So it's just as good to take it safe for the uncertain.
Then run thick!
Then drive!
The first tip when it comes to diversifying your portfolio is not to forget that you do not just need shares or funds in your portfolio.
Sure, when you are new then maybe it works, but when you start getting some more money in your portfolio then you may be wise to have several asset laws.
Yes, you can have art, you can have watches, you can have wine, you can have real estate.
There is a bunch of other investments that also go up in the long term to spread the risk in your portfolio.
Tip 2 - Diversify among multiple industries
Now, for example, when interest rates have gone up so much, then real estate shares have got it quite tough.
And I'm sitting on some real estate shares, so it's been tough for me.
So it is important to spread among more industries.
And a simple tip there may be to think that you have a maximum of 25% of the portfolio in an individual industry.
And then max.
Look at several different industries.
Because it is so, if a certain industry is affected, then it may be that your entire portfolio goes down.
And for example, American shares have been doing very well now lately.
Many people buy global funds and American tech companies.
So remember to have not too much of your entire portfolio in a particular industry or niche.
Point number three.
Diversifying among several countries.
The same goes for countries and regions.
This year, for example, the US stock exchange has gone very strong.
And what happens then?
Well, all beginners rush into American tech shares such as Nvidia and the like.
And not only do you take a land risk here if the country goes badly, but also a currency risk.
If it goes the other way, for example, that the Swedish krona is now becoming stronger against the dollar,
Yes, then maybe it is a 20% downside there.
We don't know that.
But of course the big risk here is the individual country.
For example, if you only buy Chinese shares, then you take a very large political risk.
But yes, if the country goes badly, yes, then your entire portfolio of shit goes of course.
And for example, I have had a lot of Sweden in my portfolio.
And yes, then you have to take that bang that the Swedish currency has gone bad
And that you have missed a lot of rise in the United States.
I have a little US in the portfolio, but it is still good to think about having more countries and regions in your portfolio.
So please mix Swedish, American, maybe a little European and then maybe spice up with some emerging countries.
Tip number four, invest in more assets than just shares and funds.
I am very focused on mostly shares and funds.
But what many do not know is that I have many more investment assets in the portfolio than that.
For example, I have peer-to-peer loans, I have cryptocurrencies,
I have cash in the portfolio and some other sprinkle investments.
This year for example, not many people think about it,
But Bitcoin has gone up almost 90% seen in SEK.
It can be a fun spice to one's portfolio.
Sure it's a cloud comfort to me now that the stock market has gone so extremely bad,
But it is still nice to feel that you have some other asset in a portfolio that has gone well.
At the same time, having some money on savings account with interest today you get 3-4% in a savings account.
Maybe a little peer-to-peer loan also that was a comfort last year for example, is quite nice.
And we get into cryptocurrencies and things like bitcoin.
Yes, it is an extremely high risk!
But a proposal there could be to have a maximum of 5-10% of your total portfolio against cryptocurrencies.
Some others advocate gold, silver and other precious metals,
But digital currencies, yes, they have actually historically given a pretty nice return over time.
But as I said, think about the high risk.
And speaking of Bitcoin and Ethereum, we come quite naturally to XBT Provider,
which is the sponsor of today's video.
Through XBT, such as Bitcoin-XBT, Ethereum-XBT, you can get exposure to cryptocurrencies
In a very simple way through, for example, Avanza and Nordnet.
It is very easy to buy them only when the stock exchange is open,
And you have them on the side of your shares and funds in your very ordinary investment account.
For example, on an investment savings account (ISK) or a capital insurance (KF)
which means you don't have to declare if you buy cryptocurrencies in a normal way,
Because it can be a little difficult.
So it easier to buy them there, for example, than to do it yourself over a stock exchange
Where it can be a bit problematic to get the money and such stuff.
XBT Provider was the first in Europe to launch such a bitcoin certificate.
They are regulated by Finansinspektionen and you can go to their proof of reserves yourself
and see their full transparency.
In addition, their main company Coinshares is listed on Nasdaq Stockholm.
If you want to know more about Bitcoin XBT and Ethereum XBT, there are links to the products here
during the video in the description and comments field.
Thanks to XBT who sponsors this video.
Tip number five.
Invest regularly.
What many do on the stock exchange when one's investment goes bad
is that you put your head in the sand and do nothing.
You may be waiting for it to just turn around and that it should look good once you log in three months later,
But the best purchases are usually made in the worst times.
So make sure to invest all the time, so buy a little neighbor all the time.
And my tip is usually to always have a fund savings every month
So that you always buy a little neighbor all the time when it goes up and down.
But the same goes for shares.
What many do, including myself, is that you tend to buy shares on tops
When everyone talks about the stock exchange and it is hottest.
But it is now when maybe no one is talking about shares and the stock exchange
As it might be a place to buy a little.
Then it depends on which company of course.
But instead of pushing all the money at once in shares,
Therefore, make sure to spread the purchases and drove you in.
If you have 10,000 to invest in shares, perhaps divide it into smaller portions,
Maybe a thousand kronor at a time, so you take in a little when it goes up and a little when it goes down.
For time you get a good average price, yes, which is better for you in the end.
And then you also reduce the risk of buying on a top and selling on a bottom.
So do you have any tips on how to best diversify their portfolio?
Maybe something that I forgot in the video so feel free to write it in a comment below.
And if you liked this clip, please press like.
And thank you so much for looking and thanks to all the members who support the channel.
See you in the next video.
Have a good time!
Ciao!