Are we recording now?
I am looking?
Earn the blog.
Today we are going to run such a Q&A video and now it is so that this intro-
-or last intro sucked, so now I record this on the other camera because I have a little lack of time.
So now we jump to the other camera and then I run some videos.
Hello or!
Today we will run a Q&A, a question video.
I think we jump right away.
It's fun.
Tjena Marcus.
I wonder what distinguishes between the A, B and C shares for the same company?
Emil.
Well, the difference between A and B shares is so here-
-This is the case that when you own an A-share, you have a right to vote.
You have the right to influence the company.
At a general meeting, for example, you get to vote for what you think and think.
If you think a company should do si or so.
If you have a B share instead, you do not have as strong voting rights.
An A-share is usually worth 10 times more than a B share in the form of voting rights.
Otherwise, the shares are just the same.
The more shares you have, the greater the impact you can do at the company.
If you are the main owner you usually have A shares, but if you are a small saver like you and I-
-Then it is usually the case that you drive on the B shares instead.
These shares with less voting rights usually have greater turnover on the stock exchange.
So it is easier to be able to buy and be able to sell them.
Brief answer to your question is that an A-share is worth more than a B share in the form of voting rights.
If you are not the main owner of the share, it is unnecessary to even think about it-
-And just buy the share that is the cheapest and which has the highest turnover.
Should it be a high or low p/e figure?
Earn Elin!
The P/E figure is an abbreviation of Price shared with Earnings.
Thus, the share price shared with the profit per share.
These two key figures.
How much does the share cost and how much does the company earn in profit per share?
Then you get the p/e figure.
If a share costs SEK 5 and the profit per share is 1 kr-
-Then it takes 5 years for the company to earn the profit to which the company or share is valued.
Some believe that a low p/e ratio is better than a high, but purely scratch you can say that a low p/e
-SD decided that the company is low valued compared to a high p/e figure.
You could say that the higher p/e number a company has, the higher expectations they have.
For example, we have Amazon that has had a P/E ratio of 70 up to 130
-If you look back since 2011.
But Amazon has also gone very well, increased sales quite properly.
And the share has actually more than ten times in value since 2011.
So in that is the case, a high p/e number has not been so bad.
Personally, I don't care much about p/e ratios when I choose shares.
Tjena Marcus.
I was just going to raise a quick question how you think about your own investment?
What is the goal of your savings?
How did you post it in the form of monthly savings?
And you can also add how you started.
Did you have any start -up capital or monthly saved with a lower sum and then increase?
Yes, your strategy simply.
Tjena Daniel!
I always save at least SEK 1,000 per month and today I do so in 7 different equity funds.
Gradually, I sometimes sell off some funds if I am dissatisfied with the return.
And so I buy more of my shares instead.
Often I want an 80/20 distribution between my shares and funds.
I remember when I was little and then we had cash-
-And I saved them in my piggy bank and sometimes I took out my money and put them on the floor.
Then I wrote on a paper how much I had saved.
My first goal was to save for a Sony Ericsson mobile phone.
I very much wanted to have it, so I saved as much as I could-
-To be able to afford to buy this mobile.
And it's always followed with me.
This to save for something-
-or just that it's fun to feel that you have money.
I started investing by reading a lot, I googled a lot and then I opened an account at Avanza.
Then I was 19 years old, so it's just over 7 years ago.
So 7 years ago, in 2013 I think, then I bought Avanza Zero for SEK 2,500.
It was savings that I didn't know what would do with.
And I've always wanted to learn how shares and funds work.
So I put this money on Avanza and started buying Avanza Zero.
I bought Avanza Zero afterwards, a little like that.
And then I bought my first shares after that too.
Then I went some courses and have learned over time.
You never become fully trained, even that I have been doing here for 7 years-
-To you never become fully trained, but you learn all the time and that is what is fun.
Erik Martinger.
Many monthly savings in funds, but how do shares really?
How do you do?
As I mentioned in the matter before, I buy funds every month.
Sometimes more often than that, if it swings a lot, kind of now in coronatids, I bought a little more.
Just as I said, my funds weigh more than 20 % out of my total portfolio-
-Then I usually allocate a little or thus sell some of my funds.
And buy more shares instead.
Because I think it is more fun to keep up with shares.
Mattias Sandelius.
What does your portfolio look like?
Earn Mattias!
Well, I have 4 companies in my equity portfolio today.
Some may think that is a little higher risk, but I like it to be high risk.
And I like when it swings a lot.
I think it's fun.
Today it is Castellum, Mycronic, Sinch and Plejd.
Then I also have 7 funds and you can see them here.
Gabbe Lönn Erlandsson.
Do you have any example of places you can invest in the interest-on-interest effect to secure their future savings?
Earn Gabbe
I don't really know what you mean, but interest on the interest effect you achieve if it is that you invest in anything-
-And then you get a return or interest rate and then reinvest it.
So that the following year or a while thereafter, you get a greater return or a greater interest rate.
I advise you to see my interest rate on interest video where I explain more about interest on the interest effect.
Dividend shares are a perfect example of how to apply interest to the interest rate.
How do you go about finding out why a share is going high or low?
Most often, check news about the company, reports and other things.
Through rumors, I search for news on Google.
If you search for the company, you usually find it on Google on news or on Twitter.
Rafi Newton Andreasyan.
I don't know if I said that name right, but ... sorry.
What strategy do you use to determine if you want to buy a certain share or not buy it right now?
I actually have no direct strategy, but I feel about buying a share so I buy the share.
I have a little gut feeling you could say.
If I think the company has potential and I want to buy shares, then I usually buy a small guarding post-
-When I hold and then I read about the company.
And if I get a greater belief in the company, then I buy more.
What did your portfolio look like when you started with shares and funds?
And what does it look like today?
So I am interested in how the development has gone.
The development has probably not gone so great.
I did quite a lot of beginner misses that all do the first 2, 3, 4, 5 years.
I'm still a beginner in my eyes.
I bought a lot of Avanza Zero in the beginning and a little trampled ... Yes, cancer companies and stuff.
I don't think it went really well, but I can throw up a print screen here so you can see.
Wilmer Lehtonen.
Hi, here comes a question from a real beginner.
I am trying to build a portfolio and study some different funds, but also stock-
-It feels like the stock market has been going very well lately and many funds and shares are at the top.
How to think then?
Should you wait or look for others who have not gone as well?
Or buy in at those who are high and wait for Q3 in the hope that they will go up further?
Thanks.
Yes, you Wilmer.
I think you should not contradict so much.
But should think about how long do I invest?
Is it that I invest in one or two years' time?
Is it that you invest quarterly or why are you worried?
Sure, in the short span of time it is hard if it turns much-
-As an example with Corona when the stock exchange lost 10 % in one day.
It was very busy for a lot and many sold themselves away and you lost some money on it.
The absolute best tip I can give and that I usually give, it is to be long -term.
Thinking that this is money that I invest in maybe 10 years term.
Then when investing, you know that I should not be affected by such short -term events.
So should you wait?
Yes, if you find it difficult because there is a risk that it may go down a lot, then maybe you should wait.
Instead, I usually think like this that I might invest a little less amount, if I am worried that it is a pretty high top.
And continue to invest over time just all the time.
You don't have to go all in at once, because that's what a lot of beginners do in the beginning.
That you buy on tok for large sums, so if you earn 20,000 a month-
-Do not go in with 20,000, but go in with maybe 10 % of what you earn.
If you may deposit SEK 5,000 into savings, then you do not have to go in with 5,000 at once.
It is enough for SEK 500, so if it is so that it goes down you can buy for SEK 500 more.
Then you have come in both when it is high and when it is low.
Filip Thunstedt aka boss and legend.
Do you run loan?
Yes I do.
I drive with securities loan.
The super loan at Avanza.
I run a maximum of 5 % loan.
That's my personal rule.
Magnus Sturedahl.
How to lie down long or short?
And how do you calculate a possible loss?
Lieving long means that you believe in your investment in ...
It is believed that it should simply go up.
Locating briefly means that you believe in down.
It is therefore believed that the investment will go down.
This can be done with leverage products such as Bull, Bear, Turbovarians, CFDS.
There are a variety of such products.
In fact, I do not know all these products in my head, but leverage products are not recommended for beginners.
It's pretty easy to burn there.
If you want to count on the risks with a leverage, then you will have to look at how much leverage it is in the product that you buy.
Then you get to look at the potential tender side, if it is so that it would go down 5 %-
-Multiply it with the leverage, type.
There you have your risk.
Plus any fees and interest rates for that product.
It is a very complicated question that is very difficult to go into right now.
The risk is great when you shop with leverage, so read on properly and make sure you learn first.
Tore Landin Larsson.
My real brother, the star.
Strategies for purchases, sales, reallocation.
It would be interesting how you reason about it.
So, when you take home profits, selling poor holdings, if you are long on minus placements or if you sell them with the highest development?
Well, it's a little hard to say something that is red.
If it is so that I see that a company does not develop as well as I hope-
-If it just continues downwards and down, then maybe I sell off.
For example, I invested in Catena Media a while ago and they did not go so well-
-then I sold with a loss, because it is better that you sell with a small loss-
-Ex that you sit for as long as possible and hope for a turn.
Many people say: "Yes, be long -term."
Which I also say that you should be for 5, 10 years and blah, blah blah.
But if it is so that news comes up while you invested in a stock-
-As you show that this company does not perform well and their profits are dropping, they lose money.
Why should you join a sinking ship for?
Then it is better that you get rid of that leaven.
That's usually how I think.
Then I would rather jump on a boat or train that goes and where the chance to make money is greater.
I also invest my money in something that I feel can give me more value for my investment.
Than I should have them in any sourdough that does not give me a return simply.
Tony Godlike Lindh.
Is it better to distribute the same amount to funds or a large amount on a single fund?
Yes, you Tony.
It is a good question I would rather make myself so that I spread the amount among different funds.
Some funds that I think will go better I have slightly larger amounts in.
And some others have a little less amount in which I may think is high risk and other things.
So it is different and it is from person to person.
You get to feel yourself, simply.
Erik Martinger.
When will the video come up?
Now.
Ida Runn.
I subscribe to Youtube, but still haven't received a vacuum cleaner that you promised.
I wonder where it is?
Vacuum cleaner?
So now I have answered most of the questions and forgive me if I have not answered your particular question.
I have received a lot of questions now and recently and I try to answer as much as possible.
I have an idea that we should run maybe this week's question or that I bring some of your viewers' questions-
-And with them at the end of each video maybe.
I think it can be a good idea.
Feel free to thumb if you like the idea or leave a comment down here.
Dares to introduce yourself in the comments field here on youtube-
-or in our Facebook group.
It is incredibly fun when we build here a little community, so we can learn from each other.
It's sick fun.
I get an enormous number of questions every day and it only grows every day and I get more and more messages-
-and I don't actually have time to answer everything.
Sometimes it may be that I answer and that's because I'm kind, but preferably I wish that if you have private questions-
-The sinking you can book a meeting with me for payment for my time costs.
I have to pay my bills.
But otherwise it is so that I recommend asking the question completely free in our Facebook group-
-So that others can take part in the knowledge.
But it may also be that others in the group can help you with exactly answers to your question.
And I really appreciate when you others answer questions in our Facebook group.
So I don't have to go in and answer everyone myself, because it takes an incredible amount of time away from me.
We have more many good videos that will come and if you have tips on good videos so comment as well.
I hope you also liked this video.
So we'll see you in the next.
Have a nice day!
Thanks.
Ciao.