You looked right!
I have already earned over SEK 40,000 on shares this year.
It is not that difficult to make money on shares.
I tried to tell you this in my previous videos-
-But I think that in this video, I'll simplify this.
The only two ways you can make money on shares through.
I will also show you my stock transactions that I have made money from.
So you can see exactly how things are going when you make money on shares.
In the end I give you a little bonus with my best tips for when buying stocks-
-So that you can make as much money as possible.
If you didn't know it, I'm called Marcus Lindblad.
I am the one who runs sparecash.se
Savecash is for those who are beginners who want to learn how to save in shares, funds and much more!
I want to make it so simple and easy to understand for you who are new to this.
Take out a cup of coffee, because now we run the video!
Thank you so much to you who have invited me for a cup of coffee.
Briefly explained, there are two ways to make money on shares.
The first way is when you buy shares, so you buy them for a particular price-
-To time, the price of your shares can go up and then you sell them at a more expensive price.
This way you have made money on your shares.
The second way you can make money on stock-
-This is that you buy that gives a dividend.
This means that the companies share their profits as they make.
Thus, you make money through their profit.
Then you get this money directly into your account that you own the shares on-
-In this way you have made some more money.
Coffee break!
[Marcus Sörplar coffee]
Yes, it's najs.
If we start with way number one.
It is that you make money when the price of shares goes up.
In my first video that I did about shares for beginner-
-So I show how to buy shares and I bought some shares in Plejd.
And there they went through and I have now bought a share in Plejd.
Then it was so ... that on June 8, 2020 I bought shares for just over SEK 5,000 in Plejd.
What I did then was that I bought myself in Plejd with a small guard post that I call it.
For me it means I force myself to read more about the company-
-During the time I have the little investment.
Then I also do not miss whether the share goes up very much.
I also do not go in too heavy if it is so that I have missed any detail on the road-
-Which, the share may go down a lot.
It may not hurt as much when I go in with a small post.
If we flush the band a little, I bought some more shares.
Then I bought more shares for almost SEK 15,000.
So in total I have invested SEK 20,000 in Plejd.
As time went on, it went better for the company Plejd
And so I decided to buy some more shares in Plejd quite recently.
Then I bought for 10,000 SEK, so I have invested SEK 30,000 in a total of a total.
If you look at the value today on my shares that I have invested in Plejd
-The today they are worth SEK 95,000.
Meaning an increase of just over SEK 65,000-
-To my SEK 30,000 that I have invested in Plejd.
Percentage, so means an increase of 216% right now.
So if I were to sell my shares in Plejd
-Then I had made a profit of SEK 65,000 today.
This is nothing that is normal for a share to increase so much on a year-
-Why I was simply lucky and I should thank myself for that.
You need to know however, it is that Plejd's shares ...
If the company is going badly in the future or they may be going bankrupt
Then my shares may theoretically be worth zero.
Then I have not made any money.
You have not made money until you have sold or taken home your profit.
For those of you who are beginners who may not really understand why the price of these stocks-
-In Plejd has gone up so much, then I'll try to explain it now.
The simple explanation as to why the price of the shares in Plejd has gone up so much-
-It is simply that the company has shown that they can make more money than they have done before.
What happens is that other private individuals, like you and I, or banks and other business-
-They believe that Plejd's shares are attractive and they also want to invest in this company.
If they continue to go just as well in the future.
What you do then is that you raise the price that you are willing to pay for Plejd's shares.
What happens is that the price of the shares goes up, which makes my investment more worthwhile than it used to be.
Insert number two that you can make money on shares.
It is through dividends.
I have made a video about dividend shares that you can check out here.
In that video I go through a little basic about why a company does dividend-
-and how to make money on it
But simply explained, it is usually a little larger company sharing their profits as they make.
They thank us shareholders for wanting to be part of the company.
But also then because those who own a bit of the company, as you and I-
-Or those who have founded the company should get a little bit of the profit.
To eat a small piece of the cake, simply.
Not all companies share the profits that the company actually makes.
For example, Plejd that I talked about earlier, they do not share with them out of their profit-
-whow they believe that the money they earn should remain in the company-
-And should not be distributed to us shareholders.
Because they believe that the company will use this money better.
Larger companies such as banks and real estate companies-
-which receives a stable cash flow as one calls it-
-They make a lot of money every month or every year and so there.
They are generous and want to share with us shareholders as a thank you for investing in their companies.
What I like about dividend shares is that you get some money, ie pure cash into the account.
That money rolls into the same account on which you own your shares.
Thus, you have some shares in a dividend share at, for example, an investment savings account
-The money will roll into the same account on which you own the shares.
Then it is free for you to withdraw this money and do what you want with them.
Or buy more shares, so you get a higher dividend next time.
Or whatever you want, buy a Snickers or whatever.
For example, I got SEK 3,600 from Castellum last year because I own Castellum shares.
Now I have bought some more shares in Castellum.
Partly for these dividend money that has rolled in, but Castellum has also raised the dividend this year-
-What means that I get a higher dividend, so this year I will receive just over SEK 4,000 in share dividends from Castellum.
But do you have to choose either?
No you do not have to.
It is just as good to have both a dividend share and a growth share.
Or those who you think the price will go up on the shares instead.
I have both and, and it goes well for you.
Now I will give you my best tips for making money on stock-
-When you should consider before buying shares, so you make the right choice.
Tip number one is for you who are a beginner who may not have bought shares yet.
It is to invest only money that you can afford to be without.
The stock market swings a lot, it goes up a lot and it goes down a lot.
Money that you invest you should be able to afford to be but for at least 3-5 years, I think.
We say that you have just started working and then you have put away some money from your pay-
-Own about SEK 1,000.
Do not invest all that money.
Maybe start with SEK 100 or SEK 200 that you might be able to afford to be outside
-And a little test with them, just to feel and learn how it works.
This way you avoid going in too heavy and burning yourself.
Then maybe you lose a lot of money and you think it's hard
-And then you simply will not continue to invest.
Start with a small amount and do not sell, but let it lie there-
-So you learn how it swings up and down.
Tip number two is to buy only shares in companies that you understand.
Think a bit like when you lend money.
If you had lent money to a buddy-
-When you trust.
Yes, but then you can trust that your friend will pay the money back to you.
If you were to lend money to a stranger on the street that you have never met before
-How sure are you then that you will get the money back?
Little is it about investing in shares.
Invest in companies that you know how they make money so you can understand a little better-
-If this company will use your money properly.
Very many beginners buy shares in companies that they have no idea what they actually do-
-or how they make money, if they even make any money.
Some companies are at loss and people just speculate on whether the share should go up or down.
But do you know what the company is doing and how they make money-
-The you will make much better investment.
Number three, be patient.
-Do that patience, you will make terribly much more money on the stock exchange.
When I was a beginner, I was buying and selling and holding on and back-
-I followed the stock exchange every minute from 9-17: 30 when the stock exchange closed.
Do not do it.
Invest, log out and do something else that is fun-
-What you would rather do the days
Do not sit and check every day all the time for so much you will not learn from a stock exchange day.
Have patience.
The less you are doing and shopping and buying and selling and here and there-
-So you will make much more money.
It is usually when you go in and try to make quick money in the short term that you usually lose money.
Be patient, log out a bit, and you will make much more money.
Tip number four, buy shares in an ISK account, an investment savings account.
From the beginning when you start investing, you get to choose which account you want to invest in.
Then there is investment savings account, capital insurance and equity fund account.
By having your shares and funds in an ISK account, you get a low tax and you do not have to declare your business.
You get tax -free dividends and you can only enjoy life and chill and have a good time.
The last tip, buy companies that make a profit.
If you are a beginner, do not buy companies that you have no idea what they do with-
-And then they go with a loss.
For what do companies that go with a loss?
Yes, they do something wrong.
Because it is not sustainable to run a business that does not make money or that does not make a profit anyway.
Then you have to be very sure of your investment.
Start by buying companies that make a profit.
It is easy.
You can only check out the P/E figure.
Is the p/e figure above zero, so it is positive.
Then the company goes with a profit.
If they have a negative p/e figure, they are at a loss.
Avoid them until a start, until you have learned a little more.
Then you can consider buying other companies.
The most important lesson when you want to start investing in stock-
-It is simply just starting.
Dare to invest, do not be afraid to invest.
Start with as little as only SEK 100, buy a Swedish company as you have control at-
-O which is listed on the Stockholm Stock Exchange.
At Avanza you can do it completely without commission and also on Nordnet.
It is perfect for those who may want to get started and learn investment.
I am incredibly happy that I have done it.
I started over 6 years ago and I would never think I can live on this right now-
-I don't live on my stock portfolio, but on working with this.
Teaching beginners like you about this with investments and shares and funds.
So start today, open an account via the link in description-
-and watch my other videos and check out sparecash.se-
-For there is so much information that you can learn from.
You will thank yourself in the future if you are taking this now.
Good luck with your investments.
Do you have any questions, then put this down-
-In the comment field, I'll respond to it as quickly as possible.
Thank you so much for watching the video.
Have a good one!
Ciao!
So that I have to do a little more research ...
So I have to do some re ...
[Protut sound]