Hey
In this video I was going to go through
My 2020
It is because Avanza has a summary of
How my and your stock and fund portfolio on Avanza have gone during 2020.
And you can easily go into it
If you look at the address here
So can you get an overview like the one I will show
How your investment has simply gone!
As a thank you for being so many subscribers here now on the channel so I think I should be a bit nice
Show up exactly how it went for me
To show that I am no lying ugly fish that
Yes
Some other social media have
If you have been involved in following the stock exchange last year then you might have a clue to
The stock exchange got a small breed there in March 2020
when the pandemic arose
And then so recovered the stock exchange who was lucky
And the vast majority of us
That was in the whole of 2020
Who sat still
have probably earned quite a lot of money
The cut has actually made quite a good time with money and we will also see that now in this overview
But I think we jump into the first so my total value
How much it increased with
My total value increased by SEK 213,721
And hence we have deposits of SEK 41,500 then
We have a development SEK 165,000
And dividends of SEK 6700
And my strategy in 2020 it has simply been to just
Be still and not do much.
In the past you may have gone in and bought and sold
one has been satisfied perhaps after 10-20% return
But this year I have let the shares rush
And most people have actually done that, they have gone up sick a lot of shares
Moves on to the next picture so we see then
Yes but it went better for me than the average at Avanza
I think quite a few of us may have
had that lucky to be above the cut
Both more than index and more than the avanza section
If we have been sitting on these technology shares
Sustainability shares or similar.
So my development ended at 38.06%
Percent
But my main portfolio, the long -term portfolio went a little better
Around 39-40 % so it is probably the one that makes up a larger part of my total investment portfolio on Avanza
And you have to be satisfied with that
I am clearly happy with that
But it is in the long run that is the most important thing.
Hope it lasts too
This was a very magnificent year
So I may be very happy that I managed to beat both the stock exchange and the incision on Avanza
If we move on to my best stock market buddies as they call it then we see then
The best stock I have to thank is sink
that went plus SEK 104,000
Mycronic of SEK 38,000
And plea of SEK 35,000
Have you seen my video about shares for beginners then it's pretty funny
Because we have a pinned comment there
I have promised to keep Plejd for as long as I have patience to so we will see
But the losers then as I talked about in my loss video so we have besqab
that is the loser I chose to sell off
There I went minus - SEK 30,000 on
Castellum actually went down - SEK 2,500
And then we have Realty Income Corp
We move on
In this monthly overview, we see that November went best at plus SEK 93000
And in March I sat.
on the hands and it was very hard psychologically but there you have learned something
Minus 57000 SEK I went there
And then we have these days that I think is quite interesting
And then you see March 12th
Then I was minus - SEK 34000
In a day!
It stings pretty much when you look at it
Then you have days like
April 23 plus 25000 kr
And November we have two days one at SEK 17,000 and a plus SEK 19,000
If you look at the overview shown here you see that it is Sweden that my majority of shares lie in
And then it is in the funds that I get a little more spread over the US and China
But I prefer to stay in the Swedish market, because I have the best control there now.
But I am thinking about widening a little more globally in the future.
So a total summation here now over the portfolio and it is then 2020 38 % as I said
Plus 213 000 SEK
Best month was November and the best stock was sink
I am glad that I kept and that I
Are still holding
We must see how long lasts in it
But yes it will be fun to see how 2021 degenerates
And i would very much like to know how it went for you
So please comment below how much you earned or how much your portfolio went up or down
And keep in mind that what I invest in should not see as any advice or recommendations
But it is
Entirely my decisions
You should take responsibility for your particular purchase
It is you who has to do your own research
Before you choose to buy anything
Does not trust others
And yes I look sickly positive in the coming year and I think we are celebrating
Just this one
Special
The special year with a small soda I actually think
I wish you a good continuation and hope it gets
A fantastic 2021
Have it so good