Hello you!
Today, we will talk about funds.
We were going to take up this struggle between active funds
and passive funds.
Which fund should you choose for your savings?
I have taken help from a guest who knows this with
funds and we will leg out the question so you find out
What to choose for your savings
And if you didn't know it, I'm called.
Marcus Lindblad and I operate Save Cash and Save
Cash is for those who want to learn to save in shares
funds and much more so that we will go through it
is what is an active fund?
What is a passive index fund?
Who has gone best and which ones should you save?
Then we have with us Johanna here who is a guest and we are going to
Talk about active and passive index funds.
But can't you introduce yourself a little bit so that
Viewers get to know who you are?
Big, thank you for being here on your channel and talking about funds.
I work then as saved on them at the fund companies'
association and it is an industry organization that completely
Simple seems for.
Sound fund industry in the savers' interest and my role as
Savings is that
Inform and train consumers about funds and fund savings.
And I do this by blogging, lecturing and so I try
to present
Interesting facts about precisely savings and funds in so
Many different channels as I can.
But Johanna, if you explain just a little
Shortly like this, what is an active equity fund?
An active equity fund is a fund where trustee,
The trustee or the trustee is active in.
The selection of which shares should be included in the fund,
so it is simply so that
the managers they do their analyzes and they investigate which
Companies that they believe most in and which they believe have the best
potential to get a high return in the future.
And these are the ones they choose to include in the fund.
If we only take one example then we can say that it is a technology fund
which is actively managed.
Then the trustee will try to find the technology companies that they
Believe mostly and take them into the portfolio.
Sometimes maybe even go and meet the companies for
to understand the business.
They talk to the lead.
Yes they are simply active in the selection of these funds
and an active fund usually costs, but not always
more than one index fund because the trustees and they must
The get paid for this work as they do.
But it is also the active funds that can give it as
called over returns and that means that the fund
develops better than the comparison index like the fund here.
This means that active funds.
They may be worth a higher price if one finds a good
Manager who delivers this excess return
and the other fund types
index fund that instead follows an index
And then you might wonder, says, what is an index?
Well there is something that shows
Value development time for a compound number of shares
over a specific period of time.
And one thing I really want to point out.
Medius index management
An index fund does not automatically mean that one has a
lower risk, without
There are indexes that have a high risk and so are there
Index that has a lower risk.
Everything depends on
which index that the fund chooses to follow because there is
how many different indexes and since then that this fund
chooses to follow an index and do not make any active choices
Then this management fee may also be
much lower, but that also means that
Man as a saver
shall expect a return that is
in line with the index.
And I would also like to point out that this return
as is reported
It is always reported after fees so that
You as a saver should not hold on and count someone
Fee without it is displayed by fee.
So it is that it is very easy to actually
compare how different funds have gone.
But if you are now saved and think about talking
the pretty much about passive index funds fit
the vast majority and
Some others say that active actual funds are much better
and give better returns.
What should you really choose?
I don't think there is a certain
type that is best for all savers in all types of
positions, without i think that both
active management and index management fills its
function and
When choosing which form of savings you should have so
Should you have several different factors in their decision -making process,
So you can't say that.
This particular type fits all types of savers
Then there are some shapes fits a lot of savers,
But I think man
one should include several different criteria when choosing
What fund you should have in your savings.
So if you look at statistics and data on these different funds,
What is the best?
If you look at if you should say this,
We are on the form's association for no such statistics ourselves.
But Morningstar has a one statistics bank with mass
different statistics where I found these figures
and for the category Sweden shares
so shows painable that 42 % of the active funds struck
its comparison index for one year
and for 10 years the same figure was 28 % so that
It is clear that there are active funds that succeed in beating
its comparison index over time.
But it is far from anyone who strikes the comparison index.
So for who fits an active equity fund?
Yes I think active equity funds can suit someone
which is
a little more interested in their fund savings and can think
themselves to be something more active than those who want
maybe start a monthly savings and then
forget it completely in for maybe twenty thirty years for
If you choose an active managed fund, I think it
may be good to log in sometime sometimes and and
check how this fund has developed you keep
Still with the manager
regarding the administrative philosophy or have you changed
you and have the fund performed as you thought it
would do.
O k men
Passive index funds then who will save in one.
A passive index fund it is really a very simple
Savings form that suits most and if you choose a
Index fund so you can usually be sure you don't pay
unnecessarily high fees.
But you will not receive a return that is better than
Exactly the index you have chosen to follow.
But here is also important to remember that
All index is not the same and your fund will develop
as the index you have chosen to follow.
But then I don't think that but one
Management group necessarily must fit just a certain type of
Investors without me think one can choose both
active funds and passive funds in their portfolio.
For I myself save in both active and passive funds
Maybe you think a passive fund is suitable for
a particular market
while.
One wants an actively managed fund to come
ate another type of industry.
Then I actually got some viewer questions.
First question is from Jimmy, what is the purpose of having a
Passively managed index fund?
In addition to cheaper fee.
Yes, but the purpose is that you can follow a specific index
As is the way you want the exposure
against this particular index so you don't want any others
Deviations from this index so maybe you as a saver
thinks it is unnecessary to have an actively managed fund
that makes some more active decisions if you are still just
interested in getting the particular exposure as the index
gives it.
Karlsson asks, what should a fund portfolio look like?
Yes, that is a pretty hard question actually to
Fund portfolios can look very, very different and
There is no right and wrong here.
One can have
fixed income funds, you can have hedge funds, you can have
Lots of different
kind of fund types and if one as a saver should see which
fund portfolio you should have
So I think that when you are new
As a saver should start by checking out.
What kind of risk one is looking for and from there check
which fund types to choose
and try to think about getting some diversification and
maybe start with them
slightly wider funds that most often invest in many
Thousands of companies.
Machine investment is asking is good to have only active
Funds with high risk if you save long -term?
Yeah, it's a bit tricky question because I don't think so
As mentioned, there are some right and wrong when it comes to savings.
So if you are comfortable with having taken
high risk and that you have chosen active
Funds I don't think there is any problem with it.
If you feel confident in it and you believe in your managers
so I don't see any problems with it
then and if it is in the long term as you say so can
After all, have time to make changes to this savings.
Outside, because time goes by and the conditions may
changes and and you change your philosophy,
philosophy and your savings.
Then we have a question from Adam Glimsell,
Which fund should you invest in for decent short -term savings?
Yes, that is a bit difficult with what you mean by decent
Short -term savings.
After all, there are fund types that have a lower risk.
There, the fixed income funds end up
And mixed funds fall under pure equity funds.
And there you usually like to see as guidelines on
A couple of years when talking about fixed income funds.
But there is a risk with fixed income funds as well,
So it is not risk -free to save in fixed income funds
so it all depends on what one feels that saves that you are
prepared to lose and what these money is intended to
so if you talk about in a year, would probably say that you
do not have to save in funds but then it can go well to
Insert it into a savings account.
But otherwise over which fixed income funds exist and about
you think you can get any return in this
The interest rate meeting we have.
And then it is Finance Council Barn that has asked a question
so and they ask how likely it is that one
Actively managed fund strikes index in the long term?
Yes, that is there are studies like Morningstar
have done over how
actively managed funds have gone
over time and what they have found is that it depends
pretty much on which category they have looked at,
so there seems to be some types of categories there
actively managed funds
has a little more likelihood of beating their comparison index.
But I do not have pure concrete figures on why
probability exists, without
There I think that as a saver must bring their
own thoughts about the future and
which sectors you believe in or which themes you
believe in instead of jumping on something that is
Trendy right now.
Thank you very much Johanna for wanting to join in and answer
on our questions about funds.
Big, thank you for being here with you and talking about funds.
Thank you very much Johanna, for wanting to join and
answer questions about funds and I hope you as
watching has received answers to your questions and so I hope that
See you in the next video have a good time.