Hi, tonight we stand here with Jacob, how old are you?
11 years
How old are you Mattias?
I am 13
How would you react if these guys asked you for a lighter for their cigarettes?
Excuse
Can I have a lighter?
Are you too small to get a lighter
I have morality
No, I'm 18 years old
Vaa?
You are too small, you can't keep on and smoke
Why do you smoke?
Excuse
Can I have a lighter?
How old are you?
11 or no 18
No
No but stop smoking
But why do you smoke?
He is old
It wasn't that smart
What old?
I will try to quit smoking now
You can't smoke, you will get lung cancer and look like me in a few years, it's not so fun
Villdi borrow lighter?
Can you light up?
Why?
I don't know, I want to smoke
Can you light up?
I can not
How-to?
Can you light this for me?
Huh?
How-to?
Yes
Excuse
May I have?
Do you have lighters?
Or cigarette
But you are type ten
No
Yes
Nehe, nine?
No
But shit french fries
But so sorry but you must not keep up with that
Can I have the cigar package too?
No
Well we throw the shit
Give me that one
I'll break it
Why?
You should not smoke
Ok
Can't you be silent?
Please
No God, absolutely not.
We're Schysta who don't let you smoke
Throw it there
I throw it, we throw at the same time
Ok
1, 2, 3.
Can I have a lighter for cigarette?
Sorry
Ok, no problem
Can I get a lighter for the cigarette?
Lights?
Yes, for the cigarette
Thank you
Yes
Huh?
Can you light my cigarette?
Excuse
Do you have lighters?
Thanks
But why did you want to give me a lighter?
Well but why?
in other words...
No i am minor
Why did you want to give me a lighter?
How old do you think I am?
Are you too stessed?
Huh?
Yes
Can I have a lighter for cigarette?
Excuse
Can I have a cigarette lit?
OK thanks
Can I have a lighter for cigarette?
Mm
Please
Yes
Fun
Why did you give me a lighter?
How does it counteract that I smoke?
Eh, we're in the process of filming a social experiment here
So .....
How old, how old do you think I am?
Excuse?