one of the most important
the sentences when you learn a language
Is this one
aha
is it sooo they say
I will explain why I think so
In this video and also
bring up some words that are good to be able to
When we talk about reading and listening
So then we drive
Hello Hello and welcome to Swedish with Kalle
In this movie I think
once again talk about why it is important
to listen and read a lot
and I was going to take up
a few words here that are about just this
-—-—-
hear the language a lot, read the language a lot
and see the language a lot
one might call it inflow
with a nice word it's like the language
flows in, flowing in, ie that is
you receive, what you hear, what you see
not what you produce yourself
It can be called inflow
If one wants to, flow is much like running
Often you use the English word input
instead and there is more to put in then
But that is the side of language
learning that is about that
receive the language, not to talk and write yourself
Sometimes you say that you
exposes to the language
expose
one can expose oneself to the sun
for example, that the sun is shining on a
to expose oneself to the language is
Simply to
listen and read, do different things
so that one hears the language
And read the language
and another way of saying that is to
expose oneself to the language
and it's really a little negative word
expose themselves to
But there you try to catch this particular
that it can be a bit difficult and a little hard
A little overwhelming
To hear much of a new language
or read something that is difficult too
so it is that one dares to go in
and listen and read a lot
Although it is difficult, you can say that you are exposed to
the language, this is anyway
extremely important, to get a lot
inflow
to hear a lot and see a lot
And that is also the standard tip
If someone asks, how should I learn a language
so many will say, watch TV
listen to the radio
read things to
expose yourself to the language
And this is absolutely true but
I think you can think a little about
What is it that is important
what is it you are looking for
and how to do
And then I think there are three good words here
so there are three good words but they catch too
what one wanna try to do
and the words I wrote up here were
The words note
as can also be said
with the expression notify
notify and it is simply to see
To focus on
So when you listen you note
or notice important things
It may be words that are new to you
Then you think aha, that word, it was important
I want to be able to, then you note that word
and then you can also say that you are
attentive to important words
you are attentive to or
You pay attention
So it's simply about concentration
and focus, and that not only
read and listen without concentrating
Without noting
to notice
to be attentive to
that's what you are going to do when you
actively trying to improve your language
By reading and listening
and that's where I come to this phrase then
as i think .... or so i think in all fals, that's my own phrase
But I often think if I read in English
that is my best second language
So I read a book or I watch a series
And then just: "Aha, that's how you say"
is that as they express it
Is there the way there is the expression?
so that one notes how
a writer or a person
in a television program
actually talk
and you can say a lot about this
by translating to learn
But of course one must translate
and one has to ask
How do I say this in Swedish
We can discuss that more in another video
for it is important to translate and of course
translates and looking for,
so to say one starts in one's own language
This expression is in my language
How do I say it in Swedish
But I think many
translates too much and focuses
too much on it, instead of making sure that
Get a lot, a lot of inflow
so that they learn the language from the fact that
actually hear it and read it
by people who are good
In Swedish because then it becomes more
yeah, is that how you say that
If you understand what you read
If you understand what you hear, then you can pick the important
the expressions directly from the Swedish instead
To try to take something in your own language
and find it in Swedish
-—-—-
and this is at least as important
like translating, if I say so then
because
Can't learn a language
Without getting much exposure
much inflow, much input
to expose oneself to the language, because you have to hear
How those who speak Swedish and write Swedish
In fact, expresses themselves
This is where you find the natural language
The genuine language
And it is then different then then
If you read academic text you will find that language
Do you listen to a hip hop song
so you find another language but that is there
You will find the Swedish
and be aware of how
the one you read or listen to
actually expresses themselves and especially then
Focus on such things as you need
so that when you read a text
And then you see an expression that you understand
And then you think, aha, that's how the Swedes say
When they are surprised,
is that how the Swedes say when they want to express something polite
is that so a Swede expresses himself
When he or she is angry or cursed
and take those expressions step by step
either just note them a little
So that you stop a little, aha ...
or maybe write down
one cannot write everything
one can write down the most important
But you can still stop yourself, instead of just reading on
and think, okay
there was an important expression
So you say, so you express yourself
-—-—-
my feeling as a sfile teacher
is that many miss this
I give a lot of texts and input
But when a person is to write, then the phone goes
and the lexicon and Google forward
and then one begins to try to translate instead of
Remove that layer, of the storage room
of phrases and words one has received
from textbooks, texts we read
otherwise one has exposed to
exposed to
So I think you build up your storage room of words
and phrases and expressions
By collecting things from
your inflow, from what you hear
and what you read
So if you want to be good in Swedish
and don't read and listen a lot
Then you have to get in a way to start doing
You can't learn Swedish
just by talking a little bit at school
and listen to your teacher
you need a massive, a large
a large amount of Swedish in your life
every day
It is the only chance to become good at the language
I think
So do you want tips and help with it
So maybe we can discuss it
people usually ask about movies sometimes
I don't watch so much at Swedish film so I'm not so good at tips about that
But as I said, the most important thing is to find something
that you think is fun to
listen to and read and that are
on an okay level, it must not be too hard
Because then you lose motivation
-—-—-
so think about this
How can you increase the inflow of Swedish so that you get
More experiences of
aha, is that the way they say
is that the way they write
There you have a huge key
to learn Swedish
And get better
Okay, that was
ask, comment, discuss
and have a great day
So we will be heard and see you again soon;
Hello Hello