Hello
Today I was going to talk about the word
repertoire
and how it can help us think
around learning language
Both about vocabulary
and about the social function of language
to get in touch, to get to know people
to talk to different people
So repertoire, how to explain it?
Well a good example of repertoire
It's a musician
A musician can have a wide repertoire
This means that person can play
Many different pieces of music
or many different styles of music
Then that person has a wide repertoire
A large repertoire
If you have a narrow repertoire, then you can only play a few
pieces, not so many
or maybe just a special style
You are not so flexible, you don't have that many.
different ways of doing something
So you can think about that
in language too, that you have a broad repertoire
you know many different words and you can talk in
Many different situations
You can cope with many different contexts
Then you have a wide repertoire linguistically
If you have a narrower repertoire then maybe you
Customers certain types of calls
but not so many others
my
Teacher buddy Maria Fredriksson
usually talk about having a closet
so her comparison is a closet
where you want many different types of clothing
For many different contexts
party clothes, musk clothes, workout clothes
perhaps
tough clothes for a special party
and so on, you want clothes that fit
In many different situations
It's about the same thought, you have a wide
repertoire of clothing
We can think of repertoire
In connection with vocabulary
that I want a wide repertoire
of words so I can talk
For example in formal contexts
in informal contexts
that I have words that fit at the coffee table
at work, that I have words that fit
When I study Swedish in school and so on
It can be about both understanding formal words,
everyday words and hose for example
so there is clear and obvious
that we need a wide repertoire
of different words
But I also think we can
Talk about a social repertoire
and it is more about a broader social
competence
and that we can be socially competent
In a situation but less socially competent
in other situations
So for example
for my own part if I go to a concert
So I know how to behave and I talk to people
and I talk to people so I have easy knowing what to talk about
I go on a football match so I know
not what
I'll do there, how it works
And I'm not sure about how to talk about football
with people because it's nothing I
Can be especially good
and I think that this is the case that
master different types of situations social
becomes a much larger
challenge when learning a new language and it becomes
an even greater challenge if you also
comes from a culture that does not resemble the Swedish
so this is something you need
think about and I think there is
two slightly different situations
that you need to think about
And work out
One is when a social
Context in Sweden
similar to something you recognize
from your native language and your home culture
Take for example if you usually go to church
In your home country and so you want to go to church in Sweden
Then maybe many things are about the same
But you still need to learn
a little cultural things and also a lot of language
So how do you say different
phrases and sentences
and what are different things in a church are called
This you need to learn in Swedish but it is a bit more like a
translation, you can compare
the Swedish context with something
that is familiar from your home country
But something else is.
that in Sweden you will meet at
different social situations and different
Types of calls that you can't at all
relate to something
In your home culture or in your mother tongue
It can be anything from culture
to society, to politics, to only
special places you meet at
or special ways one was hanging out on
And then it is a bigger challenge for then
Do you need to understand
this social situation
What do Swedes usually talk about
by the afternoon coffee
which subjects fit to take up
How can I take them up
What subjects do you usually talk about
do I need to get a certain cultural
general education to cope with
with this group
in this context
and
Here it will be a matter of
what contexts you are in
where you are, what people you meet
and what people you want to meet and want to get to know
for it is clear that
If you want to blend in and be able to participate
active in a social context
Then you need to start getting those tools
that makes
you can be involved at real
And it's very much about language then
And to know both words and concepts.
and
Ordinary sentences
but also know different references
that are common in that group
whatever it may be, it may be about
football or it may be about
film or it may be about politics
It all depends on
But when I listen to
calls in different groups
In Sweden I hear all the time
How different references
to culture and sports and society and so on
It is part of the social interaction
and do you want a wide repertoire
In Swedish, ie a social
Swedish, a broad social repertoire
In Swedish, then you need to start getting yourself
This type of social general education also because
Don't always have to ask: What is it?
I have never heard;
I don't know that
or to become silent because there is
too many things that are new to you
This is a long process of course
But if one is aware of it
so can you start working on it
and just this that
see it as to
There are so many different contexts
and groups and different people
where different linguistic requirements are set
It's not the same language
and it's not the same reference world
In all these different contexts
This can of course be felt
null
A little overwhelming
a bit much
But we need too
be honest with the challenge as a person
is facing if one is to
learn to interact with people
In a country on their native language
not on the same terms
But on a little more equal terms
so anything we can think of
perhaps discuss more, that is
What strategies can you have, when we now have this map
I need a broad social repertoire if I want
function in many different contexts
It is very difficult at the beginning of a new language
so there are strategies we can use
during the trip
In the process to do well
Before we, so to speak, have
provided us this wide repertoire
It's a question to you, it's a question to me
It is a question we can discuss and return to
In a later movie
null
I thank me for so long, hope that this movie
gave some new thoughts, commenting giant
come with your input, your reflections
and so we'll see you again soon
have it so good, hello hey