Hey my friends!
How is it?
Is it good?
Today we will study verbs.
I put.
I'm placing.
We use them when something moves.
a movement
Someone does something.
They describe an active movement.
The coffee cup table
I put the coffee cup on the table.
I make an active movement.
I stand.
I sit down.
milk
I put the milk in the refrigerator.
The flower shelf
I put the flower on the shelf.
I put the book on the table.
basket apple
I put the apple in the basket.
Many apples
The basket is full.
It is heavy too.
bag keys
I put the keys in the bag.
I lie down on the couch.
I sit down on the chair.
key
I put the key in the lock.
I lock the door.
I put the child in the car.
a child
Sit down!
I put the child in the car.
She sits in the car.
I sit in the car.
an onion
I put the onion in the bag.
a basket
I put the cheese in the basket.
The cheese is located in the basket.
I put the goods on the cashband.
He puts the goods in the bag.