Hello
Hope you've had a great weekend
And here's a little tip
On how you can work out
And repeat
In a simple but very good way
and that is to
Teach out something you can
to a friend
or
Repeat something
As you have just learned
by
Explain the same thing to a friend
It may be in school
or it might be in your family
It can be anyone
who also trains Swedish
so
One way is to
If you study Swedish together with a friend
So you can
decide that you are looking at each one
So different
Movies
about anything on youtube
For example, it may be
Someone who explains something about Swedish grammar
So you are watching two movies, two different movies
and maybe notes, writes a little
Then you will explain to each other
You should explain what your movie is all about
And this is a great way to ...
Then you must first
strain yourself and be sure
that you understand
what is the movie about
and then
So when you explain to your buddy
so it becomes both to
You repeat
and you have to think about and make it clear to yourself
what it was the movie was about
what it was you just learned
Of course it works just as well if
you go to a lesson at school
But your buddy is not there
So take ten, fifteen minutes
next time you meet
and explain
the most important thing from the lesson or
just choose one thing
Choose a few words, choose some grammar
and show, explain, tell
It can also just be words
You can decide to learn
Ten new words
within a particular area
If a particular subject
and then you teach your friend these words
Then it will also be easier for you to remember them.
and use the words
so...
Learn each other!
Help each other!
and
so you at the same time help yourself
It's Sunday's tips
And I hope you have a good week
and trains a lot of Swedish
Have a good one!
Bye.