Hello Hello
I was going to keep talking a little about
how to improve one's writing
and in the last movie I did about it
So I talked a little more big about that
Writing is about thinking
and discuss, both discuss with
self and discuss with others so
To write better so you need to be curious
on the world and so to speak
develop your thinking too, not
Just your language
In this movie I will try to go into a little more on
The language part then
If one thinks of yourself
the language you need to
able to express your thoughts in a good way
And then I don't think exactly
on grammar and order and such things
Without liters more how
one should find and learn
a language that one can use when one
Writes
and
A good goal
a simple and good goal to have
When writing a text, it is to
The one who reads the text should not
at all need to think or be
unsure what you mean
so especially if you write any type
by investigative or debate
or accounting
text and so on
informative text in the school, ie one such
academic or formal text
Then I think a good goal is
that the reader should have as easily as possible
To understand your thought
And it is not always easy to write
so that it is completely
clearly what one means
okay and how to then
get better at this to express their thoughts
Well you need exactly
right word
one needs many different words
and expressions of expressing one's
thought exactly
So then you need to learn it
null
And then I think the best way
To do that is to read articles
and texts and books so we'll be right away
back to this with the reading then but
One thing I want to warn a little about
that is to believe that you can translate
from your language directly to Swedish
my feeling when I read people who are on a little
higher level, perhaps the last course on
sfi, sfi d, or on the
Next primary and high school courses
a problem that I think I see quite
Often, it is that, it looks like
Person has translated expression from their own language
to Swedish
I'm not sure, but I believe that sometimes anyway
And it will be
quite often a little wrong or sounds a bit
weird, it might be the right grammar sometimes
But it won't be
correct expression in Swedish
So that's why I would say that
Don't trust that much
that method of taking
expression and words that you can in your language
and translate them with a lexicon or with
as well as that you can translate it yourself
Don't be sure it gets right
Without then I think the reading
is a better method
Please tell me if I'm wrong, I don't know, I've never learned this
self on such a high level in another language
so i guess a little here, but i think
to find all these words
and the expressions that you need
So I think it's better to look for
them in real texts on .svenska
And it's easy to say
Read more, read more
I will talk about this in at least one movie to
But then my suggestion then, if we think this is that
The goal is for it to be easy and clear
and you should find (so to speak) common expressions
as Swedes and people who are
Good in Swedish uses when writing texts
Then there are two things you can
Start looking * with * (after)
and there are different expressions and words
that tells you what time
and which place something happens at
For remember, it should be as easy as possible
For those who read that
follow
and then the person must understand which
are which places are you talking about
and how is the face of
those places to each other
We must understand if it is
two places that are close to each other or
far away from each other, in the same country or
in completely different places, if they are
equal or different and so on
And then if you read, for example, articles
In the news or factual texts
or texts in a textbook you have
so can you start looking at how
writes the writer about location
and think like this: what words and which
Expressions I can use, so I just
thought a little bit here
that you may need to say things like
closely and near
And far away
in the centre of
Sweden or in the center of Stade
in the outskirts of
or outside
by the coast, in the middle of the country
at the same place or
In another place
So, this be just examples but
I think that if you start gathering these pretty
ease the expressions, in a way
But it is difficult because there are so many
and you want to use the correct situation
And the same is with time, we want to understand
If two things happen at the same time
or if one happens before
or after
so you need expressions as
at the same time
during that period
that year
next year
soon after
A few weeks earlier
that said, these are just examples like me
thought about when I prepared this one
the movie, but I think that if you read
texts so these are two things you can think about
and when you feel this I can use
write it down then
so that you collect small pieces
small phrases, small sentences
and trying to think about
How the writer uses it
exactly what thought uses the one that has
written the text to
Explain, to tell,
In order to show one's thought
and the more such expressions you have
The more you can try using them
and then you can get feedback from a teacher
or someone who reads your texts that “I understand”
"I don't understand" "this expression
Fits well here ”
"This expression is a bit wrong"
But as I said, I guess
that if you pick your expressions
from real Swedish texts and then attempts
use them
so is there more chance that you
Finds common expressions
that fits well than if you try
translate from your language
If you have experience with this, if you have learned
to be better at writing so you are happy to get
say
Am I right here?
or am I wrong?
What do you think?
And how have you been doing?
Anyway I am
Absolutely sure that if you read more
so will you develop your language
and if you read and think about what you read
And chases
what you need to be able to express
More in Swedish
so your reading will become more
effective than if you only read passively
And the tip for this video then is to read
think about what you are reading
and look at how writers
expresses place
Explains place and how the writer
Explains and shows and
describes time
so can we get back to other things that are also
important to be able to express in another video.
Okay, I'll stop there and
Hope there was something here that you were in advance of
As you thought to
That should I think about
Please write a comment
And please press your thumbs up if you liked the video
and thumbs down if you didn't like it
and as I said please discuss
with me if you got any thoughts of this video
It is of course texted so you have not seen
the video with text so you can turn on the text in
the settings
And so I hope I can put up talk
about this by developing their writing
pretty soon again, in a new movie
Have a good time so long.
Bye.