Hello
I was going to talk a little about
how to learn and
Exercise on prepositions
Pretty many ask about prepositions
in Swedish
and thinks it's hard
so my first tip
And the most important thing I think is to
Learn prepositions
in ordinary phrases
So I think it's
wasted time, I don't think you win on
to try to learn some kind of rules
For all the rules have exceptions
and there are none
Clear rules for how prepositions
will be used
in different types of sentences and phrases
There are no determined rules
For how prepositions are to be used
they do not have such a definite meaning
so start step by step to
learn them in regular phrases
As you often need
so it can be good to start with
stuff you might say quite often
As I study at SFI
or I am studying at
high school, I go to the movies
I am going to party, I go
on the toilet
Pretty common sentences so you learn
on along with those words, but maybe then
I'm in the shop, I'm
in the center, i'm
in school
and so on, at the dentist
at the doctor
so start with the most common
that you can use frequently
null
And as I already did a little now
that you might also be able to take them and like
take a few ordinary words
As you want to be able to use with the correct preposition
and so put them in groups
So for example: in town,
at party, at the cinema
You may be able to remember some such common ones together
and then you can take some
in Gothenburg
in the center
in, whatever it may be,
in the shopping center
But it is mostly if it helps you
to find, as well as taking some small groups,
take a few words and learn together
null
yes
And what would I say more, yes
My feeling is that
make some wrong with prepositions
or make pretty big errors with prepositions
is not such a big problem in many contexts
Many times so
so do not do that much because the prepositions
not have such a clear, determined
meaning, so it won't be so dangerous either
When doing wrong
and because there is
a lot of different words and sentences
that you should use together with prepositions
so it is very difficult to get it right all the time
so my tip is to stress not
with it without attempt to think
What are the most common?
Which do I want to use
very
and learn them first and then
Step by step teaches you more and more phrases
and sentences with the correct prepositions
and don't be like that
worried that it gets wrong sometimes because
We still understand
and i have friends who have learned
Swedish as always makes some mistakes
But it doesn't matter that much, of course, it doesn't sound
Perfect but it is not difficult to understand either
What the person means
null
and then
Exercise by listening, exercising by reading
If you think about this movie
thinking about this movie
There you had a preposition
so i use a bunch of prepositions
All the time in many of my sentences
So when you listen
on when people talk, when you read
so be a little attentive
and think about the prepositions and sometimes you can stay up
especially when the usual words
and sentences that feel that, this is important
stop, think a little to
aha, now he used this one
preposition
null
Then, as well as, can
the most common, I can think so that it is
Common errors are that you say this:
I talk *to, but that sounds weird
man say i talk to
But if you listen to
People talking, so you will hear quite often
I was talking to Kalle
I talked to Johan
And if you are just ...
Like ... focus a little on it when you hear it;
so will it get stuck by itself
so
Pay attention to prepositions as you read
And when you listen, you will automatically
repeat the most common
for you will see and hear them often
Yes
so learn common phrases
Maybe way
those in groups if it helps you
to remember, some common examples with on
some common examples with in
maybe some common examples with by and for
and don't worry so much
Don't stress because it gets wrong with prepositions
and four: Repeat when you listen
Repeat as you read
Then you come
so to say being safer over time
just have patience so it will be fine
That was my tip about prepositions
Feel free to ask, please discuss, please comment
Please read my blog, please check out
My second channel
with different films about different subjects
You can listen to which prepositions I
using in those movies
In those films
in
I should also remind you that
Feel free to press that little bell
next to the subscribe button if you want
have notifications, if you want to be reminded of
when i post a new movie because if you don't
pressing on the bell so you will not
Get a message every time I post a new movie
So please do it and
yes
Thanks for this time, we will soon hear again
bye
Read www.svenskamedkalle.com
Read www.svemusik.wordpress.com
Svenskamedkalle on Instagram
Swedish with Kalle on Facebook