blueberry
There is a lot of blueberries in the forest.
Very blueberries
the forest
in the forest
Hello everyone!
Hello!
I'm in the forest.
in the forest
I pick berries.
a berry - many berries
I pick blueberries.
Look!
Many many blueberries
blueberry
They are very good.
Blueberries are good.
I pick berries with a berry picker.
It's a berry picker.
What do you do?
We pick berries.
Which ones wear?
Blueberry.
Do you like blueberries?
Yes...
Yeah !!!
null
What are you doing?
I pick blueberries.
Do you like blueberries?
Yes, I like them very much.
Look, what a lot of blueberries it became!
null
Where is the car?
Should we go there?
Or there?
There is the car!
!
At home I clean all the berries.
I clean them.
null
Now they are cleared.
The berries are cleared.
I have cleared them.
I usually bake a blueberry pie.
a pie
IM baking.
I bake a pie.
Now it's done.
I like blueberry pie.
Everyone in the family likes blueberry pie.
I usually freeze all berries.
So we have frozen berries all year.
Fall Winter
Our summer
We can bake many pies!