Hello everyone!
Hello!
Look what the weather!
Great!
It's fantastic weather today!
A real winter!
It's snowing.
It's not cold.
It's so wonderful!
I want to tell you about Hu we throw our garbage - sort.
We live in a chain house.
We have two garbage cans.
A garbage can is for ...
What a nice snow!
We can look together.
coloured glass
food waste
Residual waste
newspapers and recycled paper
It is a lot of residual waste and food waste.
But not so much colored glass.
And no newspapers
They are empty.
This is how it is:
This garbage can be emptied every two weeks.
Once every two weeks
Today we received a message.
We have an app on the phone.
We have received a message that we must exhibit garbage cans 1 for emptying.
The emptying is tomorrow.
The garbage truck will come tomorrow and then they will empty the garbage can.
The garbage can be emptied by the garbage truck.
The garbage truck should empty the garbage can.
We look what is here.
Here it is plastic packaging.
paper packaging
unpainted glass, only bottles and jars
There are a few pieces there.
Metal packaging
It's Monday, January 11th.
The garbage truck is coming.
They should pick up the garbage.
Look yourself!
Thank you so much for watching!
See you in the next video!
Bye!