Good morning.
It is half past seven in the morning and I woke up to go to the bathroom.
But check, I don't want to go back.
I don't want to sleep again.
I don't want to fall asleep.
I can not.
Now I'm going to take a walk instead.
It doesn't blow.
It is completely still.
The sun is shining, it's hot.
Everyone is asleep.
Only me is awake throughout the campsite.
We take a walk together.
One has woken up and will walk with his dog.
She should rest the dog.
We are two who are awake.
There is a flagpole, two flagpoles and you can see that the flags are completely still.
It doesn't blow at all.
The campsite is called Herta Camping.
You can look at the map on Gotland, where it is located.
Drive slowly.
Look what amazing flowers.
Giant.
Superfine on both sides.
Here is my shadow.
There is the sea.
The campsite is very close to the beach.
Check this out.
It's a cows.
Several cows.
A kiss.
Several kisses.
What do they do?
That kiss is itching.
It scratches the forehead.
Those stand and eat something.
Completely still.
This road is a dirt road.
I walk on the dirt road.
Over there is the sea.
The sea is also completely still because it does not blow.
So this is a pasture.
A cowhage for cows.
And this is a horse pasture.
A cowhage and a horse pasture.
This horse stands and eats.
It is said that the horse grazes.
And that horse is sleeping.
It looks like that.
We continue forward to the beach.
Just on the beach there are some houses.
These houses are very small.
A small house.
Many small houses.
They are not real.
I think it's cottages.
Or so before, people lived in slightly smaller houses.
I can reach the ceiling.
An old bench.
On that bench you dare not sit.
It is very old and route.
Do you see?
But it stands here.
It is so pretty.
Check.
It is certainly from the mid-20th century.
Just look.
Absolutely wonderful.
There are many good places on Gotland safely.
But this place is definitely not the last.
Wow.
It's just wow.
I am completely fascinated.
Check out these.
In many places you build like this.
So here find these flat stones.
For example, a bench and a table.
A sofa and a coffee table.
Here they have made a bench.
I think they built these houses in the same way as well.
Flat stones and then sprinkled with concrete or cement.
Or I don't know.
With something.
Today is Saturday and I will have live on Youtube.
But today I will have live at 11am until 12 o'clock.
Otherwise it will be too stressful in the morning.
It takes about an hour from Herta Camping from this place to Visby.
So if I start at 10 o'clock then we have to leave home type quarter to nine.
It's a little too early I can say.
So just today 11 to 12. I know what to do.
I'll do my morning gymnastics here on the beach.
You can look a little if you want.
Now I have done my morning gymnastics.
Now I can dip my feet a little neighbor.
Dip feet.
I feel the water.
The water is actually quite cold today.
Yesterday the water was not so cold.
I thought the water was totally okay yesterday.
I didn't bathe.
It was late at night.
But I thought it was totally okay.
But now I think the water is cold.
There may be a difference in the morning and evening.
I do not know.
We'll see.
We are eating breakfast.
Our neighbors cycle to the next stop.
To the next campsite.
They cycle throughout Gotland.
Now we are in Visby and I am starting to live.
The clock rings and I end the lives.
Today we are in Visby.
Day two in Visby.
This is Stora Torget.
Stora Torget.
Here is trade.
You can shop, buy jewelry, clothes.
There is a church ruin.
And throughout Visby, here inside the walls, there are many cafes and restaurants and right now there are many tourists here.
Many, many tourists who come from Sweden, from the mainland but also from other countries.
Santa Karin's church.
An old church from the end of the 17th century.
Check this out.
We have looked at this church.
What is this?
This is ivy that is growing.
There are many different plants here in Visby.
Plants that grow on the walls.
That climbs on the walls.
Here is a small scene.
You can do different events.
Old stones.
And here there is also the roof left.
The roof is made of small, small stones.
A sheep.
So there are large stone sheep in the square and everywhere.
In Stockholm it is lion and on Gotland it is sheep.
There is a wall around Visbystaden.
This is a wall.
This is a tower.
This is a gate.
The wall goes around Visby.
You can walk here.
Inside the wall is the old town.
Outside the wall, it is the new city maybe.
Look, there are these here.
I don't know what it is.
Here there are bikes.
They park their bikes.
And on the walls there are plants.
So this is growing.
I do not know how.
How does it grow?
We want to go this train.
Blue-yellow train.
Guided city tour.
Children, 3 to 10 years, SEK 50.
Adults, SEK 100.
Tickets are solved on the train.
See the clock.
Departures.
This watch.
What time is it?
At one o'clock maybe.
Here they hand out free 7UP.
Thanks so much.
Now we have sat on the train but we are sitting back and forth.
So we're going to go with our backs.
I have an ice cream.
We take a train.
We look at Visby, at the wall, the ring wall and listen to the guide.
It speaks Swedish in speakers.
These are speakers, so we listen to the guide.
For us, the trip with this train cost SEK 400.
Two children's tickets.
We paid for two children's tickets for the girls.
A children's ticket costs SEK 50 and three adults.
Then it will be SEK 400.
Then we met our friends there and walked with them for the rest of the day.
So all Saturday we were in Visby.
It was a pink party on the beach.
Everyone wore pink clothes.
They danced and they had fun.
Now it is evening and we will go home and lie down and sleep.
Thank you so much for watching.
Tomorrow it will be day three.
Do not miss it.
Bye!