Hello Hello
Hope you have a good Sunday
and I was going to keep talking a little
about writing and how you can think
about writing, how you can develop
your writing
how you can practice writing and what you
need to get better at
and what you need to exercise
And last
The time I talked a little about
this with that or
My tip can be said to be that
preferably do not translate from your own language
but it is better
to look for expressions in
Swedish texts that you read
so that you are looking
by expression you need
In order to express you
in Swedish texts
And my example in the last movie was place after all
and time, so I said it is important
to be able to explain or show
in a clear way was
something happens and when
something happens and to do it in a good way
so do you need a lot of words and expressions
and I believe the best way to
learn those expressions are to
simply read texts and
note
When you find good things
that you can use
You can't learn everything
you can't write down or memorize everything
but you can step by step collect
on you a toolbox of expression
that makes you can
Write and express yourself better
And I also believe that
that is good and try
get a sense of how they
Here the expressions are used
as well as when fits them
What feeling is in them, there is, for example
Some expressions like
signaling that you are
very sure what you say, or are there some
expression that signals that you believe something
But are not safe and so on
In all such words and expressions there are also
a kind of feeling or
degrees of
whether something is likely or secure
There are also different degrees of formality
how officially or how relaxed something is
and by reading texts and
thought a little bit on this so you can develop your
feeling for
which
words and expressions that fit in which
situation and in what type of text
All these things are very important we can talk a lot about it
but
I'm not afraid to repeat and repeat a little
so this is such a thing
that is important to consider
In what context do you write?
who are you writing to?
It affects
what words and expressions that fit
And last time I talked about time and place
Now I was going to talk about some others
things, some other aspects
as one can think of
and I believe just when you think about
to learn language and develop one's language
that it is very easy to think a lot about grammar
and grammar is important but
that i talked about last time
that had with space and time to do
I would rather call that rather
feature
and by function I mean: what do you want to express
What do you want to say, what do you want
do with the language?
and I think one should not get stuck in that
think of the language that just grammar
Without I think you should go ahead and
back between the level function and
the level grammar and they are interconnected
with each other too but
If you know that
you want to express time in a better way
Then you can find the different expressions
you need to express time
and
Then you have to master the grammar
for those expressions, there may be a little difference
on if using the expression in the present or past
It is difference if you use the expression in
plural or singular
and so on
But you can't become
better at writing just by beating up
Let's say one
table with adjectives and so learn
good, better, best - bad, worse, worst
It's like a good start
or part of what it is to know a language
But then you need to know how
you should use these parts
and how you use expressions and how you use words
it's often
several words together, it is quite rarely
As you can do by just keeping track
on a bunch of words alone
You have to know what other words they fit together
with and how those words
in group, in combination
What they mean then, the words, this is very important
and
It is a good thing to carry with you when exercising
language that one is not just getting stuck in
Words and lonely
word grammar without one must also understand
word in a context
Words are often included in some expressions
and then they mean a special thing
and they together in other words
so can they mean something completely different
And as I said, here I think reading is a big key
to this because then you see how the words are used
How does authors use
Words when writing, very important points
Except for location and time then
so can you say a lot of others
things that one needs to be able to do
As one wishes to be able to do
and I brought up three things here that I was going to give
Examples of, and this are just examples
It is like small tips on what you want to be able to do
and what you can look for with some
examples of words and expressions
so one thing you need to be able to do while writing is that is to compare
And value
so
For example, do you want to be able to say is something equal
or not alike
and i wrote up some expressions here, you can say
similarly blah blah blah blah
Or, however, ....
So something is not the same
you also need to be able to value
And say for example "in the first place ...."
null
So to show that this is important
or
"It's not as important that ...."
and so whatever it is for topic you are talking about
You may also need to explain if anything is
likely or not likely
So for example, you can write "Probably ..."
or the opposite "it is not likely to ..."
and you need to gather many of these
Express then that allows you to
compare things that are equal and different
evaluate what is important and not so important
and what is likely and what is not likely
And how can you say it in different ways in Swedish
Then I wrote causal relationships
in other words
cause and effect
Why does something happen
What makes something else happen
Then, for example, one can say
"due
so this happened '
or "as a result of ...
A so B 'happened
as a result of
or "These events are related to ..."
and so do you explain what they are up to
or
“The change
was made possible by .... "
bla bla bla
So this can be said, it's about cause
and the effect and what words and expressions you can
use to describe and tell
about it
Then I wrote logical relationships
logical relationships
logic is more about thinking
If you agree with me about 1
So you have to agree with me about 2 too
The two are logically interconnected
And this is important, for example
in debating and argumentative texts where you want to say
To the one who reads your text that ....
you have to agree with me about this
do you do that then you have to agree with me too
If this because they are logically interconnected
and i have three examples here, you can say
"of this follows"
So you present an argument first
and then you say “of this argument
follows
that something else is true too
or you can say like this
“If this is true
so this must be true too
or “an consequence
of this argument
is
that ..... "
Just that, I had one more here
A pretty good "conclusion will be ...."
“The conclusion is that
we have to
give more money to school ”for example
so that you have your arguments: 1, 2, 3
how many arguments you now have and then you say that
the conclusion is
Or my conclusion is that ....
so all this I gave examples of now is
Features, so it is "I want to do this"
In my text
What words and expressions can I use
To do it and then the question comes
How exactly does the grammar work
For this term, just one example
The last thing I said there: The conclusion will be ....
the conclusion - determined form but
My final
yeah when you have mine you say conclusion in indefinite
form so that ... it's such a thing
is important if you want grammar to be perfect
But first you have to know that
you want to tell us about a conclusion, these are the ones you want
do
since the grammar is this
it is the more the last finish to
The reader will surely understand
And that it should be neat and right and good:
null
right
so
my tip, my homework now is that
Take a text
look at it
how do
the writer different things in that text
How does the author "place" explain?
How does the writer explain time?
How does the author show
What he or she thinks is important
How compare
the writer different things and
How to explain the author
Causal relationships, why
something happens and how explains the writer
logical relationships
So how different things are interconnected
When we think about arguments and
conclusions
null
comment!
Ask, please like if you like the video
and maybe give examples
If you give up and are looking for expression
Can you write examples in a comment
orf ask me if there is something you think seems interesting
that you don't really understand
It will also be a tip for others who read the comments.
Keep in mind that Youtube is also a social media
If you comment then others may
Get help from your questions and your comments.
and we'll see you again soon
Have a good time so long and a good start on next week
If you looked at this now on Sunday
Bye!