It is Saturday.
It's the weekend.
I'm free today.
I am eating breakfast.
I drink coffee and eat a sandwich.
I like coffee.
I enjoy drinking coffee in the morning.
Today I have to wash clothes.
I wash clothes in a washing machine.
I have a washing machine and a dryer.
I'm washing clothes.
The laundry is wet.
I hang up the laundry for it to dry.
clothes
I'm ironing clothes.
a flower a flower
Several flowers
Flowers need water.
I water my flowers.
I water the flowers.
I am cooking.
I cook in the kitchen.
I am cleaning.
I'm vacuuming the floor.
My son does homework.
He does his homework.
I help him with the homework.
I help.
I'll help you with the homework.
What a boring weekend!
A boring weekend
I ate breakfast.
I drank coffee.
I washed clothes.
I stroked clothes.
I watered flowers.
I cleaned.
I cooked.
I helped my son with the homework.
Now I'm tired.
Now I'll go to sleep.
I hope next weekend will be a fun weekend.