We will listen to a nice melody from 1944.
Who sings?
Enter the first name, four letters, in vertical two.
- But what nice!
- Sssch!
Ulla Billquist!
- Have you already set breakfast?
- Is something better than Saturday mornings?
The melody cruise, peace and quiet and not a child in sight.
- Gustav, tonight ... - fix!
I have grinded the skates.
Can't we go tomorrow?
We will be visited tonight.
Mom and dad.
They are going to Åke and Margit and need to sleep over.
You know what it is about.
You know exactly!
See you on Monday.
Does it carry off now?
Thanks for these years!
- Dad has to travel away for a while.
- Grandma and Grandpa come tonight.
- No, then it will start again.
- It's best that I go.
Why do you get nervous when they come?
I?
It is you who gets nervous!
- Because my own parents come?
–Justus Adam - Yes!
You are ashamed because I'm a postman.
Your father wanted you to marry a lawyer.
You know he likes you.
Otherwise, he would not have invited you to hunt.
He bore like an insane!
He threw himself over me!
That was fortunate.
You were aiming for fucking a horse!
He and I do not fit together.
My parents would never come without asking for permission!
Your parents would never tie your shoes without asking for permission first.
Why do you insist on taking them here when you have released them?
The first time we were going out together, you said, right in the face of Einar:
"This is Gustav, the man I love."
I said: "This is Gustav, we should go to the cinema, I might come home late".
Don't notice words!
I felt what you meant.
- Everything goes well, only you are yourself.
- Not as the last time they were here.
- What did you say then?
- I mentioned something about a promotion.
- You would become regional manager.
-That is all!
- Don't gloss the BMW.
-Can you be quiet?
Okay, maybe I said something about a car that I would be forced to go around in.
He wants to hear how much you earn, how expensive hunting equipment you have ...
I have never asked you to lie for my sake.
As you wish.
They may take me as I am!
Good.
If you clean up, I go and buy meat.
Einar has probably shot something on the road ...
This is also yours.
Lend a hand!
- I do not fuck for uninvited guests.
- not before they came here ...
Björn Borg had different tactics for different opponents.
What then - sometimes he hit the right, sometimes to the left?
- Max, you haven't dusted up here.
- I don't reach.
- Stand on the chair!
-It's dangerous.
I'm only ten years old.
Older you will not be if you do not help your sister.
Help me put this up.
Nice to see you so relaxed.
It's our wedding present!
- It usually stands behind the boiler.
- Serve it, and I'll stop you later.
-Are you done soon?
- Just seven pages left.
Remove this debris.
They are coming soon.
-Lumber?
These are my sports items.
- Speed up now!
They should only be here for 24 hours.
I lie down at seven, sleep until nine, throw out on the town ...
Shower and throw on you some of the shaving water you got from a grandmother last Christmas.
- You seem nervous.
- You haven't smoked for three years.
I know that well.
But I'm starting now.
-Hello Sara!
- Have they come?
- Have you started smoking?
- No, it was Max who wanted to try.
Gustav says that what he doesn't get away is death and your parents ...
I love them.
They are very nice.
–What do they have for a car?
–A Audi.
"Born free, estimated to death."
It says the manager on the registration plate.
Lillan!
But how pale you are.
Sweetie!
Long time no see.
Here is Sara that I have told about.
My little chickens, what you are big!
- You don't want sweets, huh?
- Why do you think we stay?
- Can you hug the bank director?
- Office manager ... but hugging, you.
- Sara, my neighbor.
-How nice.
Hi, Sara.
Are you really killing all rabbits?
No, but hares I have shot.
Gustav says he never escapes two things: death and ...
- Oh, what you got in a hurry now, Sara!
- Yes, yes ... sure.
- Do you have it left up there?
- It's done, Dad.
- Did you know where that species belong?
- Yes, behind the boiler.
Einar and Dagmar, fun to see you!
-Hello!
-Bye.
Where are you going?
Chaos on sorting - right today!
-It is Saturday.
- But the duty calls.
If you go, I'll kill you.
- It resolved with the sorting.
-How fun.
Mom, it's time for house vision.
I want you to see how nice your painting fits in Lina's room.
You hung up the king and Silvia?
Yes, but it is an oil stain on Silvia.
- They don't see it.
-It looks like a Hitler mustache.
Mom, go to the bathroom instead!
- Take more fruit compote.
-Thank you for the food.
- What do we do with the plates?
- Gate them to you so you can wash.
- Sensors that you do not meet them more often.
- We have to send pictures.
It's not enough.
Dad and I have talked a lot.
Sorry we didn't come up, but Lina had any show.
-Which?
- Ni does so much in your age ...
- Nattery, thief smoking, petting ... - Yes, see little guys!
Yes ... now it's time, Dagmar.
It contracts.
- Maybe I should help with the bags?
- So easy you don't get rid of us.
I want to say a few words.
Mom and I are so grateful that you receive us.
- We feel warmly welcome.
- You are.
That is why we have decided.
We move here.
-What did you say?
- We move to Ekberga.
- Why don't you have said?
- We wanted to surprise you.
- The yard then, dad?
- There are things that are more important.
- We want to get closer to you.
- How close then?
What can it be?
Twenty meters.
It is the yellow house on the other side of the street.
God, so much fun!
You can look straight into the kitchen!
Now it's serious.
How should we solve this?
We can wave to Grandma and Grandpa!
Do you have a fire?
-Good morning!
- But mom, what time is it?
Thank you for sleeping in your bed tonight.
You have changed in the bathroom since last.
The bath towel must have its own shelf.
We have our own ideas on how we want to put things.
Now I have arranged it.
Where is Gustav?
It is over seven o'clock.
He has been running for a long time.
- What are you doing this time?
- We woke up five when Grandma vacuumed.
- Should they move here?
- We don't know how it will be.
When you are as old as we do, you do not have the same need for your parents ...
- Don't you want to meet us later?
- Yes, but you probably don't want to meet us.
-Why not?
- We might put us into things.
- We certainly want to meet you!
- No, I say!
Families are for split.
- I am too small to hear that.
-Me too.
- Relieved the same ... - Barn, the grill is done!
- Mom, I'm fourteen years old!
- Go in and drink ...
- Should you pull uphill then?
- That's when it takes!
In the last downhill you pulled on.
- Did you go?
- No, the bushes took the worst bang.
- But the small guys got away.
- It looked nasty.
-Good morning darling.
-What are you doing?
Einar and I have jogged.
I won.
Gustav and I sat up yesterday, so it received some this morning.
But it was a lovely brandy ...
We ran past Gustav's new office.
What a view he gets.
The whole harbor!
He can keep an eye on the boat.
- How many berths were there?
- Four front, two rear.
-What are you doing?
- Holds me in shape.
Lillan ... what has mom said?
"Set on the table pepper, salt because it is used for everything"
In the spice shelf you do not find it.
What are you usually say?
"Today is the first day of the rest of your life."
But so awful can't it be?
- Imagine if your parents moved here!
- They have been dead for seven years.
Sorry, sara ...
I forgot it.
They will force me to have a hat when I go to the bank!
I think you should have a hat when it's winter.
-What is this?
- Cookery coffee.
Just as well you get used to it!
Say you don't want them to move here.
Gustav can tell the truth?
He helps them buy the house - though he would not be fuss.
But he's up again.
Salary increase, promotion ... Sailboat.
After all, he gets sick just he washing!
I want to take care of myself!
I'm an adult.
What should I do?
Break off a treo, mix down in half vodka, half carrot juice.
I fix this.
There is a lot that needs to be done.
Just small pick.
I know people who do that cheap!
- Gustav knows where to watch.
- I live in a similar house myself.
-The inner walls are self-ignition ...-We became terrified when we heard it.
We removed everything.
But you first have to pick up the parquet and remove the moisture.
It feels heavy with such a device ...
Give me six months with the living room.
We take the rest over the years to come.
We have to wait - however boring it is.
- Are you safe?
- We can't cope with so much hassle.
I promise me and Lena and Sara-
- See find a new house for you!
- I heard that Gunnarsson's house ... --... have burned down to the ground!
- These are these walls.
Deadly!
-Yes.
It should be a prison sentence for those who decide on the walls.
Dear Margit, you have no idea what we have been through!
We will come in exactly two hours.
The car is heated.
Why so molokna?
See you on Einar's 75th birthday.
It's four years there!
But what a party it will be!
If we have stood out on the farm for 50 years, we will probably be able to do another year.
If any house is for sale we will call!
Now we have to go.
- Now have a hat on you when you go out!
- Did you know that you have a top spouse?
- mm.
Bye daddy.
Drive carefully.
Why have you been keeping up for me all years that you are a genius?
Thanks honey.
-Where are you going?
- I'm coming back on Monday.
-What are you talking about?
- It became very brandy.
I said something about hunting license and safari.
What 'damn would I say?
So you are going with dad and Åke in search?
Yes.
I'll live in their tent.
Einar said that if you have sleeping mats you can get plus degrees in the sleeping bag.
As you make your bed so you must lie...
Thanks and goodbye!
Texting: SVT Sub -text (C) Swedish Television AB