In two weeks I am at Highbury Park.
In London there is as much to see.
But you should live centrally.
- I live perfectly!
–In piccadilly then?
Adjacent to the entrance to the football stadium.
There is my hotel behind it.
- Can you follow the training from the ceiling?
-Yes.
When did you decide for the trip?
22 years ago.
- How many corn flowers should you buy?
- How many are we at work?
- Take a hundred, so you know that is enough!
-Fifteen.
And a wreath to Annika.
–170 SEK.
- You then, Dad?
-Lets see...
-One.
–Vadå one?
You are my dad.
- It's your duty to buy!
- It was neat.
- What does it cost to do one like that?
- Something crown.
- Why pay ten then?
- It goes to charitable purposes.
I support those who want to give people a more bearable life!
- The engineer's national association!
- Mom bought ten yesterday.
Mom is a manager and has a higher salary!
But okay, I'm not going to be impossible.
Give me two.
I can sell the other at work.
-Hi mom.
-Hey sweetie.
How are you?
- So there.
It's a little difficult now.
- With 23,000 a month you can withstand wear!
25,000. My staff's future is at stake.
-Is it true?
–25,000?
You haven't told you!
- It's uninteresting at the moment.
- Now we can afford the sleeves ...
I may have to dismiss some.
We have to cut down on costs.
The manager of my last building had to dismiss ten.
They broke both arms on him.
Honey, come now.
The cabbage dolmes are on the table.
It's the best I know!
- What have you cooked for good then?
–Wa?
- It's your food week.
- It's so boring with food weeks.
Mozart wrote his symphonies because anyone said it was his music week?!
- Do you want to be starving?
- I arrange this.
No more pick -up pizzas!
Hello!
These cabbage dolmes ... how many do you have?
- Fantastically what Annika can!
-What then?
Cabbage dolmen is difficult.
Either the mince becomes dry or the cabbage too soft.
- But these were perfect.
-I do not know...
-What are you reading?
- Personal list.
- I might be able to dismiss friends!
- The executioner compiles its death list.
Do not say so!
Imagine if you have to kick someone you got to know!
We don't have time to get to know each other.
The schedule is a screwdriver.
Why do we always start talking about your job, even when I have problems?
My job may be more interesting.
Okay...
This is not your fault.
You're just a cog in a machinery.
- What machinery?
- The community.
We are against them!
- We against the managers!
- But I'm a manager!
No real.
Real managers feel good about kicking people.
It was the stupidest ...!
That on TV yesterday - it shone in his eyes as he closed the factory!
- He cried, Gustav.
He was ruined.
-Okay...
- How many have to stop?
-I do not know.
Four maybe.
Think like this: They should be happy that you are a manager.
You can give them encouragement to move on in life.
-Do you think so?
- It can be a new start for them!
They had not dared to quit themselves.
They thank you enough!
- Don't you surprise now?
- Yes, but what the hell should I say?
Sleep now, you have a lot to do tomorrow.
Do you think we should have nuclear power?
Well ... we are fine as we have it.
We have nuclear power.
Should we discontinue it?
You do as you wish.
Now Mom is probably surprised.
- It smells good!
–Tandooric chicken ...
- Mom has banned take -out food.
- only pizza.
We have to be kind.
- So the gift is for her?
- To the whole family.
How many May flowers should you have?
Five bucks each.
Five?!
I paid ten!
She is harder to fool.
-How many?
-No.
I can borrow dad's.
Hello, old man, come in.
Have you received the list on who should be dismissed?
- Yes, there was just one.
- It wasn't that dangerous!
It was me.
My name was the only thing on the list.
But you are the manager.
That's just that.
They will get rid of all local managers.
- They can't do this!
- "Withdrawn services, Vivalla:"
- "Lena Svensson, office manager."
- But ... you have to say away.
- Protest!
- It's no idea.
Soon they call and say that everything was a mistake.
Phone signal
–Max Svensson.
Certainly.
- From the bank.
-What did I say!
- Lena.
Okay.
Certainly.
Yes thank you.
Bye.
-Reach?
Good news?
So there.
If the moving boxes are not out tomorrow, they throw the shit ...
- It's inhuman!
- Yes, a week you should get!
- That it would end like this ... - Can't you go back to the cash register?
No, you have to have a little pride.
Yes.
The parachute also facilitates.
Parachute?
I have no parachute.
Are you crazy?!
No parachute?!
I was offered one, but refused.
You thought it was immoral.
It is immoral when you have a job, yes!
-I have no!
- There is only one rescue.
The bottle.
The union!
I go to my trade union!
- But I don't work at the post.
- If an employee is affected, everyone is affected!
- You should experience solidarity!
- Dad has a gift for you.
- Wait with it ... - Now I'm happy for anything.
- Don't turn too much to turn ... - what is it for something?
A sleeve key set.
- A hyls wrench kit?
- I leave it back immediately.
Can't this be anything?
"You can keep order for money. Get down to the square at 13."
Åke's raffle.
I think I stand over ...
I don't think they can do this!
- "Do you have a car, are used to stores ..." - thanks, that's enough ...
I will use my contacts.
I write to companies I have worked with.
Good!
Just like Göran.
Whatever death a project is - he does not give up.
-Thanks.
Did you have nothing to do at home?
-No.
I can be here for three more hours.
- Where is Gustav?
- Hos his trade union.
"You can't dismiss people anyway."
It's Dad a living proof of!
How did Dad go?
Could they help mom?
No Unfortunately not.
There are rules for curse ...
- I had not paid.
- You got no tips?
-Yes.
"Father to hell, black foot!"
- Thanks anyway, Gustav.
When you need the union for once, they leave one in the gutter ...
–... because you forgot the fee!
- When did you last pay?
Get to see ... When did the old king die?
Well, now we have to address the problem!
See it positively!
Now you can do everything you dreamed of:
- fix at home, bake ... - I have never baked?!
Now you have the chance!
Learn to make small nut meringues with jam in the middle.
- Gustav, do you know what this is?
- The recipe?
This is my track record!
I have 20 years of banking experience.
The only thing that is required now is action!
-You are right!
-What should you do?
Take a sandwich.
- Gustav, it will never go.
- Well then ...
- It feels hopeless.
-No.
They have Peter Barnes as a goalkeeper.
No problem.
Hello!
Over 12,000 women are unemployed only in our municipality!
- You are not a woman.
You are the manager.
- I was the manager.
I got the job because they knew me.
Do they have your track record?
You have 20 years of experience.
They want hungry 25 -year -olds, not a two -child mother who got fired.
Sooner or later something shows up!
Can I get to sleep now?
- Gustav ... - what is it?
What do you say if I have to be home?
- Bli's housewife, you mean?
- If nothing shows up, so ...
It is not shameful to take care of man and children!
I'm talking about a few months.
Half a year the most.
But what a year!
You will see your children grow up!
Many women will envy you.
No, maybe I went too far there.
- We get 15,000 less a month!
-Yes.
We have managed in a salary in the past.
We can get rid of unnecessary things.
The kids' stuff, e.g.
I have canceled your football trip.
- It was a birthday present!
- You get to see the match on TV instead.
- You can't mean that!
- And we can't afford Eurosport.
Your Dreju course then?
1,800 ate the forest.
You can't even use the replacements.
- It's no swaps, it's vases!
- All 200 leaks.
It's charming.
It's nice for me to work with my hands!
Itch me on my back then!
- Gustav ... - what is it?
It's been a long time since we were arguing about money.
I know, I'm a great selfish.
We should help and solve this.
Tomorrow I pick up my cartons.
Then you and I and I and the kids start about!
Right.
A new life stands at the door.
It should actually be nice to be able to tell the truth to some some.
In the moment of farewell, one should be honest.
- Do you want to borrow the baseball tree?
- No, we have a fire ax in the dining room.
Good night.
- What is it with Dad?
-Do not know.
He has been happy today.
- He probably knows nothing about the trip.
- Here come sandwiches and chocolate!
- What is it with you, Dad?
- You are hungry?
- Did you know that Mom canceled the trip?
- She did it right.
Now I am needed at the family.
Imagine what we may be with!
Mom is at home, becomes treasurer, then manager, and then comes back home.
It is hardly you hang out.
You understand what this means?
- You will be difficult in the future.
- We have to reduce expenses.
- But we can do.
Do you know why?
- "Because we're a family."
Are you glad that mom has no job?
I make the best of a disaster.
They can lead to something better.
- Are we reslauing ourselves without mom's salary?
- How does Mayflower Sales?
- She's been away for three hours.
- It takes time to kill everyone ...
I know you think I'm boring sometimes -
- But one day like this is probably everyone happy that my postal cycle is here ...
-Hey sweetie.
Do you want chocolate?
- No, the moving boxes have to go away now.
There is no must in your life anymore.
- Do you have to quit?
- You were not enough.
Only one regional manager is needed.
Nothing gets better because you are eating this.
That's me.
I am the new regional manager.
-Congratulations Mom.
I knew it!
- Dad had to scare us up really.
- I start in Örebro on Monday.
- You had been fired, it said.
I was moved.
Gustav, follow along and carry moving boxes.
I tell you more in the car.
- I got a service car.
–What for someone?
-It is red.
- I don't ask for the color.
Nämen Herrejösses!
A Volvo 850!
Kids, up and switch to the fine clothes!
Dad got a new car.
Welcome to the flight to London.
Our duty -free goods are presented in the folder in the chair pocket in front of you.
Excuse me ... Should you have your peanuts?
-No.
It's fine thank you.
Oh, did you get honey roasted?
- Is it a video game, right?
- No, I sit and work a little.
I don't have that.
I'm going to football.
It is my wife who offers the trip.
She is the manager.
- It sounds fun ... - region manager for Örebro Sparbank.
One of the best managers in Sweden.
Good women have emerged.
I don't know that much.
But Lena is special ...
- And she is the world's best wife.
- Yes ... Yes, there you see ...
- Should I reveal a secret?
- If it's a necessity ...
I love her.
-Did you know what she said?
- That she loves you?
That we have to change the boiler.
What do you say about that?!
Despite the job, she does not forget the needs of the family!
I am impressed with you who can handle her success.
- You should be safe in himself.
- You have your own career?
Oh yes, I'm a postman.
Then I do some business aside.
A May flower?
SVT Program Settling Karin Esvik