Do you keep track of all the papers now?
I grant you this big loan because I trust you.
Here I thought to have mirrors.
Here is the solarium.
I get room for over 15 people.
This is a full service salon.
I thought it would be called "Sara's hair, skin and grill".
Behind the foot care you can buy thin bread rolls.
- You get the craving for the solarium.
- You must have professional help.
I actually have an economic consultant - Tom Lindvall.
Then I don't have to worry!
He helped us with rationalizations.
He kicked everyone who was over 40.
He is fearless.
He has written a book on personnel policy.
"Man, a necessary evil".
He has good ideas.
He wanted you to leave me and Max so you could work more.
- He sounds deadly ... - just kept your invoices and receipts.
I do!
Expenses and income - U and I. Order and ready!
I thought you would put the invoices in a cover, not in two freezer bags!
- It's simple and clear.
- And easy to freeze?
I'll meet empty in ten minutes.
Keep your fingers crossed!
- To not have a feeling in the body.
- He sat in my office and cried!
Because he was not allowed to dismiss the foreign department ...
What you seem happy.
Have you raised the postage?
No!
Today is a special day.
The state has shown me its appreciation.
- The document states my importance.
- parking fines?
No!
I have been elected for this year's postman in 1994.
That tram set?
"For loyalty, punctuality and feeling of duty" ...
... signed by the postmaster.
It is only because you do not argue about working hours.
- He buys the diploma for 19:50.
–20!
Plus 15 for the frame.
It was your turn to get a diploma.
Everyone else has received.
- Not Mardell.
- Mardell is 13 years old and prying.
It's so typically your banking people!
You don't know what loyalty means.
- But you know that?
-You can always count on me!
- Help me with the history test.
-I do not have time.
- I have to go away and work.
- What are you so important?
We drink wine.
- At seven you have interrogated Max and the food is on the table.
Do not worry!
- Should we surprise mom and do really nice in here?
- No ... - good, then I watch TV.
- hear me now.
- Not now, it's a match ball!
- This test determines my rating.
- It sounds exciting ... okay, okay.
What was the name called ... rode in to the king and to some extent ...
- Read in the book.
- There it sat, 6-4!
We won!
- This history test is important.
- Here you are involved in creating history!
Sweden can win the Davis Cup!
- How is it, Lina?
What will it be?
- Something with mash.
The meatballs burned up.
- Good, mom that I've done them.
-What a night!
Now I'm completely exhausted.
- I interrogate our son.
-Sorry.
How did it go?
- Yes, Edberg had problems in the beginning.
-I understand exactly.
With all my commitments, I have the right to take a short time rest.
Four and a half hours, more specifically.
- He knows the entire World War.
- The test is on the French Revolution.
- And food haven't you done?
- Now you are skeptical again.
-It's done!
- What are you offering then?
- Something with mash!
- "Something with mash" ...
- Margherita or Capricciosa?
- Vesuvio.
Why do you ask me to cook when you still buy pizza?
- No one likes to be moss.
- It was the meatballs that were burned!
- Why are you forcing Lina to cook?
-Who else?
Max plugged.
- We have to set up for each other.
- I don't do anything else.
I have proof of that.
- Why do you have the diploma in bed?
- I value it!
- The manager chooses me over others.
- Because you never dare to say.
- Don't you mark that they take advantage of you?
- You say, with your banking paper!
These are Sara's loan documents and I'm worried.
- She doesn't have any order!
- But you happily lend money!
- She has done a lot for me.
- Cut you?
Bolded and permanent ...
How can the bank lend such sums without collateral?
- Someone has been in the bail for her.
- What is so damn stupid?
You, Gustav.
Don't get angry now.
I must not write like that myself.
For her hair salon you risk everything we own and have?!
- The garage and the plot we must keep.
- Have you been crazy?!
Don't get like that now!
If it goes well we get part of the cake.
- Can we cut ourselves free?
- No, but cheaper.
I couldn't even do anything so stupid.
What do you think the kids say?
- Mig they know anyway where they have!
- The anticipation at the fridge or on the sofa.
This is the security child needs.
I don't play Hasard with our future.
You played away the holiday box!
We didn't have to travel away.
It was very nice in the garden!
- I create cohesion.
- You should not be so sure.
- Lina asked when she had to move.
-Never.
Soon she is of legal age and decides on herself.
I have been of legal age for 20 years, and have never had to decide anything.
Soon she has a boyfriend with her to sleep over here.
What are you doing then?
I open with a light left ...
- What do you think they do at their parties?
-I do not know.
I am not invited.
What did you do at the parties yourself when you put out the light?
Ate popcorn.
You couldn't see anything.
- What did you do yourself?
- I don't think you want to know.
Good night.
Sleep tight.
-Say it now.
-Sleeping!
- No, say first.
-Do not you know?
- Why don't you want to tell?
- I ate chips!
- It is a smoking ban here, Pettersson.
- Did you see tennis yesterday?
Wimbledon did you see in Benka's garage?
There I could concentrate on the game.
Are you going to see the match tomorrow in the cellar?
It's working day tomorrow!
Sweden is in the Davis Cup final!
Should you call yourself sick?
A good postman does not!
Then he is rewarded.
I have four those there are fog.
You were the only one who had nothing.
I was the only one worth it!
- The diploma serves an important purpose.
-Yes.
I use mine as a cutting board.
Mine will hang among my other honors!
Next to the swimming bourgeois brand and the driver's license ...
I know you're a lonely person.
Who can watch tennis whenever he wants.
- In the morning I'll watch the Davis Cup.
- Then people will have their weekly magazines!
I remember when you didn't hand out the mail order packages.
You were disappointed because you didn't get your plot.
I fixed another.
It was not the werewolf the kids were waiting for.
--Max cried.
- Lungs are discerning nowadays.
- Therefore, I have not acquired any.
- No woman wants to live with you.
I enjoy being free ...
Saying those who don't know what love is!
When I saw Lena on the school ball, I knew she was the woman for me.
- She didn't get away when you offered.
- The girls were in line for me!
- Did you sell sausages?
-Right.
I fell for Lena directly.
Since then we have loved and respected each other.
That, you!
It is trust and honesty!
Like during the ice hockey World Cup when you called and said I received cardiac arrest.
It was 2-2 and Sundin was expelled.
At 10am tomorrow, the match begins.
Then I'll be in my couch and watch the Davis Cup.
Yes, you lie there!
I will make sure that subscribers get their magazines!
Shit in it.
They still watch the Davis Cup ...
- When is France's National Day?
–14 July.
-Why?
- Because it says so in the book!
- What could have happened?
Has Sara traveled away?
- With 200,000 you get a good bit.
- You don't understand the seriousness of this.
-Yes.
You have mortgaged the whole house.
But it is Dad who goes there.
- Yeah, then it was clear.
- What did he say about the salon?
That it was hell too yellow.
Both chairs and curtains must go green.
- The business idea, what did he think of it?
- He wanted to buy himself right away.
- Undealable, then we are saved!
- Hi, Sara, do you want to borrow more money?
Take it easy.
The consultant liked Sara's business concept.
-Where are you going?
-What does it look like?
To work.
But it's the Davis Cup final.
I bought pallets.
Have I once sick leave to watch sports?
- Our wedding night.
-Yes, yes, but it was Borg-Panatta.
Now I have to rush.
- Good luck with the test, Max.
- Does anyone want to be pushed?
Have a nice time in the hot car so I'll cycle out in snow and slush.
- Here, Lina.
-Not that!
- Yes, it has old grandmother knitted.
- She's blind.
It took two years to finish.
- Do you buy food?
- Yes, what do you have another husband?
- Write on guarantee paper.
Edberg, Stich, Agassi and so Becker, Sampras ...
Time for the decisive match.
It will be an exciting final, an racker.
Hello, Conny.
Do you have any parent at home?
Not that?
Good.
Did you find someone who can help you?
Olle?
How nice!
Look at the address tags and hand out the newspapers.
You get 200 when you are ready ... where.
But dress up properly.
Wait, I forgot one thing.
Dad, have you seen my bus card?
I thought I saw it at the phone.
Say nothing to Mom ... Max?
Wait!
No!
Hello!
... American backhand side ... Edberg goes online.
- Max buys nasal drops on the way home.
-Thanks.
Why did you stand out in the cold for so long?
Edberg was superb.
You have certainly received pneumonia.
- I saw my whole life passing the review.
- Stack, were you boring?
- Do you know what happened?
- Yes, I've been close to dying.
No, no, something much worse.
Someone has tried to break into my house.
- What the hell would I do?
- Where did you get in the windows?
- Why in hell didn't you open?
- There is that Tom and I lay in the bath.
- It was so sad in his office.
- Does Tom Lindvall align in your bathtub?
No, he stands in the kitchen and cooking.
Something oriental.
Why does all men fall for you?
Could it be the new balm shampoo?
Tom wants us to become companions.
"Sara's hair, skin, grill and capital management".
- Needle ... - Can I borrow 400,000 more?
- I should cut the whole family for free.
- I can kill you for free.
Come on when the salon makes a profit.
Tom thinks I will go a long way.
It is enough to go home.
No, now I go up and bed down, so you can play about me.
- How did it go with the weekly magazines?
- I have solved that.
- How did it go for Max on the test?
-Canceled.
Miss looked at tennis.
Of course it is shameful.
Grown ups!
Yes ... but it's not the same.
I've arranged it.
Next time it is tennis on TV you will be on sick leave as usual.
- What do you have there?
- magazines.
Olle and Conny stand in the school yard and sell them for a penny each.
- Sure it's cheap!
- They have two bags full.
Hurry up!
-Hell.
-Go to sleep.
We can afford to buy our own magazines.
Yes, yes ... take a ladies' world then.
Texting: SVT Sub -text (C) Swedish Television AB