Hello everyone!
Today is Sunday.
It's the weekend.
I'm free.
I'm on a walk.
I am walking.
The weather is nice today.
The sun shines.
It doesn't blow.
The sky is blue.
It's not raining.
It's fantastic weather.
Today I want to tell you about my morning.
Watch the short video!
I wake up early.
My kids wake me up.
They jump on the bed.
I'm making the bed.
I shower in the morning.
a toothbrush
A toothpaste
I take some toothpaste.
I brush my teeth.
a comb
I comb.
I work out in the morning.
I do morning gymnastics.
My daughters train with me.
They help me.
I am eating breakfast.
We have breakfast together.
I drink coffee on the balcony.
out
I drink coffee black, without milk, without sugar.
I like coffee.
I drink coffee and read news.
News in easy Swedish
What did I do in the morning?
I woke up early.
I bedded the bed.
I showered.
I brushed my teeth.
I combed.
I trained.
I did morning gymnastics.
I ate breakfast.
I drank coffee on the balcony.
I read news.
I went out for a walk.
I walked.
I'm walking right now.
What should I do after the walk?
After the walk we will go to the swimming pool.
We're going to swim with the children.
We will do that!
What do you usually do in the morning when you are free?
What do you do in the morning on a Sunday or Saturday?
Write in comments!
Thanks for today!
See you in the next video!
Bye!