Hello everyone!
Today we will talk about verbs.
sitting
is located
stands
Hangs
one should - this table
a cup
a cup of tea
a water bottle
a cactus
A small cactus
A red scissors
a book
An interesting book
bananas
Yellow bananas
There is a cup of tea on the table.
There is a water bottle on the table.
There is a small cactus on the table.
is located
There is a red scissors on the table.
There is an interesting book on the table.
There are yellow bananas on the table.
a sofa
There is a boy on the couch.
a chair
There is a girl on the chair drinking water.
a lamp
Three lamps
There are three lamps in the ceiling.
a pillow
Three pillows
There are three pillows on the sofa.
a painting
There are two paintings on the wall.
a mirror
There is a mirror on the wall.
a clock
There is a clock on the wall.
Look!
Now it's evening.
It's dark outside.
Did you enjoy the video?
Didn't you like the video?
I enjoy.
I do not like.
Subscribe to my channel!
Thanks for today!
Farewell!