Move!
- Mom, can you lift me?
- Celere yourself when you're so short!
- Where did they live before?
- In Uddevalla.
Hell is solved!
The historyless bureaucrats destroy a cultural heritage.
- The area of the park is known ... - Park?
They will demolish Posten's café!
The postal management intends to demolish the cafeteria!
Do you understand!
We do not have coffee stains on the postcards.
- Dad, our new neighbors move in!
- Then we have to start locking at night.
Well ... Chevrolet.
It is not enough with Swedish!
- It does not matter.
- Related they look!
- Place as if they owned the place!
- They bought it from Sara!
Our little Sara.
Such a neighborhood ...
- We would become friends, I knew.
- You said "APA" in the first few years!
- Why are you always so suspicious?
- I'm just cautious.
- You are paranoid.
- Paranoid means ...
- You were the same with Berntson.
- He painted the garage door black!
It doesn't have to mean that he is a devil worshiper!
-Just.
- Oh, I was wrong.
I admit!
I had read a nasty book and was worried.
Now I go and greet.
Follow!
Gustav?
- No, I have something else to do.
- Why don't you want to meet them?
Anyone who has a bigger car, their own solarium and earns more does not want to meet Dad.
- How do you know he earns more?
- All earn more than you.
Come now!
No!
We lived here first.
They will come to us.
- God, what you are childish!
- proud, it's called!
And hungry ...
Missing historical value?
The coffee machine is from 1972!
It is not enough for K -marking?
National interest?
But then we agree!
Then I'll call next week.
Yes I do!
-How is it going?
-Slow.
Why are you so woe?
You get a new nice coffee room instead.
It's about democracy!
Major changes should be made with consent!
138 voted for and you and Pettersson voted against.
There are people who dare to take cultural responsibility!
Then you and Pettersson get to go to the municipal office on Saturday.
Not Pettersson, he has a match.
- Dad, why don't we have a computer?
- So we can think for ourselves.
The neighbors, Göran and Annika, have each through Göran's company.
Stolen, it is called.
What do you have there?
Phantom magazines.
I got them from Göran.
He is Reko.
Yes, Göran says so.
He thinks the whole area seems to be reco.
Reko?
They have lived here one day and Max comes home and is ugly in their mouths!
- What is it for people?
- I can tell you.
They were born in 1960, married for a year.
Göran is a construction engineer and earns SEK 350,000 a year!
- How to know everything?
- Göran will open an account in the bank.
–350,000!
- So it goes if you are driven!
He became "Entrepreneur of the Year" in Uddevalla.
-What company?
The masquerade league!
- Ask instead of glory in the window.
I have binoculars!
Check out what I got from Annika!
I got them for free!
Nothing is free.
They are certainly looking for something!
Annika is very nice.
It takes more than a pair of skates to win my friendship!
-Hello!
Is there anyone home?
- Hi neighbors, so nice!
I would thank you for the skates.
- Are you Gösta?
- Gustav ... Svensson.
Göran Forslund is my name.
- We have met everyone except you ... –Ni save the best until last.
Do you want something?
Coffee, espresso, cappuccino, deer saddle?
No, we have eaten the minced meat pie we got from Lena.
Well, it was you who ate it up.
Neighborhood is like a flower.
The more it is cared for, the more beautiful it becomes.
-Fine!
Are you writing too?
- Writing?
I'm in a poetry association ...
We can save that for another time.
You have to be proud of Lena.
She does not need to be ashamed of the meat pie.
No, her career!
Being able to combine work and family life.
But behind every successful woman ...
... stands an envious postman!
There are pros and cons of my job.
Without Gustav it would not have been possible.
It is a full -time job to keep track of changes and pots.
Did you want something?
- I would have to ask for a service.
- I almost thought out.
My toolbox remained in Uddevalla.
Now you want me to go and pick it up?
Can I borrow your?
That plate bag with wrench and screwdriver ...
I had intended to start some stuff, but of course you have to borrow it.
We will build a sauna and want to get started.
Building a sauna, which we have been thinking about for so long!
- Why are you going to build a sauna?
- We miss the one we had in Uddevalla.
Of course, you are not going to move back there?
- Should you go and get the toolbox?
- Göran, do you know what is getting into?
Building a sauna is more than just throwing out boards and nails.
- I've been able to build a couple.
-Nice.
Go the same way you came!
Gustav believes that the toolbox is in Boden.
It is wrapped in Christmas paper.
- Christmas paper?
- I haven't had time to open.
- I come back when I'm done.
- You can give it to Gustav next Christmas!
He took my Christmas present.
You got the toolbox in 1987 and have not opened it.
Blame yourself!
- I've been waiting for the right time.
- It came now!
Fun to be used.
I recognize the type.
Already after a day he builds a sauna ...
It doesn't have to take 15 years between thought and action!
I have talked about a sauna because we would have something to look forward to.
- I don't want to throw anything together.
-You're just jealous.
We have been longing for a sauna since we moved in!
It is possible.
But at least we have the dream left.
That's more than the one where the tool stays can say.
Did you see the moving guys?
Not a estimated crown there, not.
- It was his brothers.
- Yes, it's called so.
What does the building committee say?
Göran has its own construction company and all the conditions you should have.
-Mother?
Dad?
Are you sleeping?
- Come on you, honey.
- Is there a monster under the bed?
- No, I knew you were here.
-What is it?
- Have you seen my Phantom?
Last time I saw them was on the coffee table.
- I thought I saw Lina with them.
- She's always on my stuff!
Lena, isn't it nasty that the children run in foreign people?
Children take an easy impression!
With Göran there are fast cars, black builds, video violence, data violence ...
- Set now, Gustav.
- You think I'm jealous.
Because Göran makes a lot of money, is handy and has a very nice car.
What I care about is our family.
That my values are passed on.
I'm trying to talk seriously!
Soon you are sitting out in the garden with Göran and having a great time!
- Göran just thinks of himself!
- Fun for you - a soul mate!
If they want to become friends with us, the ball is with them!
Gustav Svensson's friendship, should you deserve it?
I have lent a tool box, stretched out my hand ...
- I want to see what I get back.
- Probably a toolbox.
Hello!
Well ... how was it in school?
Absolutely uninteresting as usual.
Dad has not come home.
He is well saving that coffee room.
- Max, can you go to the business?
- You have said that I am too small.
- It was eight years ago.
- But that was good!
Ok, everyone!
Tonight, you understand, is no ordinary evening.
- We will do something together.
-Wait!
It's not so dangerous.
The world around us is turbulent.
New values are thrown against us ...
I was wrong - stick, you.
It is important not to be deceived by the beautiful words of the lism.
- Göran and Annika ... - funny that you thought about them.
What is important in life?
Yes, the family - La Famiglia.
Therefore, I will set up a day in the family sign to be called:
Family Day.
Kids, can't we help and have a really nice party tonight?
Hello!
Do you hear, Göran and I will have a move -in party tonight.
Do you want to...?
No rush - it starts at seven!
- Line, go out and pick up the trunk bowl.
-Stop!
Stop, stop.
- Wasn't something that we forgot?
-Good!
The cardboard mugs and plates.
- Oh, then Max and I run over.
- How can you do this?
This is Görans and Annika's first party!
Come now, it will be fun!
Never!
If it is the family's day, it is, if I should celebrate it myself!
Ok.
Serpentines and balloons are in the bottom kitchen box!
I never thought my family would fall for such simple tricks.
Cheap food, some windy drink, music, nice socializing ...
... maybe a good cigar, brandy ... Satan!
Hello then, Annika!
I will come in to you tomorrow.
Greeting Göran!
Come now, kids.
-Hey what are you doing?
- I actually lie and think.
On how the Phantom is comfortable in the skull cave?
- No, but on how it should go for us.
-Don't play martyr now, Gustav!
Has it been hard?
Do you want to go to bed?
- The clock is a quarter to nine.
- Our family day is soon over.
It was no successful premiere.
You and I have talked about having a neighborhood party.
Fun that it got rid of!
When we invite everyone will come: Pettersson, postmaster Melander ...
- Everyone was there.
- Melander?
He and Pettersson talked for a long time.
Pettersson will become a district manager.
- I have applied for the place!
- You have been looking for all places for ten years.
You can apply for the job as a waitress in the new cafeteria!
The doorbell calls who is it?
- Forslund, may I come in?
- Conduct, I'm just a little busy.
Ok, come in.
Hey ... how are things going for you?
Lena told me you had to work.
Do you want some food and beer?
I do not have time.
Must be ready for tomorrow morning.
Well, Bamse's Christmas toys ...
I'm basically done with it.
- How was it at the party?
Boring?
- It was really successful.
I probably did away with the end.
The post is forwarded, but we have not received any letters.
It turned out to be Pettersson's fault.
- He got rid of his promotion ... - Göran!
Can I invite you to something?
I am so happy that we have got such nice neighbors.
I have a question.
This morning came the building committee.
Some neighbor has reported me for black construction.
Do you know who it might be?
Göran ... I have to tell you one thing.
Berntson down on the corner ... He seems pretty ok.
Many of us suspect he is a devil worshiper.
There you have your husband!
I heard that you had been named Entrepreneur of the Year in Uddevalla.
I myself am named this year's postman.
Melander offered pear cider and the table was full of almond cubes.
Like we ate almond cubes!
What fun it was with Göran and Annika!
They have such a nice wall in the living room.
With a handy man it can get really cozy.
Dad wanted to make a bar of the ping pong table.
Lucky no one was injured ...
What idea did he have yesterday?
Family Day?
Again?
Dad has a lot at work and has not become accustomed to the new neighbors.
Sorry darling.
It got stupid yesterday but we can't ignore the neighbors.
- We might have the family's day now?
- Unfortunately, family day is over.
- Now I should do something important.
-Yourself?
No, our new neighbors.
Göran - what a guy!
He came here yesterday.
Then we sat in the sauna for five hours.
- Did you know what I discovered?
- It's hard to sleep at 100 degrees?
No, Göran is a healthy and sympathetic guy.
A little overpaid just ...
- So we can spend time with them normally?
-Absolutely.
Göran is interesting.
He has worked for a year in Dubai!
Did you tell us about your year in Värnamo?
Yesterday was Göran the devil's envoy.
Now you are friends.
What has happened?
- Oh, it is nine!
-What is this?
Dear Family - We'll have a sauna!
- Göran, do you have time with this?
- Yes, before there is a spin at the company.
I can't believe it's true.
Thanks!
As Gustav said: Neighborhood is like a flower - the more care, the more beautiful.
As true as it is said!
Ok, the builder.
Down in the basement again!
Didn't you think Dad was such a fixer?
- Don't you help him?
- If he shouts, I'll come!
- When Göran comes back?
- He is in town and comes soon.
- Can't you go down and work yourself?
- I have a break.
Coffee is good when you have worn all morning.
-What have you done?
Lit the light?
-Yes.
He came early!
How long does this take?
We've had it like this for three days.
Honey, when we sit in the heat we forget that.
- Imagine that it got rid of!
Own sauna.
- It feels unreal.
When Göran is done with the sauna, shouldn't we ask him to build a sky bed?
- Göran is kind.
Don't take advantage of it!
-Use?
He thinks it's fun.
-Hello!
Do you know what has happened?
- The assembly came this morning ...
I got my first job.
Three weeks full time and well paid!
- We start tomorrow morning.
- You should pull the pipes then!
The only thing you need to think about is to bend the pipes -
- And to solder the main circles.
- I have no education at this!
- You have no education at all.
We would build together.
You do not fail a friend!
You can come at any time.
I'm sitting one floor above you.
At the postoffice!
I'm going to tear out the worn cafeteria!
Now it is best that you go, Göran.
Now we are workmates too!
There you see!
What did I say!
Chevrolet!
You can't trust such people!
Call a construction company.
- Building company?
We can not afford!
-I can afford.
Ring!!!
Tjena, Pettersson, we shit in the old coffee room.
Have you bent tubes sometime?
SVT Program Sewing: Birgitta Sunnerdal