Hello
i got one so ba ask
As I want to try to answer
The question is: How can I take
better notes on the lesson
when the teacher talks
It was Farhia who asked that
and I think that is a very good question indeed
and
I was going to link that question to
the words
objectively and subjectively
So I want to discuss the words objectively
And subjectively little
and connect it to what you are looking for
When you listen to a lesson
what you should record and
what to focus
and concentrate on
null
If I should explain those words a little neighbor then
so are
What is objective is
not dependent on your
Opinions and feelings
so
We take a simple fact that
Sweden is in Europe
It's just true, they don't matter
what you think or feel
It is so that Sweden is in Europe
It's just one
Definition of the word Europe
and you cannot influence it
It doesn't matter how it feels
or what you think
So it is objective that Sweden is in Europe
But for example, a valuation that
it is good
that Stefan Löfven is prime minister
in Sweden
It is a question that is subjective
If you think it's good or you think it's bad
it is connected
with your values, with your political
opinions and securely with your
Emotions too
so there is nothing where one can say that
It is obviously right or wrong, true or false
Without it more about opinions and feelings
it is subjective, the subjective
is connected to you and yourself
Okay, so what does this have to do
with how to record on the lesson
Well, I think like this
the best way to study a language
And the best way I believe
to go to school
is to all the time
be active
and search for what you need
Look for the words and look for that grammar
And look
After the expressions and the phrases
And the sentences
and the material, the texts
As you need right now
not to passively wait for a teacher
or that someone else should tell you
that you should learn this or you should learn this
without you constantly trying
drive your process
that you try
sit in the driver's seat
If you say in Swedish, it is you who control
It is you who gas and brakes
and holds the steering wheel, and you use
your teacher and your textbook and your
your study supervisors
your classmates for help
And guidance
they are a support and they help you find
the right path but that you are always active
And yourself is trying
have the initiative
to study independently
I see it as you are looking for
the language you need, you are looking for it
You are like hunting
you are active and attentive
and focused, on Swedish there is an expression
on the toes
and that means, during a lesson
that when the teacher takes up things that you know
That you need
or you know that you are interested in
You know it's something hard for you
or you know it is something that is important
for you to teach you
Then you are focused on it
Then you understand that aha this is important
the hot here I will write down
for
You can't learn everything at once
and you can't concentrate
focus, on everything at the same time
so you become a more effective
Student or students or language teachers
if you choose
what you focus on
So the teacher speaks, the teacher writes down different things
and you all the time
chasing for what you need right now
that is important to you
and that's what you also choose to write down
in the first place, because you may not be able to
Make a note of everything, you
Don't have time, you are not fast enough
and it's not meaningful either, because if you just copy
Everything the teacher says
so you probably won't catch
and be able to read all that, but it is better
to choose some things
maybe just a few support words, some
central important words or
some important examples that the teacher takes up
They are you writing down
They study at home yourself
and then you try to remember the other
You are trying to activate the knowledge
the subject or content
as the teacher discussed by the fact that
Look at your notes
where you have the most important
one might call it support words
Yes exactly
So there I think you have the structure, the important thing is to
work on understanding what is important to you
and then find an effective way to
Write it down so that after the lesson
can remember, what it was
you thought were important
null
and here we will eventually come back to this with
objectively and subjectively
Because if we take it objective, it is in some way easier
There are some things that are
important if you want
Speak and write good Swedish so that others
Understands you, such as word order
so to have a good order
is important, you cannot
choose or select it
Do you want to be good in Swedish
Then the order is important to you
However, you may not be able to learn everything at once
So if you are fairly new in the language then the most important
That you learn to understand where is the subject?
Where is the verb?
where is the item =
in a common sense.
When you become at a higher level
Then it starts to become important to understand
where to place not
How you build a bye
How to make different types of more
special sentences and then you should focus on it
and thus record it when the teacher takes it up
But word sequence is objectively important
you can't cheat with it, it's the same with
to bend verbs in different times
It is the same with bending nouns for example
so there is the objective part
grammar and most
common words, you just need them
It's just about to
try to learn just in a lot at a time
and try to understand what is basic
As you need to be sure first
and what is more advanced, as you can wait for
wait with;
So it's all about
Understand;
What level am I at?
What should I focus on?
What should I prioritize?
So what should I choose?
It is the objective, it is about self -insight
Then you can also choose what to note
and what to repeat
the second, the subjective
It's more about your feelings and your interests
and what makes you curious
and gets energy and feel enthusiasm
over learning the language
For example, for me it could be to learn me slang
I love slang, so that if I
had a teacher
For example, in Somali, then I would be careful
by writing up all the hose expressions
As that teacher taught
If they do
for it may not be important for everyone, but for me it would be important
because I think it's funny
and it gives me some extra energy to learn
the language and it is fun to use it
When talking to other people
another area for me personally could be
I would like to be able to talk about music
In a new language because I am interested in music
and then all the words that deal with it
important, for another person may not
is so important, they don't want to talk about music
they are not interested in it, there is something
they would not prioritize
for another person maybe it is politics
or a very academic language
For another person it may be the everyday language
that is the most important thing, to be able to do well
in ordinary situations, but again
It is about having self -insight
To know: Who am I?
What do I want?
What do I want to be able to do?
What do I want to say?
What conversations do I want to be able to participate in?
What do I want to be able to read and understand and so on?
and what makes me go on
that I get energy
that I get peppered
that I become enthusiastic and that
bring it with them when you are on a lesson
Wait a bit, now it's something extra exciting here
now i'm not going to sleep
those things the teacher writes at the far end of the edge of the board
that may be just a little extra
they are important to me now so they write up
and they learn so
The goal awareness is
The key to everything
that you have clear goals
Both big goals
and more specific goals
and that you are aiming and focusing on them
on a lesson, so I think
that one will learn and do well
Notes, because if you know what you want
and what you need, so you will
find a way to get it
to remember that, that
insure yourself
that you remember the most important thing for you during a lesson
Yes
This was my answer to the question
How can you be better at noting
on a lesson
Feel free to ask if I
told something strange or used some
difficult words
And please react
on what I say, whether you agree or disagree
or tell me how you do
In order to take advantage of teaching in the best way
Yes
One tip is to follow me on Instagram as well
I do pretty much there "Swedish with Kalle"
called the account, it's just searching
Right now I'm talking a lot about how to get in touch
with people
But I make posts about everything possible
grammar, words, culture
Lots of different things
So feel free to keep up there too and so I hope
to see you again soon
farewell
bye