Hello
Good evening
Hope you have a nice Monday night
You who listen
So I will try
talk and think a little more about this with that
practice on talking and that
Start talking if you are shy
Start talking if you can just a little Swedish
Simply, we say in Swedish: "Getting started"
and that means roughly that (you know)
you should start something
you should start something new
Then we say you are going to get started
And I think that, now first
That said, I want to record more videos
So the first thing I think about is, if you are
Maybe beginner, or fairly new with Swedish
and for me it may feel, when i will try to speak in a new language
And I'm nervous, it's like I have a stop
It's like a stop in the throat
and I might be able to say some things that
As I have trained on, like "Hello", "How are you"
But as soon as I try to say something new so ...
So it goes very slowly or it can feel like ...
The head becomes completely empty, it becomes silent
And here it is completely ....
I can't, almost, say anything
So then we want to speak open ....
the mouth and
relaxing you can say
We want to try to relax and start daring to talk a little
And then I think it's important to take it a bit at a time
You can't think, now I'll talk very much
But if you are afraid to talk, if you are nervous to talk
So you have to give up ... small
Challenges
small
tasks
so that today I will say
this
And tomorrow I'll say this,
It could be
(thus) you continue to give you small tasks
that you should say something new
or say a sentence in a new way
that makes you try different sentences
different questions, different answers
okay
This I think then, this is my tip today.
That many of you have teachers.
And do you not have teachers
So maybe you live somewhere
where there is any staff or something.
Any person you meet frequently