Hello Hello
I hope everything is fine with you
I was going to do part 2
In my little series about oral
interaction
So how you can work out
To make a call better
so you
can get longer and more
varied conversations with people
and i think there are some different things you can think about
And work out
To make your calls better
and in the last video I talked a little about
To reflect the other person
to react to what that person
saying so for example say
What fun or what a hard
such things, ie show that you are
Interested, show that you care
what the other person is saying
react with emotions
get involved
in what the other person says
another important
And basic thing
Thinking I am asking questions
so that you ask questions to the other
the person
To make that person tell
more or to check
that you certainly understand what it
The other person says
and this is important to
talk and for social reasons, to get good calls
Get good contact
in Swedish
But it is also important when reading
SFI and SAS and high school courses
the oral interaction, ie
the ability to interact while talking
and create good calls
is important to get grades
In school too
so there are two different
causes or reasons for
Why this is important
and yes, ask people then
So ask questions, I think there is
maybe two different types of questions
and one would then be control issues
verify
what the other says that you have understood
or that the other understands you too
and the other would be more
follow -up questions, ask about
More information, ask for
that the other person should develop
its story or whatever it is
thus obtain more information
Get more details, help
the other to tell more
So control questions
and follow -up questions
and control questions I think can be
Things like "What did you say?"
or what do you mean?"
Or what do you mean by ........
It may be a special word or a
expressions that you do not understand
so you can say, what do you mean by
hm hm hm ;-)
What can it be more for control questions
control issues
it could be
For example, if someone says a place
So you ask, "Ah, is it in Gothenburg?"
Because you are not sure about that place.
*if*
Located in Gothenburg, so you ask a yes/no question
"Is it in Gothenburg?"
or maybe
Was this yesterday?
So you check that you understand what time
As the other is talking about
or it may be
Well, is that your husband?
so that the person
Talking about a person and you ask
Yeah this person you are talking about
Is it your man
So if we think about the grammar
If there is a lot of yes/no questions
Is it in Gothenburg?
Was it yesterday?
Is it your husband?
but also questionword issues such as
What did you say?
What do you mean?
and so on
right
and
Because only this is because
verify
If you have heard correctly or because
get the other to repeat so it is after all
Very important to pronounce
these little phrases right
thus pronounce them with good pronunciation
and to be able to say them quickly, not have to think
And don't have to
say them very slowly, without just
"what did you say?"
“Ah, excuse what did you say?
You have to throw them in quickly.
so that the call continues
If you have to think or pronounce them slowly
or pronounces them so it is difficult to understand them
so the conversation will stop
and it will not be as good a call
So just simple stuff like "What did you say?"
what do you mean?
Can you say it again?
Such issues are great to work out
so that you say them quickly and easily
and good without having to think
It will help you very much
right
and then we had more
Solid questions then
And there are a thousand follow -up questions
The first step is that you understand approximately
what the person is talking about
And then you can ask for more information
or help the other person to
develop
what he or she is talking about
so
a way to make this a little easier for oneself
that might be to think about
person
and place and time
can we start with
so if someone tells you about
A person so you can ask for example
okay what is working
he or she with
What does he work with?
Or maybe "what is he doing now?"
To get some more information
Sometimes it might be relevant to ask
How old is he?
or "How old is she?"
For example, if you
talking about a grandfather or grandmother
Or something like that
or someone's parents, it can sometimes be interesting
To ask: How old is he or she?
You might ask: "Where does he live?"
Where does she live?
such simple stuff that still makes
the conversation continues, someone tells
About her mother, you ask, "Where does she live?"
it shows that
The mother lives in the United States, yeah then
Do you have more things to talk about
And there we were in place also a little neighbor but
If we think a little more in place then it might be that someone
tells: “I was on vacation
in Stockholm"
Okay, where in Stockholm did you live?
So what area
so the person can tell you a little more
or you can ask
- Was it nice there?
- Yeah, yes,
We walked in the Old Town, it was great
Many old houses.
So was it nice there?
You can also just ask
What did you do there?
What did you do in Stockholm?
so
collect on some simple phrases
and questions about location that you can use
When someone tells you about a place they have visited
or been on
and then the same with time then
If someone tells about their life then you can
ask about
Was this when you lived in Italy
Did this happen in your home country?
Was this when you were young?
I don't know, maybe it's a little harder but
It is possible to find questions that fit in a situation
Yes, maybe someone tells them they like
to play guitar, then you can ask
How long have you been playing guitar?
Then maybe the person tells me that "I started when I was a kid"
or my dad taught me playing guitar
When I was seven years old, yes, then you have new
things to talk about, you can ask further
The person can tell you more
Or maybe more
such things as to
Well maybe a student to me tells me about
his childhood in Somalia and then I can ask
Was this when Said Barre
Was president?
- Yeah, that's it ... blah blah blah ...
So then comes more story
the person may come to think of new
things, it won't be
so
A lot of stop
one may use one's imagination
one may use the knowledge you already have
And then you want to get in touch with Swedes
So you have the greater chance of finding good questions
to spin on
If one knows more about the culture
know more about the story
know more about things that interest people
so you have to take it a little step by step
But if you talk, for example, with a person like me
that is 40 years (haha 42 years really)
Yes then there are different historical events, both in terms of politics
and society and culture
which can
be important to me and do you know
some such things, so you can ask about them
and it can come in on time then then
when something happened in mine or
another person's life
good to be able to do things like “childhood”
youth
When you moved away from home
When you started working
in thinking about this so there is
both a lot of words and phrases
and important grammar as yes/no questions
and questionnaire issues
so this might be another way to
study and
approach grammar
by more thinking: “I want to
able to talk better,
Then I need to be able to ask control questions
Then I need this one
the grammar “for example
able to say "what did you say?"
and
What was the other one now, yes/no questions
Is that your man, for example
And then we had ... Want to be able to ask about time
Do I need words like childhood, youth,
when you were little
When you boo in ....
so
This could be a study tip
Take 30 minutes
and so think in place
What questions do I need to be able to ask
about place when I talk to another person
Oh really
simply, to get a good call
so do you need to be able to control
that you have understood
and what the other said for something
what the other means
and you need to be able to ask questions
so that the other tells more
It can also be good to compare with their own language
What questions, which phrases do you use
When you talk to someone in your language
and then try to find similar
or equivalent
questions and phrases and small words
in Swedish
yeah this is nothing you do in a day
It's something you think about and exercise
gradually
man questions and listens and record a little
When you hear something you can use
And then you test and train
and uses many times and
So you learn, more and more
And of course we can discuss here
you can ask, you can comment
you can rewrite
words or phrases you've heard or as you use
you can tip each other in the comments
So please leave a comment, please ask
So I answer
When I have time and have time
so you may have it so good
and we'll see you again soon
bye