It was fun to play badminton.
You threw yourself after each ball!
I fell.
The substrate is so silent.
Try real shoes.
The Chinese are the best in badminton, and they use sock plastic.
-Are you sure about that?
- Or if it was the gymnastics team ...
-Do you want water?
- I've been drinking three liters ...
But a sandwich would be nice!
With the new soft cheese - shrimp, bacon and salami.
It received nice reviews:
- "A perfect cheese symphony."
- Yes, I can try a little.
Now a series about the inland ice begins.
The report is made by a group of Danish researchers.
It took them eight years to compile the material ...
- It's second on all channels.
- What is it wrong with the second?
- They have both series and debates.
- You can get in 20s.
You sound just like Lena.
Set all the channels if you can!
Not needed.
They are preset.
Our host is Thorsten Flinck.
Göran ... thanks!
I had made our way to us.
But I think you should have both.
- I am not so hungry ... —do yourself!
- Do you look over on the cake tomorrow?
-Yes.
First, I wake her up in the morning.
Annika doesn't know so many here.
There is not much to feel.
Most live superficial, empty lives.
Check out - cartoon!
- They drive drawn 24 hours a day.
- How to be able to stay awake?
- Did you get any gift?
- I have built a loom.
At the construction show they showed an English variant.
She looked at it for hours.
- I have tried to build a similar one.
- You are happy that you are not handy!
I'll pick it up now.
I mount it in the living room tonight ...
- Serve if you want carrying help.
- Yes, it's heavy ...
When you offer to help, it means nothing.
It's a phrase that spreads nice atmosphere ...
See you!
Is it certain that they show signed around the clock?
-Certainly.
- And so they say the world is evil!
Gustav looks at the cartoon and laughs
- Gustav, stop!
It's half past twelve!
- Yes ... Now comes the wicked cat!
There he got it!
Right down for the cliff!
My God ... Say what you want about the Jänkarna ... draw, they can!
I am impressed.
Few adults can watch such crap for five hours.
It is fun.
And then you have to learn new things.
- Cousin has a circus.
- He had to sell it ...
I'm not interested!
- Will Göran and Annika come tomorrow?
-Yes.
They come half past eleven.
Did you buy a gift?
No, we have the whole basement full of stuff.
- I got a nice thing from them.
- You have not moved the kit ...
- The description was incomprehensible.
- It was in English.
- Did you know what she gets from Göran?
- The fool has built a loom.
It is really pretty!
Imagine putting so much work down on the one you love.
The important thing is what it is for a gift.
- A wife should get something romantic!
- Yes, what was I getting from you ...
Now we talk about Göran and Annika!
In addition, we needed new winter tires.
Every time she sees the loom, she is reminded of how much he loves her.
When you take a curve without the gossip, you think of me.
It is that thought that exists before taking each other for given ...
I am equally surprised every morning that you remain.
- Where would I be then?
-What do I know?
In the kitchen maybe.
I wake you so you can arrange everything.
I'll listen when you work.
Well ... have you been to Liseberg?
Been run out?
You wanted to see how fast the carousel could go?
What did the class manager say?
He thought it went slowly?
Well ...
Here is as usual.
Annika is celebrating years, so we will celebrate her.
Yes, I greet.
- Puzzlepuss ... - was it max?
Does he have fun?
Think so.
They have been driven out from Liseberg and are going to police interrogation.
- And you pay for that!
- He borrowed money from you.
- Till very favorable interest rates!
Look.
- Oh ... that perfume is great.
- This is almost too much.
- But it's more fun than the loom.
- It is very funny by Göran.
- Well, you didn't say about the doll cabinet.
I do not call two glued plot slopes a dollhouse.
Playing is about using your imagination.
My favorite toy was a regular little pine cone.
In the imagination I turned it into a stone, a spruce cone ...
Very interesting, Gustav, but now they come.
Everyone in place!
No, Gustav, not now!
- Yes!
Happy birthday to you...
- Where's the birthday child?
- It's probably just me.
- Do you decorate that I am unruly?
-Why are you asking that?
I am "romantic as a firewood".
It was good to take in ... a little.
All the gifts I gave her was wrong.
For three months I have talked about the necklace.
And get a loom!
- You stood at the fair and looked at it.
- What would I look like?
Planes ???
I'm tired of planks and nails and building fairs!
It's boring!
Congratulations...
The heating loops that you intend to pull into the bathroom ... Forget them!
Göran ...
- Take these and run her.
- We probably have a bottle of wine too.
- Doesn't it do with the flowers?
-Stop it!
Göran is sorry!
- Are you, Göran?
- Yes, a little, actually.
- The wine is quite expensive ... - pick it up!
- Run after her.
Say how much you like her.
- You might be able to repay this ... - just own!
Anytime.
Heat loops sound exciting ...
Go now ... Health from us.
Yes, what was it you said?
When she sees the loom, she feels loved ...
Take a look at yourself!
How romantic are you really?
I'm very romantic!
Go ahead darling.
- Why do you give me the perfume?
-I love you.
- You had bought it for Annika.
- It was among unproved packages.
Now the cat comes again!
- How is it with Göran and Annika?
- Annika and mom are out and about.
- I have never seen her so angry.
- You know little about their fellow human beings.
They have only been married for a year and should be happy.
- But they live in a nightmare.
- Dad, they have never struggled before.
- It should be a little up and down.
- Help have it calm and nice even!
It applies to everything.
"The road to death is long. Why not travel comfortably?"
Oh my God!
Andy Panda has started!
The bank does not lend so much money anyway.
I would start one in Uddevalla, but then Göran got a job here.
-What are you talking about?
- Annika wants to open a cafe.
Good idea, huh?
Here is theater, museum - boring places that no one goes on!
- A cafe is needed.
- Yes, where you can be seen after school.
There you hear!
It's about time that I chance a little.
The bank may not feel that way.
There is a lot to lock.
You have to have a guarantor who is known on the bank ...
It is already clear.
Look!
- Gustav Svensson?
-Yes.
- Why does your name stand on the paper?
- The investment is idiot safe!
- So you said about the pyramid game too ... - you have to dare to win!
- It as never ... - connect with the clichés now, Gustav!
Make a budget and formulate a business idea -
- So I talk to the bank.
Good cookies, freshly baked buns, good coffee!
Does not work there is no justice in the world!
No, the dark cookies were better.
Try to have more almond paste in the dough.
- Isn't it too sweet then?
- No cake can ever be too sweet.
- How many tables?
- Eight - and you take coffee bread yourself.
Great!
No thick glass top for.
Now the paper is ready.
Have you told Göran that you have mortgaged the house?
They can take the house away from you ...
Göran can build a new one.
- Have you come up with a good name?
-Yes.
It should be called Annika's cafe.
- It took a while to figure out ... - well!
You are Annika and have a cafe.
-Just!
- Two sharp brains in sweet compound.
- What does Göran say?
- I haven't talked to him.
- Don't be angry.
He is sad.
- He should be happy who can build it!
–Wa?
You didn't want his help.
- He does it for free.
- Annika ... - do you not have a cafe to build?
- I was just thinking of showing the color samples.
- Look at the curtains, I've said!
Okay.
Then I start to paint tonight.
Hello.
- I'll be coming soon.
- The chairs should look like in Sköna home.
-Wait!
Have you tried these?
-No.
Sin.
They are really successful.
A little stingy with jam, maybe.
Göran, sit down ...
I know it can be tricky ... I'll tell you a story.
A postman married a nice girl from Örebro.
- He was stately and strong ... - I think I understand.
Continue.
Anyway ... One day she got enough.
She wanted to go out and try something new, something bigger.
Experience a new universe.
- You mean Vivalla Savings Bank?
-Just.
- It was the best thing that could happen.
- She got a new life?
No.
They got 14,500 more a month!
The postman bought a ping pong table ...
It's not about money.
Annika is tired of me.
- Do you find that I'm boring?
- You have many positive qualities.
- Yeah.
Like what?
- You are shooting.
You built a hut for the kids.
You are kind!
- Sick ... what to do with it?
- Göran, listen to me ...
Kind is the finest anyone can be.
Annika knows it too.
That's why she stops, though you are so boring.
You are right, you should do what you are best at.
-Where are you going?
- build the cafe.
-Let me know if you need help.
- Cement mixer ...
That is a courtesy phrase.
But I'll make an exception.
But we eat these first.
The inauguration has already begun.
Where is Lina?
- Lina, we're going!
She is down with Annika at the cafe.
You drove her there.
- Have you forgotten it?
- Yes, there was some in the back seat.
He has had a lot, Göran.
He got help!
I was there for a whole night.
- You fell asleep.
- I took me a bit again.
You slept under the cement mixer.
It was a feat, as it rattled!
Hello.
Aren't you in the cafe?
- I just wanted to ask you to bring these.
- You actually have to wear yourself!
I'm not going.
Greet that I am happy with the years I got with her.
I stick to Borås.
I'll stay with my parents.
Borås - Sweden's most boring city!
If I moved every time I was angry - then I would have lived everywhere!
It is so to be married.
You fight, become the same, watch the sport ...
You don't understand.
We have never quarreled like this.
It is best to be separated.
You should not stick to something that does not work.
Honey, are you here?
People await it at the cafe.
- Release them then.
- Not without you!
How nice you have done.
Good idea with clothes hangers at each table!
These are to you.
You can have them on the counter.
On page 53 in comfortable home ...
-Are you done now?
-Certainly.
I'll just pick up the gift.
It is a cyclop that no one has picked up.
I don't understand ... one divorce, the next day party.
They hug and laugh and eat ...
And eat ... Lena, give me the binoculars.
Let them be in peace, Gustav.
Come to lie down now.
- It was useful for Annika.
–They sees marriage is not so fun
- I don't talk about our marriage.
- We have had our dusts.
- Are you our first big quarrel?
- When the baptismal dress became a hammock?
- Over the honeymoon.
- We could not afford to go abroad!
Södertälje is beautiful in the fall.
- Sin with the cafe ... - They start tearing on Monday.
That she did not suspect anything when the other premises were empty ...
And you should have seen a difference between demolition contracts and leases.
I didn't!
I'm not worried at all.
Café in Vivalla can't fail!
- You got Göran to go to the castle ...?
-Just.
He went on it.
- Dad, I want to go to bed.
- Sell the room on the left ...
- There is something in the way.
-Silent!
It's a gift for mom.
What is it?
A loom.
- Don't say you have dragged it here!
- You thought it was romantic.
It was romantic of him to build it, but I don't want the loom.
- It is going out of my room.
-Lena, place it in max room.
He will certainly be surprised.
SWEDISH SUPPORT: Karin Esevik (C) Swedish Television AB 2000