- Sites it well in the back?
- Giant, old man.
- Why are you going to have a ball?
- It's tradition!
- I remember my first bale.
Lovely!
- Where did you meet Dad?
Get it together!
I was actually there with dad, on the school ball.
I was wearing a blue dress.
- Dad had a sailor costume.
- Sjöman costume?
He did the lump in the fleet and could not afford a coat.
- You would arrange dinner.
- I've done more important things.
I have made my banner for the first train.
What do you say?
- You do not complicate it ... - Now the director's pack will be fit!
Do you have to walk in the train?
It is Sweden's biggest holiday.
Then we stand united and strong and you go out of the houses for our ideals.
- And there is free coffee in the square ... - it's about solidarity!
I'm probably the only one in the family who selflessly puts up on others!
- Do I get half?
-No.
May 1st is for you and your friends to feel important.
It is in the broad layers that the knowledge exists.
Remove all managers for a month, - no one would notice anything.
- So it's not noticeable if I'm gone?
- You do some kind of benefit sometimes.
But take Melander - my boss.
Now he is going on a luxury course again.
Shameful!
- So it didn't sound when you were on course.
- We got something done!
- You won the tip walk!
- And finished second in the karaoke competition.
The post can do without Melander.
You are jealous.
Melander is good.
- Jump down, and we'll see ...
-How nice you look!
Is there anything going on?
- It's a bale, I've said.
- You were invited by little Roger, huh?
- Patrik.
His name is Patrik.
Roger is ten years old and collects frogs.
- What fun that Patrik offered you!
- Strange.
He looks normal.
Add, max.
Follow!
I have to have someone to train drums with.
- Mom, say something!
- Help your sister.
- She can help you with something she can.
-What then?
Chewing chewing gum, read the Weekly Review ...
- Are you our first ball?
- It was nice.
Then you were nervous.
I asked your father for permission to escort you to the ball.
- What was he saying?
- "May I see you again ..."
- But you ignored that. - Yes!
Because I loved you!
Should I cook dinner, vacuuming and disk -
- Or go away and play poker?
I just wanted to check out.
Where is Dad somewhere?
He would drive us to school.
He cycles with the post.
Something has emerged.
- A tractor ... - have you read the test?
-Yes!
-Is it true?
- The truth is relative.
- It is concrete:
If you have not read the test, you will be adopted.
-Finally!
We'll be too late!
- ATTACK, wait, wait, wait ...
- Melander is gone now this week.
- The children have to go ...
Guess ... Guess who he has appointed his deputy manager.
- It's not true ... - Yes!
- Children, your dad is the manager!
- Do you understand what this means?
-Yes.
Vivalla will be without mail.
Go out, I have to talk to dad.
- Have you thought through this?
It is a week.
Melander has prepared everything.
- It takes care of itself.
- Why are you going to be a manager?
- There is fun!
- You get any longer there without compensation!
I get some managerial privileges.
- The key to the candy machine.
- Gustav!
Yes, yes ... now I have to try everything I wanted.
- Sita in Melander's room and sleep?
- Feel what it's like to be a manager!
- You said managers were superfluous.
- I was slightly categorical ...
I've never tried.
I was not elected student council chairman.
It was a difference.
They wanted someone who was a little more ...
-What then?
-Normal.
I had a clear political will!
You roared, "Vote for me and you should be liberated!"
It was such times!
Che Guevara, Student Revolution ...
- Do you recover 20 years of disappointment?
-No.
I think I can achieve something.
Congratulations then, the postmaster!
But now the kids are waiting in the car ...
Let them wait.
I will call home and tell me that I have become a manager.
Mother...
-Hello boss?
Did they obey you?
- It was a bit sneaky.
But thanks to my experience, I was able to quickly solve the problem.
- A strap loosened from a bag.
- I don't think you are a manager!
Strange things have happened.
Yes, there will be some talking pig somewhere in the United States.
Are you not proud of me?
I got a trust assignment too.
- To fill in toilet paper?
- Looking through this one.
- And that was important.
-What is it?
I haven't listed that yet.
I may ask mom.
- How does it go with the bale?
- I and Patrik - that's too good ...
Think positive!
Look at me, just.
Now I'm the manager!
Soon you will be a postman again.
I haven't dared to say a word to Patrik - and then he invites me!
- As long as you don't talk, you're okay!
- Max, be kind to your sister!
Sorry ... do you want?
Watch, the boss sits and reconscents.
How has it gone for you?
- Good, just good.
–Okey, Max.
Now you have to lead.
- You dance in the wrong direction all the time!
- It's your duty to bring me right!
Funny that no gems came away, that no paper got stuck in the copier ...
Stop teasing!
Melander gave me an important assignment.
I haven't realized what.
This is a regular work schedule.
It is needed for salary payment.
My salary is in the account every month.
That's all you have to know.
- I go through this for you.
-Thanks.
-Where are you going?
- At the Grand Meeting.
Melander sometimes has.
He goes through what can be improved ...
- I have some thoughts and ideas ... - Don't make up now, Gustav.
You will be boss all your life.
I just want to take the opportunity to enjoy.
-Okay, I understand.
Take care, you!
- It's a black limousine outside!
- Do you feel for something about it?
- No, I ordered a white.
- But it rolls well anyway.
Bye!
- Mom, you have to ...
I know what to say!
Now it's Monday.
On Friday it is as usual.
-See you then!
-Good luck!
- How is the election training going?
- They are in the fine.
Kossa you can be yourself!
- Gustav seems to thrive in the managerial role.
- He goes around in limousine and waves.
Yes, it's ridiculous.
But it's fun to go in it.
It has everything.
Yesterday we watched TV and ate salty sticks.
- Isn't it expensive with driver?
- Yes, but it is Gustav who pays.
Tomorrow is the postal cycle again ...
He is doing right.
Far too few dare to live out their dreams.
- I wrote a poem about it once ... - I think Lena understands the message.
Nämen ... you will be the queen of the ball!
- Mitt necklace fits perfectly!
- Patrik is coming soon.
- Have you seen my gold earrings?
- I will see what I have.
-How does it feel?
- Maybe you should stay home ...
- Yes, a new dick begins.
- Lina probably doesn't mean seriously.
- Health the family!
- thank you, director.
- Are our nice neighbors here?
- Wogs up nice clothes!
-Thanks.
Pure wool.
- I thought you loved your uniform.
Last week!
If you want to get somewhere, you have to dare to develop.
These I think fit ... - But Gustav!
-You look nice!
- Have you never seen a suit before?
Yes, but never on you.
Now we have to go.
- Gustav, we got no post this morning.
Rune has not received post in several days.
- I must punish the culprit.
- Easch, we will surely get it tomorrow.
You are very cute!
Do you want something?
Money, sweets, wisdom?
Tut!
Patrik is here!
What should I do?
- A tip is to go out and say hello.
- Good idea.
-Bye Bye.
If you want to be picked up, call!
I send Karlsson!
You are good looking in a suit.
You should have that more often.
- For 4,000 you get some quality.
–4,000?
Can you afford it?
- There is a lot of money on the post!
- ART ... what are you saying?
There is a lot of money on the post.
The manager cannot walk around in a uniform.
- Gustav, have you taken money?!
- Melander was very clear, he said:
- Use resources to their own head.
- And tomorrow he chops off it!
It's not that dangerous.
It is well deductible, something that managers have ...
You can get fired!
Take it easy.
Melander encourages private ideas.
He becomes happy.
Look at me.
Do you really think that Melander will be happy?
Happy may not be the right word.
But a little surprised!
- It always goes overboard.
-Sorry.
I rushed away.
You would just make sure everything floated.
I know, but I was so inspired.
When I entered the office, I felt that everything was possible.
It costs you your savings capital.
You talk about the honest employee - and then you behave like this!
I have tried to pursue an active personnel policy.
If you knew what I've invested in the staff!
I have ordered a mini golf course and I have bought a courtyard.
-What did you say?
- A mini golf course and a courtyard.
Gustav, tomorrow you cancel the track, and sell the farm.
- Then we can only pray to God!
- I wonder if one's God can help.
The staff has been a bit off.
They have resigned.
Have they resigned?
How many?
42 with the caretaker.
Do you mean that all employees in the post have resigned?
They got annoyed when I changed a bit and wanted them to rotate.
-"Rotate"?
- Switch task.
Pettersson got to try something new.
The guys were allowed to sit in the cash register.
The part -time stands got the morning tours.
- Is that no one got any post?
- People may write fewer letters!
- How much mail has not been distributed?
- I made an estimate this morning ...
–Inchy ... and ... –What?
–4,000 letters, 250 packages.
-Where are you going?
- I have eleven hours - I have time.
-No...
Nobody can!
I may be the world's worst manager -
- But is a seven -half postman!
8,000 people have gathered at Norra Bantorget.
The LO manager gives speeches at 15. We will return then.
-Where is Dad?
- Hos Melander.
- Melander is pretty angry, huh?
- If he does not, we must look in the lake.
Do not be sad.
Rals is difficult.
It's Max's wrong!
Had I had some good to practice, it would never have happened!
- Small accidents happen constantly.
- But not everyone tear the buffet table ...
I didn't think he would let me go.
- Not those who took roast beef either ... - didn't you get any more dance with Patrik?
He offered ... but I didn't want to ruin the coat with potato salad.
Gustav ... how has it been?
Melander was impressed that I distributed 4,000 letters in 11 hours.
- What did he say about the other?
-Which?
- That 42 people resigned ... - he touched it a little neighbor.
-What did he say then?
–Fa see ... it was a lot ...
The keywords were fools, kill ...
... repeated again and move from Vivalla.
But my work schedule was the best and most thoughtful he has seen.
–Wh's work schedule?
- Mitt ... our ... okay - yours.
- Health and thank you.
-Now I have to go.
- You have cycled ten miles.
-It does not matter.
My workmates are waiting for the square and then I line up!
- What should we do with him?
- They lower shark cages in the ocean ...
If there is a batter he is bad out ...
Lina Svensson.
Yes, okay.
- It was Patrik.
- Yeah ... are you going to pay the dry cleaning?
-No.
He wonders if we should be together.
- What did you say then?
-I do not know.
Heard anyone what I said?
-No sorry...
I have to call ...
How fun!
Have you met Patrik?
Gustav hit him in the head with a stone when he palled apples.
- Hi, have you forgotten something?
- I stand over this year's first train.
- You were waiting for the square.
- They waited outside.
Shouldn't you join them?
They have a banner that I can't put on.
"Death to the overflower Gustav Svensson!"
We hide in the basement!
SVT Program Sewing: Karin Esevik