You have to stop eating in bed!
Here are the plates I was looking for.
- Someone is in the sauna.
-What is this?!
A meatball mask!
Set it!
Did Max gave me this one for me to do away with it?
You will notice that on the neighbors tomorrow when you pick up the magazine.
Think, tomorrow is New Year's Eve.
16 of our years together are coming to an end.
You think we should re -evaluate how we have had it and how we should have it.
Yes, I think it's important.
I want to know.
How do you look at the future?
I look at the future much like I see on a painting:
Don't know what it represents, who made it ... and is not interested.
- Yeah.
How old are you?
–37.
You are 43. And the average life expectancy for a Swedish man is 74 years old.
- You have lived more than half your life.
- Have you so much further left then?!
Tappations
Come in, max.
Do you want to lie with us?
- No thanks, it is not necessary.
- Hi, we don't bother?
- Do Göran and Annika keep in our room?
- We have to ask you again.
Don't you want to come to a party tomorrow?
It's nice, but the New Year's evenings are sacred.
Please!
You were the first we met here, and Gustav was so helpful!
- ni mixes him with someone ... –OVa Uddevalla - friends come.
- We want them to meet you.
- It sounds pretty nice.
Come on now!
They want to know who you are and what you look like.
Should we lend our photo album?
- Come, Göran.
It's no idea.
- No ... - sorry we disturbed.
- Good night on you.
Hello.
-Hello!
-Now I'm ashamed.
They like us.
- Why are they fucking in the middle of the night then?
Good night.
- Don't eat it.
- I just have to hold it.
Call, watch ... Call, clock, call ...
Good morning Dad.
How can you eat ribs and mimosa salad now?
It's my family's New Year's breakfast for generations!
With new spice this year!
-What then?
Thinner?
- Thai Curry.
Grandfather said that a life without adventure is not worth it!
- He was also a postman, huh?
–And that you and Max will also be.
Dad, may I ask one thing?
Was your life that you had imagined?
-Yes actually.
Exactly.
-Is it true.
I've got everything I wanted.
A wife and two children who love me.
A work where everyone loves me.
- Then you have to say congratulations ... - waver ... you ponder on the future.
You do this in your age.
But my grandfather taught me something before he died.
To open a sardine can with one hand.
He looked me in the eyes and said, "Do you no hopes".
- "Then you will never be disappointed."
-How horrible!
And that's why I've done the opposite.
You have to believe that everything is possible!
If I find something I want to do, you help me?
- Yes, in 15 years you want to move.
- Should I move when I'm 30?
It is not useful to stay home anymore.
But we don't throw you out!
Good morning...
Surely we can celebrate the twelve in the square?
- It seems fun as a change?
-No.
Have we celebrated here for 16 years ...
--... So we should find something new.
-They are waiting!
-What are you talking about?
- We will eat at Göran and Annika.
- For you have made ribs ... –Anika has baked pallets.
-Never in my life!
- Come, kids.
If I have eaten this food for 16 years, I'll do it today too!
Or in the mornings.
- We will go soon.
- We don't like Aunt Karin.
She doesn't like you either.
But on New Year's Eve, the family drinks coffee there.
- I would rather stay home.
-Me too!
Uncle Hans smells bad.
Yes.
Dad is allowed to sit next to him.
Go and change!
Put on a dress, rope.
Good that you came.
We will buy flowers on the road.
Why do you look like that?
This New Year's Eve we will do something new.
- Close us as Norwegian opponents?
- No ... ski.
-I get it.
- That I want to not have to go?
- Every year you try to get away!
- What stupid you look!
- I try to avoid aunt Karin.
- Once a year is not so dangerous!
- She gets so much fun when you come.
- She doesn't recognize us!
- Last year I was "Mr. Lagerwall".
- I can't go ...
You never have to meet Aunt Karin anymore.
- You should not regret it!
- Mom, we go if you want.
- No, in two minutes Ivanhoe will start.
- I am the only one who has ideas!
- You only find things you like.
- Now I understand nothing!
I buy skis, spruce - and video even though I don't know how it works.
- Everything for you to enjoy it!
- We should do things together, we four.
Or just you two.
It's hard to be a father.
We want to protect the material standard.
- And the mail hat I got in Christmas?
- You like clothes ...
Beautiful father and daughter's relationship!
- She is souring for her to live at home.
- Moving is natural development!
Then they told the EU.
Now we go to Aunt Karin.
She does not jaw against.
- It's because she's deaf.
- Come, Lina.
Dad has cleared clearly.
That we have to go through the same procedure every year!
- What did the fireworks cost?
- The main thing is that it becomes beautiful.
- What did they cost?
- Think when we look out ...
What did the cursed rockets cost?
Two thousand ... but then you got your majesty on the purchase ...
- What did you get, you said?
-Your Majesty.
The only thing in the county.
No one has dared to buy it before.
It goes 1 km up and explodes in a cascade of colors.
- It's deadly!
- A greeting to everyone in Vivalla.
It was nice with Aunt Karin.
It's about inviting yourself.
As she hugged you today!
What did you say?
- I was Prince Bertil.
- The main thing is that you had a good time.
I invited her to the fox hunt.
And you got packages!
- Two sacks and a sudde rubber.
- Yes ... there you see.
- You then, Lina?
This.
A mixture between a Lovikkavante and a pot.
Well ... Time to make in order.
Lina can help mom with the food.
- What is it?
- Hummer and champagne.
No - shrimp and Christmas must as usual.
Max, help me with the firing ramp.
- Hi, Gustav.
-No...
- We can't go to your party.
Go home.
- Göran and I want to talk to you.
- Jobbly!
I'm waiting outside.
- We have to ask ...
You have not been able to come to any party.
Don't you like to spend time with us?
We cannot come today because we have other plans.
And it can happen more times.
It would be a shame if the friendship was destroyed because we cannot be honest.
You are right in that. We should be able to say anything to each other!
Nice that you say so, Gustav!
- What thin -haired you have become.
–Wa?
I feel I can say that now.
The flint is visible.
-Come now.
- We would be honest.
And it was stupid.
Happy new year everyone!
- I have to do something.
- It's nothing you can do.
- It delays before it falls off.
- I have to do something now!
Annika!
The plates we got this morning, they were dry!
Great!
- There she sees what honesty means!
How she can get up after that, I don't understand that.
- Well, old man, are you satisfied now?
- I wanted to be there at twelve.
- No one was there!
- Yes, Fill - Ragnar was there.
Okay, now sit down on the couch, and I'll tell you.
Well ... First, I'll ask you: Do you notice something special?
- Yes, a ketchup spot on the jacket.
- It's chili sauce.
- Do you mark something else?
- Do we not use TV?
Right!
It is now in the garage.
We'll do something that I dreamed of!
- See on TV in the garage?
-No...
TV - N has taken up too much of our precious time.
Tonight we will talk to each other.
Sit down!
Everyone has to invite a little!
On New Year's Eve, I thought you wanted to watch TV.
Calm down, I record everything.
Who feels urged to start?
Anyone want to tell you about a New Year's promise?
Or something fun to tell?
The word is free!
- It seems nice at Göran.
- Max!
- Okay, I can start.
At work on Monday, someone had carried the binders to the conference room.
We had to help carry them back.
Yes, yes ... there you see.
This can happen in the office.
Thanks, Lena ... - Anyone else who happened to something lately?
Okay, then I can tell you something.
In the post, many people think that we should put the cover material on data.
That's certainly good.
You win time.
-What are you doing?
-We are talking!
What do you dream about, Max?
About that there is peace and that the school burns down.
Then we keep our thumbs for it.
- And you?
About standing in the square in a few hours.
I can crush that dream right away.
- Yes ...
- This is going well, dad ... - What do you think of such a night?
-Should I be honest?
-Obvious!
-What are you going to say?
- You probably expect it.
Max, help me pull in TV - n.
- You prepare the supper.
- Table the shrimp, you mean?
- Get the peanut rings and the must.
Shrimp directly from the Arctic Ocean to you ...
... via six months in Konsum's freezer counter.
Imagine, it's strange ... of all millions of shrimp in Antarctica water -
- Ports this one on my plate.
I wonder if it was predetermined.
- It may be on the packaging ... - This is important!
Is this important?
Maybe not.
Give me the chili mayonnaise!
- Where is Max?
- I don't think he wants shrimp.
Something happened when we set up the rockets - he wanted to be for himself.
Don't leave him alone when he starts thinking!
How many shrimp should we add to the max?
Eight?
Four?
Three...
Little old man, are you here?
Why don't you get down to us?
How did you have it before I and Lina were born?
Was it more fun?
The old man ... It is clear that everything became more fun when you arrived.
At least more difficult.
You get a lot to think about ... Why do you ask?
Time goes by so fast.
I remember the summer when I was six years old.
- I thought you could swim!
-It's not that.
Everything was so easy.
We played on the beach, went up and ate and then we could go and play again.
You can still play as much as you want!
No!
Soon I start high school and then everything is over.
I have to get girlfriend -
- Appeal Roll - On and play drums in some band.
You think too much.
At your age you do not want to become an adult.
You learn.
- You can't fight against?
- That life takes one where it wants.
- To a townhouse in Vivalla?
-Why not?
I have two wonderful kids, and a man who is okay ...
- Dad has soon eaten the shrimp!
- Take them up!
And Dad.
The shrimp is enough.
Max ... once when I was little and low and thought like this ...
--... Then Dad said something very wise.
-What then?
"Go to sleep"?
"Life is always next to you and you can do whatever you want with it."
- Here we come with all the shrimp!
- Watch down, so we eat.
- Mums!
- How is it, max?
Are you sad?
- No, it's better now.
-Good.
I'll make you really happy!
- Should you go again?
-No.
You have longed, and this year ...
You should light up at the fireworks!
- I'm standing next to them all the time.
That's probably what mom is afraid of ... Three shrimp left.
I can take them!
-Okay, give me another bottle.
- What are you doing?
Fixes the champagne.
- Selection de Loire and our bag!
- It can't be drinked.
Well, you can mix it with Trocadero.
- They have started to postpone the rockets!
- Max, matches!
And your Majesty!
- You look best from the bedroom.
-Exciting!
That they can ... What is so fun?
That it slams?
- It has to do with masculinity.
- You mean it's idiotic?
Happy New Year!
I will be nagging dad so you can go on a language trip.
I'll nag so he buys the necklace for your birthday.
Wouldn't you postpone the rocket?
- Did it stay nice?
- It was hard to see.
- Were you satisfied?
Well ... a little buttocks it felt.
It went way too low ...
-Happy New!
- Where was anyone injured?
No, everyone got out.
- Majesty took a round in their kitchen.
- I had to extinguish.
But the smoke remains ...
- Nice, we got to celebrate anyway!
-Come in!
Here are our friends from Uddevalla.
- Here is Gustav, Lena, Max and Lina.
Funny that you came.
Remove the champagne.
If there is too little bubbles then there is a soft drink machine.
Happy New Year!
Maybe we should promise one and the other for the next New Year.
- No fireworks!
- And no ribs for breakfast.
- and lobster instead of shrimp!
- And we celebrate the twelve in the square.
Great idea!
We can invite them home, and we are celebrating here.
- bowl for a new year!
- Hope it will be as good as last.
Try to think positively!
HAPPY NEW YEAR!
SVT Program Sewing: Karin Esevik