Hello everyone!
Today I will vaccinate.
Today I will get my first syringe, my first vaccine dose against Covid-19.
I booked time through an app called ...
This is how I did.
I log in with the band ID.
Reserve
I choose ...
After I have booked a time, I get a confirmation via SMS.
In Sweden, it is free to vaccinate against Covid-19.
Now it's my turn.
Now I'll go in.
I put on mouth protection.
Now I have vaccinated myself.
Now I have got my first syringe.
Now I have received my first vaccine dose against Covid-19.
Now I'm waiting for the second syringe, the other vaccine dose.
I have received an information sheet that I will read at home.
It blows so much!
I got a card to remember.
When should you vaccinate?
Have you already vaccinated yourself?
Write in comments!
Thank you so much for watching!
See you in the next movie!
Bye!