Hello everyone!
Spring is here!
It's time to clean.
You can clean spring, inside.
You can clean out.
We will clean the yard today.
at the neighborhood yard
all together
All neighbors on our street should clean.
Come along!
This is our neighborhood farm.
to do outdoors
to do indoors
We clean weeds.
The children also want to help.
The children help.
We pick rubbish.
We clean and clean.
I rake on the gravel plane.
I pick old leaves.
We cut the grass.
She cuts the grass.
She likes to help.
She has a bucket.
She throws the grass in the container.
He has a saw.
He saws.
What is he doing?
They cut branches.
After work we grill.
We grill.
Now everything is fixed and clear.
It is fixed and clear in the yard.
Look how nice it has become!
Thanks for watching!
See you in the next movie!
Bye!