Art - or weirdness?
Sweden's art history is part of the huge story of our country.
With some selected impacts, we will show art that depict changes -
–And Creation power.
An evidence that the guts were artists with incomparable fantasy-
-And the ability to design, make up the Gothic Image Stones -
- Being carved animals and humans form an exciting time chronicle.
These have been in a group of maybe five picture stones in the same place.
I imagine it is an old meeting place.
There you have met, and also traditionally stories and stories -
- Supported by these.
In this way it's like a day's hometown -
-Or a television program, where you get to know about knowledge and learn things.
Maybe they were like the Vikings Television - the picture stones.
Just like this you are looking at.
You try to learn something, understand.
"What would I have done?"
In many ways, they were obviously like us.
They sought the same explanations.
They wanted to explain phenomena, through something that we would perceive as religion-
- But they probably didn't make a difference, as we do today.
We produce religion when it is a wedding.
For them it was constantly present.
Therefore, it is difficult to draw boundaries between everyday life, a practical life -
- And a religious, sacred life.
The Viking Age is a good time for Sweden, from the 7th century to the 12th century-
- With both trade and looting, and new influences from other cultures.
An image stone is just pictures, no text.
So what they really mean is up to us to interpret.
Like this famous scene - a man on an altar, stung by spear.
It looks like a execution - with a bird over, which is associated with death.
This stone is to tell a story about the King's daughter Hild-
–And how she sets it in different contexts -
- And the families are putting together.
One problem we have with these is that you have looked at the pictures -
- Out of the Icelandic fairy tales, above all.
Then you have also seen scenes from them, but you must probably be open to -
- That this can also be personal pictures.
Yes, maybe it's a kind of diary about someone's adventure and death.
There are also larger scenes that describe a world view -
- And an explanation for everything.
On this stone, the very largest -
- We have something that we have perceived as the world tree here in the middle.
This would then be the earth.
Then we have what we believe are opposites, sunrise and sunset -
- And the sun in zenit at the top.
Then we get a situation where we have the world here -
- Sol rise, the sun that stands in zenit, and then it goes down -
- And gets picked up by the Night Ship, which is rowing where the sun will rise again.
So we get an explanation on the cosmos.
I imagine this much like the world of science in the 400s.
So, it is art.
It is.
It is a way of expressing oneself.
We see it, that the Viking Age is very artistic.
This is someone who has wanted to shape events.
If there are texts in Iceland, the pictures are here.
It is a very good way of expression.
Many of the stories are long.
They can be 30, 40 verses.
Here you can see scenes using only four, five pictures.
Key scenes give us the whole story - provided people can.
Therefore, I think it is a place where you meet, tells -
–And trading to the next generation -
- The legends, stories and myths that are important to life.
Texting: Sarah Lundin (C) Swedish Television AB 2023