Art - or weirdness.
Sweden's art history is part of the huge story of our country.
We will with some impacts show art-
- As depicts changes and creation power.
Between Viking Age and Christianity, our art history takes a huge leap.
New techniques and strong influences from the south -
-In the 12th century artwork like this.
Hallelujah!
This is top notch -
- In our European art historical canon.
That it is well -preserved polychromy is unique.
A polychromy usually does not last long -
-But do so with the right conditions for these 12th century techniques.
This Jesus figure's polychromy - thus several different colors -
- Has stayed intact for almost 900 years.
The blue color is Lapis Lazuli, noble stone from Amu-Darja in Afghanistan-
-Imported to the Nordic countries in the 12th century.
Hemsö church is almost unchanged since the end of the 12th century-
- With absid, cows and long houses.
Crucifix was made on measurement.
We see in the church what an important role it had.
Now Christianity has been seriously broken.
Churches are built everywhere.
The Jesus image - the crucifix - may cost almost anything.
It is genuine gold that has been used on the lumbar.
It is simply leaf gold -
- As applied with the help of oil.
An oil gilding with genuine gold.
It is an artistic way of expression that shows the triumphant Christ.
He triumphs over death.
So this is the arc in which we have Jesus placed.
And we note: Jesus lives on the cross.
The eyes are open.
He looks down at us.
Yes, down here we wear people.
The ironworks develop in the 12th century.
The church and the king strengthen their power and the population is growing.
If you want to find the art you have to look in the churches.
We have now arrived until the end of the 13th century.
100 years after the crucifix we saw in Hemse.
We are here facing an entire calf group.
The place is the Calvary Mountain where Jesus was crucified.
Calvary group is the same word.
And here we get the entire release.
We get the background to Jesus' crucifixion.
To the left we see two figures that are naked -
- And stands and munch on apples.
We see how the snake winds around the tree -
- And the head of the snake that has become human.
This figure has a royal crown.
But now many crucifix is changing.
The living Jesus becomes the suffering Jesus.
The crown of thorns, the torture tool, shows up on his head.
When the crown of thorns becomes modern, it happens that you let a such thing -
- And pushes it outside the royal crown, so you get the new one too ...
... it sounds a bit anachronistic - the "fashion detail".
But here Jesus still has the royal crown, as in Hemse.
And this one is made of metal, so it's an exclusive presentation.
On the continent there is occasional crucifix with ring that we have at Gotland -
- But nothing that is as conceptual, as a whole concept, as here-
- What is unique.
Texting: Karin Esevik Swedish Television AB 2023