Russian attacks with hypersonic robots
And fierce battles around the Bachmutka river, which is described as a death zone.
The Wagner leader is fighting double battles.
One in Bachmut and one against the Russian military leadership.
What does the future look like for Prigozjin?
He paints himself and the Wagner group as the only ones who can fight
And the rest of the army as quite useless.
The war this week deepens the latest news development in the Ukraine war.
Cruise robots and kamikazavaters
should have been fired against several Ukrainian cities during the week
Kiev, Dnipro, Odessa and Charkiv, among others.
The Russian attacks, which appear to have been directed at infrastructure facilities
contained unusually many hypersonic robots
According to the UK Defense Ministry.
They go several times the speed of the sound and are then so fast
and can make course changes during the journey.
Ukraine currently has nothing that can shoot these down.
Once they have received the latest variant of the Patriot robots, the same as we have
Is there a reasonable chance to do it.
But how many of this most modern type of robots have Russia?
Tragically, we will probably see how many they have.
After a night of Russian attacks, the power supply was broken
To the nuclear power plant in Zaporizjzja.
Let me remind you that it is the largest nuclear power plant in Europe
As for the sixth time relying on diesel -powered emergency generators.
Since September, the Russian-occupied nuclear power plant produces no electricity
But all six reactors must be cooled down to prevent meltdown.
For over ten hours, the power plant was driven by reserve generators
before the power came back.
It is a dice throw every time.
If we let it happen time and time again, one day the happiness will turn around.
The Wagner Group has taken control of most of the eastern Bachmut.
At the same time, Ukrainian forces have destroyed important bridges over the Bachmutka river
in the central parts of the city.
The river now marks the front line in the bloody battles
According to the British Department of Defense, which describes the area as a death zone.
It is difficult to go over watercourses if they are larger than a ditch.
It makes it not unusual
That there will be fierce battles precisely at this type of terrain.
But will the Russians, in this case, over the river
It becomes very difficult for the Ukrainians to push them back on the other side.
Therefore, for example, this river is very important for the Ukrainian defense.
Battle of Bachmut has been going on for eight months
And is described as decisive by both Ukraine and Russia.
If Bachmut falls, many Russian soldiers will be full.
They will go down in the basements
Where the wine producers store their sparkling wine.
This celebration will also rely in Russia.
This will then be the first slightly bigger victory
Then on July 3 when you took Lysytjan.
I do not think it will lead to a greater operational breakthrough
where one gets the opportunity from Russian side
To advance on to Kramatorsk and Slovjansk.
Because here I think the Ukrainians have prepared defense lines.
Wagner leader Jevgenij Prigozjin is fighting double battles right now.
One at the front in Bachmut and one against the Russian military leadership.
Prigozjin has complained that he is not receiving ammunition
And the support he needs.
He says at the same time that only they have managed to succeed on the Russian side.
So he paints himself and the Wagner group as the only ones who can fight
And the rest of the army as quite useless.
And then also complains on the middle layer
That is, at the General Staff General General Gerasimov and the Minister of Defense.
Who then is the chief of general staff that Prigozjin is fighting?
Gerasimov, which in January was appointed new commander
for Russia's war against Ukraine.
He is an establishment figure and has been with a long time
and the Ukrainian General Chief of Staff Zaluzjnyj
says they have read all Gerasimov's writings.
Thus a military thinker
Who has held that position for a very long time and is respected.
Prigozjin has repeatedly criticized the Russian military rule
And it is speculated that he is trying to strengthen his political position.
Prigozjin is an old prisoner who by keeping up with catering
to the Russian army and to Putin has been given a position
Where he has built up this private army, so these are completely different figures.
Thus an established general, an officer who has risen in the degrees
And a prisoner who has created its own private army.
It is a very interesting power struggle.
But it could, if I dare to speculate, be so that prigozjin
that has gained its power from Putin
Perhaps it is easier to get rid of than the establishment figure Gerasimov.
According to US calculations
30,000 of the Wagner Group's Lego soldiers were injured or killed during the war.
Is it time to figure out Jevgeny Prigozjin?
The information that Prigozjin now says is supported by what we see on the ground.
That you do not shoot as much artillery from Wagner or the Russian side.
They probably don't get that much ammunition.
Then the question is whether he has any particularly bright future.
Either it goes well for him
that he establishes himself as a power factor and creates a political army.
Or that he is challenged.
Because he's located near the front
Is it possible that he could suffer a tragic accident there.
This is how you have done before with managers from 2014 in Donbas.
Poland may become the first country to send fighter flights to Ukraine.
This can happen within the next four to six weeks.
It is about the Soviet fighter aircraft model me -29
Which Poland has 28 pieces.
After Ukraine was promised a hundred tanks of the West
Is it now fighter flights that are at the top of the wish list.
An American surveillance drone of model Reaper
has overthrown in the Black Sea after a collision with Russian fighter aircraft.
It came so close to the drone that the propeller was damaged.
White House describes the Russian action as “dangerous and unprofessional”
At the same time as Russia denies that they have been in contact with the drone.
Instead, they accuse the United States of flying too close to the Crimean Peninsula.
Right now it seems that this is getting a diplomatic consequence.
Thus, diplomatic consequences, rather than any form of military.
Ukraine has a lack of ammunition
and in American scranton, nearly 8,000 km from the front
Walks this weapon factory at high speed.
We run full two shifts.
We have a third shift too.
We are running five six days a week.
Pentagon has given US weapons factories on assignment
To equip and increase the production of 155 mm artillery ammunition.
From 170,000 like this in 2021 to over one million a year next year.
Without constant supplement with ammunition and other supplies from the West
Can't Ukrainian Army continue and fight the way you do.
Then the intensity goes down and we end up in a war war clearer.
One must also on the Ukrainian side build up stock
For what you say is the upcoming spring offensive.
When tanks, combat vehicles or artillery should work for
to continue to free the country.
Texting: SVT Language & Accessibility Swedish Television AB 2023