Saturday's brutal terrorist attack from Hamas against Israeli civil targets
have aroused upset all over the world.
But this is a sensitive issue.
So sensitive that Swedish otherwise so stable news readers will panic.
This is Israel, the bright field.
There are also two areas here
Where Palestinians have more or less influence and rule.
I'm not going to go into it in detail - it's sensitive.
Thanks, Anders Kraft.
- There wasn't much power in that, just Anders.
I'm not going to review journalists.
Going into detail is sensitive.
But I understand you, Anders.
Treads wrong on this question
is it easy to be accused of being Islamophobic or anti -Semit
Or if you are really customer: both.
It is very sensitive
And that's why we look at how this terror has been condemned in Sweden.
We start at the far right.
The civilized world stands behind Israel's right to defend itself.
We must be crystal clear that we are behind Israel at this moment.
We should freeze aid to Palestine immediately.
The Swedish right has longer had a pro-Israeli attitude.
SD has wanted a little back and forth in the Jewish issue.
But the Sosses have been more pro-Palestine since Palme
But now it has sounded like this:
It is important that the world speaks with a voice
both in condemning Hamas attack
And be clear that Israel has a legal right to defend itself.
When such a terrible thing happens
The Sosses must temporarily put away the Palestinian shawl.
Or shawl ... it's probably more a kind of scarf.
No scarf anyway.
The sisters in all glory - those who have really made it their thing
We find to support Palestine at the far left.
What did Nooshi Dadgostar say about this terrorist act?
We see an escalation.
In order not to be a carnage, a ceasefire is required.
Now the violence and attacks must cease.
Of course, this also applies to Israel.
Look there, it was well pragmatic.
Sure, she mentioned dutifully Israel's responsibility, but balanced.
A classic example of two thoughts in the head at the same time.
But you know what left -wing parties think about two things at the same time?
They are not fond.
One thought, otherwise it will be super -messy up here.
On Twitter, Nooshi was even clearer: "Terrible attack by Hamas."
"I condemn all crimes against civil and international law."
Sorry, nooshi.
Which party do you think you lead?
A reasonable party that reacts with reason?
No!
You lead the Left Party.
What do you think will happen?
The internal criticism came as a letter on the post, though on Facebook.
Ekot has taken part in posts in a Facebook group for members of V
where a number of people are critical to
that Nooshi Dadgostar chooses to condemn Hamas attacks against Israel
Without at the same time making a statement in support of the Palestinian people.
Many people in V felt compelled to mark here.
Not against Hamas, but against Nooshi.
Party mates rage and call this everything from populism
to bad double standards.
Municipal politician Björn Alling thinks Nooshi "licking Sionistörö".
Sioniströv is apparently not Kosher for Björn Alling.
He came up with two simple wishes:
Nooshi's departure and abolition of the state of Israel.
Departure seems to be, but not for that bear had intended.
In the afternoon the message came that the Left Party's party board
started an exclusion process against Björn Alling.
Sad for Björn, but he has great support within the party.
It has been started a name gathering against his exclusion
which over a hundred party mates have written on.
Remember that these are people who had been standing in Manhattan 9/11
Seen the plan hit the towers and demanded that Nooshi resign.
Not from the mediocre Arab pilots, but the US war crime.
Today, on eleventh September?
Can't you wait until September twelve?
But the question remains:
What would Hamas have to do to make nooshi mildly condemn terror
Without getting internal criticism?
To answer that, I have taken the help of this old can.
It is a left critic calculator it works canon.
I am entering data over Hama's terrorist act
And so it calculates if Nooshi can condemn it without internal criticism.
It's a bit complicated, but this is an old faithful.
It has been with Lars Werner's time.
It still smells of wine.
You don't have to applaud your computer.
It has no feelings.
Applaud me.
We start with this weekend's deed:
"The worst day of Jewish slaughter since World War II."
And then I press the "Nooshi condemns" button.
Then it is internal criticism.
It wasn't terror enough.
Then it still works.
We try something stronger.
I find some evil Hamas can do.
We feed in: "Hamas carries out the Holocaust 2.0."
And then I press the "Nooshi condemns" button.
There was criticism again.
Unbelievable.
It must be even more serious.
Now we release all the barriers.
I have to come up with something really damn sick that Hamas can do.
Oh, fuck.
"Hamas for free rental in new production."
And then we press the button.
No criticism!
The whole party supports it!
Unbelievable.
In addition, the calculator says that Björn Alling pronounces:
“Bad double standards and populism of hamas”
"Licking marketing. Freeze the assistance in Palestine - now."
An incredible machine.
Those are no longer done.