Imagine Christmas is soon here again
Time flies
!
Hello phä
Hello here I come with Christmas post!
Christmas post so much fun!
here you go
Thanks
It says this:
Merry Christmas and Happy New Year, Hum and Sludder
With my Christmas present to you I want to remind you
about why we are really celebrating Christmas
Wishing everyone's friend
Christmas gift what Christmas present?
Aaaa, it was to you
Yes, it was huge and crisp to get here
How is it going
Thanks so much
Open Open Open
Oops, here were a lot of things
Look at this
Yeah
Yes, now I understand what everyone's friend has thought that we should do that we should do
Do you understand I do not understand
Neither do I
Nose here stands like this ...
Well, you just do as I say then it will be fine
Okay...
This is joseph
He is engaged to Mary
She is expecting children
One day Joseph was told he had to travel
from the city of Nazareth, where they now lived
to the city of Bethlehem, to tax
This was something that everyone at this time must do
They traveled all the way to Bethlehem
Mary was allowed to ride on a donkey
When they arrived, they searched a place to sleep on
They knocked on at several shelters
So type hotel
But everything was full
So they got to sleep instead in a stable
There Mary gave birth to his son, Jesus
At the same time on a meadow near the stable
were there any shepherds guarding their sheep
Then mittyjall, the whole sky was lit up in a strong glow and they became scared
An angel said:
Tadaa
Don't be afraid, I come with super good news to you
and to the whole world
Tonight the God's own Son has been born
He is your rescuer, Messiah
And he lies wrapped in a crib
and, yes, you will find him there
Glory be God in height and peace on the whole earth, Jo
The shepherds wandered to the stable and praised the newborn Jesus
In another country there were some star interpreters
Some show men simply
They had discovered a new big star in the sky
and they knew it meant that a new king had been born
They went away, followed the star
and came on the way to King Herod
They asked him if he knew where the newborn king was
He got angry
because there would be no other king than he
He secretly planned to kill the new king
and told the wise men:
"When you found the king, then come and tell me that
so that I can also pay tribute to him ”
The wise men nodded
and continued to look for the new king
They finally found the stable and gave presents to Jesus
They gave gold, incense and myrrh
In this way was born and celebrated Jesus
And that is why we celebrate Christmas
In short, it's Jesus' birthday
But what happened to herod then
Well, an angel said to the wise men
Not to tell Herod
So he never found Jesus
Okay
Well then it was clear!
Like that, now we have got our memories refreshed
about why we celebrate Christmas
Good work
And merry christmas all viewers
Merry Christmas
Jooo