Hello.
Hello honey, how are you I'm tired.
Who the hell will work out before.
8 in the morning?
We are so different you and me.
Ivy, you are ready for some real food today yeah wait, wait, you should get pilla yourself you can not please promise and eat it now that mom has been cooked.
Please.
You are welcome.
The silence that is in here now, it can be touched.
Oh, you seem to like it.
Hello, Hello, Hello, Ivy.
She tastes anyway, she seems interested.
She's going to take one more.
This is good that she gets to pill, I say it Jhon.
Do you know what, with this, I say welcome to a new fucking vlog.
Forgive me, but I looked at Tiktok yesterday such a discoad and I just felt, wow.
I just long even though I want to enjoy Ivy every day that is now.
So I just long until Ivy is a small individual and talks and she just says this way, mom I want to swim or mom I want to bake or whatever.
And this disco bath, I realize that Ivy is too small now, but I couldn't keep myself so I went in, I ordered a thing from ... No, I ordered 2 stuff from Adlibris.
Forgive me, I have to raise them because this is no cooperation, nothing I pay just as usual but I actually have to raise them because I placed an order yesterday.
Check it is already here and it arrived at night when we were sleeping so they sent it the same day.
It's actually sick.
However, I ordered extra for express delivery.
No, I didn't even.
I don't even think it cost extra but it really was how you can get it tomorrow type.
And then I got that and then I ordered another thing from type Young Rooms which was like a frog that sprays foam so this will be so damn fun.
I think I'm more tagged than Ivy is.
Ivy will just sit like this.
But I, on the other hand, I am so damn tagged on this disco bath.
We should have music, it should be a mood, so tagged so we will see now what came here now.
But what, Jhon now was just a thing that came, it was just ... check, this is the disc ball, this one you should put in the bath so will be disco lights.
I am so fucking tagged, but there should also be a choice that sprays water.
Well then maybe it will come in the next order then
It wasn't so good Adlibris that you placed it in 2 different orders and I didn't really like that, no, I didn't like it.
If we now have to think about the environment, everything should also come in the same package, but this, so tagged.
Good baggage, ie God, what you now notice that she thinks it was more fun to eat if she can eat herself.
To before when I have served eggs, I have shown what I think I showed it last.
So she barely eats, so she just thinks it is strange with pieces.
Even though she spits out 70 % of the food, it still is, she gets in her, she tastes, she gets interested.
You create an interest in food, which I noticed a big difference now.
So it was fun and now she got a small one where the track and sit and suck on a bit.
It can always be fun too, she will actually sleep her first nap soon and then I will sit down and work.
It is half past 9 in the morning.
Today we wake up as early as at.
7. We have actually slept to 10 every day now.
But yesterday Ivy fell asleep very much so that then it became an earlier morning.
That's how it gets sometimes so today she woke up at.
7 And then before the first nap is usually awake for type 2 hours and then on the days she usually is awake type between 3 and four, not 4 hours but 3 hours before she sleeps.
What did you say what do you want now?
If you unpack things in my office, feel free to grab them and throw it away.
Do you hear what he says.
The funny thing is that he only if you stumble down my office then it is like this too.
Yes, now, nowadays it is not even called office,
For any of us but nowadays it is called ... it is in John's room.
It is in my room because it has become that you sleep in Jhon's room.
It has become that Jhon sleeps in that room and I sleep in our room with Ivy.
I don't know why we are doing so much now that we have a little bigger bed too.
So I do not know why it has become so, but it has only become more beautiful because it feels like everyone sleeps better if we sleep separately.
I get to sleep on my own surface without being crowded in bed.
Ivy gets her own surface on her part of the bed, because now she has stopped sleeping type in her bed because we have become lazy.
I think it is so nice that we all sleep so much better and Jhon gets to sleep undisturbed when he still goes up to work and such.
So that it has become so good, wait sorry, there were several who questioned John's gift.
And I actually have to go in and defend you Jhon.
Because you misunderstand there were several who just wait so you received as a gift that he should take care of the home or your child or your child who is obvious he should do
It was not so, then you have misunderstood everything, ie Jhon and I share everything as much, but that was, for example, that I could throw in and only today I do not want to do anything I want to be serviced.
It was rather so or, for example, I take care of Ivy all day now, for example, for example, we divide it, for example when Jhon comes home from work then he takes care of Ivy.
Then he takes the lay.
It's so, but such a day.
Then, for example, it can be the way you take everything, you take everything and it is luxury, so whatever you say it is luxury.
No, you have taken out the entire banana and mashed it now no ivy.
No.
This one then, what happened to it?
Now you have to take it there and go with it a little.
Ivy is just as akward in my vlogs when she just sits and looks at you like Jhon was my latest vlog when I stood and made breakfast with Lifesum recipe.
Then Jhon stands like this in the background.
You just, you are exactly like Ian or Ivy, type in the camera.
It is actually great fun, but do you know what is we start this damn day.
We go and put Ivy for his nap, I sit down and work a little and then hear and fucking in amazement.
You will be so shocked now.
But then I'll go and exercise.
And this has not happened since I gave birth to children in principle so that today I will train and I love my PT Kalle.
So that we will probably come mostly Catcha up than to work out.
We will mostly tramp and flame, have fun and laugh.
It's kind of what our workouts usually go about, exactly.
But then we will do that.
But first and foremost NAP for Ivy.
In fact, I also want to say one thing, Ivy has basically said mom now for the first time, she says this.
Ma ma, she says, but she says mom, you understand that it is me and shouts.
For example, if she is in her lap on someone else.
Then you call up to mom, or how yes, you actually do it.
Now it is actually not just what I want to believe, but she has actually started that way.
There are several who just, God, she says mother.
So it's actually not just me, it's not a desperate mother who just wants her to say mom, but you have actually started to say so or how
But you do not say to order, because you still do not understand what I say or how no, exactly.
But as I said, now we go and nap her.
We can go and dance a little first just Ivy.
But we hear when I have added her to her first nap so we will sit down and work and have a cup of coffee and enjoy some of the silence.
So, the child sleeps and I have actually managed to take a shower even so now there will be coffee.
I would sit here and work now.
Then Dora came to visit.
I sit and then only God I have to check some clothes for Thailand only.
She just, oh, that one was so nice, and that blue.
I just yeah, you want it to Thailand if you go in the Dora, if you put it on it.
If Dora then comes in it.
So can I take on, what should we take but what should we take in Dora?
Should I get into this one maybe?
Should I get in it?
My God dora, I'm sitting here trying to find something to wear in Thailand.
This color, very nice color.
It's actually nice.
But I would like to wear something and not just lots of threads, or how you like the one who is it, a little, a little.
Who likes the little one, I think it seems to be you.
You dora I would like to have something that covers the body.
This one I think was nice, the one, now we talk.
No.
There was too much coverage is it even left?
No, it is not even clear in size.
It was very nice I think.
Dora should actually hang with us to Thailand so we will do a real little one like this family holiday.
I hope we are not robbed this time Dora no ready, please.
It will not be good if we will be again.
I'm not going to bring anything.
No bring your ugliest clothes because you never know.
But now we have each other's swimsuit.
It's fun anyway.
So now I'm on my way to the gym and as usual it will always be the last minute for me.
But I have ordered an Uber and I know you will say this.
It's not ok to go uber to the gym yes, it's take me damn ok for even going to the gym is damn really fucking ok.
That said, I've been to the gym once since type week 20 where I was pregnant there a while ago if you remember.
And I just know this is one of you more who just know this.
Why did the butt become flat after giving birth to children and have been pregnant my butt is absolutely fucking flat.
I have never had a trained tail, but I have always anyway, you know had a little put.
And it just like this, why am I totally ... it's just a back and a thigh all of a sudden.
It may be because I am, as I said, never kind of trained, that may be that reason, but yes, whatever it is.
Now I feel this way, maybe we should rebuild this put again if it even goes, if you even pallets, I will pallet once.
Hello.
Hi welcome.
Thank you, we'll see how this put this put, but now we are at least on our way to the gym.
Thanks so much, goodbye.
Here she comes.
Just yes but thank you.
Welcome back.
Then we will grab this then, Kalle.
Good job we'll see you tomorrow.
Yes but now I have booked.
Right.
Kalle, do you know what I hate it is that you talk to everyone else during our passport and when it is over you are very hard with that here at.
11 you should be ready, because then I'll have someone else.
But when it is my passport then there is no respect for me, then you talk to people, I have booked you.
There are like 20 people in a room, then everyone must have some time.
Don't you understand when I have booked you because then I'll have all the time.
I'll just replenish water.
So, so now I've been training and I can say this way to go up the stairs now.
It makes my legs shake.
I'm like spaghetti.
I'm so damn untrained.
I can say this, exercise it's shit boring.
I hate it, but the feeling afterwards, as I always say, it's amazing.
That's why I exercise and I love to hang out with Kalle, my coach.
He is a cliff I just want to say, so that's just the only reason why I exercise.
But now I'm going to take an Uber to Fermano and blow dry my hair.
Then we take a little uber there and blow dry, thank God for it, what a fucking luxury huh.
Hello.
So now both finished and finished winded, wonderful.
Now we will go up and have some lunch and then I do not know what happens more here, honestly.
I kind of need to put in a wash.
I have to fix some stuff at home yes and then just be with Ivy as usual simply.
But this is how we try to split it that I can kind of if I kind of want to train or if I need to go to a meeting.
Jhon take her at his lunch for when he works at home.
Then he has lunch for an hour and then it is when I usually kind of stick away.
And then I make sure she sleeps during that time, so it's good anyway.
And when he works in the office yes then I have her 100 % but it must actually be that I work 100 % and am a maternal leave 100 %.
I am not a maternity leave and withdraw money but I am a maternity leave because I have a child and am a mother, but you understand what I mean.
But yes, it is not so easy in that industry to have time off and be mom free unfortunately.
It doesn't really work the same way, huh
But we have nevertheless put it up well so that for us this arrangement works as well.
I don't know if I have a key with me and it is locked, of course.
Hi, I have no keys.
Bath for you then.
So, forgive me, this is always the way you know, I can stand out there, knock, knock or that you shit in me then because sometimes I start to feel that you do this just to resist.
You just have to learn, you come in when I want you to come in.
So he runs, Jhon now they will imagine that you are a controlling boyfriend that we have a toxic relationship and that I live in oppression.
Oh my God, I have fucking forgot to tell oh my fucking good you know what happened, so listen to this.
No wait.
It was so so, I and I and Ivy are home.
We are sleeping until 10 pm.
11. John has gone to work and then there at half past 12 when we go out.
Yes then I notice that we are not coming out for the door.
I don't know what has happened.
The lock has only been broken in some way as well.
For Jhon locks as usual in the morning so we don't get out, so we started getting like this nightmare scenario and just oh my good thinking if it starts to burn here and me and Ivy do not come out.
I panic so I can call locksmiths coming.
He gets my keys, it is also not possible to open from the outside.
It has broken so he can just break the entire door.
Yes, this party costs us SEK 5250, top and then I wonder, you can pull this on home insurance there are several of you who have said that you can draw this on home insurance, but I do not know.
In any case, it was sick that it was so damn expensive that it was such an expensive fucking cost, but there was nothing to wait for.
I had to come out and it was also a safety risk to open the door.
I have to get out of there.
It was so uncomfortable, but it went well anyway.
Here I and I and Ivy are alive, it did not start burning, but we are, however, SEK 5250 poorer.
Sick enough that it was so expensive.
But, now let's go in and see what Ivy does.
So I can say this, I hung with Ivy.
Then I just felt no, now I need a little refresh, so I went and did a spray tan.
So I haven't washed it yet, but so from it to this then.
Now we decided a little spontaneously that my dad and his girl Agnet.
Girl do you say so?
Girl or cohabiting, Mrs. are they married?
No.
I think my dad and his partner Agneta would come out for dinner and Jhon and I have a special and it is the New Year's dinner that we did.
And I think you should keep up with now how we did it.
We will do these starters on the potato buns if you haven't done it yet.
Look exactly now how I do, it just does for everyone's sake it does because it is so fucking good.
It is so good and for that we should have beef fillet and potato gratin and salad.
And for that, Jhon has now realized that he will cook a scrapbook.
It's just because he wants, because I said it, he just, you don't think your dad would have appreciated if I bake a scrapbook
I just, yes, but I do it if you want.
After all, I have a baked scrapbook like this is never as good as a Fröding draft cake.
I may be strange now, but I think so Fröding Kladdkaka is the best I know and it is not possible to beat it.
It sounds spoiled when someone wants to bake for me but I feel a little like that.
Then at least I said that if you want a draft cake do it.
But your dad wants.
I think Dad will be happy for the food and then we can take an ice cream afterwards.
I think of your dad.
Jhon you want the scrapbook yes.
I just do it then.
But now I come to the conclusion that I start with the food so I think we are starting to dare a little.
Now it will not be as nice table setting as last.
But we start to set a little and then we can start making the salad for it we can just stop and then what do we need to do since we can put potato gratin in shape and everything so that it is clear.
For now it is an hour left until they arrive, so it is quite a long time left.
But we get started and tablecloths.
What did you say the found cloth is on.
Your father had appreciated a scrapbook.
Jhon, if you want this scrapbook then I think you do.
Dad appreciates ... three course.
Yes, but he can get 3 dishes we can still make ice cream.
We don't make ice cream.
No, we bought ice cream.
Do you know what, do the scrapbook.
I think Fröding is better one everyone's.
Okay if I beat Frödingens ... but you know you don't come because no one I've tasted so far, even when I've tasted this ...
It's nothing to you honey, I think you're good as you are.
I tell you, I will beat Frödinges.
Challenge accepted.
Aj honey, you should always hit me on the butt.
Of course it's mine.
Now it was this destructive relationship again.
I shit in, you understand mine is mine.
Oh mine is mine too, you know, now he starts to say that I am his property here.
100 %, you haven't told me to lock you in here.
Wasn't it in this vlog I told you it.
Yes.
Exactly, should you behave or should I lock you in.
I'm kidding.
There are people who misunderstood.
I'm kidding, I had never locked in ready.
Or or?
He pulls that joke every time you just where is the joke Jhon I do not keep up with.
John, you can't stand and bake here now when I'm going to make food.
You're like a fly.
I wipes you away and then you come back.
Listen I told Jhon was with Ivy now I should make food.
Then he will promptly stand here now and make food or scrapbook.
And I was clear darling that I need this spac.
And now to the potato buns and then you should have this parm cushion and then you just take regular crème fraiche and then you take grated parmesan, so this finely grated parmesan.
And then I usually take garlic spices, salt, pepper and this is what you put like ... This is what you put as a base.
This is what you put as a base before you put like this shrimp, red onion onion before you put everything, then you put the parmesan cream.
So that's now what we do.
What do you do so now I have just mixed the crème fraiche, this kind of finely grated parmesan and now we take garlic powder and then salt and pepper.
Type was as much parmesan as it is crème fraiche, so you know it.
So it should really taste as well as cheese and garlic and salt and pepper.
Delicious.
Now it's time for the sauce and on New Year's Eve I had a funnel chanterelle and it was so damn good.
But now I didn't find it.
So now there are just ordinary mushrooms and then whipped cream and then a little crème fraiche as it gets so damn good.
And then I usually have in veal broth and some soy.
And I usually run on this one.
That veal broth.
And then just a little soy salt and pepper, and then we are at home.
And as I show, plain fucking cream and regular fucking crème fraiche.
Nothing like that where you know light cream fresh or something like that without ordinary creme fraiche to get this creamy.
I'm just saying, this sauce, divine.
The Lordship has come.
Ok, now I'm just about to jump into the shower.
Dinner is done.
Dad and Agneta have gone home and I just have to say your draft cake honey, wow.
No it was wow.
It was really good and the dinner became delicious.
I didn't actually film the meat and everything because you controlled you.
But no so it was a delicious dinner, very delicious and now I have to jump into the shower and we just have to see clear love island here which is.
So, I can only say one thing and that is that I hate Johnny, then.
I hate him.
No, i think he is so fucking ... what do you
No, I'm watching.
Yes, of course he is hard he is a player.
Well, but then, I think he is terrible so terrible person.
And I just feel this way, please someone can just put him in place oh my good, now he should choose about my fucking good.
He is so disgusting.
He is sick in the head.
So, he is changing all the time.
Oh, my God, now I have to jump into the shower.
We hear about one we hear in a little while I thought like this, but we do not.
We will hear in a few days.
Don't forget that I love you.
Don't forget that I die for you and at the next vlog maybe we can have even more Love Island snack.
Thus, my God.
Hello, see you soon you will say then hello.