- Yes, it's Dad.
- (Laura) Dad.
Did you hear?
There were so many in there who were glowing at us.
It was pretty hard, I think.
New Year's resolutions!
(Alma) What are you doing?
Good morning.
- We're in ... - Kläppen.
We came here ...
Oh!
Harry is on a chair.
Do you see?
We came here two days before Christmas Eve.
We have had a great time here.
- Here's Laura!
- Yes.
How are you?
Completely silent.
She is doing pretty well.
- Should we go and have breakfast?
- Yes!
- (Alma) Yes, a highchair.
Should we take one?
- (Laura) mm.
(Joanna) The morning coffee.
It is important.
- Morning chocolate.
- I know.
Just kidding.
But this is the most important thing of all.
Cream.
Oh!
God, so.
We live at Hotel Kurbits, located in the middle of the hill.
We've lived here before.
(Shoulder) mm.
Two years ago.
Then there was a big difference in our family.
Yes!
- This one lay in my stomach.
- Yes.
- She was almost not up.
- Yes, she was.
She was "ready to pop!"
Or, I was.
- Yes.
- I was very pregnant then.
But it's still so cool, the difference, because now we have a little girl talking!
Right?
Huh?
You talk!
Talking.
Just.
Welcome to our 6-bed apartment, this time.
Here we have a pretty nice and spacious hall, where you can hang out.
With drying cabinets, very good.
A guest toilet.
And behind the camera we have the large toilet with shower.
(Joanna) A guest toilet for all our guests.
Yes exactly.
We do not have a lot of guests, but it is quite nice when you are many in the family.
It is Dad's bait toilet where he can sit and cozy for two hours.
- (Joanna) there was someone honest.
- What f*n!
What to have to eat.
- Hörrudu ... - I don't bite for two hours.
Hey you.
Don't swear, thank you.
- Not swear!
- Okay sorry.
- Now Alma takes over and shows her room.
- Yes.
I dropped the word.
This is where I live.
Or, I don't live here.
Or yes, I kind of do because I am here most of the time when I do not ski.
(Joanna) so you have your own room.
Yes.
I absolutely wanted my own room.
I have an extra bed here, if anyone wants to sleep over.
(Axel) And in here we have Harry's and Laura's room.
It looks like Almas type.
(Joanna) Mirrored.
Laura sleeps down there and Harry sleeps up there, and they have not bedded the beds.
So it may be.
And in here, Joanna and I sleep.
And it works great.
It is a small apartment, but it still has quite a lot of common area, which still works.
(Joanna) But the best of all ... I never get tired of this view.
After all, we are not such a family that is out the hill when the lifts open.
Woho!
Laura, are you out in the lifts something at all?
Did you say "uh"?
What does it mean?
- Are you out skiing?
- No!
No.
Laura is with a babysitter a few hours a day.
We have found Elma, 17, who comes and fits Laura for a few hours when we go.
She is coming just right.
Yes.
She will come soon.
- (Elma) Hello!
- (Axel) Hello!
Good morning.
- How's it going?
- Good.
How about you?
It's just good, thank you.
(Axel) Bus kid!
- (Joanna) Someone who likes their babysitter.
- (Axel) Yes, really!
- What happens now?
- We are going to ski school.
- Take each other like this, so I can pull you.
- Okay.
Wiiie!
Alma and Harry are in the same ski school group.
Children 9-11, huh?
Oh, how good you were!
- "Kidz" 9-11.
- Yes.
"Kidz."
- So Harry is a little young for his group.
- Yes and...
But it is nice to have them in the same.
"Sorry."
Then there are children from other countries here as well.
Pretty much more than in previous years, I think.
I think you hear families coming from all over Europe.
- Yes.
It's exciting!
- But in their group it is only Swedes.
- Okay.
I have no control.
I have, because I listened to them yesterday.
Should we go a little, right?
Yes.
I have to put on boots and helmets, then we drive out on the slopes.
♪ (music) ♪
- Own time.
Luxurious!
- Very good home time.
It's a thing to get in, but then you have to get out.
Yay!
(Joanna) Here comes Alma and Harry's ski school group.
- Hello!
"High five!"
(Axel) Alma, how cool you are.
- (Axel) How's it going?
- (Alma) I managed to turn around.
(Alma) What are you doing?!
Shoulder!
Give me the camera.
- What are you doing?
- It looked so nice to just lie down here a little neighbor.
You, I think Alma thought you were embarrassing.
She quickly skiing away here.
But that's my job!
It's my job to be embarrassing.
(Axel) Alma!
Wait for me!
(laugh)
"Hugy."
(scary)
A little scary when you are so high up.
We are in the gondola, on our way up to the top cabin and will have lunch.
The family is reunited!
Yes.
Did you have a good time?
(Laura Tjar) Yes, you have had so good and so much fun!
She has so much new energy when she has been with us for a while.
Yes.
- How is the ski school, then?
- It's actually fun!
- Harry, what do you think?
- It's really fun!
- Good.
- Oh.
Host, host.
A good thing with ski school, besides learning to get better at skis, is that you meet new friends.
Yes exactly.
- I think that's a big win.
- Yes.
Good, Laura!
Laura sits with Joanna's phone, because she is completely done.
I don't know if I like it, but it is very difficult to get something in her when she is tired and hungry.
- Obviously you don't like it.
- No.
- But the need has no law.
- No its true.
Be happy that those two eat well without screen.
- Does it taste good?
- mm.
Don't forget the vegetables, children.
- There were so many in there who were glowing at us.
- How did it feel?
It felt strange.
It was a bit like being hounded, because I sit and eat and then at least 10 people look at me.
You get pretty nervous and don't really know what to do.
- (Joanna) We have become accustomed to a bit at that too.
- (Alma) Yes.
When we have lived in Portugal, we have not really experienced that in the same way, and then we go here ...
- (Laura whining) - Now someone wants something here.
Yes, it's Dad.
- Dad.
- Yes.
Dad.
Dad has flown a little drone.
- My fingers, then.
- I canceled you.
What would you say?
Or no, Laura interrupted.
When we have lived in Portugal, we have been a bit anonymous.
You can walk around and be yourself and bark at the children when they are nasty to each other or so.
But here it feels like ... it's a little harder.
- You have eyes on you.
- Yes, a little so, but ...
You have to be your best self.
Yes, but then, it is our own choice and it is great exercise to be its best self all the time, I think.
And I love our viewers.
And I love that they arrive and that they whisper and look and point ...
- Do you just love that bit?
- No, but ... yes, that's part of it.
I love everything with what we do.
So, I don't love being known.
It sounded really strange.
But, so ... I love our viewers.
I love you!
What a tok fringes!
Now I, Alma and Harry are going to ski.
- Yes.
And me and Laura are going back to the room and lie down and rest.
How nice to you.
- Yes, I think she is freezing now.
I know she freezes.
And is deadly tired.
Please, you get this camera.
We have this ... not the mitt.
This we will film with.
- Yes!
- Okay!
Kisses and good night.
"Boa Noite."
Love you!
"Love you!"
(Love you!)
- Have fun!
I will see you later!
- Bye!
Bye!
♪ (music) ♪
"Now it goes over. Now it's good."
- (Joanna) What are you doing?
- What do I do?
- I probably saw how you put away the cellphone.
- Yes, I do it when you come.
It feels like nicer.
What kind of secrets are you doing on the screen?
Tell me, tell me.
What "secrets"?
This was really a terribly ugly picture.
You look like the frog ball.
Come now.
It became your punishment for hiding in here yourself.
No, you must not post when I look like the frog ball.
Come on now.
The others sit out there and read and have a cozy.
You must not hide here with your mobile.
- But I can't cope.
- What can't cope?
I didn't sleep anything at night.
Hörrudu, you have been out and about a lot of skiing and you have been able to do so without any problems.
You don't get the energy from looking at your mobile, I promise you.
No, though I don't lose energy.
- What?
Do you lose energy by being out here?
- Yes, because then I have to touch my legs.
- But you should help cook.
- No, mom ...
- Yes.
- No.
- I do not want to.
- Yes.
- please?
- What have you thought you should do?
- Lie inside my room.
- No, forget it!
Now we're going to cook, right?
- (Axel) Yes, now we will cook.
Can you understand that this is the last vlog of the year?
- No.
On the last days of the year.
Yes.
So ... it's sick to think about.
I think this year has flown by.
- I agree with.
- Yes, it has been very fast.
- What should that imagine?
- Mozzarella.
- It looks like a small poop, type.
- What?
If your poop sausages look like that, then you have a problem.
No, they don't.
Although it looks like something strange.
What do you think has been best about this year, then?
I think it's fun when you say ... So, Laura's words are probably the most fun.
When you say "Summer Shadow!"
To her, then she gets like this ...
Did you hear?
She just, "Oh! Hugy!"
(scary)
And when you say other words, and when she is bargaining and you do so, then she just starts ...
- When waving in front of your nose because it smells bad?
- Yes.
But it is great fun that she has begun to understand things.
- Mom?
- Yes?
Do you want a hug?
Oh, should you help film?
Come.
I think the best thing about all year, if you think about the stuff we have shown the viewers,-
-As our trip down to Málaga, and then home.
And then all summer at home.
I thought that was absolutely wonderful.
- From Portugal to Sweden, you mean?
- Yes.
I think the best thing about this year was when we had Skara Summerland for ourselves.
It was so funny!
I think the best thing about the year has been ...
Oh!
She fell.
(Laura laughs)
... autumn in Portugal, because it was so hot and comfortable and we could swim pool for a long time and so.
- Yes.
- Yes, it was cozy.
It surprises me that you say summer in Sweden, because it was a lot of packing.
- Yes, but ... - Selling houses, that is ... it was pretty hard, I think.
It was hard, but it was also a very big and welcome step-
-As we brought our family, to sell that house.
We had to do it, and it feels great that we have done it now.
Mm.
- Now it's time to eat, I think.
- Yes.
Now it's chaos.
♪ (music) ♪
We are a day closer to a new year, and we have a suitable today's question.
YES!
What are our New Year's resolutions?
- My New Year's promise is that I will learn to go snowboard.
- Ooh, good there!
- My New Year's promise is to learn division.
- Okay, math.
Good!
Laura fell asleep when we sat down here to record.
And she is a little too small for a promise.
Mine is that I will take care of my health.
- Oh, what good!
- Make a little better choice in everyday life.
Yes.
It is in the middle.
- Same?
- Yes, the same.
What are your New Year's resolutions?
Comment below!
And remember to be kind to yourself now!
No one should change.
- No.
- Don't hold on and, "I'll lose weight and get slim."
- You can get better, but not hold on and change.
- Yes!
Thanks for watching this video!
- Feel free to leave a thumbs up, or down.
- Most thumbs up!
Comment, ask questions and have a great time until we see you next time.
- Happy New Year!
- Bye!