Now it's like this ...
Here are our house parts.
- Bibbi!
- Yes.
Bibbi!
No but...
What the phase!
Don't bump into!
No!
Laura, you have to jump down.
- Release Laura.
- I can not.
I have to hold the pieces.
(Laura + Axel) Aaaah!
Hello Hello!
Today we will do ...
Gingerbread House CHALLENGE!
The world's longest words.
- It is a competition where you have to make a gingerbread house.
- Yes!
- A nice, fun, lovely, inspiring house.
- Yes.
- And the one who makes the nicest wins.
- Exactly like that.
- And is the best.
We have divided into two teams.
I'm a little worried about today's competition, because ...
Here in Portugal there are not these finished, type, "Mother Anna's" house that you just put together.
- No, exactly.
- Is it so?
- I think it's called "Grandma Anna".
- Isn't it just "Anna's gingerbread"?
Yes.
Nice the same, there is not here.
Portuguese does not eat and do not build gingerbread houses.
They don't even eat gingerbread at all.
- That's how it is.
- Yes.
So we have to start by drawing up what our houses should look like.
You have prepared a dough.
- Yes.
I made a huge dough kit yesterday, so it's ready.
- mm.
And who is the law, then?
- Me and Alma.
The best team.
- And me and my mom and Lauris.
- huh?
Do you get help from her?
- Yes, she is the world's best mascot!
Wihiii!
The winning mascot.
Okay, we split up and start working a bit on the house dreams, then.
That is why there is so much paper here.
- I think we should go to the kitchen.
- We go to the kitchen and you stay here.
Schas, schasome!
Fort, fast!
Go, go!
Away!
Schas, schasome, schasome!
- Bye!
- Laura takes nothing.
We have had some different ideas.
At first, Harry thought we would make a horror house.
“Poppy Pli Time”
- And then you were at a sushi restaurant.
- mm.
Since then we have been thinking a lot about which form-
-And concluded that the simplest thing is to just print finished shapes from the net.
So we have done that, and then we will invest more in the decoration itself.
And what kind of house will it be?
Do we know that?
Harry's Toys store!
We'll see.
We may change again, I think.
But here we have little Harry anyway, right?
Do you see that in the light?
- Are you filming?
- (shoulder) mm.
- I didn't even notice.
- Should you tell me what you are doing?
I make a hat for my and dad's mum house.
TA-DA!
(Laura screams) "Hugy."
Yes, it is scary with the scissors.
It is very sharp.
No, Harry.
Bus kid.
And you eat sweets even though it's not Saturday.
Can you do it?
Now it is like this.
Mom and Harry think we will make a similar gingerbread house as they do ...
Let's see.
... because we have taken these papers.
But we really have done this for us to put the dough.
Here is for the roof.
Like this.
Just.
And now we will do for the walls themselves.
I just draw here.
- (Harry) Alma?
- Mm?
- Which bit should we get?
- This one, I think.
- Ah, the big one.
- huh?
I thought they were the same size.
(Joanna) get to see.
- (Alma) Yes, these are just as big.
- (Harry) type.
(Alma) So there!
(Joanna) Time to roll.
♪ (music) ♪
Here are our house parts.
- (Joanna) Are you satisfied?
- Yes.
- We only miss the chimney.
It is in the oven.
- Yes.
Yeah, what's that?
- Mom.
- Yes, but you have to take out the pacifier if we should hear what you say.
No?
You don't want to show it.
Stop, stop, stop!
Harry, you should probably save it from Laura.
So!
Away!
(Axel) None!
What is going on?
Our house parts crack and break ... and roll off.
- You make so advanced!
- This will never go.
Never say never.
Don't bump into!
No!
Alma, what should we do?
Oh no!
You may do a new part.
No!
This must be possible to cook.
Everything can be cooked, especially in Portugal.
We have seen that.
Everything can be cooked with glaze.
The houses are oblique and wind, and they can still cook.
- Laura broke our freshly baked chimney.
- Laura, your little bus!
It can probably get together anyway, I think.
I hope.
Now we have all our pieces.
God, what I look like in my hair.
It's so hot when standing by the oven, or what do you say?
- Yes.
- You also look a little ... weather bite.
We started to try to put together our pieces with cold stuff like this "baking glue".
Was it a good idea?
- No.
- No, a very poor idea.
So now we have had it in a water bath.
God, how I sit ... This with having Laura in your team, I think you should get a little handicap for.
Should we put it together now, with warm things like that "baking glue"?
Mm.
Drive a little there.
Now it's easier, huh?
- Is it still a little hard?
- Yes, wait ... so, now.
Okay.
Before it had been in a water bath it was stiff.
Oh, wait.
So, then we have some glue.
And so we put there.
Oooh, two walls.
So we can put one like that too.
- No no no!
- Don't take it.
- Do you want it?
- mm.
- Oh!
- Of course she wants to.
- We can take it there.
- Yes.
I wonder how long it will take for it to dry.
It does not stand.
Oooh ... This is our site, with a door.
It should be there.
Should we glue on it?
Yes.
- I think this one went pretty smoothly now.
- Yes.
That's how it looks.
Yes, you want it.
But we need it as a small weight there.
Aaah!
Okay, take it.
Should you jump down and go to Dad and Alma maybe?
I just, "Hello then."
So now.
Now, Harry.
- (Axel) This is going to be our roof.
- Without the aluminum foil, then.
Yes, the goal is for us to be able to lift it.
But then, this will not be able to dry today, I do not know how ...
(Joanna) This is the world's best day for Laura.
She just walks and poles and fixes, and she loved to hold on and roll.
(Shoulder) Gullungen.
Oh, are you going to bake muffins now?
This is going to be interesting.
- Yes, now you should also start putting together.
- Yes.
But then ...
- (Laura) Mom!
- Mom is here.
I have never made such an advanced ...
Oh, now I see that we get chopped heads.
Maybe we should raise the camera.
We have to sit down.
I'll pick up more parts, Alma.
- There is an incredibly high level of ambition on your part.
- Yes Yes.
We lowered the requirements instead.
We only took the drawing from the net.
Oh, they are different high.
Huh?
How could they be?
They are cut out of the same piece.
No, but this ... This is going to be so good.
Mm.
Harry, I need your help.
The roof.
I take the most durable bit.
Wait, wait, wait!
Do not touch.
- Harry, I need your help.
- This will never go.
Stop laughing at that ghosts!
You hear the panic.
It is clean and cut.
- No no no!
- Oh my God!
Laura ... Laura, you have to jump down.
- Release Laura.
- I can not.
I have to hold the pieces.
(Laura + Axel) Aaaah!
(Harry hum loudly)
Silent!
Our gingerbread house is starting to feel more and more like dough.
Yes, the pieces feel a little wet.
No!
- Oh.
You have to wait with your old man, Harry.
- My old man broke my leg.
Harry focuses only on his old man while I fight with the house.
- He amputated his own leg, with diligence.
- Yes.
I talked to a parent we know at the Swedish school here in Portugal-
-And told us we should make gingerbread houses.
He said, "Then you have to hurry on because they don't last that long. They like collapse because of the humidity."
And it seems to be true.
It is much more humid here, indoors as well.
In Sweden, a gingerbread house can keep all winter.
But here, forget it.
Here it lasts barely a week.
No...
What the phase!
No!
Gosh...
The name, what messy.
Should I help you?
- No.
- It is too late.
(Joanna sighs)
We have no entrance to the house, Alma.
♪ (music) ♪
We are done!
- Woho!
- Or, almost clear.
The sun goes down 17:20 in Portugal.
Beah!
- (shoulder) more?
More gingerbread houses?
- (Laura) mm.
- No thanks.
We are done.
- Yes.
We have stood in the brightest house ...
No.
... the brightest room in the whole house to show ...
- Our creations.
- Yes.
- Why did you do that?
- Nothing.
It's just so hot.
Yes, from the oven earlier.
This has been one of our hottest, sweatiest and stressful ...
And the scariest.
- ... recordings.
- Yes.
- But when we cut, it probably doesn't look so awful.
- No.
- Okay.
Who is starting to present their house?
- Me and mom.
- Okay.
- And Lauris.
- (Laura) mm.
- (Joanna) etc.
- You remember the story?
- I remember the story.
I will move forward the house and you should tell.
There was once a toy store called "Harry's Toys".
And it was created by Harry itself.
Although one beautiful day the roof collapsed, and then it was run.
So he drove to give all the presents to the children who lived in the city.
Ever since then it is called Harrys ...
- (Alma) ruin.
- ... ruin.
- Good!
- This is how it looks.
- Right.
The roof was difficult to get on.
- Unbelievable.
It just slid off.
It was once a happy Moomin family that lived in a large Moomin house.
They loved Christmas, and just this Christmas they had bought really many gifts.
But some burglars entered and took all the presents.
After all, the Moomin Family was very passed, so they left.
Then the roof collapsed, and pretty much the whole house type broke.
Yes, and now we don't know who lives here.
There is some Christmas tree lighting and other things here.
- Exactly.
Every winter they light up.
- Yes.
- Here you can see tracks from the burglary.
- Yes, there is a ladder here.
Now it is you at home who decide who has won today's "Challenge"!
Yes.
- Team Harry, or ... - Team Alma.
Comment below!
Thanks for watching this video!
- Feel free to leave a thumbs up, or down.
- Most thumbs up!
Comment, ask questions and have a great time until we see you next time.
Bye!