Hello Hello!
We are in Khao Lak, Thailand!
Today we are going on an excursion to a waterfall!
- It will be really cool!
- Yes, and of course you should come along.
But first we should go and braid Harry's hair.
Yes, to check out Alma!
- Nice, huh?
- There are even pearls in the hair.
When Harry saw how nice it was, he said he wanted the same.
We will fix that first and then it will be an excursion!
Mom is a little busy working so she stays at the hotel.
Is everything good with the beads?
Only one.
I'll fix it for you.
One, Two, Three, Four, Five, Six ...
- Does it hurt?
- mm.
When I got braids it became so awkward everywhere so I just scratched here and here.
Then it was a bit jerky to itch, I didn't know ... I didn't know if I would do it or not.
So it was pretty hard.
Now it is soon ready, Harry.
Am I done now?
The last beads only.
Wow!
- Are you happy?
- mm.
Get to see, then?
Bye!
- Hello then, thank you!
- Bye!
Bye!
Well, what cool!
He's super nice after all!
Harry, how nice to be rid of that hanging and slingy hair on the face!
This was the coolest I've seen!
- Hörrni, now our taxi is here so now we will go!
- Okidoki!
Nice car!
Blue...
It's very hot today!
It was 34 degrees yesterday.
- I tip that it's around the same today.
- mm.
It is warm no matter where you are.
Indoors, outdoors, it's just ...
- I actually hope for some branches and shade now.
- Yes.
What are you babbling about?
- He talks about marshmallows being bitten very hard.
- huh?
What kind of marshmallows?
- In a movie.
- Well ...
This heat has knocked our children.
... get life in them ...
Oh, sleeping?
- Baby sleeps?
- Yes, baby sleeps.
... to you.
Happy Birthday, Dear Alma
Happy Birthday to you!
So ... it's so cute that everyone calls Harry a baby.
"Baby Sleep?"
A little dried fruit is very good to bring with you when you have tired children.
- May I eat it?
- Yes you can eat it.
- How is the situation, Almis?
- Good.
- Are you ready for 1.5 km walk?
- Yes!
It's a pretty cool road.
You hear the water on that side ...
Maybe you even see it?
- Oh, God!
There you do not want to fall down!
- Oh oh oh!
Whoa, take it easy!
Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh!
Okay, there was a proper drop.
On this page we have incredibly dense vegetation.
- Do you know what that means, Alma?
- Jungle!
Yes, but ... "vegetation";
So it is very dense vegetation.
- Jungle!
- Yes, it's a jungle.
Check out how beautiful it is!
Is it okay to go in sandals, Alma?
Yes...
As well as...
The...
... is not completely ...
... good, but ...
- Frankly, I have no one else.
- Why not?
I've grown out of them!
- Every shoe?
- Yeah!
- Is there anyone who thinks it is warm, raise a hand!
- Yes!
- Yes Yes...
So, even though it is branches and leaves and so on, it is pressing heat.
It will be great with a bath!
We arrive at "Level 1".
Or, 100 meters it is for "Level 1".
- Oh.
My.
Good!
- Oh, check out the bridge!
Tone chong Fa waterfall
When you go back, then we will go in the waterfall at the bottom!
- Check out which big ones!
- Yes, I see.
Can you get rid of them?
They eat on me!
I think it's scary.
- Eat on you?
Big fish eating on you?
- Yes!
Yes!
- No, but God!
- I don't think it was nice!
- Are you filming?
- Yes.
No but five!
Worst big fish that nibbled!
- "Fish spa" ... natural.
- Although it was kind of this big ...
- This pool was not as nice as I thought.
- Nah.
This "pool" was not so nice ...
Alma is allowed to go first so she has something to fall on.
- Should we go up here?
- Yes, to the next level.
No, now we will never find home ...
Oh my God.
In this pool there are some ... so we go.
Yes, we check level three.
I'm not so worried about going up.
I'm more worried about coming down again.
But it is nice if we can get our own little "pool".
- I'm worried I should fall.
- Yes, worried about falling can also be.
80 meters to level three ...
... of four levels.
I think we only drive three levels.
The terrain gets worse and worse.
Wow!
So, it's so beautiful!
I hope the camera shows how cool it is!
Shall we swim?
- Yes!
And here you can go water slide!
- No...
Not a single company.
Good!
- Do you want a sandwich?
- Gladly.
It pushes everywhere around us!
- It is unclear if we are heard in this.
- Yes, but I think so.
We have some lunch bag with us.
Yummy!
The time is...
You have no watch, I have a watch ... it is five in five.
The sun goes down at a quarter past six.
Now we have to focus on getting down, so we pack the camera in the bag.
- Yes, we can't have it when we go down.
- No, but then, some parties were like this ...
- ... and I want to come down with living children.
- Yes, so we'll see you down there!
We managed.
See what we found ...
It's spa fish!
Down here...
Check out, they come right away!
Ouch!
- How does it feel?
- They ...
So they take chews!
They take chews of my heels!
After all, I have those parmesan heels.
- May I look at the heels?
- They just "Oh, Parmesan!".
Here are my heels.
Uäää ...
"Uääää"!
Check now.
They come right away!
Fish-shovel was very interesting!
It didn't hurt, but it felt a bit strange.
I thought it was very uncomfortable!
I can't understand that people pay for that.
Harry, you dared to stop your feet.
I stopped them super many times!
I stopped them three times type.
Yes, Harry is always brave.
We have a question of the day.
Moa's world wonders, "What is the best thing about being gone?".
To experience all experiences.
- Very "up" ... - Yes.
- But I really agree!
- Me too!
Do you agree, mom?
I agree with.
And to hang out with you crunch balls!
- Me too.
I agree with!
- Yes.
It's funny!
I like to play with you!
- Kiss!
- What about me?!
Thanks for watching this video!
Feel free to leave a thumbs up ...
... or down!
Comment, subscribe, do what you want with the channel besides throwing it.
- Bye!
- Goodbye, have a good time!