"Mom, mom! Can't we buy the frozen?"
I'm so bitter.
(Proprut sounds)
- Five!
- Wooo!
- Balalajka!
Hello, hey!
Hello Hello!
Today we will test ice cream!
(Axis) mmm.
You who have followed our channel for a while know that we test this year's ice cream news every year.
Yes!
Here in Portugal GB is called Glass, Olá.
- Olá!
- Olá has quite as ice cream news as GB at home in Sweden.
- Yes.
But not quite.
So, it will be News of the Year here in Portugal, but pretty much is the same as in Sweden.
Yes.
- Are you ready?
- Yeah!
Let's go!
"Frozen Snowflake Cone"
It looks like this.
- Yes, Mom ... Laura has played a little with yours.
- Yes, mine is beaten.
Laura didn't like yours.
The ice cream melts quickly here in Portugal, so now we have to munch.
Oh, Laura absolutely wants to munch.
- It feels pretty small.
- Can she start?
Or, should we start?
- Doesn't it feel a little small?
- It feels very small!
- tiny ice cream.
- So, we drive.
Oh, Laura ...
- Yes, she loved it!
- She will be so dirty after this, I feel it on me.
Can I taste too?
It is blueberry ice cream.
Super good.
(Harry) nom, nom, nom.
Oh, Laura is not visible in the camera.
Maybe was just as good.
She doesn't have such a good table.
I like the taste, and I like the aftertaste, so this one was, etc., actually very good.
What points do you give from 1-5?
- I give a strong 3rd.
- (Joanna) oooh ...
- I give a 3rd.
- I also give a 3rd.
- Dad, you ate up your whole.
- Yes.
Mums!
I think Laura gives a 5th.
And I give a 2nd.
- Check out how much Laura has eaten.
- I know.
She is completely crazy about this.
But I actually think it was a "toddler ice cream".
Can you say so?
Yes.
It is one of this kind of kind when you go to kindergarten, you just: "Mom, mom, can't we buy frozen snowflake cone?"
- And so it was actually the right size for a smaller child.
- Yes.
- But, good taste.
“Solero pineapple”
It's an ice cream that looks like this.
This ice cream is not in Sweden.
- Laura ... - You can't cheat!
She tasted a little.
- Should we others drive, then?
- Yes.
(Harry + Joanna + Axel) Mmm.
- Very pineapple.
(Harry) I like it.
It says that the pineapple comes from the Azores.
It is a Portuguese archipelago that we really want to go to.
- Right.
- Oooh!
Flabby.
- Yes, it's like a little jelly.
- Yes.
It is not like a piggelin - a hard ice cream.
Yes, you like it.
I give this 3.5.
I think it was a delicious ice cream, but it was a bit of a shame that it melted ... or, that it became cordial, so fast.
I give this ice cream 3 points.
I thought it was totally okay.
Laura seems to love it.
Is it a 4th or a 5th?
I like this very much, so I give this a 5th.
The first 5th of the day.
- If you don't count on Pipitas 5th on that snowflake ... - Just that!
But is her point counted?
- No.
- No, we find them.
She seems to like all the ice cream.
She sits and knows it with her whole body here.
She has really smeared.
(Joanna) Aaaah!
I give 3 points.
“Magnum Almond Remix”
It looks like this.
It is dipped in white and brown chocolate.
Dad, you said "white and brown chocolate".
All chocolate is brown?
Yes, if it is not dark - which we call "gubb chocolate" - or white.
- But what do you say then?
Don't you say "brown chocolate"?
- "Milk chocolate", you say well?
What do you say?
Comment below!
I think they are super -ridiculous.
They mock me because I say "brown chocolate".
(Alma) and like: a if you think you say "brown chocolate" ...
- No, then we get no likes!
- ... like a little comfort to Dad.
Okay, like: A if you don't think you should say ...
- Like: a if you like the video.
So we do, for the sake of simplicity.
- Yes.
Like: a.
Like: A anyway.
- Balalajka.
Come on, now we drive!
- Balalajka!
Hello, hey!
Balalaika!
- (Joanna) Mmmm!
- I just suck on it.
Why?
It is delicious!
Chew.
Well, now I understand.
The whole ice cream is dipped in white chocolate and almond, and then half the ice cream is dipped in ...
- Brown ... - ... brown chocolate.
It tastes almond cube inside.
I actually cheated.
I've tested this before, a day on the beach.
I love this one!
Almond cube and white chocolate.
So, you hear.
What are I living with?
It is fantastic!
- (shoulder) The apple does not fall that far from the tree.
- No.
That's good, Laura.
Good taste.
What do you think others?
Well, I don't like this one.
I don't like almonds that much, so I don't like this one.
I give this ... 1 point.
- I think it was totally okay.
- One?
Oh.
- What do you give, then?
- Zero.
- huh?!
- Zero?!
Zero, zero, zero, zero, nooooll!
You are crazy!
Okay.
I think this is a little retirement ice cream ...
- Thanks.
- ... but I give it 2 points.
Laura and I give clear 5s.
“Calippo lime”
This one probably everyone knows what it looks like.
- Very lime.
- mm.
Oh...
- Top on a hot summer day!
- Aaah!
My hands!
- What?
What is it?
- It's so cold by hand.
Aaaah!
- I like this one.
- They have frozen together.
They can't move.
The sugar is starting to get up in the heads of them.
Yes, it goes so fast.
I also feel much nicer.
I was a little tired when we started recording.
Now, just, "ding-dong"!
Yes, really "ding-dong".
Or it depends ...
-♪ "pure frame ding-dong, came all the nicke doll with us!"
♪ - Nämen ... Not the one.
♪ "pure frame ding-dong!"
♪
Oh my God.
Not only are you forced to look at the Melodifestivalen over the years, you should also have to hear those odors to songs.
- Stop being so bitter.
- I'm so bitter.
They are great!
What do you think about the ice cream, then?
That's the one we're going to talk about.
When I eat this ice cream, my tongue contracts, much like I drink something chemical.
But it feels like it contains a lot of energy.
It feels like you drink something that makes you super fast, kind of.
Look at me, then!
Zoom, zoom, zoom ...
- "Zoom, zoom."
What is he doing?
- They don't see you.
He lies and spins here on the floor.
- I give this ice cream 3.5 points.
- Zoom, zoom, zoom ...
- I give it 2 points.
Laura might give ... 3. - Yes.
Zoom, zoom, zoom ...
Gosh!
Put away my paddle racket.
Alma, what do you give?
- Zoom!
- Gosh!
I give 2 points.
I also think it feels a little chemical, if I may say it myself.
But it is nice on a warm and sunny day.
Zoom, zoom!
- What are you doing?
- Come and give points.
- Okay sure.
- Listen, zoom-o.
That one must not be here, because Laura will do so it will be very dirty.
"Hello then," we tell the rabbit.
So!
Harry's score.
Zoom, zoom.
- forward.
- Zoom, zoom!
"Salted Caramel Brownie Peace Pop"
It's an ice cream on a stick that looks like this.
- (Joanna) Now Laura comes to take it.
- (laughter)
This is also a news in Sweden this year.
- Exciting.
- Very exciting.
- Are you ready?
- Yes!
Let's go.
(Joanna + Axel) Mmm.
- Oh, what a lot of taste.
- What salt it was.
Do you want to taste?
Oh, it was like ... there was so much in this one.
Yes, you liked it.
- Almost like Arne's brine.
- huh?!
After all, it is not even like anything with brine.
- Arnes brine.
- What was it from?
What is that?
- I think it was a news last year from Sia or Triumf.
- Arnes ...
- Don't you remember when I kind of spit?
- Yes exactly.
Uncle Arne.
- Down here in Portugal, brine ice cream would never work.
- No.
GB has a brine chalk ... or, at least a licorice ice cream, as news in Sweden, but no Portuguese would buy it, ever!
- They don't eat licorice down here.
They don't eat candy ... - No.
They have a completely different culture around sweets.
The caramel was very, very salty.
So, a little type for salt.
When I bit in it I kind of got a shock because it was so salty.
It feels like a strange mix.
"Brownie and Salted Caramel", and ice cream, too.
It was very much in one.
Mm.
A little bit of everything.
It is a chicken that has stepped on mine.
It's the Peace sign, Harry ... that looks like a chicken foot.
I give this ice cream ... 2 points.
I think it was too much in one.
It was a strange mix.
- I get it.
- I give this zero-superhero.
- Zero?!
- "Scanner Eyes."
- He doesn't like chocolate ice cream.
- No.
There are second zero Harry today.
- Harry doesn't like "Salted Caramel".
- Aha.
I give 4 points.
What does Laura give?
- Five!
- Wooo!
- What is this?
- I spilled Calippo Lemon.
- You made the classic mistake and turned it.
- not "lemon" - "lime".
Calippo lime.
Not "lemon".
- "Don't do it."
Never turn a Calippo upside down.
- No.
We have a question of the day.
Alma, you are here, because it is for you.
Okay.
Yeah!
"Will Alma make a movie about Portugal?"
- Yes, I will!
- Yes, she will!
Pipito is included!
Yes, I will.
- Yes, you will?
- Yes!
- When should it be finished, then?
- I don't really know, but there will be one.
Keep an eye on Alma's channel.
"Solero Barrinha Manga"
It looks like this.
If you translate "Barrinha", it means "barbell" in Swedish.
- In Sweden, a new sandwich ice cream has come out.
- A new taste on sandwich.
Yes exactly.
This is Portugal's version on Sandwich.
Very difficulty, because it doesn't have this ... The bread itself, or what to say.
Just.
It's not a sandwich, it's just the inside measurement.
It is mango and vanilla ice cream.
This feels like an ice cream you have come up with at the last second to be able to fill this ... The sign with news.
Gosh.
It is an ice cream that is easy to make, but completely impossible to eat.
The white vanilla melts faster than the yellow mango, so it is completely ...
It is very unclear why it is not on a stick.
It will only be a giggle of it when you buy it, so I think no one will buy this one.
- I like it.
I give it a strong 3rd.
- (Joanna) A strong 3rd.
It took a little while for me to, like, understand if this was ice cream or if it was real mango.
- Well, you thought it was so mango -like?
- mm.
Pipita is just demonstrating what it will look like when people eat this ice cream in the summer.
It will be an orgy of ice cream.
Yes, horrible.
I give 1 point.
A weak 1st.
I give a strong 4th.
No...
- You have on the upper lip ... - No, a 4th only.
Not strong.
4 points?
I give this 0 points.
A really, really zero zero.
“Cornetto Rose”
It looks like this.
Like a rose.
This is not a news in Sweden this year.
It says it is "Raspberry Milkshake Flavor".
It is thus raspberry mile shake flavor.
Okay, are you prepared?
1, 2, 3!
- (Harry) Mmm.
- (shoulder) mm.
(Harry) mm, mm, mm, mm.
Good raspberry flavor.
It was better than I thought.
When it said "Milkshake" I was a little scared.
- Me too.
- No, Laura!
What have you done?
When it said "Milkshake", I became sure this would be my 5th.
Yes, it says something about your starting point.
Laura likes this one.
Oh, what she jaws.
She has come to a family that loves ice cream.
We are all "ice cream lover".
So, I love this ice cream!
This was the best ice cream we have tested.
- Is it true?!
- Strong, strong, strong 5th.
- So you think this one should come to Sweden?
- Yes!
- (Laura) ma, ma, ma, ma, ma ... - (shoulder) Yes.
How many points?
(Proprut sounds)
Oh oh oh!
That was a lot.
- She held her whole hand.
It was a 5th from Laura.
- Yes, I think so.
Was it the best ice cream?
Good, Laura!
Great, there!
You have my taste.
Good taste, that is.
- I give 3 points.
- I also give 3 points.
I give 3 points.
- This was the last ice cream news!
- Yes.
In summary, you can say that here in Portugal there are more fruit flavors than chocolate.
Than chocolate and soft ice cream and stuff.
- Yes exactly.
Like Cornetto Soft, it is not here in Portugal.
In any case, the new Cornetto soft.
Or Cornetto Dragon.
No, it doesn't exist.
I don't know if it remains in Sweden either?
- No, but it's really good.
- Yes, you like it.
Hope you liked the video!
Yes!
And if you come to Portugal you can always test these ice creams.
Thanks for watching this video!
- Feel free to leave a thumbs up, or down.
- Most thumbs up!
Comment, ask questions and have a great time until we see you next time.
Bye!