We have created a family club!
♪ Happy Birthday to you!
♪
- Last jerk in the autumn term now.
- Yes.
I feel like I have my school uniform on me.
- Hello!
My very own "plushie"!
Check!
- Good morning.
It's everyday morning.
- Yes, and I'm actually going to school soon.
- Yes.
New braids.
New braids that mom has done.
I am doing "Volume, Volume, Volume."
Now I didn't take anything.
What, "is doing and doing volume"?
"Volume, Volume ..." So, I pull them out a bit like this.
Well.
I didn't take anything.
What did you say, Laura?
What did you say?
- I am drawing.
- Yes, you are drawing.
Getting really nice after all.
An ant.
Well.
A crayfish.
An ant.
- Okay, it's a Laura-Myra.
- A crayfish.
Today I thought we might go a little neighbor.
- Yeah, how fun!
- After school.
It could be fun, huh?
Check out that Smajlet.
There is someone who likes Gejming.
- Last jerk in the autumn term now.
- Yes.
Bye.
- Have a nice day at school.
- Yes.
Bye.
Alma and Harry have taken the train to school and I have left Laura in kindergarten.
- So now it's just the two of us in the vlog.
- Yeah, for a while anyway.
There is a lot going on in our family right now.
Or, it does well in all families before Christmas, I think.
But we have had an idea that we have worked for quite a long time.
Yes.
An idea that we can finally talk about.
- Yes.
We have created a family club.
- Yes, a community.
- Where membership is free.
- Yes.
- And we think you should become members.
The basic idea is to save time and money for families with children.
We know that there is a lot you want to do as a family, but the more you are the more it costs.
Yes, and we know that it is difficult to make time enough when you have children of different ages.
So in the club we will collect nice deals and discounts-
-To everything from the necessary stuff like grocery bags, to fun experiences that you want to do as a family.
Yes.
We have over the years built up a fairly large experience-
-Kring what our family and our children think is fun to do, and what you think is fun to do.
So we have contacted places that we have been and visited, and they are now in the club with good offers.
- We have built a website with very small means.
- Pytte, Pytte, Pytte.
So, we don't have a lot of money.
And we collaborate with Miia and Ramin, our friends down here who have been seen earlier on the channel.
- Yes.
And now we are actually going to go in and meet Ramin.
- In their office in Lisbon.
- Yes.
- And look a little on the club website.
- Shouldn't you say, "hook on"?
- Hang on!
- I always feel like a child when I get in a backpack.
- And I feel like I have my school uniform on me.
Yes, you also have a backpack.
But that is the best way to wear a computer.
Yes, I feel that my back is getting old, so I can't carry any other way.
Then I get hurt.
- Oh, how dark it got.
- Yes, oh!
So there.
Now.
- It takes a while before the camera hooks on.
- Yes.
- Hello!
- Welcome!
- How's it going?
- That's good, thank you.
- Well!
Oh, what a colorful shirt!
- Yes is not it?
- Handsome!
- The Africa discovery.
- Yes.
- Perfect.
Welcome.
- I am very happy with it.
Thanks.
- I see that Ramin has filled the fruit barrel.
- A little extra calories are needed.
- When we were here last we ate everything type.
- It needs.
God, what fun.
It really looks like it's the one who listens to music.
- It's my "PAL" in the office now.
- Cuddly.
You may turn off the music, it may be copyrighted.
Yes exactly.
- Oh!
- And so they went off while the music ended.
This is Harry's squishmallow.
But he should tell you more about it later, right?
Yes.
- Check out.
Here is Lauras.
- It doesn't look quite as happy.
I know.
But yes, here they come packaged.
God, how secret this was now.
We talk more about it later, simply.
- Should we check the website?
- "Let's do it!"
Fun!
I really like this green color against the blue that comes back here in the picture when Alma sits and draws.
And then ... The gray fits great.
And the pink pops really nice so you really see where to push somewhere.
It will be great.
- "Hitåt."
Can you push, then?
- Click, click!
"Yes."
- Now we came on!
Good.
- Yes.
We have talked about separating this.
"Weekend adventure & everyday projects."
- Right.
- Exactly.
It's "in the making," but it takes some time.
(It's on)
- Yes, but now is the last jerk here.
- Yes I know.
So now it's full intensity.
Now we just drive.
Here we go!
Of course, you know a lot more about all such arrangements than I do and have someone you usually work with and such.
... and come back with your thoughts, and then we can try a meat and a fish.
We have long thought that we want to be able to give back to families and followers-
-And there we have come to the conclusion that we start an online club that will become all of Sweden's most active family club.
- Hello, what is happening?
- They are fought.
- You're home from school.
- mm.
- Where is Alma, then?
- She's on the paddle.
- And Laura, then?
- She's on her "cream".
They are very tough there.
That's actually true.
Harry's leisure closes four.
If we go to pick up Laura then, then she has not even eaten mellis.
The whole day is shot here in Portugal for the little ones.
- But you, Harry?
- Yes?
I thought you should come up instead of being under the bed, in your little room there.
Go up to bed to show your ... plushie, or squishmallow.
What are you saying about these?
- I think you say "plush toy."
- "Plush Toy", okay.
Your very own "plush toy."
They have seen it earlier today.
What is this?
It's a "plushie."
My "plushie."
Yes, that's your "plushie."
I don't know if you remember, but we talked about it for a long time ago.
When you made the "children decide" we were in a toy store.
Do you remember that we asked: Would you like to see us make your own "plushies"?
- Yes!
Viewers absolutely wanted to see that.
So we have been doing and investigating this and it is a jungle, I should say.
It is a fun project, but it takes time even when designing yourself,-
-And you look at different designs and what you can do and so there.
While we have been looking, we found this, and ...
- Can't you bring out Lauras?
- Yes.
Here.
We found a manufacturer who had each one that suited Alma, Harry and Laura.
- Yes.
- Should we pick up Almas too?
I can go.
Check this out.
Here is Alma's rabbit.
And so Hörrni, it is very tidy here now because we have had a maid here today, I will admit.
- It has such a nice cheeks.
- Yes.
Check out, when I press together ...
- Check this out!
- Yeah!
The whole family is gathered.
Yes!
We sell these in our member club, in a small webshop we have.
And in that webshop we have some selected products.
- A few selected products.
- Exactly.
A few.
And...
There we try to push prices as much as possible.
For example, we know that these we have put on a price level that is about half compared to a toy store.
- And they are very soft!
- And big, almost like a pillow.
Exactly, this is a pretty big "plushie."
You can squeeze it together so it gets small, but for a big "plushie" it is about half the price.
But if you are going to shop there, you have to be a member of our club.
So first you have to go in and become members, and then you can check out the webshop.
- And that's free.
- Yes, membership is free.
But then, we haven't even said how they find the club.
Right.
The address is: www.swedishfamilyclub.com
- We will put a link in the video text.
- The link is below.
But first you have to check the video clearly.
- Yes, because now we will go and pick up the girls!
- Yes!
"Let's go!"
But should you bring the toys, right?
- No, they may remain.
- They may have a conference with the other friends there.
Yes.
Here is the local paddle and tennis club.
Alma!
- Hello!
- How did it go?
- It has gone well.
- Was it fun?
- mm.
- It's so yellow in here.
You get the worst "Christmas feeling."
- Yes.
- It's actually Christmas decorations.
- Yes I see it.
- Hello girls!
- Hello!
Hello, Laura!
How are you?
She wants to be kissed.
It was my first time I was in Laura's daycare.
I didn't know you had to go in.
Obviously you get, it's not C*at anymore.
Or yes, it is, but ...
- It was really nice.
- Yes, it's a very nice kindergarten.
But inside I can't film.
I can't come in.
No, because there are lots of other children there and we don't have their condition.
I'm craving a pacifier.
- Well, it was ... - I'm craving a pacifier.
- You are craving pacifier?
- Yes.
- When are you not craving pacifier, Laura?
- Exactly.
Pacifier and ear pill.
- Lets go home!
- Yes!
This is my favorite food, this pasta sauce.
But then you, that pasta ... you have to fix that.
- Yes, but wait.
Stop, stop.
- Press it down.
"I NEED TO DO IT PERFECT."
Check out, it goes down, because it becomes "wobbly."
Okay.
And you, this is common ...
- I want ice cream!
- You want ice cream.
But we're going to have dinner first, Hörrudu.
- I want ice cream!
- You get ice cream after dinner.
- No, "Göt!"
No, "Göt!"
"Ingot!"
- Porridge.
- Yes.
- But listen, you have to take out the pacifier so I hear.
- Want "Göt!"
Okay.
I can actually imagine boiling some porridge for you.
She is so difficult to get in food right now, so I would like to make oatmeal porridge for her.
But what I would say was that this is ordinary spaghetti, Alma.
Hörrudu, who has eaten wheat -free all year.
Yes!
I have received from my doctor that I am not gluten anymore.
It has grown away.
She is not gluten.
You have done new allergy tests.
It's funny that with, "I'm gluten."
Surely no one is gluten.
Or?
- So ... gluten allergic.
- Alma is gluten.
Or, you were gluten.
- No, she was hypersensitive to wheat.
Hello?
- Yes.
- But anyway.
She's "fine."
She can eat everything!
- Yes.
"Happy Days!"
We have received a lot of today's question about it, so now you got who asked answers.
Yes.
So there.
Oh oh oh.
So.
Now Laura wanted pasta anyway.
But I actually boiled a porridge.
Do you want it?
No.
Anyone else who wants it?
Yeah!
- You are welcome.
- Thanks.
And Alma's favvo is pasta sauce with ham and mushroom.
- Uää!
No, I don't want!
- No, you don't want it.
Do you have it like this at home too?
- Don't have it!
- No.
Okay okay.
Do you want some ketchup, maybe?
- Okay!
My turn.
- Good.
Your turn.
Mm.
It is enough.
- Now comes the gos-anchor!
- Will the Gos anchor come?
How cozy!
- It has gone down the stairs.
- Well, does it have?
Come and sit here with me.
Oh!
How cozy.
What do you do?
We sit and have "Game Night."
I promised Harry that we would play a little, so now I'm the spider man and I fight against Harry.
- No!
- "Yes!"
I won.
We have a gejming console with several thousand old games.
So, games from the time when I was a child.
Type 100 years old.
Type Sega Mega Drive Games, PlayStation 1 Games, Atari ...
- Dad, fast!
Now!
They are fought!
- Oh!
And arcade games.
Great fun.
- It doesn't look very modern.
- No, but it's fun.
Oh!
A "power-up!"
No!
No, your mushroom!
Wait there and it will probably go back.
- Mom, come on!
- (Joanna Tjar)
Now it's my turn.
♪ Happy Birthday to you!
♪
Is it "Happy Birthday"?
S -speed.
Well, it's Lucia?
- Do you want black?
- AAA.
I don't think there is black here.
What day is it today?
It is Friday.
We are vacant from school and kindergarten because it is red day here in Portugal.
- Pink.
- Yes, it can be a pink day.
A pink day ...
But Alma, what happened to your room?
It was so tidy and nice yesterday.
I know, it got really great.
And Laura doesn't help so much with the mess.
Speaking of messy homes, we actually have an offer in the club on home cleaning.
There I got it too.
There are a lot of good stuff in the club now, and there will be more!
Yes.
This is just the start.
And the more members we become in the club, the better discounts and offers we will be able to negotiate to you.
So now we want you to follow the link at the top of the video text and go in to register as members.
It is a simple registration.
One should be adult to make it,-
-So if you are a family, then one of the parents enters the children's birthdays, because we have an idea ...
Laura has birthdays!
Yes, you also have a birthday, and everyone likes to fill years, and many people like to have a greeting.
- Laura is celebrating years.
- Yes, you turn three next time.
That's just two.
One more.
We have a thought of being able to send out birthday greetings through the club.
- To all members.
- Yes.
That service doesn't really work now, but in the long run.
Eventually.
Thanks for watching this video!
Feel free to leave a thumbs up, or down.
Subscribe!
Comment, ask questions and have a great time until we see you next time.
- See you!
- Bye!