Hello.
- Hello.
- Where are we?
- We are in Isaberg, in Småland.
Yes.
- And what do you see behind, then?
- Our house and dad, which packs his backpack.
Isaberg is a ski slope in the winter.
And now in the summer you can do lots of fun action activities here.
Very cool!
We came here yesterday and then it was full of mountain bikers everywhere.
You can go up to the top and cycle down.
We should not.
- I can't.
- No I know.
If I cycle very fast, I will be so scared so I fall.
Oh yeah ... but what should we do now, then?
- High -altitude course!
- Yay!
Yes, yes, yes, yes, yes!
We start the day at high altitude.
- Camera mounting in progress.
- Yeah.
Thanks, Alma.
How nice.
- Are you nervous?
- No.
- It's pretty high.
- It will be great fun.
- How professional they look.
- Right?
It looks like they are going up and folding trees or pulling electricity into any post, or something.
- Daddy, when do you put on your suit?
- Soon.
- We are ready!
- Yes!
Yes, yes, yes I have the coolest suit, wow!
I got a green helmet because I have the world's biggest head, so now I really look like a watermelon.
- Are these the steps to climb up?
- Right?
Worst watermelon.
We will have a review now, Harry.
These are great, because you can't open both at the same time, so you will always be locked with at least one.
Good, is not it?
If you look at these locks, at the cabin hooks, you see which one is open and which is locked.
The one that is like a C is open and the one that is like a U is closed.
Now I have one that is open, and then I can't unlock the other.
It only goes halfway.
So you are always stuck up there.
The arrow against the magnet, and press firmly.
Then you see that it is also locked, and then you will get rid of the other.
Press the button and pull it against the wire.
You don't have to use your fingers.
So, then it unlocks.
(Harry) pull up and pull down, pull up and pull down ...
Oh, I happened to hit the camera.
(Alma) Harry, stop now.
- Oh, someone is a little taken over.
- Yes ... we'll see how it goes, this.
Now Harry will try.
Connect you again.
- Here, or?
- mm.
Okay.
Where does the little rope hang?
- Here it is.
- Thanks.
(Alma) Be careful!
Beware ...
Don't do that when we're out on a real track.
- Okay.
Can we everything now?
- Yes.
- Are we ready for the first course?
- It's a bit scary to be a solo twig, without an instructor.
- Yes, it's a bit jerky.
Now you just have to.
From this low height, up there ... there, good people.
Here we go!
Okay ... This was a bit difficult.
- (Axel) Oh, what fun!
Worst sled.
- Yes indeed.
Alma is Santa Claus!
- Are you ready?
- Yes.
Run, then!
♪ Prince Ali, which magic, aliababa ♪
It feels like I'm too heavy and will fall down.
Help, oh, help!
Now I'm going to skip to the next.
It's ... half -hard to go and film ...
But what do we do because you get to hook at home.
What do you think of the high altitude track?
- Great fun!
- Perfect!
- Very funny.
- It was really fun.
And really warm!
Yes, extremely hot.
We had to go in and sit down and have lunch.
Usually, like Swedish, you always sit outside when the weather is nice, but it is almost too hot.
I know you can't say so, but yes ...
Yes, Alma got almost a little sunbathing there for a while.
Now we will test something we have never tested before, but which at least I am very embarrassed.
What do you feel?
Me too!
- I'm really nice.
- Rodel!
Yes, Rodel!
Summer rod.
The track is there.
I turn the camera.
- There.
- Woho!
- Come on, friends.
- We are running!
- Mom, should we drive one?
- We will sit an adult and a child in each ...
Okay, I want to sit with dad.
Dad is so kind.
- Do you want to sit with me, then?
- Okay.
- I'm pretty kind too.
- Yes.
You go up there, then you turn around at the top and go down.
It looks like a roller coaster, roughly.
The camera is mounted.
We are ready.
- I think you should fasten you.
- Oh, just that.
- Hello.
- Have you gone before?
- No.
- Do you get in the belt?
So yes.
- It feels very important.
- On the way up you don't have to do anything.
- No.
- It's too tight.
- Well.
It's too tight, she says.
Rather too tight than too loose, Alma.
- So.
- Thanks.
That said, on the way up you don't have to do anything.
And when you are at the top you pull out the levers, then it is full gas.
Then you hold there.
If you want to slow down you release a little, you decide your speed on the way down.
- Yes.
We run the highest speed, huh?
- mm.
- Let's go.
- Thank you thank you.
(Harry) Dad!
(Alma) This will be exciting!
Dad, jump on.
- Alma, how loud is that?
- How do they dare to ski down there?
- Are you prepared?
- Yes.
Are you prepared?
- I'm ready.
- Are you really sure?
- Yes.
- Are you really?
Are you really that?
Are you?
The gas forward.
Now we drive, Harry!
- Are you really ready?
- I'm ready.
Are you really that?
"Forbidden to stop", "accelerate" it says.
- The rowing was absolutely insanely funny.
- Super fun.
- It felt, in the curves, like you would fly out.
- Yes, it did.
So it was a creepy moment in that.
So, it was a curve that I never really dared to keep full skewers in.
- Full gas.
- Yes, full gas.
It was a bit jerky, actually.
It's fun that there is so much action here.
I get some new Zealand vibes.
Yes indeed!
A little rotorua ...
Yes!
So here it was in New Zealand - nature place and lots of action you could do.
- mm, this ... swing.
- Yes exactly.
And the Zorb ball.
- We just test a few things here, there is much more.
- (Harry) Wieee, I go cable car, wieee ...
- Golf, all the Mountain Bike tracks, and so on.
- Yes.
Of course.
This is the last stop on our Småland trip that we do in collaboration with Visit Småland.
All our stops are on a link in the descriptive text,-
-If you are curious about any of the places we visited in these four vlogs.
- Yes.
Yes.
- So check it out if you want.
Check out.
- "Yes."
"Check it out."
This is how we live.
Here is Mom and Dad's room.
Here is the living room.
- And an upside down Harry.
- Yes.
And here is the kitchen, and ...
Here is mine and Harry's room.
- You can excuse the mess.
We are on vacation.
- Yes.
Excuse us.
- And the technology has moved from bed to the kitchen table.
- Yes.
So here it is sometimes.
Here comes the camera Christmas tree.
It fits, because we are in a mountain cabin.
Yes, but exactly.
Yes exactly.
This must have been a mountain cabin from the beginning.
And then this ski resort, as it was from the beginning, has redone and become a little more summery.
- They also run skis here, when there is snow.
- Yes exactly.
When it's snow, yes.
A great facility, I must say.
I like it.
Nice with a lake nearby.
God, what a nice.
It's super nice.
We are on this awesome sauna raft.
Oh!
What a light.
So, it's still so hot.
It is six o'clock in the evening.
In there, Alma sits, and cozy.
With a camera!
Should you jump in with that one?
(Harry) Oh!
You splash!
It was a little cold on your feet.
It was a little cold on your feet ...
- Was it?
- ... at the bottom, so I got a little ...
What a pillemary mine you did.
Oh, now you made the castle minute.
Show for mom.
This is how Gustav does Vasa.
- Can you put on a Gustav Vasa image?
- Yes I can do that.
Harry was super nice.
We went past the reception, so he said, "Dad must have some snacks".
He knows exactly how to charm me.
- Chipsoman.
You get a strange shadow on your face now.
- Oops.
So there.
Give me chips pringles.
Thanks.
- There are a lot of people away at the bathing place.
- Really.
Many families.
Now it will be very good with some food.
Harry and Axel have burgers.
Alma has ...
- Raggmunk.
- Just like me.
And then you can go and play in the really fun park that is right next to it.
Yeah!
Harry, wait for me!
- "in said no."
(I said no) - "You Said No?"
(You said no?)
(Harry) This is going to be jerky.
I thought we could take care and summarize Småland, instead of today's question.
Yes.
Beautiful, I think.
Really beautiful.
- Yes.
Much to do.
- Very much to do.
For family, top.
And we say that from the heart, that is.
Many lovely bathing lakes.
A lot of coffee, everywhere.
Yes, they love coffee and sugar!
We have not filmed that much, but it is like coffee cottages, waffles, ice cream, pastries and sweets everywhere.
Mixed with flea markets and small towns.
And knob.
Yes, now it is extremely bump.
I try to stand still, but my whole body just wants to ...
Thanks for watching this video!
Feel free to leave a thumbs up, or down.
Comment, ask questions and have a great summer, and we will see you again soon!
Bye!