But fuck what this is disgusting
Yeah, who is watching this video even
Yes, it can only be sick people.
Fy fuck
Everyone just: "How are you really" - yes.
You have been exposed
What do you mean - but I have told you how
Sticky you are.
That I get red rashes all over my face after you hug me.
Do you see that I am red here it is because I just just hugged Anders.
He came in here and gave me a hug.
It is absolutely sick how sensitive skin I have.
Or how dirty boyfriend I have.
This is an intervention.
Yes?
The first time Anders and I met, he told me:
"Dirty Boy ..." Yes.
So now you have to be responsible!
I am prepared to do that actually.
Okay.
You who have been hanging out here at the Youtube channel for a long time surely remember to
I have this microscope, or what is it for
Well it's a microscope.
I thought like this tool, but microscope is correct.
It is a microscope that I have partly made a youtube video where I examined
Different parts of my own body ...
What was that
... and I made a video where I have examined mold.
But Fy it looks almost like some kind of cobwebs!
And I have made a video where I examined the dogs with a microscope.
Who is tagged on a new video
So ... last out in this series ...
... am I - that's you.
But then we'll see if I'm dirty then.
Yes.
But I have showered.
Okay.
Let's go
Yes, then we drive what do you feel?
I feel like this that I want to start with the beard,
Because I want to know why I get red outlaws in the face when you be beeping with me.
Beard me
I think I'll move the camera a bit like that so I can post the picture here.
But God, the sun goes out and in all the time, Anders.
Don't you play this now too
No, I don't fuck that.
Good, Anders but what is it, I am pondering
If we should put any trigger warning about it.
Help Anders, what thick hairs - but if you look up in my hair then?
I have nothing to compare with, when you say they are thick.
Okay, but here you have a beard.
And then up on the head, kind of what thin - oh!
They are really funny
No, how disgusting that is.
Oh, no, get away!
What is help!
That's just my baby died, yeah that's just my baby died!
Check out, you have this blonde hairs in the beard you see?
Oh - oh, you really have no pigment!
Check out how they sit.
There is the hair follicle.
Wow, what cool, Anders
What sick it was
Do you see it is like a white ... - It's a white straw and a membrane over.
Yes.
God there!
But Anders, how can I reach then?
Aj - the Anders, what is it?
Oh what the hell is that?
Damn what disgusting this is!
What is that for something then
After all, I have a blood thing here on my nose somewhere.
A blood thing - yeah so, I've happened
scratch me and ... can't you check out there
Be then - here somewhere.
Uuh!
Oh!
Take it away!
Remove it, Therese for hell!
Fy damn how disgusting it was!
Can you zoom out!
What kind of thing is that I do not know.
I close my eyes because it is so disgusting.
The nose then - oh, no!
No, no, no there are pores!
Yuk!
- Oh my good, Anders!
But Fy Faan
I feel bad about that.
You don't push so nicely against your nose either.
It just gets harder and harder.
Look there!
I can not see.
You have your hands everywhere.
Yes.
There you have a wound.
Oh - what is that?
Nämen oj - coagulated blood.
But where is it from?
From the head.
So damn what disgusting everything is!
What is this - where are you?
Yes, what is this body part - but where are you, Therese?
Is it in your ear, or where are you - here!
Well how the hell should I be able to see where you are - the YOM don't you know?
Is it in the ear where it ends
Yes exactly.
So that to the left you see the snib.
But then this is so disgusting!
I shudder are you seeing my hair?
I think it's so disgusting!
Do you see I sparkle!
Why are you sparkling is that makeup?
- mm.
Indy Beauty's highlighter.
Recommended for Women - Why can't you turn off now?
What has happened - oh!
Oh!
What's that?
Nämen Anders - what the hell is that?
Can they stop calling at some point blunt!
Anders - can solve that in some way.
What is this what is this?
It's your thumb.
Lol!
Oh!
How should I be able to look under your nails when you bite
On the nails, Anders I can't look under a single nail.
Baby!
Hahaha do you want a toe then?
- Oh my God!
I don't bite them.
What is it - what has happened?
What then - now we should check under the nail on the toe.
Yes.
That's what you wanted - I don't know.
Oh - Why do you have glitter on your toes?
Hahaha - It wasn't that bad?
Oh, this looks like some kind of reptile.
Yeah don't
Yes, maybe.
This could be a snake.
What is that - a blood bladder?
Porer I do not think is disgusting at all.
Should I scratch it up?
No no!
Are you stupid?
- Hahaha!
I was just joking.
Haha but damn what this is disgusting!
- Yes, who is watching this one
The video even - yes, it can only be sick people.
Fy fuck - hello?
How are you doing?
Yes.
I don't think there are psychologists for this.
No.
It's beyond all help.
Only Jesus can help.
Jesus - Anders has a navel.
Yes - which collects incredible amounts of cotton.
Well it is not something unnatural.
No, that's what he says.
I've never had ... I just want to say for the record that I've never had ...
I have never looked down, pulled up my sweater and seen a little lint in the navel.
But the thing is that I have hair on my stomach.
That's what does it.
Everyone who has hair on the stomach,
Regardless of the gender, which has a tshirt or shirt will have lint here.
I promise
Well then I would like to know down here in the comments section.
If it is true that all of you who have hair on your stomach, you also have large amounts of lint
It curls out under the sweater
What are you doing now - I'm looking.
Check this out!
Well it starts there.
It is starting to gather now.
And so my hair works.
But there is grass there!
Yes, I don't know where it comes from.
It feels like you are doing such ultrasound as
You do when you are pregnant.
Takes such a batter first and then ...
Hahaha batter first ...
Imagine if we were to see a little one there ... but what a hard time if there was a child there.
Oh - oh, purple!
What's that?
Decor - Decor?
May I look at the tattoo
Oh theres!
You must not scrape in the wart.
I hate it.
Check out what disgusting this is.
It looks so disgusting
No.
Want to see my scalp
It is very white.
Now look at my color there.
Oh what a difference!
You are more pink huh - yes.
Nämen Hello - Hahaha!
Hello - Oh what yellow teeth!
Close mouth then check here!
- mm.
Yes there yes.
What is it?
I do not know.
That was disgusting yes.
In the armpit as well.
If we are to finish there The Extended version you can find on the snake pit.
Hahaha
Sorry about..?
This video.
Why?
Yes, yes, actually.
Sorry.
Fy fuck what disgusting it was
Thank you for checking today.
See you again next week.
Take care of yourselves
Kiss and hug -Ciao!