[Rock music]
Are you tagged old man
[Both in chorus] Hello
The servant darling
Congratulations in arrears!
- Gosh!
Gift to me
Yeah!
- We will empty it today.
We will do that.
Champagne Nah, you bought champagne!
I have!
- For real!
But God can we sabotage it later?
Do you know how to do it?
- Yes, I've done it.
I have video proofs, do you want to see
It's the sickest in my entire life, I saw a tictoch ...
... where there were hacks on how to sabotage.
It's really easy.
[Rock music]
What is needed is that it is cold, preferably that it has been a bit in the freezer before.
So you should take everything around.
So you just pull on this one.
Listen damn careful now, because you will be learned something like this educational before.
This little ... where you see that the bottle is sealed, the seam yes.
Well said
Are you sitting backing my brother here now, is that what you are doing
[Laughter] No then
I turned years yesterday, and it ended with a fight between me and my brother, you can say.
But it always ends so when I'm with my brother and drink.
He knows exactly which buttons to press, so I get started on all cylinders
I have a bump on my arm today because he hit me so hard.
And mom says:
[Light, dedicated voice] "But it wasn't that hard"
I have too damn bruise and bump today, of course it was hard
We try to plan here, after all,
Because today we are going ... magnetic fishing I forgot for the fuck the magnet at home!
No?
- Yes, haha!
[Laugh]
I came on it now
I only have the liquor with me
[Laugh]
[Laughter] namen God
How the hell could I- [Laughter]
Damn pat wood
We don't really know where to fish.
Our biggest problem is that someone has to drive, and then someone has to be sober.
So we sit and divide if it is worth driving.
Then we might as well take one in town.
We are so damn thirsty, it's Saturday today too.
Now damn, I hope it is enough for 17 meters.
Should I send in the first then?
- Okay then.
Should I throw far or right down
I don't know, it feels like ... maybe you should throw it far out.
Then you pull it in a little.
The premiere
Now we bowl and hope we ... you can get rich in this
Yes maybe.
Be careful not to spill the beer.
Good consistency splash.
- Yes.
Take in now take in as hell!
Don't drop it so the whole rope disappears.
[Cries and laughter]
We got not a shit.
[Dog rush is heard]
GOD GOD
Namen god i don't get from it
[They are laughing]
[Laugh]
It shrugs a little when I pull like this, it feels a bit like you fish.
We do too, but.
I have something or?
Well, yes?
Or?
No...
Have they cleaned the lake or what is the question of
We must be silent when fishing.
- Yes, we must be silent now that we fish.
Otherwise we scare away ... - scares the fish away.
This is really the right kind of fishing for us.
Which is never silent.
We are silent but still we get no pacifier.
- But I think it's a scrap.
That you have to be silent.
Imagine large fishing vessels how much they sound and bonels, and how much fish they get.
I think it's a scream ...
... as all dads said because they want peace and quiet in the boat.
I believe that, and now everyone believes it just
What is like this
Eh ... - what is it?
When you stand like this
It's probably throwing a bullet or?
- Toss marbles.
Now damn ...
[Excessive music]
Woah
Damn what boring throw- [laughs]
Good throw!
- Was it?
Now we have to get something.
A fork I am satisfied with.
Now it sits on something it sat on something!
Slowly pull up then I think.
It feels like it is releasing type.
Or there are stones I go against.
Ah Nah, totally fucking empty again.
- Nothing.
If you think logically now ...
If the boats come from there,
And this bridge doesn't go up ...
Then no one is going here
But aren't people throwing in stuff then
Who should go and throw in stuff then
Killer.
- Yes but that's kind of what you want to find!
[Laughs] a coffin type.
It's something!
- I knew that too, that's it?
Though the magnet released.
Wasn't this where you knew anything too?
- Yes!
What the hell can it be
That was exactly what I felt.
You feel that you have something,
But as soon as you pull, it feels like it becomes easy.
A spoon
Yes so damn good!
Feels heavy [laughter]
"It feels heavy" yes
You are welcome!
- Thanks!
What is more then?
- A screw...
Yes the first find of the day.
Fy damn what a good thing, it feels good that we got something up, then we know it works.
It feels like it is sitting against this type.
It sits rock hard.
- No!
Damn.
Now it released.
Here type.
It's something mega ... - Mega magnetic.
It is still on now and I have lifted it from the ground.
[Mood -enhancing music]
Did it follow from the ground?
- Yes now I have lifted from the ground.
Can't we go out on the dock there then or does it lift?
It has lifted from the ground.
[Excessing music] I think damn I get with it.
-—-—-
Damn what heavy it is
It starts to decline type.
It's still on
No no no no!
Damn
-—-—-
How far was this then
No f*tta, I dropped it.
Released it-no!
It's on
What
-—-—-
[Roar]
It's still on!
- It is certainly kind of a buoy or something so boring.
There is something red
[Screams] It's a bike
Nah
[Loudly] Well what!
What
Is it true
Or ... no ...
What the hell is this
Can it with this
It's a bike it's a bike!
We must have a tactic here now.
Should we pull it right up or go with it to the edge
Up?
- Yes!
We got a bike
I have a bike now
No no!
No damn ...
Damn...
We have to get it up
I think it gets too heavy for the magnet when it comes above the water surface.
It is just that it can handle it in water.
Pull to the page, I think.
- We drive aside.
This bike should fuck up.
One would have had a hook or something.
"I have a bike now" [laughter]
I've wanted to have a bike for a long time.
It is just to change tires and it works.
Don `t you think so
Do you have it
Okay we go to the page ...
But it is shit -heavy
I say it, I fucking hurt in the back.
The back of the back ... lumbar spine.
But now I have something heavy on here or.
-—-—-
Yes, but what is this?
A knife?
It's some old ... one that one had at the railroad type
Yeah
Cool
You would really wear sketch clothes.
- Yes, and gloves.
Yes, we stand here and go to the play.
Pig -cold is that too
I really freeze.
Now we have been reinforced here by a guy, guy ... well, man.
Old man feels so nasty to say.
He was named Frasse
Yes, he has a boat over there.
What was his name?
- Frasse ...?
What was you named again
Ronny is his name.
Ronny The King.
Have you seen Copper?
- Nah.
"Don't F*CK WITH" ... haven't you seen Kopps
Is it he who shoots in the forest?
- Yes!
What is he saying "don't f*ck with Benny the cop".
I thought he was called Ronny but now when I said it was heard that his name was Benny.
Don't F*CK With Ronny The Cop.
It is probably Sweden's absolute best film.
[Shot]
xxx
Don't F*ck with Benny the cop.
Benny
[Inaudible Slud] Benny
You can find something
No...
[Laugh]
Oh God...
Where did you get this idea from
To magnetic
So ... it's my acid guy who bought this magnet.
So he had been out and got a bike, so I thought damn, that's a bike I need
It's a bike I want
So I don't have to buy one
Yes
Something a little ...
A hose clip.
It have you dropped [laughter]
Yes it does not surprise me.
It is strange that there is nothing that takes up gold.
A magnet that takes up gold, but gold is not magnetic.
No, but how do you get it up then
I mean it, there should be something that attracts gold.
A gold magnet.
- A gold magnet yes!
You should invent it.
Hurry you fast as hell before I do.
Takes patents on the shit.
Grab how many people fished for Kim Kardashians Diamond Earrings.
I think they found it!
- did them?
Crying Kim Kardashian over an earring, then it is expensive as hell.
Then it's not free
Damn what you got to take in when you pulled it up there
It sucked.
Check.
- Sick!
If you have come this far now go in and subscriba, lay and comment!
What would you have wanted to get up,
What the hell do i know, write something cute
Otherwise, you get a hit.
Press the clock.
What the hell is this mentioned!
Gosh?
A sword!
- A sword!
[Laughter] namen God
What a thing.
- What the hell is this?
[Inaudible]
[Laugh]
What do we think this is then
I do not know.
Beware so you don't cut yourself.
No.
My first apartment was over here.
King apartment.
-King apartment, fuck what disgusting it was.
It was the worst-fuck what disgusting it was!
No I liked it.
Are you kidding or so ... the decor- I can post some pictures here, if I even want to show ...
This is naked after all
Now I feel naked.
My first apartment was over here so we were always on Hamngatan and drank beer.
That is why we are Tjenis with those who work there.
Stammis.
- Stammis!
Old stammer.
The tribal price of beer, then you know that you have succeeded in life
That's the only thing I want to achieve.
We have just stopped in a little jaw, loaded the camera,
Drunk some Irish Coffee.
Should we try to find any magnetic fish
[Laugh]
He said it now, he who works here ...
"What do you have the camera for," he said.
"We've been and magnetic fishing today"
"Well, what is it for fish"
[Laugh]
It was a big silverfish ...
[Laughter] Big ...
Where is your magnet?
[Silence] ... in the car.
God, I got stroke there for a second
Here he comes, the star.
The Magnetic Fisheries King!
[Laughs]
We sat talking about Tomorrowland here exactly.
Magical trip.
That I survived that trip is totally sick.
Go there I say.
[Loud music]
-—-—-
[Inaudible talk]
[Uppet tempo music]
When we were there for the first time - there is nothing in my life that I have done that has been more fun.
That festival was the most fun I've done in my life.
But it was a first time ... - experience.
Yes, damn how nice it was.
17 scenes
250 thousand people or
Yes.
Fy damn what fun it was, it was so sick.
Now you can't sit and tell things in the vlog because you ...
We had fun, we don't have to say more than that.
Sober and such.
I brought the sleeping bag with me, I have it at home.
Did you do that
I still regret that I did not bring the whole tent with me.
Damn what I regret it.
Take to just pull up a Tomorrowland tent.
Fuck!
Everything was so damn perfect just
Should we go next year?
- Yes!
Like, yes.
- Will we be?
We go to Tomorrowland and then at Rättvik Classic Car Week.
Dance band week in Malung
-—-—-
Like and subscribe, say!
- Like and Subscribe.
[Laugh]
Bowl
You have fixed a man for me now
Dense as hell.
- Dense as hell.
Excavator operator.
- Oh, and good looking too.
Scooter cross, excavator, handy and dense.
It's like the hand in the glove.
He has sheep and lambs too.
- And have sheep and lambs.
Is he lamb?
- Yes.
He is as old as me.
- I thought you would say like us.
Perfect after all.
98a
But he has to fall in love with me too, how should he fall in love with me
Is he in love with me
Yes a little?
Beetled
But there is a difference between being hungry and in love.
He must fall in love.
He can probably be.
Can't all comment on a tip on getting someone to fall in love with one.
Do you have any advice
To be yourself.
- Yes but it's so shh ..-- To be yourself, yes.
After all, you are.
Because I mean, these fucking games you run ...
That you should not answer two days and so, that does not work, it is just invention.
It's just a invention.
The only thing we have done in this vlog is to drink beer and thaw.
Damn what a lot of magnetic fishing it was.
Good luck making this interesting I should say.
[Laughter] Good luck.
- Good luck.
Well fought.
No [laughter]
[Sad piano music]
[Laughter] So that is all guys ever.
When you hear people talk out loud ...
Then you think "how do I sound myself", I am miss decibel myself.
And I'm talking out of my nose.
Do you
[Talking nasally]
No, not really.
[Laughs] "No, not really" - how do I sound then?
How do I sound ... - full.
Okay, I'll mimic your voice so you mimic mine then.
When you are full you get to an "Iande" like this.
[With Stockholm Liding Dialist] "Hello, so I'm called Maja."
"This is my beer".
Jenny, you must not bring it.
Bring
When you are sober, you sound more cool.
"Hello ...." [Laughter]
[Stockholm dialect] "Hello my name is Maja, now we sit here ..."
She has something cool "now".
You have something that is like this ... "Cool now".
No...
Yes but that is good
You have a good voice.
No, I have a dark voice.
[Laugh]
[Silent laughter]
"Dark ..." [Laughter]
[Mimic] "I am dark ..."
You have do the doctrine voice.
Wady voice you have.
I think we are pretty much the same.
You two
That we talk equally.
I still have a dark voice
You probably have no dark voice.
[Himmar Tanja's dialect] Yes you talk like this anyway.
It sounds just like you get to the point now.
[Laugh]
What point now
It's always like this that "so."
"Now it's over"
It's point late
[Inaudible]
Nähä ... [laughter]
I'm talking like that?
- Yes.
I do it
"Do I talk like that?"
Point.
- No!
Is that how I sound?
- It's like you always spot.
Yes actually.
Oh what sick, what a good said.
I hear it myself now.
I hear it now ...
[Laugh]
What should I say?
- [mimic] I hear it now myself.
[Says in different ways] I hear it now myself.
I hear it myself now.
[Mimics] "self"
How should I get commas instead of point
No, sit.
There was no point, it was coming.
Well that's point ...
... ...
[Sings]
[Unclear which song]
-—-—-
Okay, Challenge.
Not make a sound away.
Stand up.
Shall we beat him now
[Laughter] No No.
Put it in your mouth, and you may not make a sound away from you.
Okay, beat him.
No [laughs]
You must not be tickled ...
[Talking at the same time]
You should, like ...
Okay all right.
Okay I put the timer in 10 seconds or
Or five?
- May I beat him as hard I want?
Yes, rules of play
Clear, finished, drive
[Laugh]
No sound.
[Sound from the harmonica is heard]
[Laugh]
So should it be maja, not stand and tickle
One more time.
[Laugh]
[Audio from harmonica is heard]
[...]
It makes a huge pain.
- I have pain in my arms, you have to beat somewhere else.
Hit me in the face.
[Laugh]
My brother hit me hard before.
Not too hard here.
You have to hold tight.
[Tanja laughs and the harmonica sounds]
You have to have it all over your mouth.
[Laughter and the harmonica sounds]
[....]
Breathe through the nose Tanja
Not up here, down here.
[They talk at the same time]
I have pain in both.
I have two brothers.
Jerry hit here and Jimmy hit here.
[The harmonica is heard]
[The harmonica is heard] breathing through the nose
[Laughter] you cheat
Hit somewhere else.
[Laugh]
[They Tjora]
Hardrock Hallelujah then
[Playing] "Hard ... Rock ... Hallelujah"
Ouch!
[Laugh]
[Inaudible]
Well, don't sit down now.
Näääe, stop.
You know you get a rod.
[Uppempo Country Music]
fff
[Dogs and laughter]
Tanja for fuck!
-—-—-
[They talk at the same time]
[...]
Hold your arms, what are you doing
Tighten your arms
[Laughter] buckles
Release
-—-—-
Subtitles: Alice Skårbratt