"Why can't you sit still do not blame your ADHD."
Today we will talk about ADHD and ADD.
What diagnoses do you have all
Adhd.
-Add.
Add.
-Adhd.
Adhd.
How was it before you were diagnosed?
-Chaos.
For me, it was kind of that I felt completely abnormal.
I could run out into the corridor, and everyone just looked.
When I talked to my parents, they were ...
It wasn't taboo, but they said, "Stop trampling. You're just small."
Was it you who took the initiative?
-Yes.
You others, then does anyone recognize the reaction?
Mom said: "Don't be stupid. What do you say"
"It's not just me, but you and my little brother."
My little brother was recently diagnosed with ADHD
So the probability is greater that I have it.
How has the investigation gone to
It started when I was nine and the first year of high school.
I noticed in the eighth that I could not concentrate.
We are like this.
What are you tired of hearing are there comments?
That you are lazy.
-That you are a steam child.
"Now comes her fucking hyperventilations. 'Oh, my good'"
Where do you hear that?
In school?
-Everywhere.
Home.
"You are so lazy. You have school."
It takes me anyway.
Medicine takes your energy so that you do not use it unprofessionally.
Without medicine you run around, then you have to sleep.
Do people usually joke about you?
-Yes, giant.
You are "Messy" and neglect stuff.
"Flash Gordon" I have been told.
-It's a superhero?
You are ass -fast and run around.
It's kind of it ...
Are there any taboo about having diagnoses What have you come across?
Vladimir
In the beginning I did not get the support I needed from my parents.
Culture has a lot to do with it.
There is a lot of ignorance about other cultures.
They don't know that much.
You are a bit questionable and careful.
Can you give any examples
Mom was not very positive in the beginning, but waiting and cautious.
She wanted more information, even though I wanted to proceed with the investigation.
Was it the same for you
My Dad still believes today
Because he thinks that when he was growing up, they did not have mental illness.
For him it is religious.
"You have a demon you have something in you!"
"We'll pick up an exorcist and fix you"
Mom said she knew about the ADHD.
"You're like a Duracell rabbit running around!"
Nor, you got your diagnosis quite late.
What could it be due to
The thing is that I am quite calm, though the concentration was completely pie.
I could never complete my tasks.
I think the teachers thought I would fix it
Without thinking that I might need help, which I did not have-
until just before the student.
And then you went into an investigation
My friend who plugged into a treating educator said I had ADD.
"I'll call BUP" ... -She knew right away.
She booked a meeting, and there I was diagnosed
And medicines.
I was behind in all courses.
I had too much information, but with medicines I fixed it.
Do you still take medication?
-After high school I threw them.
You get so much anxiety attacks from them.
Rough side effects.
What is the difference between ADD and ADHD
Without hyperactivity.
Everything is inboard.
The chaos is inboard.
It may not be as visible.
-Therefore, it's not that notable.
Many have ignorance of ADD.
Will it be more difficult to discover then?
-Much harder.
Can you others tell us how it was before and after the diagnosis
I was only seen as a chaos child.
My dad doesn't believe in mental diagnoses.
"We don't have stuff like that in Africa. Only Westerners have such things."
"Children should run around."
But at school I had no focus at all.
I always had to drum on everything on the tables, the chairs ...
Everything was a drum for me, and I had to run around
Because I have so much energy.
In the end, you explode and scream and just have to do something.
Then you had nothing to blame.
"I'm not like any other child, because they are calm and can focus."
"I'm just like a big explosion."
When I was diagnosed, I knew what was wrong
Or what is the basis for why I am who I am.
Then it became easier to understand what you can do.
I did not have any medicine, because I have always been told "horror stories"
About panic attacks, but I already had such things and didn't need more.
But I got tools instead, which helped so much.
Then I could catch up.
Vladimir.
What happens if one is not visible and is part of the crowd
You went in a messy class.
How was it
When you are in a messy environment, you fall into the crowd.
It will be difficult to pay attention to it.
How did you find out that you had ADD?
-When I started in high school.
It was not a socio -economically exposed area, but there were resources.
The classmates usually sat on the lessons fully concentrated
And they were committed and said things.
One noticed that I could not follow instructions
Even though I wanted and had the interest.
Viktor, how was it for you
When I was diagnosed, I was relieved.
I knew I had something
But the schools never wanted to investigate.
I had to go in special classes.
Why didn't they want to do anything?
-They said it was a phase.
Lucky you got extra lessons.
-Fast it didn't help.
But in high school I was old enough.
There was no phase anymore.
The investigation said I had ADHD.
How did it feel?
-I began to understand myself more.
But a diagnosis is not so much fun.
What did you think of others when you were told that you have ADD or ADHD
What was the first thought?
-It was both a relief and "damn!"
Then you fall into their "you are a diagnosis child".
Did you tell people around, or did you hold it to yourself
In the beginning, I became worried about whether it would affect me in working life.
"Will people think I'm stupid"
Once you say it to someone, they can speak this way:
"ADD, ie the disability"
What "disability"
You get a stamp, but I just have a little difficulty with the concentration.
They say, "Why can't you sit still and don't blame your ADHD."
But that is the thing.
You do not want to blame it and explain.
On some lessons ... I have a tendency to hit a snuff box
Against my leg, which people disturb, apparently.
"You may sit in that room with a link to what we are doing"
"But you can do it safely."
Then you get ostracized.
I will be the problem, though I am not.
Don't make us a problem.
We just need a little extra help.
When you are stuck, your thoughts come:
"The lamp is gray, the carpet is black ..."
You think of 500 other stuff.
"What should I eat when I get home"
Then you come nowhere.
Some teachers do not understand.
At school I lie after
And then they say: "You've got these lessons on you."
But I have a harder time taking things in and need more time
But you only get these lessons.
The problem is that teachers do not ask what kind of help you need.
They just assume.
-What did they do after your diagnosis?
Then they only gave me extra time, but I couldn't focus anyway.
I need someone who tells me, otherwise I just run around.
I needed someone sitting next to it and wrote down the steps I would take.
Did you feel any change when you had received your diagnosis
For me it has been as before.
I have not received anything positive from it more than I know for myself what I have.
What would you like your teachers to do
I need someone who understands me and who is genuine and trying to help
And not just say "you have ADHD".
Now we will talk myths and claims about ADD and ADHD.
There are some
As we were going to test with you now.
We run "fact pingis".
Clara comes in with ping pong rackets to you all.
You see that it says "true" and "false" on them.
I will give you five different claims
And you respond true or falsely.
Let's go.
Number one:
"You can't have ..." Wait, you might see the answer.
The answer is here.
"You can't have ADHD unless you are hyperactive."
Do you hang with three, two, one, up.
Everyone holds up.
-"You better explain!"
Am I right?
-All responds "falsely" except Viktor.
Why?
-Add and ADHD are two different diagnoses.
That's why I answered that way.
What do you say is anyone who is a hundred that you are right?
No?
Do you guess - is there anyone who has any idea?
Hyperactive is to run around, but some may be a little stressed
And maybe fiddies with a pen.
You don't have to be hyperactive.
You need to move.
-It is right.
It's false.
Hyperactivity is one of the symptoms.
-The limit can be floating.
There is a gray scale.
Let's say someone is cleaning at home.
One second they wash, but they do not make it clear, but go and vacuum.
You do everything half -finished.
-You find something to pill with.
You clean and find something that shines.
Are you ready for the next number two:
"You can get ADHD of poor food and too much sugar."
The diet can give ADHD.
Damn people are determined here.
Three, two, one, up.
"You better explain!"
-Now Vladimir can explain.
I do not know.
I think...
I agree with a little neighbor.
If you eat a lot of sugar, you get more energy
As you have to get rid of, and then you are more hyperactive.
But people with diagnoses usually already have the level of hyperactivity
So food probably doesn't affect that much.
False was right.
You can get hyperactivity from sweets and poor diet, but not ADHD.
They always said when I was little that I was crazy with sugar.
For us with ADD ... I need sugar to work.
When I can't concentrate, the sugar helps.
"You can't get ADD and ADHD later in life."
Three, two, one, run.
Sorry.
-"You better explain!"
“You can't ...“ Decide.
"You can't get it later in life."
You change your mind.
-That was what I meant.
Can anyone explain?
-It's...
There is no age limit for when you can get it.
It's about your psyche.
It develops in your brain.
It can come with age.
-Add and adhd are born with.
It can trigger, so you end up in investigation when you are older
But ADD and ADHD you are born with.
Can anyone pick up ... I don't have the sources.
We can find out later.
Write the sources down here, so people can read.
But it is proven that you are born with it, then the symptoms can come later.
That's what I meant anyway.
This is right.
-You would be right if you were wrong.
It was fake I was thinking about.
-We everyone was right.
Listen carefully now.
"Either you have ADHD, or not."
There is nothing in between.
This question was giant ... "what"
Either you have ADHD, or not.
There is nothing in between.
Okay.
You must not explain.
You get.
Nothing is black or white.
After all, everyone has a fling of something.
No one is perfect, and ADHD is gradually.
Not having ADHD does not mean that you do not have any of the symptoms.
So it says in the script.
It's a gray scale
Just like in many other diagnoses.
Sometimes it can be difficult to draw the limit for where you are.
Then we run the last.
I don't know who is leading.
It says the same.
-Then there will be exclusion.
Number five:
"ADD and ADHD are new diagnoses that are increasingly used on messy children."
Three, two, one ...
Nour?
-Take the question again.
"ADD and ADHD are new diagnoses that are increasingly used on messy children."
Yes, because nowadays it feels like you just throw on ADHD on children
As soon as they can't concentrate.
It may be because something is boring and that they don't like what they do
But the teachers can directly judge-
That the child has ADHD because of it, so I definitely think ...
What are you doing?
What do you answer?
-Sant.
Okay.
Why do you answer falsely?
I do not feel that people use it as an apology
And says you have ADHD when you run around.
I see it as so-
That an investigation is required to find out.
You are right.
The reason for more diagnosed
is that there is a lot of research and that you now know how someone with ADHD
behaves, and the diagnosis has been around for over 50 years.
You were right.
I have a rash issue now.
Do you want to win?
It doesn't look that way.
-I am stressed.
I will give you a question
And in case you have a guess, answer, but you only get one attempt.
"How many percent of the adult population is estimated to have ADHD"
What counts as an adult?
-Over eighteen.
How many percent of ... -9 percent.
Okay.
-Don't check me!
-—-—-
Should I also say 25.
Far from ... -Are you what you said?
You said 9.
-—-—-
"None of those there."
-For loud, but Vladimir was closest.
2.5 percent is the correct answer.
The winner here comes a trophy.
An applause to Vladimir
First prize.
-Get you?
Obvious.
It's just sharing.
Okay.
-I thought it was 6 or 3.
I thought 5, but said 10. -This with school ...
You who have received extra help, how was it received by other students
They were treated differently.
-How?
I could get comments from others that I went to school with.
"Why can she sit in another room" "Why does she get more help?"
"But I'm much harder to do this."
"You may also have a hard time with focus, but I have a mentally difficult."
Explained the teachers to the students what you had
They said, "She's a spec child!"
What do you want teachers to do for you How do you wish them to be?
That they should be more understanding and want to help.
If they do not want to, then you do not take it.
They just do it for the money.
It doesn't feel genuine.
When you got help, how was it received in class
Type you got extra time on the tests
They think you are left behind.
It was not taken well
But you have to stand up for yourself and explain.
Vladimir, you plug in university.
How does it differ from high school
There is a greater responsibility on one's self to make sure everything has done.
You do not get the same backing as in high school and elementary school.
One has its own responsibility to find out their rights
And how to get them satisfied.
Thus a student who records for you
Or one with whom you have lectures.
Then one must tell you about their needs
Instead of just getting support.
How does it feel to have to take the extras step
I have tried to explain to the class
But haven't really dared to tell, because it feels strange.
Many people think that those with ADHD and ADD are "losers"
But then many people do not see those who are actually very smart.
My friend has ADHD, but plugs into a civil engineer.
She may be hyper
But she does what she should and can.
When doing the investigation they see that you are often over -gifted
And as well as "over average".
It leads into my question.
Have you heard the word "superpower" used
From my psychologist I have been told, when I was diagnosed with the diagnosis
That I have a good pattern memory.
I can memorize incredible amounts.
When doing the investigation they show a picture to memorize
And then put out on time.
I do well because of the "superpower".
No local mind, memory, forgetful ...
I have no local mind, just patterns.
Have you heard "Super Power" used when describing ADD and ADHD
It is very difficult to know.
You do not know if it is because of the ADD or because you can do this.
At least I know a thing you saw in the diagnostic test.
I am quick -thinking and can take it as a superpower.
But the concentration pulls down on ... -it becomes harder to learn things.
May it feel problematic that many people use the word “superpower”
To describe ADHD as something nice?
It's a good thing.
-It glorifies the diagnosis.
But you have your "ups and downs".
Once you have it it feels good, but when you have dips, it sucks.
How about those who don't feel at all they have a superpower
You just become more "specborn".
Speaking of music.
You were part of a competing TV channel music program.
We do not mention any names.
How was it then affected the ADHD in any way?
The ADHD helped me very much through my journey.
It took me down in a way that I just let all my feelings fly out.
The ADHD helped me, because I was always ahead.
Without the ADHD I would have given up
But now I pushed myself to the end.
I had a goal and drove on.
It was something I love, and there the ADHD also kicks in.
If you love something you go "all in".
One last thing I wonder is what you have for tips
To someone who goes through an investigation or who has just been diagnosed?
Find out your rights.
There is a lot that I do not know about, but there are rights I can get.
And also to ask what there is for tools.
What can I get to make it easier for me in everyday life
Great tips.
Find out your rights, "Embrace it" and drive.
Thanks.
Do you want to be with, or do you have any topic that we should take up-
So there is contact details down here.
Subscribe to our channel so you don't miss anything.
The next section is now coming on Wednesday.
See you then.
bye
Texting: Linda Eriksson www.btistudios.com