It is perfectly normal for it to be.
Hoods can be long and short, wrinkled or completely straight.
Nothing is wrong.
When you get a stand, the foreskin must be a little wrinkled, because when the penis gets bigger, the foreskin must follow.
Otherwise, it hurts when you get a stand, if the foreskin is too tight and tight.
This is because the foreskin is narrow.
So it is for most guys under the age of 14.
After the age of 14, the foreskin usually widens by itself.
Or by masturbating.
If it does not, there is great help to get at a youth reception or at a health center.
Girls have no foreskin in the vagina that is the equivalent of guys penis.
But on the other hand, there is a kind of coat on girls clitoris, it is called.
It can be likened to a little with a foreskin.
When girls are excited, the clitoris swells and then you can clearly see that it sits like a small foreskin around it.