No, now I've happened to lock the cash register!
- Then it's time to change keys.
- I want it to go well for her, but I don't know.
I don't think she will have any benefits in here.
- In Janne's kiosk, the sausages are ready.
Here we have to cook it from scratch all the time.
- This is going to be fun!
So Agnes should now without help run the kiosk for a whole day and receive hundreds of customers.
At the same time, Janne should be responsible for the staff at a luxury restaurant-
-And also cooking for a large bunch booked evening guests with extremely high demands.
But one thing Janne and Agnes do not know about.
At the end of the day we will bring in a professional jury and let our challengers compete against each other.
Who is doing best?
A cutting chef in the kiosk or a sausage guy on a luxury pub?
- The news grill.
- Now are you feeling bad be Agnes?
- Yes, now I'm feeling bad for real.
It can probably be among the most difficult I have done, I think.
- Is that so?
And then you have made it very difficult anyway.
- Yeah
- A little bigger than the street kitchen anyway.
Nice to do away with the Swedish people later.
- Does it feel nice?
It feels good in the stomach?
- What is a sausage sausage as well?
If I sat in the shit before-
-So I think this will beat everything with horse lengths.
- As you now step in, there is no return
There will be hundreds of guests today.
You don't even know where things are.
Is it hell that hides behind you?
- Ahh, fuck.
- Welcome in, Agnes.
- Here is your staff today.
- Hello!
- Hello Hello!
- Hello to you!
- Yes ...
- We have a menu we're going to drive here tonight
- Swedish Flatostron Edu ...
So what is this?
- This is then the menu
- Yep.
- Thoughts?
- No.
- They do not know that we are guest by you in the kitchen, so it is super important that we keep the level we always do.
Which is world class.
- Yes.
At the same time at Kungsholmen, it was time for Agnes to enter her new workplace.
- Are you kidding?
Does it call on?
So literally it is.
You haven't seen the kitchen ...
- No, fuck!
The news grill?
- Yes Hi.
I was going to order a jalapeno burger.
- Jalapeno burgers?
-Yes.
- When do you want it then?
- Yes, as soon as possible.
- In ten minutes you get one.
- You have to make a jalapeno burger directly!
- What the hell is that on it?
- We have sausage bread here.
- We have sausage bread there.
- Here he will have a hamburger pocket.
- Good good good.
Pommes!
- We should have french fries.
Now the burger will need ...
Oh, Satan!
- No, no, no, no, no, no.
- Oh, heart attack.
- You have received an order so far.
And you are already close to heart attack.
Are you the one who has ordered?
- I have ordered.
- Bank card 25 bucks.
I can't take 25 bucks for a burger.
- Now it will be 10,500.
- For 10,500, then I really expect it to taste special.
- Here.
Oh, damn!
Overrun requested
What should I do then?
Great.
You are welcome.
- This first I can say that ... I'm a little worried about how Burgarn became.
At Restaurant Sparrow we start preparing the food.
In 30 minutes, guests will arrive.
- Who should do what?
We have to go through.
-  I will...
- You are the manager, Janne.
- Then we have the calf year here.
- And this one should we just have?
- Yes exactly.
- you will ..-
Yes.
- I fix.
Linus, now this is clear
- So, there is a bit of a lot of membranes left.
- I would just show you that is right.
- Yes.
- Don't delay it now.
- Did you say not?
- Yes.
- Janne ...
- Linus?
- Yes?
- I want you to enter my office after the end of the work session.
- Okay?
- I hope you are at checkout.
- You already have a new attitude as soon as we gave your managerial role.
Celari 94 degrees inside temperature combi it says.
- What the hell is this?
I can call a friend.
- Who are you feeling?
- A friend, adib.
- Is he good at root celery?
- Yes he is the best.
- Best in Sweden on root celery!
- Hello?
- Adib, it says 94 degrees inside temperature combi.
What does Combi mean?
- May I ask why did you get more break now by talking to Adib?
- Yalla FaceTime
How to make 94 combi?
The root?
What does the root mean?
Have you seen?
I have made a great dragon mayonnaise, check out.
- It's like another guy when he talks to Adib.
- Do you see?
- There are two different people.
A Svenne -janne.
- And a blatte - Janne.
- What are we going to do now?
- Set up the station for service.
What does it mean?
Well, set up station for service ...
I do not know what to do.
- Are you starting to wash your hands now?
- No, I'm going to my kiosk instead.
This is hard for me.
- Hi welcome!
Now let's make a roll.
- Yeah.
You still have control, I think!
- 100%
- Oh, wait.
No wait.
- Agnest, now you actually have to think about here.
It's a very nice customer here.
- Oh no...
-What?
Why did this get so bad?
- Yes ... I regret.
- Yes, me with ... extremely much.
- That's not what I would have.
I would have a maradon roller.
The sausages feel half -finished haha.
- Now I think it is a meeting with the staff, because now the guests will be coming soon.
- Is there anything you wonder about?
Jalla, then we drive.
- I'm really going to clarify, it's like no extras, but it's real people.
And you are responsible for their money and food now.
- Yes then we run
- You think we fake this?
So there will be people!
- What should they eat then?
Your food Janne.
That's the whole concept here.
I wasn't kidding when I said you would take over the job.
Then they came one by one.
All unsuspecting guests.
That did not have a rush that this star's pub
Right now was run by Janne from the local grill.
I think I should have a tartar
Yes, but we are sucked on the oysters
Nice, thank you very much.
Lovely, we fix it.
Thank you, thank you very much.
- I think...
- Yes, damn.
This is not okay.
- There, yes there.
Bullseye.
Like a glove in hand.
Why don't they buy pre -peeled?
Please, bling!
- Four oysters?
Yes, one without onions.
- one to tartar?
- Okay, a tartar.
- What does it say on the menu?
- Dragon salad.
But what is dragon salad?
- Do you know what it looks like?
- No.
- Imagine if the guests knew that the chef stands and googles dragon salad inside the kitchen.
- What the hell, check out, it became a refrigerator.
Here.
Halloumi.
Oh oh oh.
Without onions, please.
- Two tarts here on the calf of the vessels as it should be divided on
- Yes.
- Nice
- Thanks.
- Can I taste.
- What do you feel?
Are you satisfied with your bet?
- So the thing is that the arrangement was ...
- It doesn't feel like that.
- No.
- The sauce I thought was very good.
- Yes, it was very good.
- Oh oh oh.
Now I got sauce.
It was delicious.
- They seem to be happy.
- This was delicious.
- It was delicious.
- Two pepper roast, then I want a medium well and a medium rare.
- What the hell does that mean?
- We can make meat we can do in the meantime.
Heat on so that it is warm.
- That sauce huh?
- No.
- It?
- I'm so cash on this.
- Someone ordered the medium.
- I don't even know what that means.
- What's his name?
Linus?
- Yes.
- Does it work well?
- Yes, it goes well.
- Good, tell us if you need help.
I just fool him, I know nothing.
- Do you know huh?
I don't think you've cheated him.
I will cover the sauce here with the meat because then it is not visible how much they have been fried.
Okay?
- No.
- It tastes like rubber, but it's good.
How many pepper roast, six pepper roast should we have then?
Six???
- Three ...
- Okay, I'll fix, I'll fix.
Give me just a few seconds.
They will be satisfied my customers.
- Fort now!
You have to fry.
- But then no, I put too much.
- Janne that is not professional.
This is not good.
- This one is medium, this one is well.
- It's well done?
Yes.
And these are two french fries for them.
- Oh, thank you.
- Hope it tastes!
- I make that more worried about, they ordered some mediums, some ordered medium well done.
Everyone became ...
- But I think it will be good.
- Is it grilled?
- This piece of meat was dry.
- I got a tough bite now so I can't chew in it.
- I might get this for me, but the salad was ... It wasn't good.
- Ten out of ten.
Minus points because it was cold.
- I have no connoisseur, but I thought it was dirty.
- But you're not that difficult, right?
- The news grill.
Hello?
Oh, he hung up.
He heard it wasn't Janne.
What the hell is Mauri?
He would be my sidekick.
- Now we have run Håkan Söder, chairman of the Friends of the Tunnbrullen.
Now you should order a thin bread roll by Agnes and see if it keeps the measure.
-Welcome.
-Hello.
-What do you crave?
- I was going to take a thin bread roll
- What does it cost then?
- Then it is up to you to decide what it should be in it.
A little currytchup if you have.
- This was a good bong.
Ketchup.
Curryketchup.
This was not currykhetchup.
Now we have to find Curryketchup.
- A little shrimp salad is good.
- Shrimp salad, do you want roasted dive?
- Ah
- and now to the rolling then
- Now I think he looks a little uncomfortable.
From the customer oh, it was a fun shape today.
- You are welcome!
- Yes thank you very much.
- Now I was just going to tell you, Agnes.
- No, what is it now?
- This is Håkan.
- Yes.
- He is chairman of the friends of the thin bread roll
- No!
It's true!
I am redoing.
- You usually say that you want a tight roll.
That it should hold together well.
- Yes.
- I'm not really sure.
And then she made a very strange strut, huh?
Yes, but it was almost just ketchup.
After all, it became like a children's roll a little neighbor.
But still interesting that she works as a chef
But this one ...
- All tables want creme caramel so there are eight.
- Okay.
What did he say?
We fix.
I have to have plates.
- Janne, it looks terrible.
- No no no.
- What is this?
- This...
- It must be dried or how.
- You can't serve it anyway?
- No absolutely not.
- No.
- Janne, this one is impossible even worse ...
- Do you think this is better?
- No, problems.
- Problem?
Classic problem.
- Yes, I think we have to have a coffee now.
- Coffee?
- Do you feel that you have control?
- Yes.
- We give them some ice cream then
Oh check out!
So she can't give me failed now
Then she gets fired too haha
Pling!
You are welcome.
- Vanilla ice cream?
- Yes
- With cream?
- And lemoncest?
- Yes
- But I don't understand you got any kind of mess?
- It was because I was a child.
Then I got glass.
- God, they look completely different.
How fun.
- It was pretty good indeed.
It doesn't look good.
- Oh, this one was cute.
- The grade goes down because you look at it
But then it is good.
- The same dish, it is completely different.
- Is it a tastiest dessert you have eaten or?
- Not in my life but ...
10 out of 10.
- Now my Adamer and gentlemen are the lunch rush up and Agnes Puls has risen from 110 to 140.
- God, then.
Oh my God.
Oh, Satan.
Ahhhhh !!
- How are you doing right now, Agnes?
- really bad, money just lies everywhere
It's totally sick.
Now it's not fun anymore.
Now you have to call Janne.
Now I can't cope anymore.
- For real?
- Yes, call Janne.
- Jan, you have to come.
- There, Janne!
- Everything in the burger.
- Check out what a good looking it is.
- Oh, damn!
- So there, then my friend sorry you had to wait.
- This kiosk means a lot to me.
It is...
I do not know.
In fact, I see almost many customers more than I see my own family.
So, now the last three months I have opened and closed every day.
Seven days a week.
But at the same time, I know nothing else.
Alongside my family, this is my life too.
- Now dinner is type ready.
Now they have eaten all dishes.
I go and now check how they thought it tasted.
- I am waiting.
- huh?
- I'm waiting for you.
- That's really good.
- I just would like to thank everyone for being here at dinner.
And then I would like to present today's chef.
Which has cooked all food itself.
But as has never been in a restaurant kitchen.
Welcome to Janne from the local grill!
Come Janne, come!
- Hope you liked the food.
- But Janne, this was just heating.
Now the real challenge begins.
Now it's time for step two.
- Okay.
What have our challengers really learned during the day?
Now it is time for a competition where Agnes and Janne get to cook whatever they want in their new workplaces.
A sausage guy with access to extremely exclusive ingredients and a star chef with the limited supply in a kiosk.
The question is, who makes the best right?
And then will be judged by a real star jury.
- Everything I've cooked in life has led me to this particular moment.
- This could be the most important event in culinary history.
- I resigned from Sweden's master chef to join this jury.
- But this is ... it's like ...
- It's a bit like this ... If the sausage guy succeeds just as well, then the whole chef church falls as well.
- You could probably say that it is your reputation as a chef in the future that is at stake.
- mm.
- Hello?
- Hello, Adib.
I need your help to cook.
Adib, you are the professional now.
- What should you cook?
- Adib, this is serious now.
They are filming.
Then followed a ten-minute confused conversation there-
-Jan and Adib came to a fairly safe card.
Dragon Mayonäs, clove potatoes and a really good piece of meat.
- Okay, does it feel safer or?
- No.
- You then start with liquid egg yolk.
- Yes.
Damn, this doesn't look good.
- No, it's fluid.
- Yes.
- Yes, yes, yes, Janne!
- Adib listen, it gets loose.
- Yes, it has cut.
It has cut.
- And maize, should I put in the maizena?
- No, it's best to make new ones.
- Okay, Jalla.
- What will be the big challenge of the sausage guy?
- It is perhaps if you put the bar too high and want to do too much.
- If you use ingredients he has never tasted and machines he has never tried-
-Then it can go really badly.
- Warning?
New attempt.
Try number two.
- I think you should taste this now.
- Should I?
- Yes what was it called?
- Mauri.
- Taste this one.
- Now!
- Taste that one.
- Next step.
- Now I'm going to try to wash some vegetables and start frying the potato to the meat.
- I'm going to try a gnocchi thing.
- Are you going to make a gnocchi in a street kitchen?
- Yes.
- It's like luxury food.
- It's delicious.
- That's what you get at finer restaurants.
- Really.
- Will it go?
- I do not know.
Hope.
- And what will be the star chef, big challenge?
- I think the big challenge is to find a red thread and know quickly what to do.
Yes, it is exciting.
- This will be ruffled.
- It's so cozy that you start singing for yourself.
-I can do it, oh!
- Are you a little annoying?
- Yes, 100%
- You want a sweet tomato sauce.
And you get that as well.
When you caramelize onions it becomes sweet.
We will try to make a flavored butter.
- What, so you should taste butter with chorizo?
Mashed potatoes?
Now you have pulled out an onion.
What are we doing with the onion now?
Oh God!
Hand on heart.
If you can guess, will you beat Janne?
- No I do not think so.
- Can you show me Agnes Cup?
- Which trophy?
- As she should get now when she wins.
- You, up with self -confidence.
She also has a tough time.
- Who will win?
- I'm not entirely sure.
If the sausage guy only serves as he is used from his own kiosk-
–Desa delicacies that he gets access to-
- So it should be very good anyway.
It is difficult to do something extremely interesting in a sausage kiosk maybe.
- Nice colors.
- Yes.
- A little autumnal.
What kind of meat is that?
- Back steak.
- How do you know that?
- ehm ...
- huh?
- Oh...
You ask so much.
So this is not good meat.
- Hahaha!
Janne, Janne, now it's black!
- imagine a little of the good bearnaise sauce I did
- The bearnaise sauce?
- No, the dragon sauce.
- The dragon sauce?
- What was it I did there?
The dragon butter?
- Dragon mayonnaise!
- Dragon mayonnaise
- So.
- Oh God!
- Damn what good!
- Now gnocchi is going into the tomato sauce.
- Yes exactly.
- Aa ...
- It should attract a bit.
Now comes the chorizo butter.
- In terms of taste, where do you think we are there?
- So better than it looks, I think.
- Cheers!
- It's really good!
Will you win this now?
- No, I know maybe.
So I don't know.
- Voila!
- There we have it, Janne!
Bullseye!
And quite frankly, I get really excited to eat it there.
- Thanks Bram.
- Thanks!
- Stop talking to me like I'm Adib.
Before you go to the jury, it still feels like it's a guy who should come here-
-And check how it was before you present it to the jury.
Welcome in...
Adib!
- What a hero you are, Adib!
- How the hell did you succeed?
Check out, check out what sexy plate.
- Walla it's fantastic!
It's really neat.
- When you talk to me ...
Your break also disappears when you talk to me.
Why is it like that?
- I do not know.
- But now I think, as this has somehow become your right,-
The question is whether you should not present it to the jury together
- Yes.
- Are you nervous Jan?
- Yep.
I don't know what to say.
- You can imagine telling you what you have cooked anyway.
- Fried steak with fried potatoes, some fried vegetables and ...
What's the name?
- What kind of thing?
- That sauce.
- Then we release you Jan, and then the jury should eat.
- Thank you, Jan.
Thank you all.
- The sauce.
What do we say about the sauce, mayonnaise?
- It almost needed a little more, I think.
-Everything is quite dry, like the rest.
- I think it's pretty good.
It has a good acid in itself and it is resilient
Compared to a finished bea or some finished sauce it is very good.
- What I appreciate is that it is not a mayonnaise consistency.
That it is a little thinner.
- If you had stood there in the kitchen with me, you would have understood what an unlikely randomly it is.
That this mayonnaise is still approved for you.
- Or is it also the feeling that he may always cook on some kind of intuition?
- Yes ...
- You continue.
Now I see that you are sitting and pressing.
You eat the more.
- 100 percent!
- You have to rate this later.
But before that we will take in the next competitor.
Agnes
- Hello!
It's a gnocchi I've done on the mashed potatoes.
So it's a tomato sauce and then a little onion.
Just that, it's a chorizo butter too.
- Yes, I would say it is completely vegetarian.
- No, it's with Chorizo.
- you set up worried
- Hahahaha
- Like this.
- See you Agnes soon.
- Bye.
- I like the presentation.
It feels like something hip like in Brooklyn or something like that.
- So sometimes the simple is difficult.
The chorithzo butter really made the trick.
That is what lifts the whole right.
Because it adds so much taste.
- What impresses I think in terms of the chorizos butter is that it is just right.
She has found an incredible balance in this.
- Blown Away by her creativity.
I really have to say that.
- But hopefully there were a little more fresh tomatoes left that you could have had.
There were probably roasted onions in the street kitchen that you might be able to do ...
She could have ...
- Then the question is how to judge it all?
Because it is quite obvious that she is a better chef than Jan.
It is the conditions themselves.
- But the question is which right you thought was the best.
- Now it's time to count how much points they get.
And we will start with ... should we start with Jan?
- Now we really slaughtered
- Jan, of me you get one ...
Second.
- Edvard Blom.
- Jan, of me you get a four.
- Gullis
- Jan?
- I am satisfied.
- In total, Jan gathered ten points.
And now it's time for you, Agnes.
- Yes, ush.
Not fun.
- And tea, you start.
- Yes!
- Five
Great!
I did not believe!
- Extremely impressive cuisine, but ...
At the same time, I'm a meat guy, so it's ...
- Yes, totally okay.
- This means that Agnes, you now have eight points in total.
If you get three or more of Marcus, then you win.
This is a shudder.
- And it is he who is so strict.
That's it, we know him.
- Yes, so so severe that it almost gets sexy
So you are so really strict.
- I can say this, I always try to be very professional and fair.
But now it should be decided.
Gnocchi ...
It's not really my favorite dish.
So that I still landed in a point ...
That gives you ...
YES!
- We have a winner!
Congratulations!
- Thanks!
- Congratulations!
Or what a congratulations, sorry.
Well fought!
But should we end with?
- With a pilsner?
- Hahaha
It's actually a great idea.
Should we have a beer or?
- Get chairs.
That is why you have with Edward Blom for such proposals.
Bowl!
There we sat and drank beer and found that it is about as difficult for a sausage guy as for a star chef to change jobs.
Then Jan was introduced to the priest's little crow.
The priest's little crow would go out and go, no one had him driving.
And he slimmed here, and he slipped there, and he slipped you in the ditch.
And then he slips into the ditch!