But then there are people around Sweden who put down their entire lives to prepare for disasters
They build bunkers, they collect preserves and they fill weapons cabinets.
These people are called preppers and it is precisely them this section should be about.
Are they madmen or do we have something to learn?
And what are the disasters they think are we facing?
You will meet three people in the form of a top list.
We will start with an extremely knowledgeable hobby type to learn more.
Then we will meet the leader for a secret prepper organization in Småland.
And then we will end at Sweden's perhaps most prepared prepper-
-which completely left the community and now live full-time in its evacuation housing-
-To secret place in deepest north country.
But this trip starts in Nynäshamn at our first prepper at level 1.
- Because out here lives a guy who many of you may recognize, namely Kalle Zackari-Whalström.
No but!
He is!
Hehehe, what an aggressive entrance!
There we could have ironed out.
- No, but I was in control.
- Did you have control?
Are you sure you were in control?
- I am fixing firewood.
You can bring wood home with you if you want.
This is more worth more than gold nowadays.
- Scream ... oh.
- My trip into the prepping, it was that I lived into town and longed for the country.
- Yes.
-And I started to listen to a podcast with an old man in Texas who is preparing.
Now he has become a little sick in his head I think, so I stopped listening to him.
So he has been radicalized, I think.
- But that is a trip you are also out on.
- Yes maybe.
- You get a little psychic from living like this, it is.
So this is my type of readiness.
It was just having an ordinary life in the countryside 50 years ago.
It is not me who has become strange, it is society that has become strange.
- Can you go with?
- Yes, come, come!
- Surely it is wonderful?
- Like hell!
Here you have celebrity Sweden's biggest prepper, Kalle Zackari Wahlström, who will help us understand the phenomenon a little better.
- What is a prepper?
- One prepper is that you are interested in preparing for different eventualities.
- What are they afraid of?
- You can imagine a more dangerous pandemic.
And then war feels like a scary thing going on in the world.
- Yes.
How dedicated prepper are you?
- So we have protective masks for everyone in the family in case it would be nuclear war
An operating kit from the Swedish defense that we have bought.
If we had to operate someone.
I have so that we can do well here.
MSB has gone out and said like this, everyone must have food for a week at home, one or two.
And so it is type 28 percent who have it or something.
What the hell is that?
Do you have food and water for a week at home?
- No.
- You should help others, you should not be a load.
- Yes.
- Then the state should focus on taking care of weak, sick, old children.
Make sure they get food and water.
Instead, oh no, Mauri, the TV celebrity.
We have to give him, fast.
He must have Ramlösa!
He does not drink plain water.
It's like you have failed all these who are looking now.
- Have I?
By not being prepared?
- Shit in it.
Should we go and look at the hens?
- Okay
- Ah came
- So there are quite a few pancakes that you can fry by these
- You just go.
You have such a natural pondus.
Now talk to them.
You are like your own being.
As one cannot control and control.
What do you have in here?
- Here I have meat.
- Oh damn what a lot of meat you have.
I think this thing with prepping is like this ...
It gets so big.
It can also just be like this.
That I have some flour.
There are just a few extra weekly documents.
So do you have it at home late
- You could survive in a war out here for five years.
- Yes.
Yes, I would.
- I am impressed.
- How cute you are, please.
- I think you're cruel.
- You have no small children.
You live alone.
You have a pretty bold salary.
You have the way to control your preparedness.
So you haven't done it in just ... it's laziness.
I think it's so damn tragic just.
I think it's tragic.
Hahahaha
- What is the fucking tone?
- Here I have made snus.
That is why it looks like this.
- Wait so ... in a possible crisis you wouldn't even have to buy snuff.
- We move on, come!
This is tobacco.
So this will be snus then.
We move on, come.
- Yes, yes, yes, yes, yes.
Yes Yes.
Where are we going now?
- We may say goodbye to the kisses.
- In what way is this good for a prepper?
- So it's half a ton of meat that goes around here.
Come.
- It's such a speed on you.
- How do I go?
Shows here how I go.
- So you go.
So it's yours ... it's your walking style.
- Yes.
Here you can see my secret prepping weapon.
- huh?
- 2.5 tonnes of wheat.
That's what I can do for quite some time.
- How 2.5 tons of wheat?
- Yes.
I think so
It is like bread or porridge or overnight oats maybe.
- It doesn't feel like a crisis.
- No no.
- But that's ...
- No, but we must say porridge is a crisis.
- Porridge is crisis.
- Now let's go to the cellar.
- The cellar?
- Yes.
- This is a lot of water cans.
- Water is what goes on the ass first for people in crisis.
Come.
- Oh.
- This is what they look like.
- So if there are nuclear weapons or something, then can these help you?
- 15 years ago Sweden had protective masks for all citizens.
Then there was someone who said "ah it calmly", and then they just fired up the masks, so now there are no longer.
- Was it so smart?
From the 1940s onwards, Sweden built a world-class civilian defense.
There was plenty of food, protective equipment and medicines in the event of crisis.
There were even 7.3 million protective masks, one for each citizen.
But during the 1990s everything was dismantled.
Warehouses and shelters were bombed again and millions of protective masks were burned up.
But in recent years, Sweden has begun to rebuild its civil defense.
- You look pretty cool.
- Yes actually.
- A little sexy.
Is it?
- Yes, quite.
That I lie inside the bedroom and you will enter just the gas mask.
It's still tickling
- Oh damn!
What would it look like?
- Do you want coffee or?
- Yes please.
It also feels.
2023 It is a war in Europe.
We have just come out of a pandemic.
There is talk of electricity shortages.
You know, you are a little stupid in your head if you do not take responsibility for your crisis preparedness.
- But are you a little crazy bunch?
- There are absolutely crazy preppers.
- Do you have weapons?
- Yes I have.
- And then you are not shy to use in a crisis if someone comes here?
- Well, I would be, I would be very shy to shoot someone, I think.
I would think about once and twice before I actually killed someone with my rifle.
- But then you shoot.
- So, three quick thoughts.
Then it slams.
- Where do you think we will end up on this trip as we get deeper into the core of the prepping?
- You will surely think people exaggerate.
Instead, try to have an open sin and think like this, they do what takes responsibility for themselves and their family.
If something happens, then the preppers will be kings.
So tighten you, now it gets off.
- Yes.
Yes, now we raise it another snap.
Because before you get to meet Sweden's most prepared prepper, we will go to the border between Småland and Blekinge.
Here has been a man who has been the leader for a fairly light shaded prepper organization for several years.
And his greatest passion in life is crisis preparedness.
- And here ...
... then this man lives.
And I guess I simply have to tap.
- Hello?
- Hello!
- Mauri
- Reidar
- I immediately note TV and video surveillance.
- Yes, it started with it being for the prepping.
Plus I have had some worries with Practical Jokes.
- Okay.
- Among other things, a friend here who came here and put where you have your car.
A stone of 2 tons.
- But what kind of friend?
- I wonder that too.
- Would you be able to walk around and have a look at all the prepping details?
- I have stuffed a bit like this.
It is not really legal to hold.
So to speak.
- So we can't see it then?
No, but there is something else.
Here I have picked up some stuff from a prepping place we have.
- A bear trap?
- We'll see if we can rig one here.
- Yes, just gently.
- Good to have.
- I think the state has more secrets than we would like to know.
As in the US, you have area 51, which is a prepper we have talked to a lot in the US.
He is determined, for example, that Bigfoot exists and that the state knows it.
But there are secrets within the state.
Absolutely.
Then I have a harpoon too
There are also a couple of old people bought in a market that I was going to renovate.
- Here you have a harpoon.
But God, it is too damn charged Reidar
Oh, can you have this kind of thing?
- No clue
May be good to have.
- May be good to have in a crisis.
- I talk about pigs.
Tell it to him in there.
- Is he a pig?
- No, I have a pig in there.
- huh?
Inside the house?
- Yes
- No!
It's a pig!
What are you doing here?
What is it called?
Ludvig.
Hi Ludvig
- I won he at a competition on Facebook.
- He doesn't bite, right?
- ehhhhh ... both yes and no.
- Both yes and no?
- But you are a man with many surprises Reidar.
It feels like you have at least one more messy thing.
- Yes, it would be the home building over there.
- This is your Bug Out Vehicle.
So what you use if you have to escape in a crisis situation.
- Exactly.
Each group will have one to two vehicles each.
We will have about food for 9-12 months with us.
This one in our community will be a communication car.
So it will have a comradio.
It should have a much larger battery system in itself.
I got it for 3,000.
- There is your wife.
- Hello!
- What is it like to be the wife of such a dedicated prepper?
- You have quite a great patience with a prepper.
I try to keep him in control anyway.
- You try?
-I try to.
- How much are you talking about this with your wife?
- It is as soon as possible.
I think she is getting tired of me now.
- The first time you Reidar met, how fast did it take before he started talking about prepping?
- We sat non stop and talked for two to three hours.
-If?
- If prepping.
- Oh!
Have you told me everything you have for me?
- Some things are safest not to know.
But where are they unknown, hidden things?
They are scattered each and all around the country.
Huh?
You have as a group of prepper for which you are partly the leader.
How many are you?
For several years now, this group of families have jointly planned escape routes, scouted hiding places and bought equipment.
They even have a secret mountain bunker in Northern Norway.
Right now, this group will have a meeting.
We should keep up.
- There are some who have grunted a little for me to sit and film.
They are a bit skeptical of the media you can say.
- Yes, you can really say that.
- But is it just to wait for them?
- Yes.
Then we take coffee for so long.
- Can you tell the camera how much coffee you drink every day?
- Three to four such a day.
- It's too much, Reidar.
- No, I'm just feeling it.
Then the guests began to roll in from different parts of Småland.
An incredibly diverse crowd of people who all snow in on Prepping.
- Yes, welcome then.
We have received some complications.
Route 2 is gone.
I have found a suitable place there.
- Yes, up there yes.
- What will you do in this place?
- There we gather all vehicles, all our preppersaker and camp.
These crosses.
These are places that we know there are military barracks.
- Is this all military bases?
- As we have found so far.
- What's that?
- This is a regular inventory list now when we order.
These think we are a restaurant.
There I sat and was impressed by their dedication.
These people on the outskirts of society who perhaps most of all just want a project.
While the meeting ended, I took a walk with Ludvig.
- There is something with Reidar because his passion ..
He must be the most passionate we have when it comes to preppers.
- But how do you eat an ordinary day?
- Yes, an ordinary day consists of different types of food that are available.
Now we have consumed everything.
This is what we have left of the prepper supply itself.
- Why have you consumed it?
- Due to food prices and electricity prices right now.
- So you have had to eat your prepper food store like?
- Yes, right now in this crisis situation we have had here now I have done it.
But we have not traded food in seven months.
- It has to pain somewhere for a prepper to have to eat up its storage room.
- Yes that...
Yes, it stings.
It does.
- The dream right now is to rebuild the store.
- Oh yes, that's it.
Because it is as they say, if you are at the bottom, there is only one way.
And that's up.
- But I think we can cook a lunch then, as you usually cook it?
- White prayers and old honest goulash soup.
- Now Reidar has not talked about prepping in three seconds.
- It's a record!
- New record.
- Is it a new record?
- Almost.
- An applause to Reidar.
Three seconds.
- Then I get more time to think.
- On what?
- Prepping.
It's not so bad food to live on.
- I thought this was delicious.
- Everything you can eat, only they are the right spices or some good accessories.
- Yes, is the situation as it is so.
Because Nina and Reidar's situration look like it does-
- I felt there was one last thing I wanted to do.
- Due to the economy and your prepper store-
So I thought I would invite you to a surprise.
- Okay.
Oh Lord, Jösses!
- Oh, but God.
No, but so God.
- Come here with you.
It feels like now we are able to ride out the storm a little longer.
The first time someone does this for my sake.
- Is that so?
- I don't know what to say.
- I also thought of Ludvig.
I would like to give a really cheerful pizza to Ludvig.
This is just for you, Ludvig.
Short break for pictures of Ludvig when he was little.
When we are still on the move, we say hello to wonderful Reidar and Nina.
- But before we visit our last guest, you wonder ...
We who have not prepared ourselves at all.
What can we do to be sure if the crisis comes?
Therefore, I have invited the survival expert ...
... Martin Svennberg!
- Can we release now?
- Yes absolutely.
What are you looking for?
- In a shorter but intense crisis, it is most important to have water and heat.
You have a little plaid.
- But this is.
Plus points?
- Yes, not many, but a bit anyway.
- Here I have sunscreen.
I have a lot of that.
There I am well -spread.
- Yes but that's good
- Are you a little proud of me?
- That you are the only one who has sun protection 50 in March.
It's pretty cool indeed.
- Now it gets a little exciting.
No, but February 20 this went out.
It contains no one nourish your fridge.
So this is not really good.
Ten ice cubes.
- How long should I survive in a crisis?
- Three days.
But then you haven't eaten anything.
So then you will be a sad person too.
- I'll die and I'll die sad after three days.
Then you wonder what the most important things to have at home?
- This is number three.
This is a crank radio.
- With just this one can always get updates on the situation in the country.
- Number two.
- Gaspis.
- To boil water is the easiest way to clean water.
- But this one can also have to heat food.
For example, if you want to heat your tuna.
- What is the scornful tone?
- Number one.
Just dealing with water exclusively.
For three days without water, do we manage?
- Not on...?
- Not on.
Hello.
Return up to the trip to Norrland and our last visit.
His name is Andreas and is Sweden's biggest name in prepping.
- When it comes to the modern Swedish balanced prepping, you could call him the Urap.
For several years he blogged under the name Urvaken and even appeared in the media.
But a year and a half ago, he suddenly put the blog down and disappeared completely from social media.
- Andreas went from being the wound to just disappearing all of a sudden.
- He may have gone completely off-grid.
What happened was that Andreas moved out permanently to his evacuation home.
Since then not a squat.
And no thanks to all kinds of media.
- I tried to do TV shows about prepping.
I tried to contact mass preppers, including then the ancestry
Could not get hold of him.
So you have managed to fix it, it is damn powerful then.
Hour after hour by car towards deepest Norrland with a promise not to state his coordinates in the program.
- Type here, like all civilization, ends.
Deep in that forest he lives completely alone.
It is completely impossible to get here by car.
You have to walk the last kilometers as well.
Is this where he lives?
This is where he lives.
Listen how quiet it is.
Absolutely silent.
- Hello!
Hey!
- Mauri!
- Andreas!
It feels like you have made prepping a lifestyle in a way that not everyone has done.
- Yes, that's how I have chosen to live my life.
- Should we have a little look at how you live here?
- Can we do.
- What is this?
It's a simple greenhouse to extend the season so I grow in these.
- Solar cells are located there to be installed.
- And what is it in the freezer there?
- If you open, you will see.
- What is this?
- It's rice, macaroni, salt and sugar.
It's all possible there.
- No!
- I'm pretty introverted really.
That is what people have very difficult.
My mother is very difficult to compare that I live here myself.
How can you live like that?
Aren't you alone?
Although I don't think so.
- How many years would you survive on all the food you have out here?
- If I'm myself, I would say four years.
- You have four years of food here.
- But I won't be myself, so ...
- Are I invited?
-No.
- I'm not invited?
- Thanks anyway.
Why can't I come along and come here?
What is a bad style?
- I saw that a scooter is here.
Can I go scooter?
- You don't know that even you have tried.
- No.
Wohohooo!
- And it's in here that you live?
- Here I live, for real.
If you need to escape, so to speak, then you live wrong.
- Do you think some crap will happen?
- We have just undergone a pandemic.
- Yes.
- And now we have a war in Europe again.
- mm.
-But you are absolutely sure that some crap will happen within 10-20-30 years?
- Absolutely.
- What is the most likely disaster?
According to you?
- A solar storm.
- huh?
Hello?
- A solar storm is really when you get an outbreak on the sun.
And these bikes return by about 120 years.
- When did we have a solar storm last?
- Yes, about 120 years ago we had something called the Carrington event.
At that time there was not so much electronics in the world.
There were telegraphs.
And those telegraphs started to burn, for example because there was so much electrical charge in them.
- So there will probably be a solar storm soon that beats out half the world's technology?
- Yes.
Yes, and it's like ...
- It was boring news to me.
But you see all the small prepper details everywhere.
- Yes, there is food everywhere.
- And what's in here?
- Here is the toilet.
And since there is no drain and no water, it will be toilet afterwards.
- It doesn't smell midsummer in here.
- Don't it?
- No.
- I sacrifice a lot of things by choosing to live like this.
I could almost say that I could be prepared to kill for a hot shower sometimes.
- And there is just one machete type.
Should I be scared?
- No.
If you are not going to be invited like that.
- But I'm invited here.
- We have discussed this so many times you and I now.
It is like a private party where the word private is very with big letters so.
- Yes, private.
Not everyone can come.
- I may have to be clearer with my no.
- Yes, may I come?
- No.
- Yes, it's ... because now you flash, I think.
- This one is a little fun.
It is to measure radioactivity.
- Yes.
- That's if there were atomic bombs, kind of.
- Yep.
- What is it up to?
- It's 0.10 millisievert.
- 0.10 Millisievert?
Who the hell is Siewert?
Wondering then?
- Yes, he is, Siewert Öholm.
- What can you really joke about?
- But Siewert Öholm is dead.
Are we looking for Siewert Öholm's spirit then?
- If you hear someone who starts whispering video violence and such things, then ...
- It's 0.10 of him here.
* whispers* violent society.
* whispers* 19-year-old Satanist
Siewert ...?
- It's too little Siewert for him to answer.
- It's too little.
- Yep.
- Very hot minutes.
- It's hard not to note that you have walkie talkies there.
It also feels a bit like madness.
To have two such, ready.
Like it could play tomorrow.
Do you understand what I mean?
- It's because it can actually hit tomorrow.
- Yes.
- What do you have in this cabinet?
- I have hunting weapons and then I have silver.
These are not affected by inflation.
- How much are all these silver coins worth you think?
- So a silver coin I would say is worth about SEK 300.
So you keep it in a thousand or so there.
- But wait then your silver coins are worth SEK 100,000, which is here.
Oh God.
You can't avoid having weapons here too.
- Yep.
- Look at yourself.
You are ready.
- I've been working on this for 15 years.
It's just accelerating.
- Yes.
Against here.
- Yes ..
No!
- It is a secret world in many ways prepping.
Have you told us everything, everything you have?
- No.
- huh?
But you have kind of hiding places.
- Then I choose not to answer.
- God, it's like a politician there, it's a little exciting.
Do you have a little bunker?
- Did you see any bunker when you have walked around here?
- So, you are crazy in a good way.
But what else do you have?
Can you have?
- And here you have even more food.
How many kilos of food have you prepped totally?
- I think I have an Excel file.
- Can we develop an Excel file and look?
823 kilos of food you have.
Damn!
And with that, maybe I thank you.
- I thought you would say back to the studio.
It would have been a little fun.
- Why?
- It would have been so fun.
It would have been so clumsy in some way.
- Thanks for today.
- Thanks.
- and back to the studio.
- huh?
- Yes, we are live.
- What live?
What do you mean?
- Musty Mauri?
He has handed over to the studio.
- What?
Has he handed over to our studio?
How is it even possible?
- Has Mauri handed over here?
No, but then you have to go back to Youtube.
- What the hell!
- But what are you doing here?
What the hell?
Go away!
This is not mission food!
- Jonas calm you down.
- I'm getting annoyed as hell!
Drag!
Go away!
- Yes Yes.
This was probably a little wrong.
- The world's strongest pizza.
- Mauri, wrong channel.
This is food coma away.
- Yes, then we were back on
Youtube channel.
A new day has Grytt in Norrland
- And I felt yesterday there was like a question that hung a little in the air.
Now I'll go and ask that question one last time.
- But we have discussed that, no!
- A hug?
- You can get that.