- So now we roll the most powerful intro we have ever had on this channel!
We will do this as a top list.
And we start with number 7.
In this, this section is that, incidentally, in paid cooperation with Revolut.
And now it will be about one of the world's most iconic voices.
You've all heard it.
We will meet the official Swedish Kalle Duck voice.
There are probably few votes that are as iconic as this one.
And since 1987 it has been made by the same man, Andreas Nilsson.
Now for the first time we will see the face behind Swedish Kalle Duck.
Hello!
Hey!
- Hey how are you?
Hahaha
Yeah so can it sound
- It's so damn magical!
You are so incredibly talented.
- Did you hear what did he say?
Talented, he said.
- Talented!
Did you hear that Bandhagen?
He is talented ...
No one hears us
- no no one hears us
- He is the official Swedish Kalle Anka.
- Hey!
How is it?
How fun!
- That is sick.
- Wow!
Books
- Oh, you're read, Kalle.
- Yes so there.
- No, like that.
After all, this is a thousand books.
- Is it...?
- huh?
- What are you saying?
- I think so.
Can I see a little, Kalle Duck?
- ne.
- It's copyright, for damn.
What did I say?
I swearing!
Hello?
!
Out here!
- Yes no, yes no!
Kalle?
- What is it?
Do you want coffee?
- Gladly!
- Wonderful!
Gnesta Mölnbo!
- huh?
But how rich do you get to be Kalle?
- Huge!
- It's absurd?
- poor can be become
- You have made a lot of different Swedish voices in all children's programs.
- The first five, six years we were seven who made all votes in all series.
- Yes, I'm thinking short break for super marathon-
- No!
-with you.
- Is it time?
- Drive through all the most classic votes.
You notice that you are an acting soul.
One, two, three, drive!
My name is Professor Heinz Doofenshmirtz!
Unite everything in a movement for us to reach heaven.
I'm going to pick up the car Master Wayne?
Ohana means family
Ahhhhhh
Yeah how is it he sounds now, pinocchio in shrek
No, no don't put it in the nose.
Nicke ...
Think of something nice, a girl to fight for
*Kalle Duck Sound*
- You never use the voice when you go out on the town or so?
- I work in the hidden.
- It's not very damn right now.
They film us.
- No.
- Yes.
- But you said that this was just between you and me?
- How does this salt bowl sound?
- Salt!
No, if you were to go and take a sprinkler then after work.
I think I'm pretty handsome.
*Kalle Duck Sound*
No no.
- Yes, but now we have been busy a little too.
- Now we have been busy.
We have got so much on the schedule today.
- Yes Yes.
- Maybe it's time to wave goodbye in slow motion.
It feels like you could wave without we setting slow motion on the camera.
You start practicing.
- A little strange to wave this slowly.
- We can do it in real slowmo if you want.
Thanks for today.
And now it's time to present the next guest.
And we do that with the help of you, Jeppe.
- Time for place number six, Mauri and a new guest in a chacha.
- Maybe more a conversation?
It's not Lets Dance this
- At the number six, Mauri, in a video call where you get to meet the voice-
-As has made the most commercials in Swedish history.
Receive Mikael Roupé.
- There you have him, the velvet, best -selling and passionate.
Mikael Ropé-
- Hey!
- How many TV advertising have you voting?
- I stopped counting somewhere around 7000-
-7000?
- Yes, 7000
- the largest sell-out in Swedish history-
-and I love it!
- I'm actually a little proud of that.
- But then we can get a taste of this unique voice you have that everyone has heard.
- These are absolutely fantastic prices!
This is not wise!
1990!
Take care of what you think —-
-Our new suits are completely electric.
Here we have the new one with Maybelines, you know.
Awesome ...
It went so far that they even started a Facebook group called Dead Jyskman.
It's true.
- I will be so curious if I had sent an advertising text to you.
And then we just see how it comes to life with your voice.
Have you received any email here now with my ...?
- There it came!
This section in paid cooperation with Revolut.
- Yes, so this is really a paid collaboration with Revolut.
Revolut is a financial superapp that is easy to use in everything from everyday expenses to savings.
Download Revolut and register your account in minutes and get SEK 250 when you become a member.
- And I can proudly announce that I have just downloaded Revolut and after transferring the money, just start using.
And you don't have to wait for this beautiful card to come home to you.
Without you can use your digital card on your mobile at once.
- Totally amazing!
You can also save by shopping in the app.
With up to 30 percent discount on major brands such as Adidas and Nike.
- Well said, Mauri.
- Thanks so much, Micke.
- No, you should have thanks.
- Oh now give you Micke.
Drive on, drive on.
- But I've listened to this.
When you are out of surrounding you can spend money.
- Now I think things are going a little too fast, Micke.
Just a little, a little slower.
- When you're abroad you can spend money with your revolving card-
-Os bad fees and with the actual exchange rate.
So when I go out and travel I can use Revolut to withdraw money for free from ATMs.
- So what are you waiting for?
Click the link in the description to download Revolut already today-
-And take part in your 250 SEK.
Thank you revolver for making assignments food possible.
Revols the financial supera app!
- There you demonstrate your skill!
What fun it has been to talk to you!
- Yes but the same you hear!
Hello then, see you on any radio channel or TV channel.
- We'll do that.
Hello!
- Welcome back!
Soon you will meet the man with this lean voice.
You will also get a Face Reveal at Alejandro Fuentes Bergström.
And meet the man who says comes to the cinema this fall.
But first, it's time for place number five.
- Now I'm sitting here with coffee, with a pier in my stomach.
Soon I will be joined by the voice that we have all heard most times in life.
Without registering it.
This voice has heard in local traffic, in telephone exchanges, on radio.
In addition, she has been crowned to be the very miss.
This iconic service that since 1934 has helped people set the clock right.
- You were a little impressive about who to meet.
- Yeah!
- It's still an iconic voice.
- It's the same phone number.
- You know the number?
- Yes, I will never forget that.
- Now you call the Miss now.
13.8.8.
- That's right.
- She knows the time.
- God, you are completely embarrassed.
Hope she keeps time.
We actually said ... yes she is two minutes late.
- No, there she comes.
- There she comes!
Here she comes walking.
The trustworthy, but above all fantastic.
Johanna Herman Lundberg.
--Wow!
What a reception!
- I found some fans.
- You may ask where it is.
- Then we call.
No no!
- bowl there on you.
-Bowl.
- Can you have the voice heard in most places in Sweden?
- Yes, I almost think so.
But...
Now it's starting to rain.
- God what it is raining.
- Can you mention in all the places you hear your voice?
- I am the Swedish Tax Agency, the subway, countless gears.
Then I have been a bank.
But I don't know everything.
- Last morning I tried to call a friend, who did not answer.
Who tells me that the person can't take my call right now?
- Is it me?
- Yes you are.
- I don't know.
- It is you!
-"The person you've called is busy in another call."
- Yes, that's me.
"Leave a message after the tone"
I did not know that!
- Can you say that you got the job because you had a slightly more comfortable voice on the cut?
- I had another type of voice.
A little lower, a little more like this ...
I sell that you believe in what I say.
I can read any text, and you believe in that text.
- What can you say that still becomes credible?
If you had said that Leif GW Persson murdered Palme?
- I think you pull it far.
- Now we go far, but we may still be able to get a prosecution on GW.
I know Leif GW Persson murdered Palme.
On February 28, 1986, Leif GW Persson is in the corner,-
-tunnelgatan, Sveavägen, and waiting for Olof Palme and his wife Lisbeth-
-To he wants to try to get to the perfect crime-
-What he also succeeded.
- Gw, the sick bastard!
- He who chats so much about that all the time.
- He got away.
- Yes, he did.
- You make the voice in the local traffic subway.
- Yeah.
I have a speaker with me.
We're going to fuck a little with people.
- Next station.
The castle.
Fun!
- Now we pull towards the subway.
Excuse me, may I ask you one thing?
- I have gone past you.
–Wa?
- He didn't talk, right?
He didn't talk to me.
- God, what fun!
-Info.
- Bus 1 towards Frihamnen departs in a minute.
- Did you hear the voice?
- Bus 1 towards Frihamnen departs in 11 minutes.
- Isn't that sick?
- How fun!
- Okay, now we get into the subway here.
- I want to start at once.
I just want to say things.
Next station Västerås.
Next Östermalmstorg.
Mörby center.
Yes, now I talk a little in my mouth.
But then change to Mörby center.
- You got a little minded?
- Yes!
Next Ropsten end station ...
- I thought it was you, it was she.
- You didn't understand that she was talking.
- I didn't even understand.
- But then, thanks for today.
- Is there anything you have left that you want to do?
Is there any dream?
- I still have one thing.
After all, I still want to be a wicked Disney witch.
- But wait, this guy is pretty good at animating and drawing stuff.
After all, we could have arranged a little mini witch role for you.
We could have made a small short film where you are a wicked witch.
And I'm an innocent prince.
Or what am I?
- Innocent prince?
Yes, you can get that.
Or such a small frog or something.
- Okay, I'm a frog and you're a witch.
- Hello Hello!
I'm a nice little frog like going out.
- Now I have caught you, little ginger frog!
- What are you going to do with me?
- I need your musty frogs to complete my witch brew.
- Ouch ouch ouch!
It is hot!
- Now it's time for place number four.
- Now we will meet a voice that is in some way TV4.
You have heard him say things like the premiere, September 1 on TV4 and Cmore.
There is something about these vocal cords that almost make a little arrow.
There he is.
Hey!
Hello!
Yes, there you have him.
As velvety as wonderful.
Ola Ringdahl.
- Can we taste you a little?
Premiere at Cmore.
- How long have you been in such a voice?
-25 years.
It has been great fun.
-It's fine now.
- Up and down, now it is not as good anymore.
Ten years ago it was much better.
But I have a job, I should not complain.
- But you're a little out in the cold right now.
- No, not in the cold, I couldn't say that.
- You are completely alone, no one is calling.
- I am single and the children have moved.
-Are you single?
-Yes I am single.
- But God Ola ...
- But do you want a friend?
-Yes.
- But should we go on a buddy date?
See if there can be something so you can get someone who comes out here sometimes and meets you.
- Finally!
- Now we go friend.
Buddy dating
- But I have a funny story.
- Oh, should you invite us to a funny story?
- Yes.
- How long will it be and how fun will it be?
- Very funny and you can tell me how long it should be.
Because I Speaker you can say you have 15 seconds or you have a minute on you.
- You have 20 seconds.
Time is starting now.
- Many years ago, 20 years ago, I was assigned that I would make the voice a juice package.
And then a nice girl comes into the apartment, the juice packages have a party.
I have the last juice package.
I can't get away.
So when he opens the refrigerator door, then I stand there and then I should say oh or oops.
So I stand for an hour.
- Oh, there was time out.
Hahahaha!
I'm sorry Ola.
But we must not hear ...
What a fucking anti -climax!
- How the hell do you stand out with him?
So you have a lot in salary or?
We can go to my recording studio if you want and talk.
Voice.
- Lol!
What a nasty offer!
Want to get into my car and eat sweets?
Hahahaha!
But I think this buddy dating is going very well.
- I think so too.
- Soon you are not alone anymore.
Imagine everyone who will listen to TV4 in the future.
And when they hear your voice now just ...
That's him.
Wonder how he is feeling.
- Do you know what the deppost is?
- No.
What?
- I've just got rid of a CMore job.
-  No!
- They put together TV4 Play with CMore and then I am not needed as a voice.
It happened a month ago.
- What, so you have coded that job too, your main job?
- Not too.
- It's been an honor to meet you.
- Thank you, the same to you.
This is the most fun thing I've done in several days I would say.
- days?
Nice to hear.
Have a good one.
Now we are in a summery Södermalm together with a very cute cat.
We are here to meet Sweden's most famous computer voice through all times.
She is the voice in GPS, for a long time Siri on the iPhone and is heard almost every time you ask a computer to read something for you.
Hello!
Here you have her, the fantastic, inimitable, multi -talented and above all incredibly good looking Sara Edvardsson.
- Your voice now, say hello.
- Hello!
- It doesn't really sound like the other voice.
- Can you get a taste in what contexts you have heard your voice?
- Welcome to Fredbank.
Call Mom.
Unfortunately, I cannot answer that question.
Turn right.
Stop hamra.
... west out on Kärhågsgatan towards Nytorgsgatan.
- This is not ...
- It's not me.
It is another nice woman that we do not know who it.
- Not very nice.
Bother me a little.
- Right?
Of 400 meters.
Then we will drive left.
Turn right.
-Yey!
That's me!
- Ey!
- Should you and I have a quick lunch?
-I am very hungry.
- Me too!
On the way to the restaurant, we noticed that the taxi driver used a GPS with Sara's voice.
... to the ride towards the center.
- Do you usually have the GPS player's voice?
- No no votes I don't like that about 200 meters turn left no.
It's a bit goofy I think.
- Yes, it's really, really goofy.
- mhmm
- You know that her voice, as you said was hard.
That's her voice.
- No are you kidding?
She is the voice.
- Ne hahaha.
No, but come on.
Do you drive with me or?
- No I don't drive.
So I didn't take anything.
It is not the very voice, it is the directive when you hear.
- Now he is changing history.
- Now I would just like to do a last little experiment with you.
Okay, then it's time to test if we can fool the Stockholmers.
I'll let people test this computer with the world's best AI.
And with a computer voice that everyone recognizes.
Hello Hello!
That's me.
But in fact, everything is controlled by Sara who sits in this car.
She sees everything, she hears everything and will create the coolest AI experience-
-As the world has seen so far.
Here we go.
- Do you want to test the world's smartest AI so far with me?
You can talk to it, communicate with it.
- For real?
- Yes, yes, yes.
- How are you?
- I feel as I deserve.
- huh?
- Yes, it was a bit AW yesterday you can say.
- So I'm scared by this shit.
I don't like this.
- Test, continue.
- What's your name?
- What do you want me to be called?
- Magdalena.
I do not know.
- I want to be your Magdalena.
- Oh no, no that is enough.
- It feels scary.
- I hate this kind of crap.
- It is almost nasty how far they have come with the technology.
- No, for real?
No, but damn!
So, you got to get shivers.
- In a hundred meters turn right.
- Fy damn, that sounds ...
- God, you are frightened for life.
- It's cool.
- What the hell.
No, that is scary.
- Damn.
Okay, wow!
- What will the next government look like?
- It depends on how you and your friends vote.
Probably you will vote a little to the right.
- Yes, it can be true.
- Do you have any dating tips?
- Just make them listen.
- It feels like you are disappointed.
- But what the hell?
- She was the one who was sitting in the car.
- It's sick.
- So it's just scam?
- Yes, it's scam.
We are engaged in scams.
Maybe we should stop making people disappointed and thank you for today instead.
Maybe we should do it anyway.
- And now it's time for a historic Face Reveal on Sweden's perhaps most beloved stuffed animal.
Now it will be about the Chilean monkey Alejandro Fuentes Bergström.
He appeared on television for the first time in 2006 and has since reached a cult status in Sweden.
He has been on television, radio, advertisements, music videos, but we have only seen the monkey.
Today, the man behind the voice for the first time will show his face in Swedish television.
- But before that we have to get acquainted with Alejandro himself, of course.
So, we are so boundlessly peppered.
There he comes.
- Hejsan Svejsan, my name is Alejandro Fuentes-Bergström.
You are very welcome to my house.
I hope it will be good to taste.
-Otherwise?
-Yes it is good.
Yourself?
- It mopes and goes.
This is the first time I talk to a redhead guy actually
We had a scared man in the village where I grew up.
But I didn't talk to him.
I'd rather not talk about inbreeding problems.
But he could be a little violent.
- You are known for your structure.
Are you just as good at it now?
- Of course.
Thinking structure is not a fashion fly.
I think it is a matter of course to have a structure that is hardworked.
- Then Alejandro wanted to invite me to some tacos.
I note that you have patches on each bowl.
- It's better control.
If you use two different senses, then you are faster, reptile fast.
- You are so Beautiful.
I like you very much.
- Do you belong to the other kind, that you have gay?
Then I think we can continue this dinner and have a good time.
- Yes, we do so.
- Fresh cream, avocado, meat three, salad, a mock cup, small bowl and tomato square.
- Let yourself taste.
- What did you say?
- Let yourself taste?
- As I said.
- I thought about what we talked about before with gay and stuff?
- I think you have a problem that addresses that topic all the time.
You stare and try to provoke a gay from me.
- It is so difficult to determine where you are on this issue.
You are for everyone to love who they want?
- At the right time, in the right place, at the right time.
- What do you even mean at the right time?
- What time .. You have to plan a socializing.
It can't be random people you meet.
And they come to you and you have social holes about noise.
Chin Chin, Mauri.
I think you're really nice guy.
- Thanks, Alejandro.
The same, bowl.
And now my ladies and gentlemen.
Is it time for the historical moment-
-When we should meet the man behind Alejandro.
- What?
What?
What did you say?
- We'll meet the man behind you.
- Welcome.
- Smoke machine.
Oh, it's bad with smoke.
There will be no smoke.
It came anyway.
1, 2, 3!
You can really get around?
- Yes.
- and put you?
- I sit down.
- How did you even find this character?
How did it arise?
- It was me and Martin Marklund, screenwriter, Sweden's best.
We were on a movie recording and then we found Alejandro.
We just saw his eyes on him.
And then we started testing different dialects.
And then we started tanning as hell when we came to the Spanish Swedish.
Because it was not so used in any way right then.
- mm.
- Fifteen years ago.
- But do you have any parent from South America?
- No.
My parents are from Poland.
- huh?
- Yes.
We can speak Polish if you want.
Slightly.
With a Polish break.
- Thanks.
- Thank you, Mauri.
You are very sympathetic.
Actually.
I hope we get to meet again sometime.
- I hope so too.
- My ladies and gentlemen, it's time for place number one.
Mauri goes out far to sea on a deserted island
-To meet a man who has never shown his face to the Swedish people.
- Out here in a wonderfully summery Stockholm archipelago-
-Bore Sweden's trailer voice number one.
You've all heard hono say-
-Coming to the cinema this fall.
Or...
And the nominees are ...
And now we will meet the man behind that voice.
Inside.
HE HE HE HE HE HE HE HE!
- Yes, there he is.
The man with Sweden's perhaps sexiest voice.
The One and Only, Benke Skogholt.
- Can we just hear you say those things you usually say?
- The nominees are, out in the fall, a man, a mission.
- It also feels like a real women's magnet to have that voice.
- Yes, yes, yes.
Well, yes, yes.
- Now Benke got a little shy.
-How has been your job for a long time?
- Oh since the advertising radio came to Sweden.
- And it's been your full -time job ever since?
- Yes, I am a musician too.
- You can sing too?
- Yes I can.
- You say you Hurt.
Almost Lost Your Mind.
The Man You Love.
Treat you so unkind.
- Have you ever been on TV this way?
- No.
- Here he is.
Oh, such a thing too.
- Yes, Peace.
Or double peace.
- Oh!
- Double Peace.
You love Him, Stick to Him Like Glue.
- Scrap militarism.
War is a disaster.
It hurts me too.
And then an incredible amount of money should be spent on it.
Build roads, schools, hospitals, amusement parks.
Double Peace
- Is this this that we the recipe for a good voice?
- It can be part of it.
That and whiskey.
- And then we end this with what you can call it ..
Can you call it Benka Skogholt diet?
So what has created your voice maybe.
A cig and a whiskey.
- If you end it, the question is at all.
- Once the whiskey is now, it feels stupid to stop.
- Yes, of course, now we drive.
Now the plug is out.
Cheers, Mauri.
- Into the fog.
- Now we sweep.
- That tasted good.
- You and I Benke.
- Yes, it's you and me, Mauri.
Crikey.
- Yes, it tear well that.
- Cheers!
I actually have one thing I've dreamed about.
We on assignment food have never won a prize.
- Oh really?
- And you tend to be the one who always says who ...
- Yes, I usually talk about who has received it and who is nominated and so on.
We look for here.
And the winner of Benke Skogolt's whiskey prize is ...
- Wait wait!
Could you say this?
Not in just want to be cool first.
- Is, not in Want to Be Cool.
Not Joakim Lundell.
- Not Therese Lindgren.
- Not Therese Lindgren, but ...
- And damn not RMM either.
- Benke Skogholt's whiskey prize.
- 2023.
- 1920-23.
I was saying hehe.
And the winner is ...
Assignment food.
You are welcome.
Then you get the note here.
- So damn poor gala with such a damn expensive voice.
- It entitles to another whiskey.
- Is it a whiskey until now?
- Yes, yes, yes.
- Cheers!
And so I had finally met them all.
The cushioning, busy Kalle Duck.
Legend Mikael Roupé, Johanna Hermann Lundberg as warm in the soul as in his voice.
The permeable Ola Ringdahl, everyone's our computer voice Sara Edvardsson.
Alejandro and his equally wonderful father, and finally Benke Skogholt-
-When you would have liked to spend time with for the rest of your life.
Thanks to Revolut!
- It has been an honor to meet you Alejandro.
I'm a big fan.
- Thank you who says it.
Are you gay?