Today we will meet Sweden's ten best lookalikes.
Greta Thunberg's secret double -hit in Helsingborg.
Leif and Billy's copies that also take over the stage and deceive the audience.
And then I finally get to meet my own mirror image.
But we start with number ten that we find in Bagarmossen outside Stockholm.
Because here it is said that there is a shoemaker who should be ridiculously similar to Robert De Niro.
And he will try to find now.
Just that, I forgot to say, this section is in paid collaboration with Revolut.
- May I ask you something?
- We are looking for Bagarmossens Robert De Niro.
A shoemaker.
- Yes, it's the farthest away.
- Yes.
- Have a lovely day!
Hello Hello!
- He is very wonderful.
He is actually like Robert De Niro.
- Is he?
- Fixes everything.
- A top guy?
- Yes.
Listen what a nice thing it was now when you cut yourself.
Was on time.
Sorry!
- huh?
Now we are starting to approach shoe and key service.
I think he is.
Oh!
It says on the sign.
Bagarmossen's own De Niro fixes everything.
Hello!
There we have him!
Bagarmossens Robert De Niro.
- Hey!
It's Robert De Niro in Bagarmossen's shoemaking here.
You Talking to Me?
- Gabriel De Niro.
- Yes I am Talking to you.
- Welcome to my country!
- Do you think talk to me?
But it must be with a gun.
You have a gun or?
- We have no gun.
- What should I do without a gun?
It doesn't get tough.
- The sick thing is that you sound like De Niro as well.
Can you speak English once?
- Just a little, what you want.
Ask me.
- It's still Lebanese Robert De Niro.
You hear that anyway.
- So, now it's done.
- Is it clear already?
- So.
- It took like 27 seconds.
- 27 seconds.
- You are a genius.
- Thanks so much.
- I appreciate the one you told me Geni.
- It's like I'm with Robert De Niro.
- That's true, yes.
You are filming me.
- Yes he does.
- Yes that is good.
- The funny thing is that you are extremely similar to De Niro.
But my photographer is also very good at being like Deniro.
- If we just sound ... Gabbe, if you hold this for a while.
- Are you talk to me?
- Aha, yeah, yeah.
- Talking to me?
- No, you're talking to me.
- No, you're talking to day.
- I don't know, this here, only this here.
- Thank you so much for meeting you.
- Thank you and also fun to see you.
It's a little, you're just a little long.
It gets hurt in my neck when I look at you all the time.
It was a little difficult.
It is better that you play basketball.
In doing so, we leave the shoemaker in the bagamoss and take us up a level to Istan's number nine.
- The next guest we will call.
Now it will be about Piteås ...
Erling Haaland.
Hello.
- Will people come forward and tell you that you are like him?
- I play football and every team we meet just says, here we have Haaland Junior.
- It's something when you smile and have the camera a little underneath and look up.
And smile with the teeth open.
So.
And then you look up.
Smile more.
Fuck, now we cod the drawing.
Now we are stuck on a Frame.
We put a point there and move up the list instead.
You will soon be able to meet Anders Bagge's unknown looko-
-And Sweden's Leonardo DiCaprio.
But we start with the number eight of the list.
- Now we have traveled south.
Because here, right up there, still lives something so unexpected and luxurious-
-It feels like Helsingborgs Greta Thunberg.
Hello!
In paid collaboration with Revolut, I will send 10,000 to my photographer.
He has 60 seconds to spend.
Ready?
Drive!
In any case, Revolut is an online bank where it is quick to sign up.
And if you download the app for free today, you get 250 SEK when you use the card for the first time.
Rappido, Ey!
Rappido!
You can easily add money to the app by bank card, Apple Pay or bank transfer.
And when you then spend money in the app, you get cashbacks at brands like Nike and Gymshark.
Andale, Andale, Andale!
One of Revolut's absolute most delicious features is how easy it is to spend money abroad with their incredible exchange rates.
You can switch money in the app, or you automatically change your money to the correct currency when using the card.
It couldn't have been easier.
Ay Caramba!
Carajo!
With Revolut you also get access to a walking card that you use at one time online.
When you pay, it disappears and is replaced with a new one.
In this way, your payment information can never be stolen.
There was time out.
Thank you for competing.
Get Revolut Free with my link and get 250 SEK when you use the card for the first time.
- Where is that link?
- It is in the description.
The link is in the description.
Thanks, revolut.
- Hello!
- Here we have Emmys who in 2019 went viral with this clip.
Which got half the world to believe that Greta Thunberg was lying on a shooting range.
- How many saw that video?
- Any number.
I don't know how many millions of views it has.
It was first spread in Brazil, then it got well attached to the rest of the world in the area against people woke up that day.
- So it was like millions in one day?
- Yes.
- But how similar are you Greta as a person?
- So I like to play computer games, ride a motorcycle.
- What do you play for computer games?
- Oh, don't judge me.
- So?
- No, I play Russian fishing simulator games.
- Now it's on g. Oh damn, he was heavy you.
- Be he?
- Yes.
- I have five meters left.
Oh oh oh!
A cod!
YES!
- We got a cod.
- I would probably say that our interests probably differ.
I don't know what she does about the days, but I like firearms.
- Pang, pang?
- Yes Pang Pang.
The best there is.
- Jesus!
Fuck!
- Oh, shit!
–Up, up, up!
- Oh oh oh!
- God, now comes security personnel.
I can't be there anymore.
Oh!
Sorry.
- This you shot just recently.
Now we're going to shoot this one.
It will slap much higher.
–And it makes you happy?
-Yes.
- How rough is this weapon?
--Otrously rough.
- Do you even decorate?
- Yes, I'm starting to get adrenaline.
- What the hell am I going to do then?
I'm going home.
- Yes, it will go well.
- Fucking Hell!
- What the fuck?
Are you kidding me?
- Oh my God!
- You have to test this.
- No no no no.
Now we thank you.
My God, what a bang.
- Are you a climate person who is very much based on the climate?
- No, I see it more like I was a vegetarian and vegan for seven years.
- What do you want?
- I would like a kebab in bread.
Extra meat.
- She has met Angela Merkel, Trump.
You feel like you're not impressed at all.
- Well actually.
I am very happy.
- Is it going well?
- It's fine.
But he is not so impressed.
What do you think about the climate and stuff?
- The climate here, it's very cold.
- Right.
- We come from Turkey, you know.
- It's warmer there.
- But we are happy here.
The people are hot.
- The people are hot, yes.
So you're positive about the climate?
- We are happy for them.
Then the food was finished.
And then one of the pizza bays wanted to take a picture with what he thought was Greta Thunberg.
- Yes, do you know what?
I got a bad conscience now.
This, so she is just like Greta.
It's not Greta.
It's not she.
In other words...
It's not Greta.
Unfortunately.
I got such a bad conscience now.
She's just ... No, she's just as Greta.
It's not Greta.
- He's a big troll, but ...
- He's a big troll?
No, I'm not a magician.
- No, I'm not troll.
It's not joking.
- No, it's not Greta.
That's true, it's not Greta.
Or, you can take a picture.
- Yes.
So confused!
He thinks I'm kidding now.
Yes, okay, I've been kidding.
Run, take a picture.
I just want to say it's not Greta.
- Okay.
- You don't believe me!
- Drink like this imperialist soda and eat meat.
- God so tasty!
- Yes.
- Check out how she just chops in on the meat.
You like NATO sliding weapons and meat.
It's like ...
- Yes, but it was well summarized.
It's like what you need to know about me.
- But how similar is Emmy really Greta appearance?
To test it I wanted to see if we could create a viral cliff-
-It pretended that Greta has started sniffing loose.
A strange yet credible news that could act as a test.
Will people see the difference between them?
- You have to change.
I have to buy loose nus.
- Yes.
- This is a real fur.
You absolutely cannot wear it.
A small scarf, just because that effect is so extreme.
So I pull and buy some loose snuff.
Let's go.
Now we are going in the same direction.
Fuck.
- It's so ridiculously the same.
Excuse.
You couldn't imagine being a statistician in a scene.
You can give some credibility to the stage that we are creating.
Are everyone ready?
- Yes.
- Are you ready?
1, 2, 3.
That is still Greta.
Can you see the similarity?
- It actually got really good.
- I have a friend who has a big MEME account on Instagram.
Which is very much about snuff and stuff.
If he posts it, we simply see what happens.
Hi beaver.
I just sent you the clip.
- Run it out!
So we'll see what happens.
Now it is just letting time go and we see where this clip is going.
The vast majority seemed to be happy about the unexpected news.
Only a few bores questioned whether it was really real Greta.
The clip spread on Twitter and Tiktok and only on Instagram it got over two million views.
Most of whom now seem to think that Greta Thunberg has started with Lösnus.
However, we are going to number seven.
- And now it will be about my own lookalike.
In recent years, we have received hundreds of tips on people who should be like me.
No one is really similar.
Now we have a guy who really hopes will be the closest we have of me in Sweden.
So now it's up to proof.
There he is!
Yes, that's him!
Come out!
Hello!
My name is Mustiga Mauri.
I am 17 years old, I go to high school-
-and I'm 175 cm tall.
- Hello
- How's it going?
- It is good!
Do you imitate me?
- I'm like this.
- Is it true?
It's a bit the same energy on you.
But this was still a little better than I thought.
- It's so, yes.
You should know how many people say I'm like Mauri.
- Does it happen that people think you are Mauri?
- On Odenplan, I went.
And then a little guy comes up.
So five, eight years or something.
He came after me and said, apologize, can I take a picture?
- No?
And I just, eeh, and then just, no wait it is not you.
And then he goes on.
- If you had been two meters.
- Yes then.
- If we had just put you on stilts.
- I can stand on that one.
- Now, now, like that.
- Now he's ready.
So I have received so many people who say they are like me.
Actually, it's just that they are red -haired.
- Yes.
But with you here there is something a little more.
- Yes I know.
- It's something.
- I know.
- Shall we have a coffee?
- Let's go.
- How often does someone say you are like me?
- Yes, it happens all the time.
It is not possible to count.
At school a few years ago, they didn't even know me.
They just went and shouted.
Mauri!
Excuse me, can we take a picture with you, Mauri?
- At school?
At school?
Damn!
But what, how often have people wanted to take a picture with you?
How many times has it happened?
- Three, four times maybe.
- Damn what anti -climax.
- Cheers.
- Cheers my mirror image.
- I've been wondering if you are my secret cousin or dad or anything.
No one in my family is Ginger.
- What is your mother's name?
- Beatrice.
What did you do in 2005?
Nah.
Are you my dad?
- Welcome.
- Hello.
Why did you go?
We would just have some fun as well.
- No no no.
I am your father.
And now we travel quickly to the number eight of the list where we find lookalike to Noel Fike from the band Hovet.
And for the first time in world history, this visit will be made by a trainee.
- Now we will meet Noel Flikes Lookalike.
No, sorry.
One more time!
Hörrni, now we will meet Noel Flike's lookalike from Hovet.
And he lives here.
This is going to be fucking fun!
Here we go!
There he comes!
Hello!
Hi, yo, yo, yo!
My name is Noel Fike, I am 22 years old and live in Uppsala.
I usually kick back mirrors on the way home.
- New at work?
- A little, a little.
Do you have anything?
I can try to come.
On something too.
But I do my best!
You have nice eyes.
- Do you think?
The same.
- Thanks.
- Talent!
- Your voice is almost identical.
Can't you rap a little?
- I'm just starting to rap a little.
- Run some freestyle.
- mm.
- My name is David and I live in Nacka.
I sit here with Mauri and we talk.
We are very nice.
Nice clothes, red -haired and ...
- We sit in Nacka and talk.
We are so nice.
We drink some coffee.
- Coffee, coffee.
Yes...
No no no.
No corner, this won't go.
This won't go.
I can not.
This is for ...
- I may think we stop there.
- Nice.
- It was awesome.
- It was the weakest segment on assignment food through before.
- Before the next visit, I thought we would look at some of the tips you emailed but that did not join the clip.
How about the girl who realized that as a child she was very similar to Ola Conny?
Or this woman who is a huge Camilla Läckberg?
And so this incredible GW locomotive bale which unfortunately was unable to record.
This woman is still like Carola.
And so this girl who is sick like in the middle of nature, the program manager, in a very exciting way.
And so my personal favorite, the guy who is not really really like Calle Morreus.
And that was it, now time for the number five list.
And now we will meet Enskedes Anders Bagge who apparently works down there.
And this is where he should be.
Hey!
Hello!
There we have him.
Hi, my name is Anders Bagge.
I have had a construction company here in Enskede for twelve years.
And yes, I'm Anders Bagge.
- It's also the same beard.
- I've had it for 20 years.
- Was it Bagge that turned off you?
- I think so.
- That damn ...
From profile here.
From here it is Anders Bagge.
Here it is ... it is still very much Anders Bagge.
How often do you hear that you ...
- Very often.
- Is this snuff?
- I sniff a lot.
- Now real Bagge will be a newspaper on me when I have such big boxes.
- This is what you call a box too.
That you have it in the back pocket.
Yes, you think it's yummy, huh?
- It is the best.
Do you want a snuff?
Now you have to try a real snuff.
If you dare.
Are you ready?
- No.
- Shall we drive?
- Yes.
- Okay, one, two, three.
- Oh my God!
- You have all your mouth.
- I'm getting completely dizzy?
- mm.
- I would probably spit it out.
- Yes, I think this is the location now huh?
- I think you got a Nickokick.
Congratulations!
- Thanks.
- Which one like a cute personality you have.
- Oh really?
- You feel so damn giggling and warm all the time.
- Well, that's not what my wife says.
It is difficult.
It's women.
They're going to talk.
It should be talked about.
With the great insight about women we left Enskede.
But also with a gratitude for living in a country where it is the most fun of the most fun.
Namely guys who own construction companies, at the same time can be exactly this cute.
Now, however, we are moving on to the number four of the list.
- And now it will be about a Swedish lookalike to the world's most famous actress.
It will be about Tjörns Leonardo DiCaprio.
Hey!
- Hey Hey.
You are like, after all.
You have no filter or anything.
That's you.
- No, I'll show that I have no filter.
- Now you are even more similar from this angle.
- Haha, yes thank you.
It's fun to hear that I could be helpful.
- It was incredibly fun to talk to Tjörn Leonardo DiCaprio.
- It was incredibly nice to talk to Mauri aka Ed Sheeran on stilts.
- Haha okay.
Thanks.
And now it's time for the list number three.
- And now we will meet a girl who is very similar, one of Sweden's largest international actors.
We will meet Malmös Malmö Åkerman.
- Oh damn!
- Hi Malin.
- Mauri, nice.
Hi, my name is Malin Åkerman.
I am 29 years old and work as a contracting engineer.
- Now you are even more like her.
- It's just growing.
- Do you know the actor Malin Åkerman?
- Yes.
- If you were to ask a question to Malin Åkerman, what would it be?
- Oh, no idea.
- It's not every day it goes around a Hollywood actress in Malmö?
- It really isn't.
Are you at home on Christmas visits then or?
- Yes.
- Lovely!
- Do you know Malin Åkerman?
- Do you?
- No, okay.
- What series have you seen with her?
Do you remember who?
- Oh most movies.
You were with Ryan Reynolds and she Sandra Bullock was it well?
The proposal.
- Yes exactly.
Yes, I remember a little.
- Yes, it feels a bit like that to go around and lie.
- Well!
- Would you like to cut a Hollywood actress?
- Clearly!
- Do you recognize her?
- Yes!
- Who is it?
- Malin Åkerman.
- Would you say you have a good look at Malin Åkerman?
- Yes.
- If I were to say that this is not Malin Åkerman?
- You are completely in your own world.
- But you look exactly the same?
- I know if we look exactly the same.
- May I ask you something?
- What did he say?
Rather, do I die?
Did he say that?
- Did he rather die I?
- I think so.
- He dies rather than answer a question.
- You are like Malin Åkerman.
- mm.
- But then how good the actress are you?
- I don't think I'm such a good actor.
- But okay, now we take this.
Now I dump you.
And then you get really sad.
Now I'm a douche that dumps you.
Are you ready?
You ... I want to end, I thought.
- So, you're sure?
- Yes, I wanted to end you.
PGA has infidelity, which I have been doing.
- You've been in infidelity.
- Yes.
- Okay, so it's just from nowhere?
- mm.
- Why?
- infidelity.
- huh?
- mm.
- Who?
- Rather which.
- Who is she then?
- Ehh from the Baltic.
- From Balti ...
Hahahaha
- She lives below.
- In the basement?
Hahahaha
- You're kind of good!
You were kind of pretty good.
It was kind of strong.
- Ah?
No...
- Thanks for meeting you.
- Thanks for coming.
- It's damn sick how similar you are.
- A final time.
Now it is time for both number one and two on the list, as we will soon reconcile them as a duo.
- Now it will be about Claes Eriksson from Leif & Billy.
He has an absolutely incredible lookalike, we suspect, far down in southern Sweden.
Today I have attracted him from Blekinge to Stockholm, because we two have big plans.
You are joking!
- Hey!
- It's so sick!
My name is Claes Eriksson and I am a county coordinator in mental health in Blekinge in county.
- Hey!
- Satan what nice!
You have the same hairstyle and beard and stuff too.
- Yes, and birth mark even.
- huh?
Oh damn, he also has a birth mark there!
You are joking in the same place!
- I cheated my mom and sent a picture to her and said I had cut myself.
But then it was a picture of Claes.
- What so even your mom?
- She went on it.
- And you and I, we have some plans.
- We have some plans.
- We have also found the lookook for Billy.
-Okay, now we are at the T-Centralen and we will receive the Alfred lookalic.
Which comes in all the way from Småland.
Is that so?
Yes.
- Thanks so much.
- Thanks.
Have a good day.
- damn, how fast it went.
- There comes our Alfred.
Hello!
- Hi Andreas.
My name is Alfred Svensson and I am a plumbing engineer.
-Hey.
- Hi, Claes.
--Oj, Satan, no?
- Her god, what the same.
- And the best thing about you is that you are quite similar, Alfred.
But you are also similar in a different way.
- We were born and raised in the same city, both in Vimmerby.
- Yes.
- We discovered both theater through the same theater association in Vimmerby.
- And then we both have trained as actors at Kalle Flygare here in Stockholm.
- And there they are.
The real ni.
- Because here they play their show today.
And of course we should go in and meet your original.
- Lol!
Damn what fun!
- But first change.
Hello!
Wait, get a little closer.
You just said they are awesome.
Hello!
- Do you recognize them?
- Claes!
- Yes, yes, yes.
And while the selfies hail, the originals made ready to meet their copies.
- I am afraid that it will be so similar that I get existential scams.
- Yes!
I die.
Why am I dying?
- Everyone is so nervous!
Oh my God!
Come and look!
Here you have them!
- Hey!
- Oh damn!
But but, fuck what sick!
Oh that's so damn sick!
- What is it?
So I get a scam of this.
Oh god what strange this is.
Servant, hello you!
- Damn what special!
- So I have to say ...
- I really agree.
It's damn sick.
But I'm totally wandged.
Because there are extreme similarities.
- You have birthmarks in the same places.
- It's actually totally sick.
- We have some plans tonight.
You have a sold out show here at Scala all winter.
You drive tonight.
- Yes, we would have liked you two to go up and take the evening.
- Oh, damn.
- I get shitty too.
- Say this: Servant!
My name is Billy Öhman.
- My name is Billy Öhman.
- Well, you think you will have fun.
Tonight?
- Well, do you think you will have fun tonight?
- Hahaha.
- It is almost after all.
- Do you think you will have fun tonight?
- It's fun, it's just fun.
Damn what fun it is to be here in the big city.
- Damn what fun it is to be here in the big city.
Hahahaha.
- Is this your interpretation of Northern?
- Damn what fun it is to be here in the big city!
- Yes, but it's fun.
For this audience will be like this ... What is happening now?
- Yes!
- Ohhhh Hey!
How would the unaware audience react?
How long would it take before they realized that something was wrong?
- Now it's close.
The show is about an hour and 20 minutes long, in an act without a passport.
But now it's time.
- My ladies and gentlemen, give a warm applause to Leif and Billy!
- Hello
- Ah.
Hello Hello!
- Hello Hello!
- Are you tagged?
- Yes!
Are they going on it?
- There is no funeral here.
Are you tagged?
- Yes!
- God Cursed Billy.
We will introduce ourselves first.
- Yes, of course.
I'm Billy Öhman.
And this is my brother.
- I'm Leif.
And it was somewhere where it started to get up for people that something wasn't right.
And the remaining minutes on stage, became a bit of a nightmare.
- Yes, today we will see a wonderful show!
- This is a disaster.
- What happens?
Does it work or?
- I think we would drive Småland huh?
Or how was it?
- I do not know.
What do you think?
Northern or Småland?
Northern, yes okay.
- Okay, then we shit in it.
Then we drive in Småland anyway.
- It doesn't work we have to enter.
- In in!
- In hell!
God damn!
Didn't you say you could Northern?
- I can do that.
- So, go out this way.
It is good.
An applause!