The Romans originally come from India.
Today there are Roma all over the world.
In Sweden, Roma has lived since the 16th century.
There are many different groups with their own tradition, culture and religion.
The Romans' own language, Romani Chib, has several different dialects.
The Romans have a long history of persecution, exclusion of harassment and discrimination.
During the Second World War, half a million Roma were destroyed.
Roma have also been discriminated against in Sweden.
During the 1900s, Roma were described as an inferior breed, based on racial biological ideas.
Many Roma were forcibly sterilized and children were taken from their parents.
Roma were not allowed to obtain housing and many were forced to live in camps.
It meant that Roma children could not go to school,
And adult Roma had a hard time getting a job.
Between 1914 and 1954, Roma was not allowed to travel to Sweden.
The Roma who already lived here could not leave the country because they were not allowed to come back.
On April 8, 1971, the first international Roma Congress was held in London.
Then they agreed on a Roman flag and a national anthem.
Since then, April 8 has been International Roma Day.
Racism against Roma Antiziganism-and political decisions during the 20th century have influenced the opportunities of the Romans to be part of Swedish society.
Roma still find it difficult to get housing and work.
Roma children face discrimination and difficulties in school.
But.
Roma should be able to participate in society on equal terms as others.
That is why in Sweden we have a national strategy for Roman inclusion.
The goal is for the Rome that turns 20 in 2032 to have the same opportunities in life as everyone else.
On January 1, 2010, Sweden received a law on national minorities and minority languages.
As a national minority you have a strengthened
protection to develop your culture and your language.
You decide for yourself if you want to belong to the national minority Roma.
You as Rome have rights.
Uppsala Municipality is obliged to ensure that your rights are respected, protected and realized.
Our business and our services should be adapted to your rights.
You should get information about what rights you have.
We have a special responsibility for protecting and promoting your language and culture.
You should have influence on issues that affect you through consultation, meetings and conversations.
In particular, we will promote children and young people's opportunities for influence on them.
If you want to know more about your rights at the Contact Center, you can get information and guidance.
Here you can also get in touch with a community counselor
in Uppsala municipality that has Roman language and cultural competence.
Welcome!