Good job with the series!
Now there will be a lot of source criticism jobs.
The future is light!
-God juice, right?
-Scrumptious.
-It was to my mom.
-Now it became to us.
Sorry, but we celebrate our successes.
We are busy right now.
Just for my sake, could we have a little recap?
-Daprate through what we've been talking about?
-Sure, why not?
Absolutely!
Åsa Larsson and Jack Werner started the Viral Reviewer.
Today, they run the source criticism, Sweden's national team in source criticism.
Now they, together with Edwin Safari, are doing Källkoll Corona.
We have handled urgent things.
Corona Virus!
-Jack, check out this video!
-Atta so I'll just call Åsa.
No!
Don't say it's a scam!
Can't something be nice in the world?
No wonder when it is very strange that is spread.
I have a tip for everyone: don't cough on the elderly.
Corona is not just a disease.
It is power play and big politics.
It's a lot now, but wait until there is a vaccine.
-Top, but then: concrete tips.
-Yes, we have also come up with.
-There every day as April 1st.
-The news picks up the deviant.
-San it gets so big.
-Richly hot it will be ...
... if you take the time not only to press the first search result.
Good, but I want to know more.
Don't you have anymore?
-Yes.
Do you know who Elisa Granato is?
-No.
I didn't know that either until I heard that she had died.
"Britain's first subject in vaccine study against Corona has died."
The article was widely circulated, also in Swedish Corona groups on Facebook.
But since this is our program, I guess it wasn't true?
No.
Just.
Elisa is microbiology
-And one of two subjects in Britain's vaccine attempt.
She had to wake up to the news of her own death and said this:
I live to the highest degree.
I'm drinking tea.
It is Sunday, April 26.
Three days after I got the vaccine or placebon.
I enjoy Sunday.
What can you do when you see such a story?
After all, we have distributed tips.
Practical tips are to google things.
You can google on names, places and times.
Search the pictures.
Check out different search results.
Does it seem as if it is stated?
The last one might not be relevant.
The eyes should go to the most important thing: the sender.
Who is talking?
What is the site?
Use quotation marks when searching.
Then you only get the wording.
You can delineate names, places and phrases that you want to search for.
If you suspect that something is fake, try using it.
For example...
... "Elisa Granato" and then the word fake.
Then you get this.
You can also click around the site.
Write "Click around the site".
Try it.
Then it may turn out who is behind it.
It is a bit difficult to determine who is behind this site.
-There is no story about the site.
-It is made two years ago.
Then it has not been used until recently.
And the oldest articles ...
It is Stock Photos - genre images - used.
It is some kind of nonsen text fills the articles.
Weird.
One can conclude that it seems to be a click fishing site.
Someone tries to gather ad clicks and posts whatever seven ...
-.. Whether it's true or not.
-Perfect!
Thanks!
We have been educational.
I designed the entire Swedish media market.
Things come in from the world and Sweden.
TT sends them out.
And when I made my illustration of how rumors spread ...
So nice!
Some circles.
We're talking about four events-
-But something that has been noticed so that so many people have heard about it.
Very good!
I am so impressed with you!
But what should you do now?
Now?
This will roll on.
We are out of for life here.
-Money in the bank!
-We shall see...
-The producer!
-The job offers!
Social distancing!
- Edwin, I received your email about the program idea.
GREATE!
You are fully trained regarding source criticism.
And you have such a ... young speech.
Should we go and talk about the program?
Yes, yes ... he left the juice anyway.
For each source check Corona there is educational material at Urplay.se.
Search "Källkoll Corona", Choose "Pedagogical Material"-
-And click on the worksheet to open.
Texting: Jussi Walles www.btistudios.com