Help me.
I don't get a single penny on my swish journalism.
-Din Swishjournalism?
-Yes.
Look!
Yes, and now to the weather.
It rains.
It was all for Edwin-News.
No swish!
Swisha me!
Give me Parra!
Swisha!
- Why?
You are doing right as a journalist.
But if you most want money, you have to think about it.
Explain, please!
Journalists Åsa Larsson and Jack Werner started the Viral reviewer.
Today, they run the source criticism, Sweden's national team in source criticism.
Now they and Edwin Safari Källkoll Corona are doing.
If we start with what it looked like before the internet destroyed everything
-So we can look at some examples.
Imagine this is a regular news editor.
Let me guess.
Sofie is a reporter.
She does research, interviews, writes factual, impartial news texts-
-There she doesn't tell what she thinks but produces facts and refers.
It is the most well -known professional role of journalism, which you may think of.
But there are more professional roles in a newspaper, which Nicolettas.
She is a leader writer.
She thinks things as a job.
It is her work to run the newspaper's political line.
If you say "they think this" you refer to the leadership writer.
That's the point.
She should take out the turns and provoke a little.
You don't have to agree, but she runs the social debate.
Then we have Fredrik who is a news chronicler and commentator.
He analyzes things and tries to make us understand what has happened.
It is explanatory and like.
You not only want facts, dry reporting on what has happened-
-Why you want to have analysis and hear someone else's "take", someone who knows more-
-As gives a picture of what everything looks like.
Sometimes you want to be provoked by someone who thinks just the opposite-
-As to feel that "no!"
And get a picture of how you look at the world.
-It's pretty nice.
-The newspaper houses hold all three things.
You get facts, analysis and opinions.
But sometimes it is people who do not understand the difference.
A leadership writer comes with thought, but not the news reporters.
Because a leadership writer thinks something, you do not know what the reporters think.
This is a nice model, if you are in the sentimental direction.
But it belongs to the past.
So it will not look in the future.
If you have to guess, given the Corona crisis, several media houses are pure.
There are not as many newspapers in the future, or journalism jobs.
And it doesn't look bright now with a threatening economic crisis.
But what does that mean?
That more journalists work like this.
Some of those who have been kicked have become a freelancer.
They sell articles to the media houses.
Some work directly towards readers or viewers.
You get money directly from them.
You can make fundraisers, get money through subscriptions from readers-
-or get money through swish as gifts.
I have tried, but no one sends anything.
According to Wikipedia, safari is both a wilderness expedition, a browser-
-and UR's best host.
Well ... you may have to work away as the listeners can find themselves.
They don't want you to check Wikipedia.
You can drive a hard line of opinion.
Many people prefer to give money to people who say what they think.
The loudness they are, the more money you want to give to them.
The disadvantage of that becomes that one sometimes risks saying things-
-No loud and more determined to get more money.
You become extreme because you know how the money comes in.
Is there anything else I can do?
One model is to take an area you are the best in Sweden or the world on-
-And then you become very niche and focused on that subject area.
-You are very good on tarot cards.
-It's not a bad idea at all.
In the future, I think it will be more common with journalists-
-Or focusing on areas they know well and receives revenue directly from the reader.
It becomes important for us consumers to be critically set-
-And critically consume this type of independent journalists.
Is this reporter an expert, credible or bought?
Is it sponsored?
We have to get better at seeing it.
A world grows where both you and your readers can fit.
It becomes more important how journalists act.
Are they professional?
Do they stick to facts without personal opinions coloring the reports?
Can they correct?
Are they purchased?
Edwin, you know the tarot card business.
You would never be purchased and can deliver both news and analysis.
This is the top.
Become a reporter about Tarot cards.
You do not fall for loud opinions.
You go the narrow path of the fact.
-Thanks!
Now I'll go and work.
-Gott conscience is the best pillow.
Today's card is "The Moon".
Mercury is in retrograde.
I'm expecting malproofing and fake news.
Each section contains educational material.
You can find it at Urplay.se
Search "Källkoll Corona" and select "Pedagogical Material".
Click on the worksheet to open.
Texting: Gabriella Eseland www.btistudios.com