When talking about proteins you usually think of food such as meat and egg-
-But rarely do we talk about the thousands of proteins that build our bodies.
Without them we would not exist.
There are several thousand protein in the body.
They are called the body's building blocks as they build up bones, tissues and muscles-
-But even hormones, enzymes and antibodies are proteins.
They are found everywhere in the body-
-And is of great importance for the body's functions and structure.
The proteins are produced in the body's cells, more specifically the ribosomes-
-cellen's small factories.
It is our DNA, our library in Cell nuclei-
-Whow sends out recipes for the type of protein to be manufactured.
It is this process we call protein synthesis.
Protein consists of even smaller building blocks, small organic molecules-
-which is called amino acids.
There are 20 different ones.
With instructions from the body's DNA, they are linked to long chains.
The protein gets specific properties-
-Dore depending on which amino acids are involved and their order.
The combinations are almost endless.
When the chain is done, it is folded together and the protein gets its unique structure.
In order for protein to be formed, the amino acids must be found in our bodies.
We cannot make all ourselves.
We get nine pieces through the food.
In the past, it was believed that proteins were unique to a specific tissue.
That they were just there.
But that theory is littered.
Today we know that a protein in the knee joint may be in your gut.
Proteins are not just building materials in tissues, muscles and bones.
They are much more than that and are behind many chemical processes.
Enzymes, receptors, hormones and antibodies are all protein-
-And has a role in our cell communication and interaction.
Hormones are formed in glands and transported to different organ-
-Where they affect different cells.
Receptors are protein that captures external signals-
-And sends them into the cell.
Antibodies Flag marks intruders in the body-
-and calls on the immune system's killer cells-
-What breaks down the unwelcome guest.
The function of the enzyme is to catalyze-
-It wants to say regulate the speed of different processes.
As an example, the enzyme amylas may speed up the decomposition of the food-
-What it reaches our intestines.
And the enzyme PRDM2 is involved in regulating impulses in our brain.
They are very important for processes that can otherwise take hours or days.
They are shortened thanks to our enzymes.
What can we learn from this?
Without proteins, we would not exist.
If the cells fail to produce sufficient amounts, the body is affected.
If you have a lack of growth hormone you do not grow normally-
-And if you have a lack of insulin, you develop the disease diabetes.
Swedish text: Gabriella Eseland Iyuno Media Group for UR