-What fun to do new "Källkoll"!
-Really.
It always needs to be checked.
Fun to meet Edwin again.
-Have you seen his new channel?
-No.
Hello World!
Welcome to my channel!
-Oh my God!
What are you doing here?
-Hello Hello!
Fun that you support.
Do you remember your tips for me to start my own?
"It's going Fabulous!"
Very funny, but shouldn't you be with us and do new "Källkoll" programs?
Check out things, go deep, source criticism online?
If I have time.
I have many followers to take care of.
-Many DM's.
There came a new one!
-Do you really have 700,000 followers?
-Sorry?
-Okay, lovely, wow!
-But now we're going to do "Källkoll".
-Yes, "of course, Darling".
Then we have to "level up" a bit, give it "Production Value".
I mean, your outfits, for example?
So ... like this.
We go away and file on a press release ...
-.. So we see what it gets.
-"Oh my good, yay!"
New "Källkoll".
With edwin and company.
Explosions, smoke machine, confetti.
Here we go!
Okay, it's a news, but is that a big news?
-What?
-That we start over with "Källkoll".
-Yes, now that I'm involved.
-Yes Yes.
Yes, yes.
I guess the newspapers write more about something-
-If a celebrity is involved.
Therefore, gossip magazines use celebrities as click bait.
"Ooh! Juicy!"
But how do you know what will be a news?
We can address this when we learn about information, communication ...
Yes, but I want to know what makes a news big!
I checked with my "fellow gen-zedders"-
-On my channel, and they said like this.
There is something that has happened that may need to be noticed.
A new event that affects society.
Something that has happened in the world that is posted on the internet or in newspapers.
Something important to lift up, type.
That is worth knowing.
What has been big news since we last saw?
-Pandemic.
-"Miss Rona, We Know Her."
What else?
The storming of Congress in the United States.
I sat up all night watching.
I also.
And I got stuck because they found a hole in Estonia's hull.
It sounds awful.
Does it have to be awful to be a novelty?
It tends to be greater news of things that are not good.
It is not always so, but unfortunately often.
Bad news beats higher.
Estonia was a ferry in the Baltic Sea which fell in September 1994.
According to information from the rescue management in the Turku-
-Had probably 838 people died in the Estonia disaster.
It was one of the largest vessel disasters in modern times.
And one of the biggest news events in Sweden.
-A national trauma.
-No the State Accident Investigation Board ...
... who did an investigation, it was due to the bog visor raging off-
-And it came on board water, she sank.
But wait a bit.
This happened in 1994.
-Why will it be a news now?
-Ward objection.
Temptuality.
It is one of the criteria for a news.
The news here is not that Estonia fell 30 years ago, but that ...
One can say this: the disaster has been surrounded-
-A of conspiracy theories and speculation since it occurred.
Not everyone believes in the Commission's conclusion.
There are theories-
-If Russian submarines and blasts.
Last fall, a filmmaker was down and filmed at the wreck-
-The trot that there is grave peace there and it was illegal.
But he found a hitherto undiscovered hole.
Oh, look!
And the hole thinks many ... "Think if it occurred in connection with the sinking."
Then it may have contributed to her sinking.
So of the old news did it become a new one?
Not just one - several big news.
The filmmaker behind the grip to dive down with a drone and film the wreck-
-Where alone about doing so.
It is because there is grave peace.
There are hundreds of corpses there.
There is a grave peace since ten years.
So he was alone about it and broke against the law on grave peace.
Therefore, he was prosecuted, but he was also alone in the pictures.
And being alone and first with a news is important in news context.
"Got it!"
What else makes a news a news?
Proximity in time, space and identification.
Time is simple.
It just happened, or we were told about something recently.
Room is that it happened near us, or pretty close.
In Sweden.
And it happened to people who could have been, and also where-
-No neighbor, a friend in the same school, a mother.
Just.
But identification is a bit tricky-
-The all of us are not and tjenis with everyone else.
I do not share the experience with you two of being a warm-up-
-But if something would happen in Värmland-
-I assume that you would also feel with affected warmers.
It depends on who you are as a person, how much you take in the outside world-
-And how much you identify with others in it.
However, we generally seem to identify ourselves more with those who are like us-
-An like that we perceive as strangers or different.
It also seems to be so mournful that we care more about celebrities.
Kim and Kanye's love story ...
Jireel and Alice have ended.
But he is a completely different person ...
-"Absolutely."
-San we have the effect.
Thus, whether what has happened affects many directly or indirectly.
Just.
Therefore, the pandemic has become so great.
It affects every cone cone in the whole world-
-and it keeps happening.
We don't know what's going to happen-
-So we have to continue to care about this.
When can you go out?
But on the other hand, what is happening now tends to fake as news.
Most are pretty tired of hearing about Covid.
While in the beginning you panicked every time something came up.
Corona has become everyday.
The big news had been if Corona had disappeared.
A news is not something that is as it always is.
There is something different.
Or dramatically, like finding a previously unknown hole in a shipwreck.
-How went the trial, by the way?
-He was released p.g.a.
a technicality.
They dived or sent down their drone from a German -flagged ship.
-He was released, anyway.
-But was lowered the boat, right?
We don't know yet.
The documentary has been criticized for being speculative-
-And that those who are interviewed produce conspiracy theories.
And he did not show that they had found more holes.
They only showed one.
Maybe because it weakened their case.
That it would have had something to do with the sinking.
It seemed as if it were spectacular.
Now it is perhaps that it was naturally causes.
The hole they found has been enough for it to be worth an investigation.
Sweden, Finland and Estonia have said: We are thinking about a new investigation.
This news has potential.
It may come out of it.
Just.
Then it becomes like ... Sometimes media blows up large air castles.
And then, when you review in depth, it turned out not to be anything.
All this talk about water ... I'm getting thirsty!
Coffee?
-Yes!
-"Let's go!"
-Mm, editorial coffee!
-Lovely.
Right!
The storming of capitol, how does it stand as news?
As news - pretty good.
It was very, very violent.
There was deadly violence, many injured themselves.
It was heavenly upset.
USA!
Then the question is: Was it unexpected?
The police did not seem to be prepared for so many to come.
The Capitoli Police had counted  m  ed a dissatisfaction demonstration.
instead it became a storm.
Then it was also so that if Trump tried to stay at the power-
-Then many people said in advance: "This is getting messy."
Sure, it's been talking about it for a long time.
But that's another thing-
-When the warnings for Trump's behavior become reality.
Thus, when a "parliamentary building" is stormed.
It is hard to see the pictures from the storm-
-Or to raise the eyebrows.
That is sick!
Then it is not in Sweden.
It is in the United States, on the other side of the Atlantic.
On the other hand, we seem to care a lot about what is happening in the United States.
But that may change in the future.
You don't know that.
That is the most important-
-This more than seeing it on TV, are things that happen in our everyday lives.
There is a criticism of the media:
News is what the media says is news.
It happens very important things that affect a lot of people's life-
-But it does not end up on news sites, so it will not be news of it.
A bit like news is something you can make money from creating?
Absolutely!
One can make money on news-
-and "borrow the news clothes" to do it.
Journalism and news are something that we should confidence in.
Confidence you can try to earn without having earned it-
-Do to dress up their advertising so that it looks like journalism.
-There are fraudsters who work that way.
-In last election, 2016 ...
... when Hillary Clinton stood as a candidate against Donald Trump-
-It there a guy who created a fake yelling:
That she was involved in the murder of an FBI agent.
He pulled it up on a fake news page-
-What was built around the fake, but there was nothing on it.
The goal: to make people believe that what they saw was a real news site-
-As could fool people.
This with news and articles ... We can draw it a little better.
If Edwin can have a channel then we can have a channel!
-Obvious!
-I go away and fix it.
Do it!
Now you get competition for your subscribers.
We will talk about news and the news formula or recipe.
First we'll just talk about: When you scroll in your news feed-
-Then a lot of things show up, mostly probably entertainment-
-But some things are news and articles.
What do they look like?
First, top, a heading, which will summarize what the article is about.
Then we have the preamble - the extra -black text at the top.
There, the thing should stand, what it is about.
If you are going to tell something to a friend, then you will not start from the beginning-
-What you say what has happened.
"It rolled down an aircraft wing on the road in front of me."
Not: "I started walking along the road this morning."
So the thing itself is what is going on in the preamble.
Then comes the rest - the article - with all the details-
-All that will comment, the background, etc.
What is going in here is what is relevant to the article-
-D.V.S.
Things that matter for what happened.
Fake items and advertising would like to borrow the article's clothes.
So, look like a real news and signal it.
They want to borrow the credibility that comes with it.
Remember the ingredients for a news:
It must have happened recently and close.
It should be unusual or unexpected.
The more you affect and the more you influence, the greater the news.
Okay!
"Ah, Cute!"
So it really is enough to just read the headings on a news-
-To know what it is about?
Admittedly, the heading should be about the thing itself-
-But if you just read the headline, you miss shades and details.
A friend did an experiment.
He wrote a chronicle with the headline:
"Researchers: People who don't read books are smarter."
In the chronicle itself it said: "No, I was just joking."
But!
A study shows that 59 % of all articles on social media-
-Delete without being read.
That was the whole point to show:
"Lol! You are so departed, you who share articles without reading them."
Then there is the problem that headings do not keep what they promise.
You attract people on false grounds.
Clickbait and so on.
So basic, what we need is celebrities, a little action, a little drama.
-Do we have any good gossip?
-What so, big news ...
Then the principle of proximity applies, if it affects society ...
A celebrity?
"Moi!"
A second, only!
It would be good if we ...
Hi, Babes!
I have heard that educational radio, or ur-
-Sh change name to VR.
They will do everything in virtual reality!
You have to have a VR headset to keep up.
"Like, Comment and Subscribe for More", and most importantly:
Share!