We have always been fascinated by space-
-But if life can live there has long been a mystery.
It was believed that space was hostile and that everything would die directly-
-But that's wrong.
A human being survives seconds without space suit-
-But other life on our planet is better at surviving in space-
-for example.
The bacterium that produced the air we breathe.
That knowledge can make it easier if we move out into the universe.
My name is Natuschka Lee and I am an astrobiological scientist.
I investigate how microscopic life can survive in extreme environments.
In astrobiology, research on life in the universe.
You are particularly interested in extremes:
Microscopic organisms that live under extreme conditions-
-like the ice on Antarctic or inside volcanoes.
These environments are similar to those on other planets, such as Mars.
It is important partly to understand how life has arisen on our planet-
-And what conditions we have to colonize other celestial bodies.
Some day our own planet will be swallowed by the universe again.
It can be through an asteroid, as on the time of dinosaurs-
-or that the sun goes out.
No man has yet set foot on Mars, the race is underway.
Natuschka Lee is researching the European Space Organization Esa-
-It to demonstrate life in space in general and Mars in particular-
-Ope which life from the earth can survive there.
We have sent different organisms to the space station.
There have been extreme bacteria, fungi, lichens and mosses.
They have been sitting on a container that we attached outside the space station.
Then they have been allowed to circulate around the earth for 1.5 years.
So we hope to simulate how organisms from the earth can react-
-Or genuine space conditions, e.g.
If they ended up on Mars.
Many survived cosmic radiation-
-Or oxygen and nutrition and under extreme cold in Natuschka's experiment.
I.a.
bear animal
— which can turn off its metabolism and can withstand the radiation-
-But even five viruses, ten plant species, 25 fungal species-
-and 60 bacterial species - including cyanobacteria-
-which with the sun's energy creates its own nutrition through photosynthes-
-Ornan the atmosphere of the earth.
All survivors managed without oxygen uptake-
-And some could make new oxygen.
Here we enrich algae and cyanobacteria.
It is these tough organisms that have been shown to withstand outer space.
In addition, they have changed our own planet.
It is thanks to these, which are enlarged 1 billon-
-As we have got oxygen in our air.
Cyanobacteria produced oxygen that enabled multicellular organisms.
It was the start of life's development on earth.
One can say with high security--
-Oft cyanobacteria have existed for at least 2.5 billion years.
It is amazing that organisms here-
-In all cases to some extent can survive in space.
The hope is to use them-
-To create better conditions to survive on another celestial body.
Swedish texture: Per Lundgren Iyuno for UR