-Good juice, this.
-Really.
-But you, where is Eddie?
- Should he be free today?
-Oh, there he is.
-Gosh.
-So.
-Hello!
Why haven't you answered?
-No don't answer when you need you.
I had to connect to the intranet and into the big screen ...
-.. for you to even react.
-You really are Edwin?
Someone on a screen that is on public service.
-It sounds like a Russian troll.
-Ad off, that's me.
You can't believe that people are Russian trolls because they are angry online.
Okay, okay, you're right.
Sorry.
No danger.
I just wanted to check if you had ...
In fact, you have a good point.
Now we make a section on this.
Åsa Larsson and Jack Werner started the "Viral Reviewer".
They run the source criticism - Sweden's national team in source criticism.
Now they do and edwin safari "Källkoll Corona"
Last fall, Anders Ygeman held a speech-
-And said the Nordic region would be the world's first 5G region.
Instead of a few hundred Facebook comments, he received 2,000.
Most were critical of the 5G expansion.
Sick huh, Edwin?
Yes.
But I just wanted to ...
By New Year, Ygeman went out-
-And said that a Russian disinformation campaign was behind it.
Russian trolls.
"Some interests want to whip up a negative picture of 5G"-
-"and disseminate uncertainty between state and citizens."
Then it became quiet until April 5.
SVT has investigated users who have commented.
We can't find Russian bottoms.
The tracks lead to an apartment on Södermalm.
-In who remembers section seven ... -We must talk about what 5g is.
We talked about 5G technology and how some are worried about the expansion.
They had sat in their Facebook group and commented.
It does not mean that everyone was Swedish Facebook users-
-And we know that Russia is involved in the 5G issue.
But Anders Ygeman had not proven that everything was Russian disinformation.
They had urged each other to comment.
So it can go.
It may be misunderstood that 5G is dangerous, but you have to think so.
That's how opinion -forming works.
People go together-
-To influence politicians to make good decisions.
It is not just opinion -forming, it is democracy.
Cheers for democracy.
Sometimes drives and criticism is perceived as invented.
You do not experience them as real because it sounds too angry and strange.
But you can't dismiss them because you don't like what you hear.
Hello, listen.
Can you just check if I ...
A critical debate is central to democracy.
You are not foam if you do not agree with Anders Tegnell and Stefan Löfven.
It is not wrong to think something else.
The holders and authorities must have their eyes on whatever they think.
You want as many people as possible to eyes on what is right-
-And especially on what gets wrong, so that small errors are not big wrong.
Critical voices are super important-
-As the doctor Li Wenliang, who was one of the earliest to alert about Corona.
Errors are constantly noticed.
At the Public Health Authority's press conference-
-Where Emmanuel Karlsten last to ask a question.
By asking the question-
-He had a great deal of inaccuracy that the Public Health Authority had missed.
First, I have to get a clarification.
Did you say that for every confirmed case of Covid-19 there is 1,000 more?
I don't get the mat together.
Surely there are 6,000 confirmed cases in Stockholm?
If you start from the material you have calculated-
-The for each confirmed case there is a dark figure of 999 more.
The math was not so easy to sort out.
The error became a front page news.
The entire material had to be withdrawn and the report itself.
All because a single journalist had asked a critical question.
We should all have such eyes with us.
Eyes that are awake for wrong, small or large.
-Nice bonus at work.
-Yes.
But what happened to Eddie?
Eddie ... Jösses, what he is doing.
- He's on Mute.
-Oh my God!
I just wanted to ask if I forgot a bottle of juice at work.
It's my birthday present for mom.
Wait.
What are you drinking?
What the ---?!
Each section contains educational material at Urplay.se.
Search "Källkoll Corona" and select "Pedagogical Material".
Click on the worksheet.
Texting: Stina Hedin www.btistudios.com