Have you seen this movie?
A young, healthy and well -trained woman has got Corona and become Assjuk.
It's scary.
Corona is not dangerous if you are not old and sick.
Someone has written that it is an old movie that warns of smoking.
-You might have found a scam there.
-Shey, fake?
-Many doubted the movie.
-Is that fake or not?
Journalists Åsa Larsson and Jack Werner started the Viral reviewer.
Today, they run the source criticism, Sweden's national team in source criticism.
Now, together with Edwin, they do Källkoll Corona.
Before we look at the woman, we should have it clearly and clearly-
-At Corona, Covid-19, worst affects those who are older.
It is the clear picture from everywhere.
If you are over 40, you suffer worse.
But in the news feed, which comes from all over the world-
-We also hear about what stands out.
This spoke the state epidemiologist Anders Tegnell Om-
-To a press conference.
When one has a disease that in a short time affects a million human-
-The all diseases will have odd events.
This brings us back to the woman on the movie.
This was a two-child mother from the UK who became inserted
-And then turned out to have covid-19.
I'm on intensive.
I can't breathe without this one.
She described it as having glass in her lungs.
She became very scared and wanted to tell about it to her friends.
This movie was then spread throughout the world.
Everyone was quite stressed by it.
Then people began to comment.
"This is fake."
"It's an old anti-smoking film."
Maybe because she said like this:
You who smoke, put away the cigarettes.
You need your lungs.
People said they had seen the movie before.
Some claimed that she was Justin Trudeau's wife.
The Canadian Prime Minister?
Because of all the rumors, she decided to make a new movie.
Yes, I'm Corona-infected.
I smoked a long time ago but not now anymore.
Then she got to be in the morning TV.
You look much healthier.
It's true.
This woman has felt abusive and she is now feeling better.
It goes contrary to the larger picture, which is also true, af-
-That you don't get so sick at her age-
-If you do not belong to a risk group.
This is what stands out.
It is the exception that confirms the rule.
It's much like this Facebook post.
A woman talks about her brother Olle, infectious physician at Huddinge Hospital.
Olle has told a long thing about how he views the Covid-19 disease.
If you were to look at this-
-and assess whether it is true or false, what would you say?
We have someone who is referring to a brother called olle-
-Whow is allegedly working at the Swedish Medicines Agency.
There are no links to any sources.
I would say it's fake.
Mm.
This is what is difficult, that is.
When we were going to check this, I searched the web at Olle.
He happens to have the same last name as his sister, so there we had a little turn-
-And he is a doctor at the Swedish Medicines Agency.
Then you start to get a grip on the situation.
I called the Swedish Medicines Agency and they said:
"Yes, he exists. He is this person. He has said this."
This is something they have posted on their info site.
This is very similar to what is spread when it is fake.
We spread this because it is relevant and urgent.
It is important.
This is information we want to come to our surroundings at once.
Just so we do even when we spread rumors that are false, and chain letters.
We think everyone needs to know it now.
The thing with rumors is that they are sometimes true.
Otherwise, we would not have spread rumors.
If we knew that all rumors are fake-
-Ad we had 3,000 years ago stopped spreading them.
But we continue, because there is, now and then, what is actually true.
We have gone through two examples here.
Should everything be like this?
Should I have to examine everything in detail-
-And call the Swedish Medicines Agency?
I want it to be easy to recognize.
I also get tired sometimes, but this is how it is.
There is no magic wand that shows whether it is true or false.
But there is something that is almost as good.
Practical tips!
First and foremost, the most important thing is to question oneself.
We walk around and have opinions.
We think things.
What we think colors how we look at the world.
This means that we accept information that corresponds to what we think-
-And close your eyes for things that go against what we think.
That is why it is important to start by questioning yourself.
Do I want this to be true just because I think it's true?
You can google things.
You can google names, places, times-
-And check out what stands, and not just go to the links in the text.
Really hot it will-
-If you take the time not only to press the first search result.
When you are looking for a result at the top, but then more will come.
There is page two, page three, page four and page five.
If you click on any of them, things start to happen.
We like that.
I will question myself, search and look at more than one place.
He has taken this.
We are done.
Thanks.
-Do you have coffee?
-Yes.
Texting: Henrik Johansson www.btistudios.com