Hello and welcome.
My name is Fredrik Weisner and I lead Vinnova's Digital change area.
Today we will discuss what a next step in Sweden's AI development can look like.
We will do that together with an exciting panel of five persons
which stands in the middle of AI development.
Hello and warm welcome to the panel.
The reason we invited to this panel discussion
Is because AI development now goes fast and has come a long way.
It is also clear what great values can be created with AI today.
In order for us to be able to take advantage of AI fully as a country
for both a better society and our global competitiveness-
Sweden needs to take a big next step in its AI trip.
That is what we at Vinnova consider need to happen.
That is what we are here to discuss.
I think we continue with an introduction of you in the panel.
Can you tell me what you are working on
And how have you been involved in the AI area in recent years?
We start with you, Evelina.
Hello.
-Yes, hello.
It's fun to be here.
I am called Evelina Anttila.
I am CEO of a venture capital company called Wellstreet.
We invest in early tech companies.
Very exciting times now with AI and all the opportunities that bring with it.
Both new opportunities, but also apply to existing portfolio companies.
I have been working with AI for the past eight years soon.
I was involved in building up one of those
First major AI companies in Sweden, Peltarion.
I have been involved since then in questions related to both
Ethical and legal challenges, especially when it comes to AI.
I have a background as a lawyer
So there are also questions for the reason that is close to the heart.
Fun to be here.
Thanks, Evelina.
Then we move on to you, Martin.
You are CEO of AI Sweden.
What is it for something
Yes, I am a managing director at AI Sweden.
AI Sweden is a non -profit program in Sweden, you could say.
A national center to push the application of AI, simply.
We work broadly across sector boundaries in Sweden.
Everything from small private companies to large, public sectors and academia.
And in collaboration try to drive and get forward faster.
Thanks, Martin.
Then we move on to you, Sara.
What do you work with and how have you been involved in the Ai area in recent years?
Hi, my name is Sara Mazur.
It's fun to be here.
I am an executive member of the Knut and Alice Wallenberg Foundation.
I have worked with AI for more than 10 years.
For the past 9 years I have been very active in the Wise program.
First as Deputy Chairman, then as chairman.
Before that, in my previous role as head of research at Ericsson
was AI one of the areas we focused a lot on.
For those of you who are not aware of, Knut and Alice Wallenberg's Foundation
Sweden's largest private research financier.
We fund basic research in Sweden in science, medicine and technology
with over SEK 2 billion each year.
Our largest strategic program is the Wise program:
Wallenberg AI Autonomous Systems and Software Program.
Thank you very much, exciting.
Then we move on to you, Johan.
Are you kind and tell us who you are
Absolutely.
Johan Harvard is my name and I work at Silo AI.
We are perhaps quite unknown to many, but mainly work behind the scenes
with many of Europe's and the Nordic region's largest companies.
What we do is in principle to build uneasy solutions.
We have customers like Ericsson, SKF, Scania, Assa Abloy in the Nordic countries
But also large companies and customers in Europe and North America.
We also have AI training and train language models-
with focus on Nordic language-
Like not the other players has as much focus on.
I have a background from the Government Offices, where I held AI issues for several years-
and something called Combient, which is a collaborative-
Between some of Sweden's largest companies, where AI was of course also central.
Thanks so much, Johan.
Last but not least we have you, Göran.
Are you kind and introduce yourself
Could you be mute: ad
I was mute: ad.
-Let's go.
Thank you, Fredrik.
Fun to be here.
I have worked for quite a few years with AI.
I figured out that it is 39 years now
So I must replace what I lack in quality with quantity.
I have mainly been engaged in being a serial contractor over the years-
And driven various scaleups forward.
I have also been a number of years at the Government Offices.
In recent years I have worked a lot with Martin
Who is here, at AI Sweden as well.
I have been seven years in the United States during the Ai-Revolution that happened in North America-
But has been back in Sweden for just over a year.
At the moment I happen to work in the United States.
Otherwise, I work a lot with advice to larger companies.
I work a lot with lectures and some investigations and such.
That's my background.
Thanks so much.
Good, then we have the panel introduced.
If we take out the picture on today's agenda, it looks like this.
We will start with an external voltage at present from Göran.
Then we get into the panel discussion.
We start at present and then we are moving towards possible initiatives and measures.
Because that's where we want and what we want to talk about.
Then we end the discussion with you who are watching
Can ask a few questions to the panel via slido.com.
The information about slido.com and the number will be available on different occasions
In the box also under the program-
So you don't have to worry about missing it.
Finally we do a rounding where you, Göran
Also do a summary of what you heard during the conversation.
You are of course also included in the panel.
Top, then I think we are running.
Then we start with your world -running and analysis, Göran.
You are welcome.
Thanks, Fredrik.
I will take some time here to begin with.
I will try to be more quiet under the panel and compensate with it.
A little neighbor my view of AI, the big things that happen
in the world and Sweden in this context.
The other day the annual report came from Stanford, including
called AI Index Report.
There is a lot of interest to look at
in terms of comparisons in the world, different countries, and so on.
One thing I thought stands out is that you find out nowadays
that AI significantly increases productivity and quality.
You have enough investigations that confirm it.
This, of course, makes it from a business perspective
So this is with AI extremely interesting.
What you can look at the organizations in the world that have come the furthest with AI
is that they have acquired any kind of platform knowledge-
Which allows them to reuse what they have done with AI in many contexts.
They do not have one, two or three applications
Without significantly more, those who have come the longest.
This has affected in the last at least ten years
the competitive situation in different industries.
It may be that you have competitors who have already gained well on their way with AI.
Perhaps even more interesting is that many customers and suppliers
Sit and thought about:
"What parts of the processes could we crunch
"And raise market shares on, on the basis that we use more AI?"
You also have a certain relationship then with many of the startups that exist within AI.
That is, that too ... [no sound]
... which has its AIEKOSYSTEM and enters into new industries.
When examined this in, for example, North America
generally know ordinary companies that your own industry is-
During strong opening, that it dissolves in different ways.
You do not get the same results in Europe at all, so far, but sit a little more safe.
But of course, the old truths also apply here.
If it goes faster on the outside than the inside
Could it be a rather difficult situation in the future with the development.
Looking at those on the left, the big AI companies-
and on the value, and compare the United States with Europe-
So we have nothing at all in Europe similar to what is in the United States.
These AI companies in the USA-
has come across three trillion dollars in value.
Europe's largest company is then more about
Perfumes, handbags and slimming pills.
There is quite a big difference in the focus, so they are smaller.
One must also have in the background that Europe has a 30 % greater population than in the United States.
So the gap is quite large, and between these two parts also exist
Additional AI companies from the United States, in the form of Meta, Tesla and so on.
Of course, several Chinese will be accommodated before the European companies.
So that which moves the fastest forward in the world within AI
and have done in the last few years-
is North America, southeastern Asia and the United Kingdom.
What do they have in common
Not everyone has everything of this, but most people have the most.
You have a strategic priority.
You are located in Cabinet Office in London, in the White House, and so on.
It is not as common in the EU, that you have that priority.
Above all, there is a strong collaboration with the industry.
When Martin and I were in the White House just a year ago
We asked the question what they thought they were less good at.
The first thing they mentioned was that you see that in the UK and Canada
lets the export industry go ahead and try to take advantage of it-
and in several ways find incentives to take advantage of it-
into the public sector and to small businesses.
Many of these countries work on democratizing AI in different ways.
An exciting initiative in the US right now, I think, is to work with
The whole population's creativity and see, how can we use this?
Both in terms of entrepreneurship, but also to create culture and other things.
I would say that several of the countries have a direct aggressive policy
to attract the competence of various kinds.
You are also involved in building different Aihubbar.
That is, geographical location, around, for example, university campus
where one has some of the large AI companies-
a couple of universities and public sector-
And startups in one place.
Today one expects Canada has
Twice as many AI hubs as you have in the EU.
Canada with a population of 35 million.
There are also plans to train leaders in a very explicit way.
To just take an example of what this results in
In, for example, health and health care, so is North America-
Or Canada and the United States rather, with 5 % of the world's population ...
Today, they account for 58 % of developments in health and healthcare.
The fastest part is Southeast Asia and Australia.
If we quickly skip to Sweden, in the limited time.
How does it look there
As I see it, we have some very strong benefits in Sweden
In this in the future.
We have a tradition of a strong entrepreneurship.
We have internationally a very good leadership.
We are good at transition, not just on the private side
but also on the public.
We have a good digitization in the basics
that is necessary many times to do this.
We have good quality data for a long time.
I wasn't going to immerse so much in the forces
But go a little more into weaknesses.
I think it would be interesting if we could do something about them.
There we have some problems, as I see it.
We have a fairly problematic self -image many times.
I meet many Swedish politicians
And often it is stated that we are probably already the world's best on this with AI about.
Leadership returns, both as a strength and disadvantage.
We are far too quick to delegate this with AI.
We have a problem in Swedish academy, as I see it, with strong division
And for vocational preparation training, not broad enough.
You go either towards stem training, science and technology-
Or on the other hand, the humanities, behavioral science and others ...
Like leadership recurs on both sides
So I see it as digitalisation returning on both sides.
That is, we want to push down AI as part of digitalisation.
To comment on this with the leadership talk parts we have
Do I see quite often in Sweden that we delegate Ai-
To some one in the company management, which in turn starts different projects.
I was recently at a relatively large Swedish authority
that had worked for 2.5 years with Proof of Concept for an AI application-
Which was not really important to them.
Instead of doing like those who work more strategically
that is, make sure that everyone in the lead-
have sufficient knowledge of and understanding of what one does with ai-
What you can and can't do.
Not knowledge about technology and mathematics, but on consequences.
It is really quite natural, if you think about it
That this is where it belongs, because it is really just there-
one has a holistic view and can prioritize-
between all the tens of thousands of possible AI applications available.
This is where you can work with the legal aspects and risk assessment.
However, the companies or organizations often go to the right
In a next step to train all staff, so to speak.
A little bit about this with
How we look at our self -image, and so on.
Today Sweden ranks in the Global AI Index
As most people consider to be the most serious ranking of countries-
In 17th place by about 60 countries that have been ranked.
What stands out negative is that there is a number 44 to the right.
The headline for the one who is not visible here is how strategically you work with it
From Government, so to speak.
Then you can look at the first one here, that's the self -image then
How a proposal came relatively recently to Parliament-
that Sweden should regain this leading role in digitization and AI.
Not only that we will regain a role
I personally think we never had within Ai-
So we should also show the world how AI can be used.
As for our view of AI as part of digitization
so comes this from the responsible minister-
that it is very important that we do not do an AI strategy right now-
but rather a digitization strategy.
This is a relatively Swedish concern, I think.
We miss the business and political opportunities with AI
By pushing it down into something that maybe more often ...
The improvements of the small steps then.
But we have quite great opportunities, as I see it, or very large
to do something about this kind of way.
One is that things have been very fast in recent years in Sweden
within our large export industry.
As everyone knows, the small country has Sweden, at 10.5 million inhabitants
An over -representation of large companies that work with exports.
Here, most of these do not have any single-use applications-
Without a strategic way of working with AI.
There I think we need to find a way
To do as the United States, Canada, UK and so on-
To help small and medium -sized companies, help the public sector increase the pace.
Another thing where we are well located, thanks in large part to Vinnova of course
are our startup-
where we per capita are almost as far ahead as the UK-
And is in par with the best countries in general.
Another possibility I've seen in recent weeks that one has taken
Among other things, within the Swedish regions and municipalities I have worked with.
That is to go in depth and look at the new aistrategia proposal-
As AI Sweden has joined, which Martin will surely develop later.
Then also an advantage ...
If we now come late to the party
Do we have the advantage that we can look at everything we have done in other countries.
All experiences and things that have gone well and less well in other countries.
We have a huge opportunity
If we just start working a little tougher with this than we have done hit the hit
And are not as reclined as we may have been in the last ten years.
To draw a lot of things that our politicians usually tend to
And we others too, I think.
Where we can take advantage of AI.
We can look around only in the Nordic countries and find a lot of good stuff.
But to do this, of course, we need competitive companies
that today has begun to take advantage of Ai-
But maybe even small and medium -sized would have to do it a little more.
So Fredrik, I hope I didn't pull out too much on time.
I leave over to you.
No, we are well located.
Big thanks, Göran, for your valuable analysis.
We have actually been able to get a question from the audience.
We have about 400 viewers right now, so it's fun.
Thomas Deming asks:
How do we avoid trying to compete with the outside world
In the same areas they are investing in?
And number two:
How can we take new creative paths
Where we can use unique Swedish qualities?
It is about strength areas, and so on.
Do you have any spontaneous response to it
The question, as I see it, is that we want to compete in terms of our companies.
We want to be good and compete there.
What I suspect the issue is about is the benefits of welfare for example.
I think we learn way too little today.
Speaking of this self -image I'm talking about
is there a picture that we should learn internally in Sweden-
And then we will bring it out in the world, which I showed on this exercise.
It's pretty common.
I think you could turn this around.
Those who are ahead, so to speak, we learn from.
The word world best and world leader has returned in budget proposals
in terms of digitalisation and AI for many years.
I don't see it negative that you do something good
for the elderly care in Copenhagen, or childcare in Oslo.
It is rather just to go there and learn and take advantage of it.
More international collaborations, I believe.
Some who were very early and good at this were Region Halland
As many feel to-
Who learned almost ten years ago from the best in the world what to do.
More of it, I think.
I forgot the second question, sorry.
Yes, but we may be able to return to the latter.
As for Swedish areas of strength and how we should think there
From a perhaps technical perspective.
Good.
Before we start with the panel discussion I will briefly show a slide
on what Vinnova's investment in AI looked out over the years.
If you can show it slide.
Good.
These bars show the size of the financing decisions
We have taken for AI projects every year.
For example in the last four years we have decided on average
About SEK 700 million per year on AI-related projects.
Göran, do you make any reflection when you see this
Timing, or something else
From my perspective, I think it looks good with timing.
I think Vinnova was relatively early.
We see a lot of results from this, which are interesting.
I do not assess this type of public funding
Or the one that Wasp stands for, the private, as one of Sweden's concerns.
On the contrary, it is rather strength areas then.
Without what I tried to go through earlier, weaknesses were other than this.
I think this is very important
If it can continue in this way and be built up.
Swedish entrepreneurship.
Okay, yes.
We can take it back for a while.
Briefly described, before we move on, it is so that our support of AI
Started with the fact that AI projects were more organically picked up in our broad calls.
About 2017, AI became more and more in focus.
This led to larger specific investments and calls.
In 2018 we contributed, among other things
To start AI Sweden, which Martin represents.
Especially from 2020, we have significantly switched our investments.
We are now working with AI on many fronts.
We run the Innovation Program Advanced Digitization ”
Together with Teknikföretagen and several large Swedish industrial companies.
We have an aiprogram-
A power collection for AI in municipalities and civil society.
We work internationally, and so on.
Of course, it is interesting to understand what is behind the numbers.
To make a long story short, we work both short and long term.
We work with lace, excellence and lace technology.
We work with broad ability.
Partly basic data issues and partly advanced implementation projects.
It is briefly what Vinnova's investment has looked like.
Then we go ahead and enter the panel discussion.
The first part is Swedish current situation, strengths and weaknesses.
The question then becomes ...
If we continue on the theme presented by Göran.
Where does Sweden stand today
What do we have for strengths and weaknesses, according to you
What do you say in the panel about this
I'll start with you, Sara.
Two questions then.
Partly, do you want to add something to Göran's presentation
Then from your perspective, how do you look at this
Yes thank you.
I was going to start with, where is Sweden now within AI
Göran showed this Global AI Index from Tortoise Media
Where we are in place 17.
What we can also see is that there are areas where we are stronger and weaker.
In the case of, for example, research and access to competence
we lie slightly better than 17.
As for what they call operating Environment
we are in place 2, which should be a strength.
It is about Sweden and the Swedish Society's
Ability to absorb new technology.
At Government Strategy we are in place 44
As Göran pointed out, it's not that flattering.
On infrastructure we are in place 21.
I would like to say that we had not had that position today
If it had not been so that we had been so early to invest.
We started the Wise program as early as 2015.
It is Sweden's largest individual research initiative through the ages
with a budget of 6.3 billion-
for basic research within AI, autonomous systems and software.
With the aim of conducting excellent research
and skills build -up within AI, autonomous systems and software
for the benefit of Swedish industry, but also Swedish society.
What we do in the program is partly that we recruit researchers.
We will recruit over 80 new researchers to Sweden
that will establish new research groups.
Today we have 60 of them in place, so we are good on the track.
The program runs until 2032, so it is very long -term.
We have a very large research school, where we educate doctors.
The target is at least 600 graduated doctors.
Today we have about 110120 that have already graduated.
A new doctor will be produced a week.
We have 440 in the research school.
What is extra fun is when we look at
What happened to those who have a PhD from Wasp research school.
Two -thirds of them actually work in Swedish companies.
A little less than a third in the Swedish Academy.
A handful of seven, of the first hundred have left Sweden.
It is very gratifying.
So it gives results.
We see that the research we fund is very highly ranked.
It has been published over 1,550 articles
which has a significantly higher quotation rate than we normally have in Sweden.
It gives the result that we build competence.
But all this is basic research.
It is as Göran points out that it may not be there ...
There we have bet a lot, and it gives rash
But there are other areas where we are not as strong at all.
We lack investments around how we apply AI.
We have AI Sweden, but we would have to do much more.
Specifically also against the public sector
And as Göran mentioned, small and medium -sized companies.
All of these are areas where we would have to do much more.
Thank you so much for that review, Sara.
Then we move on to you, Johan.
How do you look at the Swedish current situation
Maybe from the perspective of Swedish industry and Swedish tech company.
I can really agree with the picture from Göran and Sara.
What I see is a very double and divided image.
It happens both lots at a few
But very little with a long tail company.
Of course, we have worked primarily with research -intensive companies
As at the top, 1-2 % are companies.
Technology company, financial industry, pharmaceuticals, perhaps energy companies
Which has in many ways been forced to apply AI.
Without AI, they do not have a chance in the world market.
So it has really been a necessity for them.
There we see more and more that more people see the light, that they have to start investing.
Export -oriented companies see that:
"If we do not invest in this, we will not be part of the match at all".
They see that they have to race and on.
But it is difficult, because just as Göran is in on
So you miss a lot of this fashion.
You get stuck in the fact that you should very clearly count on investments in advance.
You are not used to experimenting and Pilota.
But AI is not like regular software.
You can't always count home and know what the AI solution will give you-
Before you start experimenting and see what value is in the data.
Then there is a great deal that gets stuck in a position of wait and see
that are a bit scared of the fact that it goes so fast within Ai-
So maybe we should wait a few years and see if the dust has settled then.
But the risk is, of course, that then competitors have run further
And you yourself get stuck there and have a long way to race.
But it is obvious, I think
that Sweden has good conditions today to apply a lot of AI.
Thanks to WASP, among other things, we have strong research and expertise.
More and more talented engineers are examined, etc.
The competence is there, so now it is about application.
Great.
Thanks, Johan.
Then we move on to you, Evelina.
How do you look at the Swedish current forces, weaknesses, and so on.
If you want from an e-commerce and service sector perspective perhaps
As I think Wellstreet is active to invest in as a VC company.
Yes exactly.
I thought that fashion is absolutely at startups.
That is why I believe in a closer cooperation with industry.
We invest in all types of tech companies, sectors and verticals.
It is an incredibly exciting time to be an early investor.
I would say it's not a better time right now ...
There is no better time than right now to jump on the Aitåget.
We notice that in the startup scene.
It pops up Aibolag that mushrooms out there.
It is a large AIHAJP that is going on.
That shark is very related to Genai.
I think it's a bit of a shame that there is so much focus on Genai
When there is much else to focus on.
Not least when it comes to industry.
So I hope that will get some more attention later.
But if you look at what is happening within generative AI now
So from an investor's perspective, it is interesting to look at ...
What to say...
The kind of tech stack that is starting to be built up-
Where you can categorize the different types of AI companies.
I do Aibolag [handgest], because I think that in day-
are all companies tech companies, and as soon as ...
Before we know so much more, everyone will surely be aibolag.
But if you look at the tech stack, we try to understand:
Is this a hardware provider, which is at the bottom?
Or is it in cloud, enabler or model provider
Or a company at the top of the pyramid, which is an Application Provider
That really uses models to solve problems that customers have.
There is, as I said, a lot of courage right now in the startup scene.
The important thing is to consider as a founder::
What is it really for problems we solve
To build successful companies is about solving a problem.
Preferably a big problem that many have, where AI can be part of it.
What I was going to say further is that
Since the cost of intelligence is now almost down to zero-
AI is not really a differentiator, which makes you have a USP.
Many companies now need to think about how to defend themselves.
We talk in the VC world about Moats, moat.
That is, what is it that makes you succeed in the competition
There it is interesting to look at, it is to appropriation data
Is it the customer base or is it something else?
There I think the big companies have a lot to win
Because you already have a lot of resources, processes and capital in place.
So I just believe in this closer collaboration
With brave startups and industries with a lot of potential.
How interesting.
Thanks so much.
Time goes very fast when you have this interesting discussion.
We move on to part two, which we have certainly come into already.
Our needs, opportunities and priorities ahead.
What are we need to grab then
We are a little into it too, so I think the word is free.
Who wants to capture that question first, and perhaps comment on something said
You can raise your hand.
-I can hook in quickly.
Just briefly back to the last question, I totally agree with the speakers here.
A great strength is that we have the tip.
Thanks to all the work you have done, Sara.
It is fun to hear that so many stay in Sweden.
It's a fantastic figure, I would say.
As you say, Johan, we have the companies that have actually come a long way.
And what you were in, Evelina, about the big companies.
There we have companies that sit on a huge amount of proprietary data
Without really getting started.
I think that is a really great opportunity for Sweden
Given the diversified industry we have.
I would say that it is very much about going from lace to width
Where we start making this much wider.
I think, just like Göran, is that the leadership here is an absolute key.
That we get it up in more organizations, and of course preferably from government.
Thanks, Martin.
You have many members, also many from the public sector.
Do you have something you want to share
Just what the situation is there and what the opportunity looks like?
It has happened super very much, but simplified you can say
That AI Sweden's members also reflect what Johan says.
It is above all those who have started early and who go ahead.
Although we may think that we have many members, 130 now, it is ..
For example, we have only less than 1 % of all Swedish companies
With more than 250 employees, it is an extremely small part yet.
It indicates that we need to get involved much more in this issue
and as has been said, invest in application and use it-
In a way that makes it spread across sectors and across the country.
Okay.
May I fill up a bit?
-Yes, I was just going to give the word to you.
I totally agree with Martin, but what I would like to see ...
We have talked about that we are starting to gain skills available and good research.
We are starting to get better at education.
But I still think that when looking at the use of AI
That it is very much so that it is in the form of test systems and demos.
I think we have to get started and start using AI really in production.
In products, services in the real systems
in the companies and the public sector.
There I think it goes too slowly.
We need to increase the pace and get better cooperation.
We need to help our above all small and medium -sized companies
To get started and use AI for real.
Thanks.
Evelina, you wanted to come in.
Yes exactly.
As Sara is in, I think it is very important.
Just like startups are striving to find Product Market Fit
This is how it is AI initiative to also find an AI problem fit.
For all problems, aite technology does not require.
I think it's very important to get these successes
Which makes you dare to invest even more in the long term.
The other thing I was thinking about was jacketing into what Martin said.
I think leadership is A and O.
It must be at the board level, which we previously heard from Göran.
Because these are strategic issues.
These are both short and long -term issues.
It is board issues, simply.
Something I think and wish ...
I do not know if it is the Aic Commission that will come up with that type of encouragement.
I would like all stock exchange boards, or all major boards
Has an AI expert on the board.
I think we in Sweden also have
Very many talented people who have been engaged for a long time with Ai-
which may not necessarily have a classic board background-
But that can add an incredible amount in this respect.
Then I think we could really take some steps forward
If you have that understanding up here.
Thanks.
If we move into the last part, that is, the way forward.
What measures and bets, in addition to those you have already lifted
In different parts of society, you see that Sweden needs to take hold in-
And where there are opportunities?
Johan, how do you look at it
I think it's...
As many of us are in, gratifying that we have such consensus.
It is precisely that the conditions are starting to be good at research and skills.
There are skills shortages.
There I would emphasize that the greatest lack of skills I see
is not about specific skills to build AI models-
without deploying them.
Perform a production in a robust, reliable way.
We have many people with us, but we need many more.
They are hard to find.
In general, I think it would be good to point out a direction for Sweden.
There I would call for the government, that the government could play a role.
Look at France, Canada and others, who have ...
You don't have all the answers here and now, you point out a direction.
"We want this way".
Set up an ambitious goal.
What could Sweden do around, for example, use?
How many who not only use AI
Without also moving on and participates in developing AI solutions.
Something that I see clearly is that you will not be able to be competitive
only by purchasing some AI apps and AI solutions that you use-
For example, to write software code faster.
Everyone will do it.
You can be competitive and get lasting benefits if you look at:
"What kind of unique data and unique processes" do we have "
"How can we build unique world -leading solutions in that particular niche"
So not only use, but also participate and develop.
Dramatize to develop disables.
There is a lot that can be done.
Above all, it is possible to pilot and test on a small scale.
Everyone should test that Pilota's resolutions for their unique problem.
I still think the innovation system, and even politics
Talking too much about conditions.
Now we have them in place.
Now it is about looking forward to application and use.
Thanks, Johan.
Martin, you recently launched an Aistrategia for Sweden.
Why did you do that
It connects very well into this call.
We did this to be able to push properly on many more leaders out there.
Those who have already been on for many years and come a long way
we don't have to be so worried about.
But the incredible amount
Both public and private organizations we have in Sweden ...
We have a very decentralized public sector, for example
Which has not yet started, but began to feel that there is something here.
Then we wanted to give them a guide really, a way of thinking
And a huge call to actually get started with these parts.
Then we believe that even this strategy is applicable as
input even to decision makers in the public-
For how to allocate means and catalyze, you can say-
A faster progress here.
If we look at the public sector, it makes up almost half of our GDP.
A leadership from government with incentive
to develop this in collaboration and share solutions between each other-
Would be a very successful Swedish model.
Thanks.
Göran, it was a little while since you came in.
What would you like to add about our way forward
As for companies, to begin with, I want to supplement what Evelina said.
I see a certain interest in what Evelina mentioned
About having someone on the board who is good at AI.
Unfortunately in Sweden, sometimes someone comes ...
Yes, what should we say professor of technology about.
Someone who comes from a fairly technical point of view.
When I educate boards in other countries you have more interest in all
not all minus one, but all on the board and corporate management-
Have a rudimentary knowledge of what it is about.
I believe, if possible
That Sweden would have to be even more offensive there too.
As for politics, as Martin came into
So I think it's a bit similar.
One is quick to delegate to any single person who specializes
And delegates to official management, and so on.
I don't think it will work so well for Swedish either.
I see how to get away, and have been doing for several years
on summer training, congressmen and senators-
to MIT and Stanford in the United States.
While we in Sweden have a single day in the Riksdag from time to time
Where some come and tell them quite generally about what AI is for something.
You sit a little too much on the stand, as I see it.
Thanks, Göran.
Then we find that we need more leadership
More interest from leadership and a higher level of ambition.
Sara, you are welcome to add what was said here.
Before you do, I have any questions that you can pick up if you want.
For starters, the development is not directly still.
There are things beyond large -scale language models and chatgpt, and so on.
What do we need to keep track of there in our investment
My second question is that AI affects the conditions for research in itself
Thus, general research.
We see how to develop new proteins in furious speed
Thanks to AI models and so on.
Is that something you want to catch up in what I said, Sara
Absolutely.
I start with one thing we need, which may sound a bit boring.
But we actually need infrastructure in Sweden as well.
We have funded infrastructure for research
with the Berzelius computer.
But there is no such for companies, authorities, the public sector to use.
So we also need to invest in infrastructure.
Then if I start with your last question ...
An area I find exciting
Is the role AI plays in pushing research forward.
Now I'm not talking about aiforship-
Without AI as enabler for science, life science and new materials.
There we see that protein wrap is such a thing you started with quite early.
Now you start moving on to the next step.
How can we use AI to actually understand what makes cells get sick
So that we can cure these diseases?
How can we use AI to develop new materials and molecules
Who can help us cope with the challenges we have with sustainability?
My conviction is that if we are to cope with the very challenging goals we have
both in terms of sustainability and health and sustainable development-
Then we must use AI in research.
So it will be incredibly exciting to see how AI will work
in the service of research and as an aid to the researchers.
Thanks.
Then it is a matter of aiformity standing still.
No absolutely not.
It moves lightning fast forward.
It's just trying to invest forward as well.
There is no other option.
Thanks, Sara.
Evelina, do you have something you want to add
We also have a regulation from Europe, AI Act and so on.
Do you have any reflections on it how can we take it as an opportunity?
What is important for the way forward
I think first and foremost that it is important with the visionary leadership
Like everyone here in the panel is in.
I think it's important at all levels.
Not least the discussions that have come up about how it will affect jobs ahead.
Where we notice some concern in the market, and early tendencies to it already
With a strike that went on in Hollywood not so long ago.
There I think you will have to work much more.
And show the opportunities for this, that a new type of job will emerge.
Another type of re and upscaling will be required in society at large.
Then I also think about this with the fact that visionary leadership is about ...
Now many people understand more what AI is about, thanks to chatgpt.
It is important for education in society, which in the end is a matter of democracy.
If we are to be able to do these things forward, it is important that everyone is allowed to keep up.
Right now we have a world where ai-development-
Actually, five companies happen at a certain place in the world.
I think about it partly.
Even when we talk the issue of democracy, we know that half
The population is missing from this revolution.
Most research reports ...
Companies that are started have not had women to the extent that it should be.
No.
The other thing I think based on the visionary leadership is to
This is a social issue, and it is about resilience.
I think you should remember that AI development is very important-
In understanding that we are all part of the total defense even forward.
It is not only the climate issue, but also the geopolitical challenges we face.
I think that all boards, regardless of level, should put AI on the agenda.
You should have a plan for it.
That plan is likely to
Do not look as you think in the beginning, it will need to be revised.
But to think about Aiadoption within the company.
If you have to do that, you shouldn't?
Why?
Advantages and disadvantages?
As part of it, AI Act will be something we will all live with.
The important thing there is to try to use it as a guidance in getting started with AI
Rather than seeing it as being a stop for AI.
For something that is really positive about the regulation
is that we get a clear guidance-
in how to develop and use AI in a sustainable way.
I think we will see that kind of regulations forward in other places.
Thanks so much.
Time, as I said, goes very fast.
You should get the word, Johan.
We simply start with our last words.
Then I will take one at a time, so you are happy to get 3040 seconds to sum up-
What you think is most important for the audience to get Sweden's way forward.
As a short recording to it, Johan, it is so that we find out
That we are entering what you might call an AI revolution.
We are right at the beginning
And sees what great power the large -scale models have.
Then they have barely begun to implement them into the entire community.
So we all understand that it will be a pretty big transformation.
Then we have the next wave of innovation after that.
When it comes now, but maybe not so far away.
It may also be that we as a nation will have to think really big
About what we will be for country in the future in this revolution.
So what can we succeed with and what do you want to send with as last words?
It will be my final summary there.
Johan, well.
I would like to emphasize that the Ai -Revolution is available to everyone.
Very much tools are open sourcade and can be pilota.
More and more skills are trained.
You can borrow an ex -worker from a university.
You can have access to start doing this.
This is not just for Amazon, Microsoft and Openai.
This is for all possible companies in Sweden that can use this.
So take advantage of that opportunity, because it is an opportunity for you
To secure your business, future-proof Swedish job-
by developing and renewing them.
The opportunity is here and now.
Don't wait for it.
Don't wait for an app to solve it, but start working on this.
If anyone from the government listens, I suggest that you can look at ...
Maybe you can screw on the research deduction.
It can be a concrete way.
Can be enabled for research deductions even for AI development-
A little easier than goes now, in companies?
So not only research -heavy companies, but also medium -sized, can use it.
Maybe you can also be inspired by the robot lift
which brought together small and medium -sized manufacturing companies with robot experts.
To be inspired by the road forward.
Good.
Thanks, Johan.
I need to ask for a shorter response from you others.
We move on with you, Evelina.
What are your last words to send by for the road forward
I think it's just the right time to jump on.
It's definitely not too late.
Many people compare this revolution with the Internet.
So it's much like saying in 1996 that you are late in the Internet Revolution.
Time is now, it's just as good to jump on.
Thanks.
Martin
I just fill up.
Let's start and take the first step.
It is very clear that those who understand this best also invest the most.
If we get started, we will create value and take it from there, simply.
Thanks.
Last but not least, Sara, because Göran will make a summation.
Yes.
Our purpose as a foundation is to be rural.
I think AI is a technology that we have to use
To ensure that Sweden is successful in the long term.
It is both about Swedish companies.
It will be a necessity to use AI if one is to be successful.
It is not just about efficiency, but also completely new opportunities.
And also in the public sector, where we see that care is kneeling.
You can't do what is needed with the resources you have.
You have to use new tools, and that is AI.
Just jump on and step on as soon as possible.
And it's not too late.
Thanks.
Good, then we get into audience issues and at least have a question.
It is aimed at all of you.
Sweden's Unicorns has often been applicants and marketers
rather than deep tech.
Is it likely that it will also be Sweden's role in AI
Should we invest more in models and basic techniques
Or product and application to benefit from the development?
Someone who wants to comment
Johan
I can take a first attempt.
We actually build great language models.
On Finnish supercomputers with Finnish state funding and eufinance-
So we are building world -leading Swedish -speaking models now.
It is difficult.
It requires tremendously deep pockets to lead within Deep Tech.
It will probably be difficult for Sweden to do so.
This does not mean that we should not try to understand.
Thanks.
Someone else with a very short comment
Good and interesting question.
I think we don't know the answer.
I think it's important to be humble in ongoing revolution
in the form of not knowing what happens in six months.
The important thing that Johan is in is rather back to the issue of democracy.
If we have large language models that we are very dependent on
So it is problematic.
Sara, did you want to add something
I was just going to say that historically Sweden has been good at deep tech company.
I would not want to exclude that opportunity at all.
I think we should do both parts.
Okay.
Big thanks for your summaries.
We can easily last for another hour, it feels like, and maybe more.
Then I turn to you, Göran.
Would you be able to in a few minutes max sum up the most important things you heard today
And how you look on the road forward?
I thought there were many very important views that came out.
I think it is easy for us to underestimate how important Wasp is.
You need a broader understanding of it in society overall.
I think it would be good if the public could meet up and match a little
The investments that Sara describes from the WASP hold.
Johan had very good views
Around that a lot is happening at a few right now in Sweden-
While he described a long tail by many where not much happens.
I think that is very much about incentives.
The export industry has no choice, they must do this.
What I see happens more in Sweden now is that municipalities and regions lie
quite long before the Swedish authorities because of this particular with att-
75 % will do 125 % jobs ahead in municipalities and regions.
That is, they have no choice either, but must use AI.
Evelina mentioned something important
Namely, there is much other than generative AI.
Generative AI is somehow the top of the iceberg, the visible.
It is a fantastic thing and will add a lot to Sweden
But there is much else too.
Something I stuck to as Evelina mentioned was AI's importance to the total defense.
Martin was in on the fact that
We have to go from the tip we have to a width.
We must explicitly invest in use in different ways.
Possibly my own summary is that we have somehow ...
What would the military say clear sign from Colonel.
We have a clear sign from research, from use within Sweden
Especially outside Sweden, lots of experiences to take off.
It ends up very much on Swedish leaders, to act now.
On my part, this is no criticism of poor leaders who have a lot to do.
But one needs to prioritize this issue quite strongly, I think
From a leadership perspective.
Good.
Thanks, Göran.
We're pulling over a minute.
It goes well, I hope.
Big thanks for all your input in this very important discussion.
We can note that much of Sweden wants to see a completely different level of ambition
Around how we invest and take care of AI.
Vinnova is fully included in that ambition and look forward to that in every way we can
assist in this power collection to invest ahead.
We believe it is incredibly important.
It may be my short summation.
We look forward to a Sweden that decided to invest even more in AI.
Big thanks to the panel and to you who listened
And all the questions that have come in that we have not been able to answer.
We take them with us.
Have a good weekend, what it suffers.
See you.