Hello and welcome to a new vlog.
I am actually on my way from home now
And will go to TC to go to Ljusne and work a weekend with the little bridge.
Tomorrow I know it will be partying.
Johan turned 22.
It is completely sick, so he turned 22 on March 17.
So tomorrow it will be a little minical for Johan.
Then we'll see what it is off.
I've been working all day today.
It has been a packed week and it will be a packed weekend I think.
But I will also take the opportunity to work a little what the computer on the way to Ljusne and be a little time efficient.
See you when I'm there.
I have to hurry to the subway.
Now I have come to Söderhamn.
Mom is here too and will pick me up soon.
The train journey went well.
I sat and worked most of the road.
Then I chilled a little with Youtube and snacks.
This with filming yourself while people check ...
I am very tired.
It is half past nine now and if I feel right I will not be able to film so much tonight.
It's not so much that will happen either.
I know Johan is safe and sleeping.
He will surely be mad at me and not listen to a single thing I say the first few hours.
So I think now it's free Friday night for little me.
See you tomorrow morning.
See ya.
Hello
Good morning.
Saturday.
What time did we woke up today
Four
I feel really good for having a party today.
"Giant Pig".
Yes what is happening now
It's like ...
I have worked all week so the night I have sleep tomorrow I always sleep at least ten hours.
Yes and Johan sleeps like a prince in his new room.
Just what has happened since the last vlog?
We have equipped Johan's bedroom.
So now it is no longer 200 teddy puh he has more
Without now, it is a mix between Nalle Puh and Hockey.
We actually have Örebro's shl shirt hanging on the wall.
Look at that
So we have ...
We will try to get together a complete SHL collection for that wall we thought.
It is great fun because that room has looked the same for 15 years.
Chaos
Was it difficult for him to get used to it took a lot of time?
Yes.
Last time we arranged in his room so we removed maybe 200 Nalle Puh
Then it took three weeks before he thought it was okay.
Now we have removed 100 teddy puh
And now he is also angry.
So he goes in there then he just sleeps but he does not go in there and plays.
Soon he will do that
But he has the most important things he needs.
The paintings he likes, and so he has a card on grandma.
That's what he needs to have.
So God what good it was with tea cookies.
I know
I haven't eaten like that for any length of time.
Thumbs up
So today it is party.
Then you should see.
This is cute because it really is typically Johan.
He cleaned what he thought was important.
The tablet and teddy bear.
Error everywhere here.
We have heard that sound for 20 years it feels like.
Yes.
He gets a new teddy bear every year in Christmas.
Oh I have a sandwich in my hair.
Johan.
Hello
Can you wave
Hello you can wave
To the camera.
Hello you want coffee
Yes.
Should you help pour in milk
Should you help then come.
Should you pour in
Stop.
Good oh how much it was.
But it was good, or how
So bye
What are you going to check out
Want to check out the animals
What do you want to check out
Want to check the dog
Mh.
Do you want that
Look
What are you watching
No you look at the voff
Hello, I'll see Highfive!
Now haha ... I have just given Johan some porridge.
And as you can see here, I have the world's nicest little tiger.
I was going to jump into the shower a little short and then take a walk with Johan.
While they reveal a little at home and fix before the party.
Then Johan will change and then it is Kalastime
Double chin.
See you then when Johan and I go out for a walk I will take some cat therapy for so long.
In addition to meeting Mom, Micke, Sebbe and Johan again, this is how cozy.
No, but the cat
Johan what should we do now
Shall we pull the cord
Ah okay.
Should we wave then goodbye!
Now we go for a walk.
Bye
We are on the walk
Walkix.
Where are we going
We will pull the cord.
Where are we going somewhere then we will press the button.
Where should we go to school yes!
Ajjemen.
There is thus a string or button that you can press to open the door.
And open and close doors is Johan's specialty.
So that he wants to go there so we go there.
There are tractors here and Johan thinks that is very fun.
No but it was locked
Should we try to press the button then
Try to press the button
Push the button.
No it is broken.
Where are we going now then
What are we going to do now
Now we will change.
To some nice clothes.
And then it gets partyed.
Hello come here, we're going to change
Come on now.
Okay, Let's Go.
Now I thought we would end this vlog.
Now that we are in the middle of the party you have had to hang out with a little.
But hello Johan we are not ready.
We must try to finish on something here
I really hope you liked this vlog and that it was nice that I mixed in a little more
My way here and back and what it looks like for me and such.
Johan can you wave
Okay.
Hello, in Guess.
Yes Johan was not so tagged in being involved in finishing this vlog
So I have to do it myself then.
I made a brave attempt anyway.
But I really hope you liked this vlog and that you like to see a little more how it is for me, on your way to and from Ljusne
And what it looks like a little to me.
And then when I'm at home with Johan and such.
See you pretty soon again.
I think I end now and then we will focus up here on Johan and have a little coffee and celebrate a little and such.
Yes, hope that you are fine and we will see you soon.
Bye