I was and greeted a friend who had started plugging here
and had one of my most fun weekends ever,
Which meant that Örebro University actually became my first choice.
I had traveled around a bit in Sweden and looked at a few different universities.
Then I came here to Örebro.
And then I just walked around the premises.
I just got a good feeling.
The important thing for me was that I saw a future.
When I had read the training clearly
So I could work on what I read.
I didn't really know if I would actually take Örebro University.
Then I went up the subway.
Then I saw the ads and then I thought I had to start there.
What I like about Örebro is that it is located ...
Can you say centrally?
It is a very central city in our elongated country.
So it's very close to most people.
I also think this is one of the reasons why you choose Örebro.
Then you do not go home so often.
So, the city, when I looked at Google Maps and so -
After all, it wasn't like this -
It's not a big city, after all,
And at the same time, it is bad though good because everything is so close.
Because it can be bad about ...
Although no, it's not bad.
It is very close to everything.
For example, you can cycle everywhere.
And you are in ten minutes/a quarter,
Actually no matter where you are going.
From home to town it is ten minutes/a quarter.
From home to school it is ten minutes/a quarter.
And from school into town - ten minutes/a quarter.
The teachers are canon.
The teachers are great.
I think the education at Örebro University is very good.
There is a lot of help to be obtained.
Something I like with Campus is to
Most programs are gathered under one roof,
Which makes you get to know other people who plug other things.
The introduction at Örebro University is between three and four weeks.
For example, if one is in the introduction
So it is very easy to make friends and get a socializing.
Still, I thought it was pretty easy to make friends.
People were very likely to become friends, or what to say.
The balance between the activities that one may do during the introduction,
and that you have things almost every day,
makes the introduction at Örebro University
Easy is one of the most fun you can be involved in.
But it's fun!
It's really fun!