Can you treat people with psychopathy?
My name is Henrik Andershed and I am a professor of criminology and
Psychology at Örebro University.
In this section, we will talk about the incredibly important question:
Can we treat and prevent psychopathy?
These are people who do not apply for psychiatry and say:
Hi, I think I have psychopathy.
It is probably that many people with psychopathy do not have a feeling of illness.
The people I have met primarily in the Prison and Probation Service.
And where they have received a psychopathic diagnosis.
Should I guess that 9 out of 10 of the cases are very surprising.
And don't feel at home in that description either.
It says that there are quite often people who fail in insight.
If you fail in insight, you do not think you have the problem.
Then you also do not think that you have the need for treatment.
First, we must probably clarify what we mean when we say:
Can we treat psychopaths?
Do we mean that we should cure them from psychopathy.
Make them feel empathy.
Make them less impulsive.
Make them lie less.
Can we change a 35-year-old person who has done this all his life
To begin to feel empathy?
Is that we mean?
That we should cure psychopathy ourselves?
Or do we mean by treatment that we should
Ensure that people who come in criminal justice and forensic psychiatry
which we find to have psychopathy does not relapse in crime.
Should we work with behavior change?
Ok, you might have psychopathic personality
But we do not want it to have these consequences.
There are two potentially quite different approaches
And focus in treatment.
Cure the disorder itself or perhaps accept
disturbance but work with behavior instead.
To get the person not to commit crimes.
What has been seriously tested in research.
That is if you can reduce relapse in crime.
Among people with psychopathy compared to people who do not have psychopathy.
The answers we get there are: It seems pretty problematic.
For quite a number of years it was said that it is not possible.
The best thing we can do is lock them in.
We hear that quite often in the media that this is how it is.
I would like to say that it is not a correct picture of what we can show in research.
There is absolute reason for cautious optimism that we can do something.
There are studies and you have references down here in the section description
that shows that we can reduce violence and crime
Among these people.
So far, we get in no huge effects.
But it also does not get on criminal non-psychopaths.
I think we can develop methods that can do this pretty well,
What you do in the methods is that you work quite a lot with the risk factors for crime
Among people with psychopathy.
One is not working so much to change the psychopathic core
in the person necessarily.
If you abuse alcohol.
Work on the abuse.
If you have problems in the labor market.
Work on it.
Known risk factors for crime.
Can we reach psychopathic individuals with that type of treatment?
It seems pretty difficult.
You are manipulative, grandiose etc.
You may use the treatment.
We see such examples, absolutely.
We see that it is often excluded from treatment programs because they do not take care of themselves.
I'm not saying it's problematic.
But that it would be impossible we have shown that it is probably not.
If we see that treatment is problematic.
Maybe not impossible.
What about the question then:
Can we prevent psychopathy?
Can we make it not develop?
When we see that something is going on at an early age:
Can we steer it away?
Can we steer it away with good parenting?
Or with other support.
And here is research.
Among other things, research from Örebro University
Who has started to find out this.
We study this and so do many others
Researchers in other countries as well.
We try to find out how early you can measure these personality traits.
And psychopathy's risk factors.
How early in life we can measure it?
And we seem to be able to measure it as early as the age of three.
What we want to do with that research is:
What are the most important risk factors for adult psychopathy?
To be able to identify those children early and help them.
It is definitely not about stamping children and calling them psychopaths.
Without it is about seeing early risk indicators.
Can we then help those children.
For example, it may be that we see in a child that there is a lot of lack in empathy.
And we also see that it can relate to being very aggressive.
Now we have a problem that could be manifested over time
and stables in the individual and develop further into other problematic behaviors.
And maybe actually develops psychopathy.
So then the question will be: Can we work with empathy?
Can we work with empathic ability?
And maybe other psychopathic traits such as impulsivity.
In early age.
Can we do it in preschool age?
And there are studies that indicate that we can probably do it.
It seems we can work with perspective -taking
And other things that have to do with empathic ability.
It seems that we can work on this to inhibit.
When you get very angry.
That it does not fall into a act of violence.
That you can learn to inhibit and control yourself.
And it is promising to prevent psychopathy.
That research is in its infancy and there are a number of studies that are promising.
But to have entire pre -built and preventive programs for this.
We're not there yet.
What to do if you think your child has this kind of
Personality traits and problems?
The first is that it is not about this.
We have talked about that before.
There may be other similar problems that look like these features.
It may also be that you have individuals of these features.
That is, you may be very impulsive or shortcomings in empathy.
Thus, individual psychopathy -like features.
It is not psychopathy.
Then the individual features can be problematic.
If they are related to physical aggressiveness.
Or other threateningness.
Or whatever it may be,
I still think the advice should be if you worry so much
If you see that it can lead to problems for the child.
And maybe it already does.
Then I think you can seek help.
You can start by seeking help in child and adolescent psychiatry.
So they can certainly help you further.
Thank you for being with us today.
Like if you think what we do is good.
Feel free to comment and do not forget to subscribe, of course.
This is the series about crime.
Where we seriously talk about crime.
It is important that we give nuanced images of crime.
Instead of what happens in your information flows every day.