Hello everyone!
Hello!
We are home.
We are back from our trip.
Look!
There is also snow here.
Not so much with anyway!
It's cold.
It is winter.
I want to tell you about our trip home.
I want to tell you how we went home from Kl채ppen.
From my home to Kl채ppen it is about 400 kilometers.
It takes 6 hours to go if you count on a break.
In order to stretch the legs
Food break
6 hours took the trip there, from home to Kl채ppen.
From Kl채ppen home, the trip took about 8 hours.
Why?
Why did it take so long?
One thing happened on the way home in Mora.
Look!
You know what?
We have been punctured!
We are not at home.
We are in Mora.
That's quite a few kilometers home.
We have called service.
You can google a phone number.
They should come here with a wheel, a tire.
They should change and help us.
It will cost a lot of money.
I don't know how much.
We park the car.
From Mora to my home it is about 300 kilometers.
4 hours to go
We got puncture 300 km from home.
Everyone was tired.
The children were tired.
We were tired.
But it resolved.
I have a receipt here.
Here's the receipt.
We can look at it together.
There is a phone number.
There is a date.
Time is there too.
How much did we pay?
We paid...
one tire
mounting of the tire
on -call fee
It costs a little more on Sundays.
Thanks for the visit and welcome again!
It was so kind that we got this help on a Sunday afternoon.
We could come home the same day.
We had no extra tire but now we have learned.
Now we will always have an extra tire in the car.
I'm out for a walk.
Now I'm starting to freeze.
I'm going home now.
Thank you so much for looking!
See you in the next video.
Bye!