Hello!
How is it?
That's good, thank you!
How are you?
It's just good, thank you!
Where are you going?
I'll go to a clothing store.
I'm going to buy a sweater.
I need a new sweater.
Do you want to come?
Gladly!
Come then!
A child cries.
Need help?
No thanks!
I am just looking.
I walk around the store and look at all the clothes.
It was good looking!
What do you think about this?
Very hot!
I take and try.
I take some sizes.
We'll see which one fits.
Where is the fitting room?
The test room is located over there!
Where?
OK, then we go there.
a fitting room
I try this size first.
What is the size?
It is size L.
Does it fit?
No, it doesn't fit well.
Why?
It's too big, look!
I try another size.
I try size S.
Does it fit?
No, it doesn't fit well.
Why?
It's too small!
I try a pineapple size.
I'll try size M.
Does it fit?
Yes it fits well.
Look!
Is not it nice?
It looks great!
I take it!
It's the right size!
It's really pretty!
I take it!
How much does it cost?
It costs SEK 299
And that's a discount!
So it costs ....
Great price!
I take it!
Are you happy now?
Yes, I'm really happy!
Now I have a new nice sweater.