Hello everyone!
Hello!
Today I want to tell you about my workplace, about my job.
a workplace - my workplace
This is my workplace, my school.
I work at Komvux.
What does Komvux mean?
Komvux means municipal adult education.
Education for adults.
What does adults mean?
Komvux corresponds to elementary school and upper secondary school.
Komvux is a school for adults who lack knowledge corresponding to elementary school and upper secondary school.
At Komvux you can study Swedish.
You can study SFI (Swedish for immigrants)
When you are done with SFI, you can continue to study at SVA Basic.
SVA = Swedish as a second language
You learn to read and write from the beginning of SFI course A.
I teach in Swedish at SFI course C and SVA Grund sub -course 3 and 4.
Previously, I worked with SFI course A.
Right now, all students are studying at home, online, because of Covid-19.
They study digitally with a mobile phone or computer.
The school is located at a fire station.
Look what firefighters do - they go sledding!
I enjoy my job very well.
I love my job!
It is visible, right?
Do you study Swedish in school or online?
Write in comments!
Look what nice snowmen we have!
A snowman - two snowmen
We also have a nice tree for birds.
They became afraid of me and flew away.
Otherwise, there are usually many small birds here.
Thanks for watching this video!
See you in the next movie!