Hello everyone!
Hello!
Today we will go to a grocery store.
We will look at the Christmas theme in the grocery store.
Come along!
A red flower
A poinsettia
There are many flowers.
There are red flowers and white flowers.
Lots of clementines
Lots of gingerbread
There are different gingerbread figures.
It's gingerbread house.
Gingerbread costs SEK 24.90.
a heart
Look what a good thing!
A nice heart
Merry Christmas!
cheese
cream cheese
Lots of soft cheese with different flavors.
There are many different flavors.
I enjoy eating gingerbread with blue cheese.
Buns with saffron
saffron buns
lice cats
Gingerbread balls
gingerbread house
You can build yourself at home.
You can decorate.
There are also Christmas eggs.
Christmas cracker (crispbread)
Christmas wort (Christmas bread)
You can order the package.
Saffron cake with genuine saffron.
Boiled Christmas ham
herring
There is a lot of herring you buy for Christmas.
Herring in different marinades, such as mustard.
There are many jars.
different flavors, cancer marinated
mustard sill,
Santa Claus - Christmas
File - gingerbread
Gingerbread file
file with taste of gingerbread
And so it is very mulled wine.
mulled wine without sugar, with chocolate and chili
cloudberry
different flavors
mulled wine mix
Here it is cranberries and almonds, you can also have raisins.
Christmas must of course!
In Sweden you drink a lot of Christmas must.
Christmas stars - Christmas chips
Christmas napkins
Ell candlestick
Lots of sweets, lots of chocolate
Gift paper
Christmas card
chocolate
Chocolate plots
Christmas foam
It's candy for Christmas.
My kids love it!
Thank you so much for watching this video.
See you soon!
Bye!