Imagine a little guy whose daily walks were so punctual that you can set the clock after them.
Immanuel Kant was a German philosopher from Königsberg, a city Germany losing to the Soviet Union
After World War II and then renamed Kaliningrad.
Immanuel Kant was to the exterior a very unassuming man,
But philosophically, he undoubtedly belongs to the greatest.
He is for philosophy what Newton is for physics or Darwin for biology -
Creator of a theory that all descendants must relate to, whether he agreed with him or not.
Kant himself meant that his philosophy was a "Copernican revolution" -
comparable to what Nicolaus Copernicus achieved in astronomy during the 16th century
By assuming that the sun, not the earth, was the center of the universe.
So far, Kant meant, assumed that our knowledge must adhere to the objects.
But that is not the case.
It is the objects that adhere to our knowledge ability.
In this section, we will take a closer look at Kant's theory of knowledge.
His view of ethics (Kant was duty ethicist and formulated, among other things, the categorical imperative)
Treated under Chapter 3: Ethics and Morality.
So what is the theory of knowledge?
Knowledge theory, or epistemology (from the Greek episteme, "knowledge"), is the doctrine of knowledge.
Here you examine boundaries and conditions for knowledge and ask questions such as
"How do we get knowledge" or "How do we know that knowledge is true"?
Already Plato devoted himself to these issues and he defined knowledge as "true justified faith"
Based on the view that knowledge is that person A knows X about and only about:
X is true.
A is convinced that X is true.
A has good reasons for believing that X is true.
Thus, there are historically three necessary requirements for knowledge.
By definition, this means that there is no incorrect knowledge, only knowledge or error.
Traditionally, knowledge theorists are divided into two camps;
Empirists and rationalists.
According to empiricism, all knowledge is founded in sensation experience,
A reasoning that can be traced back to Aristotle.
Empiri is based on scientific studies of reality, observations and experiments,
rather than on pre -set theories or philosophical reasoning.
A rationalist, on the other hand, claims that knowledge of the world originates from reason, thinking and congenital ideas
(Although sensory experience may of course be involved).
It is believed that the sensations are too unreliable to constitute knowledge,
A reasoning that is well exemplified by René Descartes and his systematic doubt.
What Kant is trying to find is the limit of human knowledge.
His reasoning can be seen as an attempt to preserve the best out both empirism and rationalism,
While taking into account the criticism they directed at each other.
This is a theory of knowledge often called critical or transcendental idealism.
According to Kant, one must distinguish between two kinds of knowledge: experience knowledge and reasonable knowledge.
Experience knowledge (or empirical knowledge) is something whose truth
We cannot know without reference to experience.
An example of this is that Paris is the capital of France.
We know this from experience - we have learned it by using our minds
For example, we have read it in a book or heard it from our parents.
This type of knowledge calls Kant "a posteriori", which means after experience.
He calls the second type of knowledge "a priori", before experience.
This is knowledge we have without reference to the experience - for example, 5+7 = 12.
In mathematics, for example, we use reason to determine what is true.
But how can such knowledge be possible?
Kant replies that Knowledge A Priori is not based on the world that surrounds us,
Without how our consciousness is organized and works.
Here, Kant also points to the limitation of knowledge.
He initiates the book "Criticism of Pure Reason" (1781) by claiming
“That all our knowledge begins with the experience, there is no doubt at all [...]
But even if all our knowledge begins with the experience, it does not arise from the experience. "
Everything we perceive - whether it is mind impressions, feelings, thoughts or memories -
We perceive through our body's knowledge organ;
Our five senses, our brain and our central nervous system.
Everything that these organs can sense can therefore be experienced,
While eventualities they cannot deal with can never be perceived by us.
Our knowledge of the world is thus limited by what our senses, brain and nervous system can handle.
Thus, on the one hand, there is what exists regardless of us and our perception
(the objective reality)
And on the other hand, what we have the opportunity to perceive (the human interpretation of reality).
There is no reason to believe that these two types of existence are the same.
There is almost certainly much less of the latter than the former.
In addition, there is a "filter" between each human and the objective outer world.
Which allows us to only interpret reality - never really experience it.
This filter can be likened to a pair of colored glasses for reason.
In the same way as a pair of blue -colored glasses, reality is perceived as blue -tinted,
perceives reason reality as spatial, timely and causal (causal)
- Something edge calls views.
We cannot possibly have experiences decoupled from the views.
This, like a priori knowledge, which also forces our impressions in order to understand them for us.
Time and space are like our experience of colors - they are not in reality, they are only mental constructions.
Kant himself expresses this as “thoughts without content are empty;
Observations without concepts are blind ”.
Edge thus distinguishes between the thing itself that exists in reality as it is
Regardless of our interpretation of the (by Kanten named Noumenon), and the thing for me
- The human interpretation / filtration / experience of a thing (by Kant named the phenomenon world).
Of these, only the phenomenon world we can have knowledge or experience about.
What is beyond our experience of the world we have no opportunity to know.
This means, according to Kant, that we will never be able to reach knowledge of, for example
God's existence or free will.
Kant himself expressed this as that he excluded the knowledge to leave room for faith.
Kant's theory of knowledge has been of great importance to philosophy when he was thrown out
All so -called "evidence" for (or against) for example God's existence.
Since Kantt's time, among philosophers has been virtually generally accepted that certain issues
is beyond what man can theoretically have knowledge of.
Kantts thus describes how both the natural sciences (phenomena world) as well as metaphysical
Issues and religion (Noumenon) can coexist without any mutual contradiction.
He also shows that there is a clearly defined boundary between knowledge and faith.