Hello philosophers, my name is Joakim and welcome to this first of two videos where we examine
Friedrich Nietzsche's philosophical ideas.
We will investigate his view of morality, nihilism, suffering, truth, superhuman,
Amor Fati and eternal repetition.
Nietzsche, maybe more than any other philosopher, is open to interpretation.
With statements like "what doesn't kill me makes me stronger", "God is dead!
And we have killed him! "
And "the world is beautiful but man is a disease" is his philosophy both tickling and provocative.
That is probably why more than 20,000 different books have been published about him and his writings.
He was born in 1844 in a small village in the eastern part of Germany where his father was a priest.
He was considered a wonderful child and became a professor at the University of Basel at the age of 24.
However, his career was not successful.
He got tired of his colleagues, gave up his job and moved to the Swiss Alps
Where he lived alone and wrote on his books.
He was sickly, opium dependent and disliked his family:
"I don't like my mother and it's painful to hear as much as hearing my sister's voice".
Women rejected him and his books did not sell.
Only 44 years old, he had a mental breakdown when he saw a horse being whipped by the cousin.
He ran to embrace the horse screaming "I understand you!".
He never recovered, sank deep into madness and spent the remainder of his life at a mental hospital.
Furthermore, he was vegetarian, abstinent in terms of coffee and alcohol, and had a crazy big mustache.
He was strongly influenced by Schopenhauer's thoughts that the world we perceive is our own performance,
Thus, a purely subjective experience.
Although he came to deviations from his philosophy, his perception of his life remained
Related to Schopenhauer's pessimism.
For Nietzsche, philosophy was not only abstract theories, but had a practical purpose.
The philosophy was intended to facilitate the emergence of a new and better type of man who devoted his life to development,
self -realization and life -affirming - a man who was not held back by moral views
Like right and wrong, a man who affirmed the animal in itself.
Nietzsche saw himself as a guide for such a person.
“Only these are my readers, my rightful readers, my predetermined readers.
What does the rest matter?
The rest is just people. "
Central to Nietzsche's philosophy is the concept of "the will to power"
which should be seen as a response to Schopenhauer's "the will to live".
Where Schopenhauer believes that everything in the universe is an expression of the will to live, Nietzsche said that
The main driving force is not life but power - "an inexhaustible, generating vitality".
According to him, the operation is to expand his power stronger than the operation to adapt and survive.
This will to power is wherever there is life, and even the strongest of creatures
will risk their lives in their quest for even more power.
Unlike Schopenhauer, however, Nietzsche does not see the will as a negative force
Without something to affirm even if it can sometimes be destructive.
While Schopenhauer sees the pity as a positive resort,
It seems to Nietzsche as a life -inhibiting factor.
This should therefore be interpreted as a psychological explanation for human behavior and an explanation for why we devote
We ate risks in life, such as warfare and competition.
It is the power of power that spurs man to everything she takes on: progress, ambitions, self -realization,
Personal maturity, the desire to reach the highest possible position in life - everything is products of the will to power.
Nietzsche's exemplifies with the ancient Greek heroes and aristocrats that not mainly
Searched a long life, without a life of power, honor and greatness.
Here we also expect what came to be Nietzsche's big struggle - a questioning of the traditional morality.
If now the will to power is what drives life, how come it is often considered morally wrong
Or ugly to stand for that opinion?
Nietzsche agreed with Schopenhauer that there is no God or any immortal soul.
They also agreed that life is a meaningless story characterized by suffering
And guided by an irrational force that can be called the will.
However, he rejected Schopenhauer's conclusion that we should feel disgust for this world.
On the contrary, he meant that we should live our lives so that we get as much out of them.
A large part of Nietzsche's philosophy is about just this
- How to live a rich life in a meaningless and godless world.
Nietzsche had extreme things to say about Christianity.
"Throughout the New Testament, there is only one person worth respecting: Pilate, the Roman governor".
According to the Bible, Pontius Pilate was the person who decided to crucify Jesus.
Christianity, in Nietzsche's interpretation, had arisen from Roman slaves who had lacked the power to achieve
What they really wanted and instead created a philosophy that made virtue of their cowardice.
Christians, whom he called "Die Herde" - the flock, also wanted to enjoy life (intellectual challenges,
Creativity, six mm) but were too incapable to achieve a high level of pleasure and satisfaction.
Therefore, they joined a hypocritical faith where they condemned what they wanted but were too weak
To achieve - and paid tribute to what they happened to have, but did not demand.
In the Christian value system, sexual inability became purity.
Weakness became goodness.
Apathy became patience,
And inability to revenge was forgiveness.
According to Nietzsche, Christianity was a gigantic machine of bitter denial.
"After coming into contact with a religious man, I always feel that I have to wash my hands."
Nietzsche meant that what made it possible for us humans to leave the animal stage
and developing a civilization was that the weak incessantly was eliminated by the strong,
The inept of the capable ones, the stupid of the intelligent.
Thanks to these processes repeated through the millennia
The man developed into the creature she is today.
But about 2000 years ago, something unfortunate happened.
The moralists, with Socrates and Jesus at the forefront, then came and said that this development process was wrong.
They claimed that there should be laws that protect the weak against the strong ones.
They meant that justice would go before strength, that the earth would belong to the lazy, not the entrepreneurs.
“Independent thinking and powerful intellect is considered dangerous;
Everything that lifts an individual over the mass scares, and is henceforth referred to as evil. "
In every human being there is an instinct Nietzsche calls flock behavior,
A need to adapt to the masses.
Often this comes as an expression in adapting your morals, ie what you think is right and wrong in society.
"Morality is the best of all devices for leading humanity in ruin"
Nietzsche proclaimed in the book "Antichrist".
Such a morality, which was accepted by the masses, called Nietzsche for slave morality.
He meant that this morality served a clear purpose
- Giving mediocre individuals the conviction that their weakness is not an error, but a strength.
"I've often laughed at these wavers who thought they were good just because they were missing chlorine,"
Nietzsche wrote in "So Zarathustra".
In this way, slave morality claims that properties it itself lack are evil.
Through the slave morality, they gain weak respect.
Sheep-like qualities are hailed as good, and individuals are thus pressed to become weak and obedient.
Therefore, we must, Nietzsche, flee the shackles of the slave morality and in its place create a new one,
Independent and life -affirming morals - the male.
We have to fight the slave moral as the disease it is, but in order to succeed in this one must first
Physically separated from the shock and live a life in loneliness.
Nietzsche meant that weak people structure their lives so they never have to reflect
around the difficult questions of existence.
But in order to achieve greatness in life, we must ponder the issues for which the shock is scared or too weak.
And for this we need our loneliness.
“Because he now has to penetrate into the depths of existence with curious questions on his lips: Why do I live?
What lessons has life taught me?
How do I become what I am and why do I suffer from being who I am? ”