Sartre ...
Sartre!
Sartre?
I'll say "Sartre".
My name is Joakim, welcome to this lesson on Jean-Paul Sartre-one of the greatest philosophers of the 20th century.
Anxiety is an unpleasant feeling why we subconsciously try to deny our freedom.
If we are so free we must choose, and then we will also be responsible for our lives.
Since we also show the way for our fellow human beings, the choices become difficult and anxious.
With our choices and actions we don't just create ourselves
Without also a picture of how we want man to be.
“In fact, it's not a single one of our actions that are not, at the same time it creates it
Man we want to be, also creates a picture of man as we believe she should be.
Choosing to be that or it means at the same time that you affirm the value of what you choose,
For you never choose anything bad.
What you choose is always good, and nothing can be good for yourself without being for everyone. "
Our attempts to deny our freedom are in fact attempts to escape the anxiety that comes with the elections.
But anxiety is something positive, says Sartre.
It shows that we are free and have choices.
In short, trying to escape their anxiety means denying their choices.
We have a responsibility that is total,
We can never renounce it by blaming, for example, cowardice, says Sartre.
Then we choose to be cowardly.
As is well known, we choose our essence through our choices - and thus also the cowardice.
The anxiety arises as we can never fully review the consequences of our choices.
It is an anxiety for the future, for what nothing should be filled with.
This is an anxiety we can never escape as it is inextricably linked to being human.
But the anxiety is something essentially positive as it shows that we have a free will.
This view of the foundation of anxiety differs from, for example, psychologist Sigmund Freud who considered
That it had to do with the past, with traumatic childhood experiences.
Because our freedom is intimately associated with anxiety
We often try to flee our freedom and the responsibility it brings with it.
We believe that things must be in a special way and close your eyes to the alternatives.
We then say no to ourselves instead of to our situation.
This calls Sartre "bad faith".
We believe that we are subject to our life conditions.
We think we are cowardly, we think we need to follow traditions or cultural norms.
We do not realize that we choose to be cowardly, that we blame circumstances.
This belief does not disconnect us from responsibility, even if we think it does.
We are always responsible for our actions and choices, even when we choose not to choose, not to use our freedom.
Man is by its nature, but our fear of freedom makes us flee into bad faith.
We see ourselves as victims of the circumstances or as tiles in a game.
Sartre sees it as its most important task to wake us up from this evil faith.
He sees three ways to deny his freedom through bad faith:
Make a thing, go up in a role and become a dozen people.
When you make a thing you do not understand that you cannot influence your situation, so it makes yourself a thing.
You can be taken like a doll or led like a dog.
You blame your childhood or on your intoxication - as if you were mechanical.
You let things happen and blame on weakness or inability.
One imagines that circumstances govern, that society, upbringing or the biological heritage
Has characterized and shaped one's life - that you are your fate.
Another way to deny one's freedom is by going up in a role,
to tell yourself that one is predetermined for someone else's purpose.
This role is determined by others - by the family, by the authorities or by God.
You not just play a role, you are the role.
The clearer the role is designed, the better the hiding place it becomes.
If you have uniform on, an order becomes a law.
The soldier who goes out to war and blindly obeys every order has resigned the possibilities of freedom
and identifies with their role.
The reason why German soldiers could participate in the Nazi mass murder was just that, says Sartre.
Hidden in their roles they took no personal responsibility, they said no to themselves.
The responsibility was always somewhere else, not with them.
The big problem with this is that the role exists before playing it.
If you want to play a play, roles and replicas are already predetermined.
In the same way, it is with the roles we voluntarily take on everyday life.
Each role limits our freedom.
A third way to protect against anxiety is to live as a dozen man
- A reasoning that Sartre has taken over from Søren Kierkegaard.
One lives unengaged, listening to the music, they see movies, visit the places
and performs the actions that "everyone else" does.
This just to have listened, seen and visited everything you should have done.
We try to free ourselves from the elections by becoming just like everyone else.
We humans thus strive to rationalize our choices and freedom.
We are looking for answers and guidelines that do not exist, says Sartre.
Nothing wrong with being "average" but the risk is that you end up in a superficial life full of illegitimate acts.
We humans need to be seen, from the eyes of the environment and assessments.
That is why we strive to appear happy and successful for the surroundings.
But what really happens when we are caught with something embarrassing,
When we lose the mask and start to be ashamed?
Being caught, being seen means being transformed from subject to object.
We become the subject of other people's values and are assessed.
At that moment we stop for a moment to exist as a human being and become a thing in the eyes of others.
This, says Sartre, is the other's look - the rightful judge of who you actually are.
We ourselves mix ourselves with the one we believe or wish to be.
When you are seen by others, you suddenly get a view of yourself and the action you have performed.
You are ashamed.
For ourselves, we can only be a subject, a self.
If we want to know who we are, we must first become an object, a thing.
Only in relation to others we know what our performance is worth.
Concepts such as beauty, talent and talent become completely meaningless without a yardstick,
Without a relationship with the fellow human beings.
You need the other to understand yourself, says Sartre,
And adds that "one cannot possibly be vulgar in solitude".
“I've just made a ridiculous or vulgar gesture.
This gesture hooks up to me, I neither condemns nor judge it.
I simply live it.
But now I suddenly raise my head.
Someone was there and saw me.
Suddenly I realize how vulgar my gesture was and I'm ashamed ... ”
The other is thus needed to understand himself, but the other is also a constant source of discomfort.
Our lives largely consist of trying to realize our dreams.
But the job you are looking for also wants someone else for.
The other has plans, he tries to organize his surroundings and control it.
The risk is great for collisions and conflicts as our projects collide with each other.
You try to control the other but the same does the other with you.
We try to see through each other, valuing each other, putting labels on each other
- We objectify other people, see them as if they were things that could be predicted.
Similarly, the surroundings objectify you, even though you are not reducing to something predictable.
How, then, can positive relationships between people be possible
In a life where we constantly reduce each other to things?
In his philosophy of love, Sartre examined the possibilities and conditions of love and judged them as problematic.
Love presupposes two free conscious individuals
At the same time as both parties have a need to control and own.
We demand promises of the one we love;
You have to be faithful, you have to come back, you must always love me!
We try to enslave the one we love.
At the same time, we are annoyed by these promises when we are exposed to them ourselves.
On the one hand, we want to own the other's freedom, on the other hand being voluntarily loved.
What then does it serve to try to force someone to love one?
Thus, love must be both bound and free, a voluntary captivity.
Maybe you can shorten the moment to see the other as an object.
Maybe we feel for a while not superfluous but on the whole
Staying love "a hopelessness" says Sartre.
He therefore highlights the free relationship as the best possible solution,
Something he practiced with his life companion and colleague Simone de Beauvoir.
According to Sartre, money was a big and contributing factor to why people did not feel free.
The unfair distribution of money and the misery it contributed to, annoyed him.
He saw capitalism as an inhibitory factor in people's lives
And something that makes us believe that we have to live in a special way.
Sartre was a dedicated communist and strived to release the individual from materialistic life.
Capitalism limited people's freedom and was therefore something that would actively be fought.
He visited Fidel Castro and Che Guevara in Cuba, the latter mentioned by Sartre as
"Not only intellectual, but also the most complete person in our time".
During the 1960s, he supported, along with the Beauvoir, the student occupation in Paris
and was repeatedly arrested by the police.
However, he was pardoned by France's President Charles de Gaulle with the words "man arrests Voltaire".
Voltaire was a 18th-century, philosopher and debater
which was forced to flee to England because he has made himself uncomfortable in France.
Sartre came to be a powerful opponent of the Vietnam War and started together
With, among other things, the British philosopher Bertrand Russell "International War Crimes Tribunal"
to highlight the US war crime.
Furthermore, he was deeply involved in the Palestinians' struggle against Israel.
Towards the end of his life, he abandoned communism, largely in protest against the development of the Soviet Union,
And then anarchist titled himself.
Sartre's thoughts have come to have great impact for many people seeking meaning to life
But who are not willing to turn to religion.
He succeeded with the piece of art to maintain purpose in a world without inherent meaning
by focusing on the subjective at the expense of the objective.
When Sartre died in April 1980, 50,000 people gathered on Paris streets to witness the funeral train
And pay tribute to the great thinker.