Hello philosophers, and welcome to this moment of existentialism.
Existentialism, or philosophy of existence, is a philosophical movement born during the 19th century
With thinkers like Søren Kierkegaard, Friedrich Nietzsche and Fjodor Dostoevsky.
But it was only after World War II that existentialism got its real breakthrough
With Jean-Paul Sartre and writer like Franz Kafka and Albert Camus.
What is it that links these philosophers and writers?
Well, they all tried to describe the human existence and questions such as:
"What does it mean to be human?"
"What is the meaning of life?"
"How should I live my life?"
Different existentialists have had different answers to these questions,
But they share the view that the answer is subjective rather than objectively.
An existentialist therefore usually takes away from all all -inclusive theories (ie theories that apply to all)
who try to explain the meaning of life, whether they are religious, scientific or philosophical.
Existentialism is thus a relativistic philosophy.
It is easy to see the attraction in religions that claim to have the answers to the existential questions.
As many as 84 percent of the earth's population are also believers
(In Sweden, which is the world's most secularized country, the corresponding figure is 35 percent).
To ponder the meaning of life without the support of religious or philosophical theory is undoubtedly difficult,
But that is what existentialists mean we have to do.
Many existentialists even mean that religion is harmful to individual development
to a free and authentic person who takes responsibility for his or her actions.
The problem with these all -inclusive theories is that they do not take adequate consideration
To what it means to be human.
They assume that meaning and purpose originates from an alternative and objective sphere
such as heaven or Plato's world of ideas.
Many of the traditional religions also answer the philosophical questions
From the perspective of an omniscient God, forwarded to us through prophets.
An existentialist believes that what we need is not a divine perspective, but a human such.
Or as Nietzsche put it, after all, we are "human, too human".
Another problem with the divine perspective is that it misses a fundamental aspect
of human existence - our mortality.
Most religions deny life's perishability through the belief in some form of aftermath.
Existentialists have pointed to the insight about our death
As a way to stop following others and create one's own meaning with life.
The idea that the meaning of life is individual is closely related to another existentialist idea
- That for man comes the existence before the essence.
To understand this central statement about human life, we must first understand the term "essence".
The term was coined by the Greek philosopher Aristotle.
He felt that every subject or thing has an essence - something sometimes called its nature.
These are properties or characteristics that are necessary for the thing to be what it is.
Aristotle said that human essence was reason - we are the sensible animal.
But unlike other animals, man also has the opportunity to choose
Whether she wants to act accordingly or not.
However, he did not think that the individual could affect his essence as this was innate.
Neither for those who believe that God has designed and created the world is the essence something impactable.
The essence of the individual is something in advance of God, which is why the essence precedes existence.
The same can be said of many science theories.
One claims that the meaning of life can be traced to biology, or that a person's actions are a consequence
From the individual's genetic heritage, it is also believed that the essence precedes existence.
According to the foreground figure of existentialism, Jean-Paul Sartre, human existence is unique.
We are not, like the thing that surrounds us, created with a predetermined purpose.
A clock's essence is to show time.
It is thus created for a specific purpose, which is why its essence precedes its existence.
Man, on the other hand, is born without purpose and our ability to free choices
Gives us the opportunity to create our essence through life.
There is no pre -given human nature or any objective purpose with our existence,
Without it, it is up to everyone to create meaning themselves with their lives.
For man, existence comes before the essence.
Sartre, who was atheist, meant that since there is no god
So there are no predetermined values either - no fact for right and wrong or good and evil.
He even went so far that he claimed that man is "doomed to freedom",
That is, we not only can but actually have to take a stand and create our lives ourselves.
In this chapter we will take a closer look at Søren Kierkegaard, Friedrich Nietzsche,
Jean-Paul Sartre and Simone de Beauvoir.