The only one of the ancient philosophers whose importance can be compared to Plato's disciple is Aristotle.
He was the scientist whose theories were dominant for more than 2000 years.
If you can say that Plato can say that subsequent philosophy history was only footnotes to this one,
Can we call Aristotle for the father of science.
He was born in the city of Stagira in northern Greece.
As a 17-year-old, he traveled to Athens to study philosophy at Plato's academy.
There he came to stay for 20 years - first as a student to Plato, then as a acclaimed teacher and researcher.
After Plato's death, he came to leave the academy to start his own school - lyceum -
which over time came to be a much larger and wider than its predecessor.
In their early writings you see a clear admiration for Plato's thoughts,
But since then he will deviate more and more from his teachings.
His theories eventually came to collide with Plato's perceptions
and constitute an alternative explanation model of the world.
Where Plato's worldview is based on the abstract world of ideas,
describes Aristotle world without referring to other levels of reality.
You could say that he moved Plato's ideas to the world of mind.
We see this clearly in Rafael's famous mural "The school in Athens" from the beginning of the 16th century.
In this painting, found in the Vatican Palace in Rome,
Rafael has collected many of the great Greek philosophers.
In the middle we see Plato, pointing up at the abstract world of ideas.
He is an idealist and believes that everything is basically ideas, and in order to understand the truth we must first understand the ideas.
At his side, his student, Aristotle, goes,
As with his hand clearly shows that he stays on earth - he is a realist.
He believes that the world we live in is the only true world.
Aristotle said that everything in the world consists of matter and form.
Matter is the physical structure of the thing (eg wood or iron) while the shape is its individual structure.
These two ingredients cannot exist without each other
- Matter cannot exist without form and form cannot exist without matter.
In all reproduction, it was the man who supplied form while the woman stands for matter.
Each dog has a unique shape but consists of the same matter (which would be muscles, bones, blood, etc.).
Therefore, we recognize a dog as a dog, but also as a unique individual.
Therefore, no dog's idea is needed.
Did you want to study the dog you had in front of you would instead use your eyes
Instead of inventing an abstract dog's idea!
This may seem to be an obvious description of the world,
But the theory could not explain how change could happen.
Just change already considered the old natural philosophers to be a major problem,
Why, for example, Zenon meant that reality must be an illusion.
To explain this, Aristotle also introduced the concept of "potential".
Built into all matter, there was the potential to become some things.
In an acorns there is the potential to become an oak, however, not to become a dog.
When something has adopted its form, the potential has been updated.
The thing has now become what it can be.
In addition, there is an intention, one purpose, built into everything.
The reason why the acorn strives to become an oak is to secure the species' survival.
Just like his predecessor Plato was Aristotle interested in how to create
The perfect society - something he describes in the book Politiken.
Here he shows a much more pragmatic, and to some extent conservative, attitude than Plato.
He was positive to the Athenian democracy -
This despite the fact that he was not allowed to vote himself because he was not born in the city -
But defends the then prevailing view of women and slaves as lower standing.
Democracy was a matter only for free men, he said.
He assumed that man was a social being,
A political animal that wanted to live with other people.
For this to work, a strict hierarchy was required;
At the bottom of the slave then the children, the wife and at the top man.
This was the natural order and the system would lead to good and safe life.
When the individual has accepted her role, she also becomes happy.
The state's task was to help each family, and, by extension, every individual, to reach this good life.
In the book "The Nikomachian ethics" Aristotle describes its view of ethics and morality.
According to Aristotle, man has a special position in nature.
We are not controlled by instincts but by reason and free will.
We also have no congenital knowledge of right and wrong, good or bad,
Without this, we must learn through training.
We become friendly by performing friendly actions, moderate by performing moderate actions, etc.
By developing and refining their virtues, its positive qualities, we will become better people.
Thus we will automatically act right in different situations
Then good documents originate from good traits.
There are two types of virtues - moral and intellectual.
A good person is also a happy person, Aristotle says.
We all strive to live as social creatures in a society, something that a virtuous person is easy for.
To become virtuous, we must have a balanced attitude to our emotions and desires.
Where this golden middle ground goes varies from person to person, but he gives some simple examples:
Courage is the balance between dumbness and cowardice, generosity is the balance between waste and greed.
The goal of happiness thus goes by learning to become a balanced personality - to be adequate.
As a philosopher, Aristotle was in many ways different from his predecessors.
His research was systematic and based on careful observations of the world
And his philosophy is mostly about what we would call science today.
Thus, there is a clear link between Aristotle and the natural philosophers.
Throughout his life, he immersed himself in research in a way that is unparalleled in Western history,
And his influence is difficult to overestimate.
His geocentric worldview, but the earth in the middle and the planets revolve around this,
was prevailing until the 16th century when Nicolaus Copernicus, Galileo Galilei and Tycho Brahe
Could prove the heliocentric worldview - that it is the sun that is at the center.
This was largely due to the fact that the Catholic Church used his thoughts to construct his worldview.
The Bible's view of creation is also compatible with Aristotle's view
that everything has a built -in purpose, an intention.
To be able to conduct his science, he needed deeper insight into how correct conclusions worked.
The rules for this were not yet known, after which Aristotle created what is today known as logic.
It was not until the end of the 19th century that this logic came to be further developed into what it is today.
Aristotle's engaging with virtually all the sciences of the time, except for mathematics,
And was probably the most learned man of antiquity.
He was the one who mapped many of the sciences we have today - and studies rhetoric or dramaturgy
Is it still Aristotle's virtually unchanged works that you read.
His categorization of plants and animals were prevailing
Until Carl von Linné launched his systematization during the 18th century.
To manage his research, he categorized philosophy in four different categories:
Physics, metaphysics, logic and ethics.
This is a division that we, with some modification, still have today.
We have relatively good knowledge of Aristotle's philosophy
As more of his texts are preserved than from any other antique philosopher.
What is preserved is mainly lecture manuscript (47 pieces),
But unfortunately, all of his books have disappeared.