Now we are going to the first block of the day.
Where is the limit for what to do and express?
It is a discussion in the borderland between aesthetics, politics and human rights -
- But also power, which Anna touched so wisely in the introduction.
It has never been hotter than right now, it feels like.
We now have the opportunity to take the discussion in depth and it is fun that so many are here.
We are extra happy to have Kerstin Brunnberg here -
- To give us initial fuel for the discussion in today's first "keynote".
Thanks!
And thank you for emphasizing the importance of collaboration in your invitation.
You could only have said: "Yes, we cooperate well, then."
But the question, of course, arises with whom, who, how and why.
I'll try to give some clues.
The other day I was at Vasavarvet with two six -year -olds.
It was a successful visit with a lot to see and talk about.
A surprising question to me was, "Did you know Gustav Vasa?"
Okay, I look old, but not so old well?
But for the six -year -old, moving between the ship Vaasa, his virtual worlds -
-Radioapan in its iPad, between their books -
- Or between "Fejstajma" with his father who works in the United States sometimes, the issue was no wonder.
He lives in the global contemporary, but seeks the context -
- And we all probably do that a little.
Time, space and contexts are relative concepts.
Today they are more relative than ever -
–In the time count I usually divide into bg and ag-
- Ever "Before and After Google".
But above all, we live in unpredictability now -
- There are some things snail in small, imperceptible steps and other things go very fast.
The slow is perhaps more important to pay attention than the fast.
Clearly, a number of major events exist to point to -
- As I mean has changed our everyday lives more than we might think -
- And given rise to some things.
The 2008 financial crisis, which led to liberalization -
–And Riksbank that took the place in front of politics by printing money.
Politics stood quite empty.
No one could point out a long -term plan for a new era -
- It is less secure that the money was used for real investments.
They actually went to short -term consumption -
–And to people who did not engage in research, climate -
—The art, education or acquired new skills -
- Out more to consume.
In this context, the lobbyists were more fast -paced than politics.
The financial crisis, globalization, new technology are all roles in a drama -
- Which is real and is neither at HBO nor at the cinema.
These forces together have doubtfully created an economic inequality -
–A which creates even greater conditions for those who see how digitization can be used -
- And who then uses it to pick the lowest hanging fruits.
It leads to a redistribution to some who can all -
—A — from Facebook to make money on digital solutions -
- which does not really lead to us all keeping up.
The banks do not have to employ cashiers and others get rid of the job.
There are those who have to move from the place where they live -
- And those who have to come here because they flee from direct threats.
Therefore the migration is the solution for these people -
- And properly handled it will also be a solution for Sweden.
But politics has a hard time responding to changes -
- For it works with democracy as a process or with consultants, and it takes some time.
These are more serious explanations for the fact that democracy in our time is questioned and weakened -
- Like its institutions.
Populism and nationalism easily take place where politics backs.
Populism becomes the power of the person who has been powerless when the large industry moved -
–And then when even the replacement job, in the form of a call center, moved to Moldova -
- Or when the robots take over the mining.
When Sweden went from an agricultural country to an industrial nation, many were needed.
Today, the change forces may create digitalisation and new technology very good -
- But also concerns and wonder about the major changes that have gone fast or slowly.
It becomes the perfect soil and nutrition ate the forces -
–Do, undemocratic, racist, religious oppressive, violent and huge -
-And just waiting to come back and promise you that everything will be like before -
- And is reminiscent of the need for nationalism.
The Nazi forces have not been away -
- I am in my simplicity thought they could never come back.
On the contrary, they have just expected, grown and take over where politics leaves a void.
Holocaust deniers and open racism are two things I didn't think would come back.
John Sifton, who is the head of Human Rights Watch in Asia, speaks om-
- How the entire human rights thinking after the Second World War has weakened.
Democracy is under attack.
Journalist Per Wirtén writes in his excellent book about Europe -
- The fear characterized the past, not our future, but it has changed.
Now we have reason to be afraid when we see the development in our neighboring areas -
–As in Hungary and Poland where you make it easy for themselves and change the independence of the courts
- Just by retiring the judges who do not judge as the power likes.
The transition from one to the other is creeping -
- And we have to watch out when the transformation takes place and when the lie becomes truth.
Why then talk about it when we talk about freedom of speech, art and culture?
Well, because the anti -democratic forces that now act in different ways -
–And that pops up on streets, in organizations and political congregations -
–And who more than others understands to seem digitally ...
There is one thing they see as their greatest resistance and as most important to fight -
- And it is freedom of speech, which is a prerequisite for independent media and art.
For they cannot control people's experience of art-
- And has realized that its effect of influence is so great and therefore they want to censor in different ways.
Now I am not talking about the performance "Krilon" at the Stadsteatern in Stockholm -
–To on reality in Sweden and in Europe.
PEN, ICORN AND FREEMUSE are organizations that have spoken about - in their reports
- How independent art scares these anti -democratic forces in Sweden and the world.
The close to 30 sanctuary artists found here in Sweden right now -
–And that has been able to stay here after the two years that the scholarship means -
-Is an overly unused resource to understand and tell about what is an irreplaceable asset -
- Fair art and how the fragile art lives -
- And what a professional ban for artistic work means.
Those organizations have also warned for a long time, just like the media and artists -
- If what really happens.
Together with the climate experts, such as Rachel Carson and his Palmstierna -
- As a long time spoke about the climate ...
All those who have pointed to what's happening have received as much attention from us -
- As the cabin crew talks about the security before the flight.
Therefore, the attacks on democracy are now a moss fire in our country -
- But an open fire in many other countries.
And that is why the role of art has never been as challenged and important to defend as now.
"It was fun to hear," you think.
But many people joined when many refugees came to Sweden -
- And worked together and made a difference.
Very many joined together when the fires raged this summer.
In the same way, we must arrange joint forces -
- To take back the political void that Per Wirtén and Daniel Poohl speak om-
- In their analyzes of the time we live in now.
Our time requires more than other collaboration and responsibility for each other.
No question can be solved today without cooperation and conversation.
I will not list all the abuse that we are told every day -
–But urges you to follow Pen, Freemuse and Reporters Without Borders -
-a couple of times a week.
You can support them just as you support Amnesty.
These organizations are not special interests, but everyone's representatives.
What should be done?
Yes, what should you and I do as individuals?
First, we will pay for the art, with both common and own resources.
Secondly, we should respect copyright.
As little as we with lowered taxes can afford to obtain your own ambulance -
–Or can build your own art museum or opera house -
- So we will together finance the conditions for the art.
The public has a responsibility for everyone to have access to art throughout the country -
–And therefore support systems must be created that are reasonable -
- For artists to be artists.
Harry Schein writes in his book "Can we afford culture?"
From 1962 ...
I actually have to quote him.
Now let's see ... I'm browsing.
"Requirements for increased community support to culture are usually rejected" -
- "With references to the state financial situation."
"The uninvited artist in economic things then leaves the office" -
- "with a vague feeling that a higher income for his or her part" -
- "would cause a state bank route, mass unemployment and inflation."
"He or she does not know that the state financial argument is stated" -
- "To justify all rejections on grant requirements that are not directly silly."
Some of the suggestions that are on the next government's table -
- From the artist's political investigation is both renewal, understandable and handy.
They point to the need to reduce detail regulation -
–But also on the fact that the state must take responsibility -
- Because the artists' conditions are also generally improved.
The social insurance system is an example.
The main focus should be that responsible decision -making bodies design criteria -
- For which artists should be eligible to receive artist policy support.
The authorities themselves should, not the government.
Cultural policy is probably the most difficult policy area.
It is easy to measure that the speed trains go faster -
- But much more difficult to measure what art and culture really do for use.
I can only say that cultural policy is really simple.
Money will be in and lots of money to be distributed so that the independence of art is maintained.
But it is so vulnerable when it gets into the hands of those who want something else -
–And easy for new genres and forms of art to be covered either -
- When it is an overly detailed support system.
That's why Schein says, which I quote for the second time:
"Rather too many bad artists than too few good."
But without detracting an important discussion on political control of culture and art-
- It is still at present perhaps as a western fan -
- compared to when in Harry Schein's book also read his description -
–As how the then Ministry of Commerce opposed the proposal -
- If the stage artists' salaries would be listed as everyone else was paid.
The Ministry said: "Wouldn't it be better if they played plays that were more crowded?"
"Then they would get more revenue."
It might as well have been that a department had said -
- That Swedish Radio does not need so many channels, especially not P3.
Or: would it not be good to put down the symphony orchestra in Gävle -
- Or the bytheater in Kalmar?
These are some of the Swedish Democrats designated, threatened candidates - the closure -threatened candidates -
- As Anders Rydell describes in his excellent article in Svenska Dagbladet.
Now is the third and last time I quote Harry Schein.
It is a joy to read his uncompromising demands on what sought -sought -
- In the Cultural Council's working groups or the Artists' Committee's assessments.
Assessments and distribution of support must therefore be made on the basis of professional quality criteria.
The cultural policy work must be conducted according to strictly artistic quality principles.
"Therefore, members of support distribution institutions should be appointed" -
- "From the artistic disciplines' own main expertise" -
- "And a statutory compulsory circulation is carried out to prevent academic."
"But also for some years after year to decide the public quality valuation."
It can be changed.
Schein calls this undemocratic for someone who pays taxes.
Sure, but each one has the right to their own taste.
"But assessments of support requires as much special and specialized knowledge" -
- "Like, for example, science. Therefore, the quality requirement is not undemocratic."
He predicts significant political difficulties to get through this -
- But the reasons for are so big.
He also describes how the professional art -
—As with its ability to go before contemporary contemporary -
–An spread like rings on the water -
–And develops the art that no one could imagine.
Other that needs to be done: lower the digital VAT.
Don't talk about it, but do it.
One can also wish for a more sincere recognition of the value of copyright -
–Os players like Spotify, Google, Facebook and Amazon -
- And that the artists' compensation should not be seen as a gate of goodwill.
Support and develop the system of sanctuary artists -
- which are not individuals, but principles for showing ...
... to show what freedom of speech is really worth and how fragile it is.
The Migration Board must be getting better at showing artists -
–Ast come from different countries where visas are required to come here -
- And not be afraid that they will stay.
The school must show early on what art and creativity really are.
That it is as important as math and physics.
The interesting thing then is that you speak so much about the fact that cooperation is growing in importance.
The cooperation which means that in a certain situation also release the control, delegate responsibility -
–Emen Detail management and accepting a process of changing conditions -
- Where the foundation is something as banal and basic as trust.
How, then, should we deal with the gap in between - control versus confidence?
It's a question for this day.
But remember one thing:
Art has no task more than being art.
For the art, as Benny Fredriksson has said, the inexplicable defenders -
- In a time that wants to explain everything and forget what cannot be explained.
Thanks so much.
Thanks for a great deal of fuel for the discussion.
I am now inviting the first panel of the day.
Lars Anders Johansson from Timbro, well.
We all applaud together when they are invited.
Ulrica Källén, operations manager at Klys and a member of the Swedish UNESCOR Council.
And Carolina Frände who is a director.
We welcome them with an applause.
Now Kerstin has deservedly spoken warmly to freedom -
- And at the same time we have the word limit in our themes.
I start by asking the question how the panel looks at that perspective.
Is there a far limit or no limit at all?
Here you go.
Who wants to jump in there?
- Should I start from the artist perspective?
-Yes please.
Freedom of speech for the artistic professionals -
- Should be as wide as possible, but there are boundaries.
We have legislation and a society.
Art is in a social context that naturally affects.
It is impossible to say where the limit goes.
It varies from time to time and depending on the situation.
So I can't answer that question.
But the development we see is alarming.
From Klys and my work I can say -
–Ad every time the freedom of speech is limited we react -
- And trying to oppose us that development in referral opinions and other things.
Do you then think of the political governance -
- Or on the development of the expressions that exist in the public space today?
I think of the political governance -
- But also on what Kerstin was in, the conditions of the cultural creator.
That the conditions look like this today-
—To you as an artist do not always have the opportunity to dare to express you -
- Dare to experiment and provoke in the way society needs.
It is a limitation that we are very concerned about.
Thanks.
- You are welcome.
Freedom of speech and political governance often collapse.
As Ulrica says, self -censorship is an almost equal threat -
- As a kind of political restriction on freedom of expression.
I have seen ROP - for a number of years
- On the fact that one should restrict the possibilities of commenting in the public space.
On Dagens Nyheter's cultural site, we have been able to read calls for private companies -
- To start limiting the opinions expressed on Facebook and so on.
The sitting government had a meeting with Youtube -
- About how to limit access to dissatisfied views.
On Youtube it is the same group ...
This has a number of strange consequences.
On Facebook, people can come together against political opponents with mass notifications -
- And then Facebook removes the posts or even closes by people.
It becomes a kind of bully mentality where you silence those you disagree.
On Youtube we have seen how counterproductive this will be.
You may read about the Swedish Democrats' film about the Social Democrats -
- Then was removed from Youtube?
It had several consequences.
On the one hand, the Swedish Democrats were able to put on their martyrki web that they like to wear.
In this individual case, it was also well deserved.
On the one hand, the debate was not about whether the image they conveyed in their film was true -
- Out whether they had been silenced.
So even opponents of the Sweden Democrats shot themselves in the foot -
- When their film was removed.
There are many examples where one supposedly good purpose -
- Sying deviating opinions, and so it has exactly the opposite consequence.
The Facebook algorithm's change in February this year when you were to make Facebook more enjoyable.
Zuckerberg's purpose was that we would not get irrelevant things in our flows.
But it has led to the consequence that the hate sites have increased their traffic -
- At the expense of other sites, thus the exact opposite result for what they were sought.
The platforms go through what democracy went through too long ago on limits.
They are experimenting with it now but do not want to listen to anyone else, so that's a problem.
Do you want to jump into the discussion?
We who are engaged in the direct artistic activity often have a self -image -
–This our institutions where the art is done in a way is unusual -
- Of the freedom of speech and border problems.
We can no longer take that for granted in any way.
We must think about how we can professionalize the part of the institutions -
– Or the parts of the art -practicing side -
- Which receives the political assignments.
We talk a lot about political governance, but often forget the intermediary.
There is a political governance, and then hand over to some -
- As either distributes the money or does the art.
We also have a tendency to get stuck in the contradiction -
- Between cultural bureaucracy, or art bureaucracy ...
That is what the practicing world often calls the exercise of authority -
- And other types of interest organizations in cultural bureaucratic field.
We fast in a contradiction between artistic practice and cultural bureaucracy -
- When we should go together.
Kerstin talked about the fact that there is a void that the policy leaves there now.
I also identify that void in the art.
I am a primarily performing artist.
Although I have been a manager for about fifteen years, I can see -
- The movement that exists in politics is just as much in the art.
When it becomes too combustible or too hot to enter into an ideological debate -
- So we would rather renounce and talk about the arts -
–Com by using the argument for the being of art that Kerstin brought up -
- The art should be nothing but art.
As if that were an argument-
- To refrain from interfering with opinions about freedom of speech or artistic freedoms.
It is extremely important to set boundaries, just as you started by saying.
Borders are crucial for artistic freedom to prevail.
Those limits should in some way formulate the principles, agreements -
- And other things that many people in artistic practice often find boring.
Policies and stuff.
Because if we cannot defend human rights within the institutions -
- And we can't really today, then we can't expect to be able to keep the art free.
I led a media investigation recently -
- Where we had with the democracy requirement and what you are in, and that is a combustible issue.
Those standing on the freedom of speech-fundamentalist side-
- I think that this is an intervention and that the limit is too narrow.
I want to say two things.
One is that you have become aware of how fragile the system is.
How easy it is to change for those who want to change it.
But also what you are in with social media -
- As you can love on the one hand, but hate just as much.
There are no democratic structures -
- This means that we get to know what it is we are not told and who is stopped.
When Facebook is editor of what is written on Facebook -
- I'll be dark scared.
There, anything can come in and start controlling it.
We see today as I do in my naivety -
- Near did not think could occur.
The second, that Carolina takes up ...
Who has said that in the production of art should not advise -
—The common decency; human rights -
- Jimination and respect?
Then I have to say that what the art does, I shit in that.
But in the production of art, in the collaboration ...
Then all support systems have a tendency to become guiding -
- Propping of self -censorship, and therefore you need to discuss them.
If I am going to take on the fundamentalists that we have not represented in the panel -
- So they would say that when we instrumentalize the art expressions in that way -
–And says things that are okay at this time as it can be a danger -
- As every time has its taboos.
Now we have broken a taboo with "metoo" that you couldn't talk about five to ten years ago-
- And could not express in any way.
What do you say about it?
There has never been any legislation against talking about Metoo.
It has been a norm simply -
–And that's what I think is interesting, in what you said Kerstin -
- If we must be able to create reasonable production conditions and working conditions.
It has nothing to do with what is then said in the art.
Absolutely nothing.
We are still living in a mythology of a little worse working conditions -
- There is a little "ruff" climate, provides better art.
I have worked for 20 years as a director and am a living proof that it is not true.
Had it been, I would not have been in the profession.
If it had been a compulsion to have poor working conditions.
I think that within the artistic we actually need to evaluate -
- This is the structure and not the content.
Thus, the structure for collaboration and so on.
- We easily slide there between the different parts.
- An important distinction.
If one is a freedom of speech fundamentalist -
—To one is aware that publicly controlled organizations -
—Recodes the ideology that characterizes public operations -
- Then I am happy to take that role.
I think it's a pretty nice concept.
Unsurprisingly, maybe I do not share Kerstin Brunnberg's view -
–In the introductory lecture -
–If that would mean an increase in artistic freedom -
– That one shifts power from civil society and the private sector -
- To public institutions.
I rather believe that there is a danger there, due to public institutions -
- All time will reproduce the values of political power that prevail at the moment.
The only way to counteract this is institutional competition -
- Over if we talk about private or publicly funded institutions.
The more concentration of power in the cultural field, the less artistic freedom.
Should we have two cultural councils then?
- Yes, it would be good if there was one for cultural council.
- Attach, then!
Artistic freedom occurs in the space between the institutions.
You can never order artistic freedom from a political point of view.
What you can do is not limit artistic freedom.
Do you want a reply?
You get it.
We think it is good that there are several authorities -
–Or works with the field of cultural and artist policy-
- Because we complement each other, have different knowledge and support different parts of the area.
I just want to say that the state has a great responsibility, as well as regions and municipalities.
But the private, you ...
Private donors have a huge responsibility -
- And probably a great interest in there being both parts.
But there is so much of art that must actually be supported by our common resources.
You have to point that.
It's harder to go to the neighbor and say: Can't you spend your money on art?
I have some respect for those who support art with their private resources.
You said that tax cuts never led to increased cultural financing.
It is not true because the shift in power took place -
–Bae by the state expanding its commitments -
- And that they undermined the opportunities for private financing.
So it was a two -way process.
Then it is so that most of the cultural life is funded by all of us with private funds -
- So all are cultural power to a greater or lesser extent.
But that is the problem with part of the public funding -
-It the target conflict that always exists -
- And that cannot be bridged with the principle of arm's length.
Namely that our elected representatives -
- Must be able to demand some form of detectable results -
- From the operations that are financed.
There, after all, there is a contradiction between the freedom of art -
- And the rather sad reality found in all politically controlled activities.
That is exactly what is the problem with providing resources.
So the state, the public, should support media and art.
- That's the problem.
- Now that debate is over.
- But how do you make it less brittle?
--Ulrica wants to jump in.
From KLYS, we are for a variety of sources of financing.
The private initiatives can work supplementary and promote artistic freedom -
- But it is incredibly important that there are public institutions -
- Which are strong and that we can invest more in.
The important thing in terms of them is the second line at arm's length-principle-
–Stious that the artistic assessment is to be made by independent experts -
- And preferably cultural creators, in reference groups such as at the Cultural Council and the Artists' Committee.
That part of that principle is for guaranteeing the freedom of art -
- And that officials should not interfere in the content.
I want to say that in that.
This is a bit of value with value.
You were on it in your introduction, Kerstin.
So when the recipient becomes a consumer and how we look at the value of art.
How to measure it.
Your cane horses were around short -term and long -term.
If we dare to reflect on where we are on that scale today -
- And where we are going.
You were on freedom of speech.
Facebook does not see itself as a platform for freedom of speech -
- The without defining itself as entertainment.
How do we look at different arenas and what does it do with the value?
Maybe I'm a little too philosophical?
I read media researcher Mike Ananny who turns on freedom of speech:
"We have talked for too long that freedom of speech is about being able to express myself."
"We haven't talked enough about my right to hear different perspectives."
The transferred sense may be able to kick off a discussion about the value.
It may not be so concrete.
But the idea of the conversation as a foundation in the artistic communication -
- Over the genre you talk about and also in medial communication.
That is, multi -way communication, not monological communication - not
- Are a very threatened form, I think.
It is also a matter that regardless of the source of funding, one might wonder:
How should we fulfill the idea that I think many of us share -
- If as many people as possible should be able to take part in as much culture and art as possible?
It is also a prerequisite that the participants, the visitors, the audience ...
What you now do for the type of art.
The viewers.
It is a matter of in the power discussion -
- Although include them at the moment of art.
Now it becomes less concrete -
“But I think it is important to think about how they can be included.
Because there will be no art without those who take part in it.
Then there is no art.
I think that in recent years we have been characterized a lot -
- Of a reduced conversation with those who do not like us.
That is why the art is so incredibly interesting.
I once went to the cinema and saw a movie that I didn't really ...
I went alone and afterwards I sneaked after people to hear what they said about it.
I think that is one of the big stuff with art.
Of course, it is an inner experience -
- But what it creates from conversation and discussion with others.
And you should not always agree with each other.
A temperature meter so that the audience does not fall asleep.
How many have backed from participating in some arenas in recent years -
- Because there are different elements that make you not want to be there?
Here we have some self -censorship.
- Lars Anders, you wanted to jump in.
We also have to talk here about the public -
- And the institutions that maintain and constitute that public.
Thus, the joint conversation or the arena where different perspectives have been able to meet -
- But where in recent years we have received an incredibly infected discussion -
- In the limits of this public.
It is called opinion corridor, filter bubbles, etc.
What we have seen now that it has appeared so -called filter bubbles -
–This different opinion clusters just sit and discuss internally -
- is that the public has shrunk, or rather the range of opinion that is accepted.
The one who then does not fit into the center -hold -
- Risk to be completely frozen from the public conversation.
Then we instead get a downpour public or several different public.
It also provides that kind of moods -
-When people who do not feel welcome in the public arenas -
- Experience that there is an establishment that keeps them out.
Here I believe that all actors, ie public cultural institutions - -
—The public and private media houses -
- And opinion leaders in social media, have a great responsibility.
There has always been a limit to what is accepted and not in the public conversation -
–But become these limits too narrow, other publics will arise -
- Where different perspectives do not meet.
Now there is research that says that is not really true.
There are proper reports that we get broader networks and inflow in social media -
- Enta in the bubbles that we actually live in.
This is a bubble that we sit in - the cultural bubble.
It is important to say.
- You wanted to say something.
I think you are right in it to some extent.
A few years ago I did a performance that was about Ayn Rand.
The interesting thing about it was all new meetings I received.
People I had never met from another public, if it is now divided.
But also the pretty strong reactions I received from my own industry -
–When did not think it was right in its place -
- To lift a self -appointed ...
... philosopher, but also writers, and her thoughts as part of a public conversation.
So of course it needs to develop -
- This is to broaden what is to be talked about.
It does not deal with political positions per se, but about a story and a conversation.
What I also think you have to do -
-Is to lift himself out of its own permanent world of imagination about something -
–And actually seriously take part in a different perspective -
- As you did not think you would think was interesting.
It is something that rests us all, to move our own performance limits.
It feels like a good rounding comment.
The logo for this context has been a wave.
When we get more freedom, we also get more responsibility -
- And it is very much the case as individuals.
We should get a broad picture of everything before we decide.
It is about a broad influx.
To hear a lot of voices -
- But also to take in different parts of the cultural landscape.
That's something we all have to carry with us.
A closing word from the rest of you?
I just want to get back to how important an offensive artist policy is -
- For artistic freedom.
Not just the artist policy supports -
- Without what Kerstin mentioned, the social security for freelance cultural creators -
–And copyright.
If we are arranged for those systems, the artistic freedom will be greater -
- For professional cultural creators in Sweden.
I want to be the gloomy person - then
–And warn of how dangerous an offensive artist policy can be for the artistic freedom-
- If it ends up in the wrong hands.
Wrong hands, yes.
I think it's extremely important that all -
- So from cultural bureaucracy as an employer perspective - -
–And the union side ...
That everyone is struggling in the same direction of professionalizing the cultural and art area-
- For it will probably help us a bit on the road.
- Kerstin, a closing word?
- I just stood here and took in.
- Yes, we would listen.
-Yes exactly.
I just want to agree with you, Lars Anders -
–If this with how to adapt -
- After systems, rules and criteria.
It is fatal and therefore it is so difficult with support systems for art and media.
- Even if you have the solution.
-No I do not think so.
A large applause to the panel.